Previously on The Primal Hunter

Finally, out of the Tutorial, Jake is able to actually explore Earth and see what the transformed planet has to offer. And what it has to offer is a giant lightning tree on a massive cloud island he can check out together with his newly-gained hawk friend, which Jake naturally named Hawkie (yes, yes, very original name, but in his defense, it is a hawk).

On the way up to this cloud island, Jake and Hawkie kill a bunch of birds before finally encountering enemies that arrows do not work against: living clouds. Cloud Elementals, to be more exact. Not to worry, though, Jake had not wasted his time on learning mana-manipulation for nothing as he goes full-on mage to beat them. That is until he gets a notification that his Pylon of Civilization is under attack.

Flashing back a few days (because everyone loves flashbacks), we see that at his newly established “city” consisting of four people and a wooden lodge, Miranda, his newly employed City Lord, is figuring out her abilities—until a party of five appears nearby and makes contact. After some conversation, Miranda comes to learn that they are being chased. The group ends up staying, and they begin preparations for the upcoming attack.

The attackers are a group led by two comically evil characters, Abby and Donald, the cousin and uncle of Neil. Abby is a space mage, and Donald is a guy with a cursed sword who literally walks a path of power where he abuses and kills women and traps their souls. Yeah… maybe I overdid that one a bit, but I kind of wanted to show that the system was neutral when it came to morality, and even fucked up Paths were possible. And, hey, exaggeration increases understanding, right?

Anyway, evil attackers arrive, a fight ensues, and the good guys are obviously losing until a very pissed-off Jake returns, thinking Miranda has betrayed him and tried to steal the Pylon. After Jake understands the situation, we have one of those stereotypical face-slapping moments where he beats Abby and Donald, killing both and even stealing the cursed sword. Totally not something he can make into something very useful later.

It also turns into a great opportunity to finally expand the budding settlement further, even getting a space mage to join them. After this whole debacle, Jake flies off again to join his hawk friend and get some more levels. Shortly after returning to the cloud continent, Jake gets his final skill in E-grade and manages to kill his very first D-grade. His prowess impresses Hawkie enough that he invites Jake back to meet his family.

That is how Jake would come to meet a Mystsong Hawk (naturally called Mystie) and the mother of a baby hawk-to-be, as she is guarding an egg within a ritual circle to help strengthen the baby.

Throughout this all, our favorite snake god is also busy doing the usual snake god stuff, like killing gods from factions that refuse to fuck off or become his subordinates and taking over the massive planet the Order of the Malefic Viper is placed on. Good stuff all around on his end.

Back with Jake, the poor guy gets convinced to help with a ritual, and all he needs to do is help kill another D-grade. He does this by acting like human artillery, and he returns to help with the ritual. During the ritual, Jake does “stuff” and ends up influencing it a bit more than initially intended, something her parents sure would be happy for in the future. Jake gets given the egg to him to care for as he carefully carries it back to his lodge, the two hawks deciding to follow along, the presence of a powerful D-grade not at all disturbing to those there.

Not long after, Jake is asked to come along and finally make contact with another human settlement, making him leave Haven for something other than killing stuff… even if every damn reader of this genre knew that this little adventure would lead to killing stuff too.

This other settlement is an old fort that has been taken over by a guy called Phillip and is run by him (there is also a guy named Arnold here who makes drones and stuff. Not an important character at all, barely worth mentioning). The Fort is also under constant attack by angry monster cows, and they are having quite the problems, so of course, Jake steps up to help them with their bovine issues.

They repel the attack. Jake notices sketchy stuff, heads off, and does some actual tracking to figure out what the cause of these attacks is. He finds the source, a D-grade Minotaur Mindchief that has remembered his less-than-pleasant times in captivity and has some legitimate complaints about the farming industry. Sadly for the Minotaur, his hatred had turned into pure hate for humanity as a whole, and even more sadly for the Minotaur, it turned out to be specialized in mental magic. A school of magic, it turns out someone with a Bloodline to act not based thinking is quite good against

Jake ends up killing the Minotaur, but not before it unleashes its entire horde of angry cows upon the Fort. This ends up only being a chance for the D-grade hawk Mystie to show off by defending the Fort with Myst magic by summoning magical beasts and stuff.

After all this, Jake heads back to his settlement again and leaves Miranda and the others to handle the diplomacy stuff. Back there, he does some alchemy, upgrades some stuff, strengthens his hatred of blue mushrooms by nearly getting killed by the one below the settlement as it turns out to be a powerful D-grade, and prepares for the egg to hatch.

Surprising no one, the baby hawk egg hatches as a Sylphian Eyas, a far more powerful variant than either of her parents.

This baby hawk is named Sylphie. That is at least more of a real name than her parents. Jake quickly comes to like this cute and very eloquent baby hawk. Who doesn’t like cute murder birds, right?

With a baby hawk to take care of, Jake chills a bit with the hunting for a while. Chilling in this context meaning more alchemy and preparing to kill the hated mushroom that nearly killed him. But this time, with science!

The guy Arnold I just told you not to worry about comes in here and provides some poison injectors to poison the ground the mushroom is growing in. A bit later, Jake also finally does some transmutations and upgrades Touch of the Malefic Viper by taking the cursed scimitar from earlier that I also told you wouldn’t be important and turning it into something important.

Oh yeah, a bunch of stuff also happens to secondary characters in this book. Carmen, from the intermission I know you all read in book 2, claims a Pylon and most other notable figures on Earth (most of which were introduced in the Intermissions. Read the damn Intermissions) also claims Pylons, and it is announced that soonish the World Congress will begin, finally allowing the scattered Earthlings to meet.

Miranda also ends up getting blessed by the Verdant Witches, allies of the Malefic Viper, making her position as Jake’s de facto assistant (read: babysitter) official. They also decide to name the “city” Haven (yeah, I know, it sounds generic, but a bit of fun trivia here. Haven also means “the garden” in my native language, and I thought it fit, so suck it).

Back with Jake, his plans for the D-grade mushroom end up working out, and he kills the damn thing. With his arch-nemesis killed, it is some to evolve to D-grade himself to truly show the blue bastard who is boss.

The evolution to D-grade turns out to be rather uneventful, at least for his race. When it comes to class, it is a bit more exciting as Jake becomes an Avaricious Arcane Hunter, getting a far better variant of class than what he had in E-grade, as well as some cool skills. He flexes a bit on the hawk family before moving on to the profession.

After upgrading his profession to Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper (quite a mouthful, I know), Jake gets a new skill to see Records of the past related to the Malefic Viper. He does this and sees a vision of back when Villy was only C-grade, all with the purpose of letting him experience the Legacy skills of his Patron.

After that, Jake sees it is only five and a half days to the World Congress, but he still decides to head out and learn about his newfound power a bit. Heading out, he—

Oh, wait, this was where I decided to end book 3.

Book 4, go!

Chapter 1

A Real Shitfest

The figure leaped from atop the tree and flew several hundred meters through the air, landing on another crown before swiftly taking off once more. A few beasts below considered attacking, but once they felt the difference in grade and power, they swiftly changed their minds.

It was far over three hundred kilometers from Haven, and the density of trees was only increasing. Furthermore, many of the beasts were now reaching around level 80. It was a bit deeper in than where Mystie and Hawkie had placed their nest back before they relocated to the city.

The figure was naturally Jake, who had decided to ditch the wings and do some tree-hopping instead. Would flying be faster? Most definitely, but making massive leaps from tree to tree just felt awesome.

One Step Mile wasn’t that useable due to the sheer density of trees making it hard to travel in a straight line on the ground. The trunks could be many meters in radius and reach hundreds of meters into the air, reminding him a bit of the outer area of the tutorial.

Thinking about it, perhaps the tutorial forest had been inspired by the true forest here on the reformed planet—or was it the other way around? Maybe a bit of both? Either way, it wasn’t the first time he had noted the familiarity. It was quite certain this wasn’t the same thing, though…

Because sadly, no lockboxes.

Jake wanted some new gear soon. His whole getup was beginning to feel a bit dated, even if it had only been a few months. The only great pieces of gear he really had were his necklace, mask, new scimitar, and, surprisingly enough, boots.

Were those boots the ones with the lowest required level and still only rare rarity? Sure, but they were also still the toughest damn things he had besides his mask, which he still hadn’t managed to put even a slight scratch on.

He doubted he would find anything within this forest, but one could always be hopeful. Even if he couldn’t find a lockbox, maybe he could find some good materials to use in the future.

One might wonder why Jake didn’t use his newly upgraded Touch of the Malefic Viper to transmute his current gear, and the reason for that was quite simple… because he was ninety percent sure it would end up making the majority of his gear worse than it currently was.

Jake’s version had to rely on the existing enchants, and as his many tests had shown, using Touch would ruin what was already placed on the gear. A lot of his gear had stat-giving effects, and Jake honestly had no idea how to replicate that. The only thing he would do was turn those stats into possibly making the armor poison people touching it, or maybe use his arcane affinity to make the armor a lot more durable. Oh, or he could make it self-destruct by transmuting it with a shitload of the destructive part of his arcane mana.

Quite honestly, he would prefer just to have stats over that.

The only item he was considering actually transmuting was his Windsoar Bow. It wasn’t because he didn’t want or like the enchant on it; in fact, he found its ability to remove wind resistance and even turn the wind into an assisting force to be damn good. No, the issue was that he feared it would break if he didn’t.

Arcane Powershot was not a gentle skill. Far from it. While he charged the attack, the bow and his body would both be put under considerable strain, and the bow would be forced to absorb obscene amounts of energy and have the highly destructive mana also coat its exterior.

He could handle his body breaking a bit—that would heal by itself—but he couldn’t handle his weapon suddenly exploding in the middle of a fight. He still vividly remembered how the first Infused Powershot he’d ever used absolutely destroyed the tutorial starting bow.

Without a new bow or transmuting his current one, he feared that could happen in not that long. For now, it was fine as the bow still held up, but as time went on, it would surely become an issue. Not just because he gained levels or more stats, but also just because he would get better at using the skill and pour more mana into it.

Actually… can it handle a full-throttle Arcane Powershot with Limit Break active at 20% as it is? he suddenly wondered, remembering that he had never used Arcane Powershot while using his Limit Break. Yeah, I really don’t know.

The wisest decision would likely be for Jake to stop now and just transmute the damn bow already, but he really didn’t want to. His entire body felt restless, and he really needed a fight. He had yet to truly battle anything after reaching D-grade, after all. No, the fight with Mystie and Hawkie didn’t count; that had just been a bit of sparring.

Also… he needed to test out his Scimitar of Cursed Hunger, too, didn’t he? It would be a shame if he just one-shot most opponents.

His travel continued for a bit longer, and he noticed barely any beasts below 80 in the area. A few of them saw him and ran away, but some of them acted a bit more suspiciously and began following him. They were these monkey-like creatures with an extremely long tail that they used to swing from tree to tree. They were also surprisingly small for beasts at their level, being only about the size of a chimpanzee.

[Lighttail Monkey – lvl 83]

The name contained "Lighttail," but from what Jake could detect, the "light" in that word didn’t refer to light magic. It was more related to their low weight. He noticed how the small branches they used to swing didn’t even budge, and how they appeared to float a bit through the air with every swing. It was like they weighed nearly nothing at times.

I wonder why they follow me, Jake thought a bit cheekily as he smiled. He didn’t feel any danger from them, but only a strong sense of curiosity. There were more than a dozen on his tail now, with a few more joining every minute.

He also noted how they were the only type of beasts in the area of a decent level. Honestly… it couldn’t be more obvious that this was their territory even if they put up glowing neon signs.

Well, their constant screeching as they followed him also made him believe they weren’t happy with him being there. It was a little rude, actually, and woe would he be if security showed up with a few D-grades.

A few more minutes ticked by. With every passing moment, more monkeys followed him, and Jake felt the entire atmosphere of the area change. It reminded Jake a bit of the mana released by his Pylon, but it was clearly different… Actually… wasn’t it a bit closer to the energy released by the giant lightning tree? Not as in it being lightning affinity, but by how it was powerful and yet "neutral.”

This energy is likely part of the reason why the beasts were able to evolve as they did… The very environment is nurturing them at all times.

Jake even saw a few trees around with budding fruits. None were ripe yet, and he suspected the monkeys ate them as soon as they were, but he believed every one of those fruits on the trees were considered low-level natural treasures.

Ten minutes later, he felt the first aura lock onto him. A few seconds later, a second and a third joined the first one. A small smile crept onto his lips as he sensed that all three of them were D-grades. Finally… he had reached the inner area of the territory of these monkeys.

And one had to remember… he was still in the outer parts of the forest as a whole.

He saw the three of them the same moment they laid their eyes on him. They all looked a lot like their E-grade brethren, but they were slightly larger and had two additional tails instead of only one.

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey – lvl 102]

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey – lvl 103]

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey – lvl 105]

A bit disappointing with their levels, he thought as he saw the many E-grade monkeys surround him in his sphere, all hiding in the trees clustered around the one he occupied. He was standing on a branch nearly a hundred meters in the air, with the three D-grades only a few hundred meters in front of him, just staring him down.

Just as Jake considered if he had to open the show himself, another presence arrived. One quite a lot stronger than the other three… but far from enough to make Jake feel threatened.

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey Crusher – lvl 112]

This one was buffer than the three others, but not much was different from that. It was likely just a more powerful variant of the other three. It had "crusher" in its name too, which was kinda cool, but it also gave away what their powerset was all about.

Weight magic? Gravity? Something like that.

Jake was excited as he summoned his wings and prepared to fight. The moment the two wings appeared, the monkeys saw it as a sign of aggression and attacked. Well, they had planned on attacking all along, based on how they had clearly surrounded him; he had just sped up their decision-making a bit.

With his sphere, he saw the regular E-grade Lighttail Monkeys begin condensing some kind of substance in their hands that they promptly threw after Jake. He instantly had a bad feeling when he noticed the nature of their projectile and didn’t hesitate to dodge.

The substance smashed into the tree and made a dent in the supremely robust bark, clearly showing that some magic had been used on it. It was more condensed, heavier, and more robust than it should naturally be… because Jake saw exactly what the monkey had thrown.

Did you just throw literal shit at me?

That’s right—the monkeys above level 80 used their own shit as their chosen weapon… making Jake’s next move completely and utterly justified.

After swiftly summoning his bow, he turned and fired an arcane arrow. The monkey in his crosshairs didn’t even have time to adequately react before its head was blown off by the exploding arrow, sending monkey parts flying everywhere.

*You have slain [Lighttail Monkey – lvl 81]*

Jake saw the notification, as well as its lack of experience earned. Seems like my theory of only earning experience from higher-leveled or at least equal-leveled opponents is true, he thought as he dodged a pile of poo and retaliated by firing a Splitting Arrow.

The singular arrow appeared to split for a second, but soon the copies lost their shapes. Jake frowned as only the original arrow found its goal and exploded. Dodging a few more shit-slings, he fired one of the non-exploding arrows with Splitting Arrow, and while it appeared for a bit longer than the shot before, it soon fizzled away too.

Splitting Arrow does not work with my Arcane Hunter’s Arrows, he thought, both perplexed and annoyed. The fact that he had to consider how to make the damn skill work while dodging an avalanche of literal shit didn’t help either.

He kept trying to use Splitting Arrow and figure out what was wrong as he fought the E-grade monkeys. The D-grades still hung back for now, but Jake could see they were getting impatient at their lower-ranking brethrens’ inability to hit their target.

Finally, one of the D-grades moved. Its three tails sent a wave of mana towards him, and Jake instantly felt his entire body become heavier as he allowed it to hit him. It was enough to stump him for a fraction of a second and cause a bit of the damn feces to hit his cloak. Thank Villy it only hit the cloak.

The impact from the shit wasn’t an issue, but he instantly noticed that something was off. It was way too damn heavy. Just the small part that hit him weighed down on him, and while it was far from enough to affect him, he suddenly understood the strategy of these monkeys.

They would pelt their target with shit, covering them in the substance to weigh them down… and then the D-grades would move in and enhance the target’s weight even more, amplifying the effect and effectively crippling the target.

It was actually a pretty sound strategy that Jake could see working well on many beasts, especially larger ones. It also allowed the entire tribe to fight together, and the D-grade didn’t have to risk their lives that often. Of course, the whole strategy did have a few weaknesses. Okay, a lot of weaknesses.

Now, while he did find out that the damn stuff was very adhesive and even resisted his mana when he tried to push it off, it wasn’t impossible. He could also just toss the cloak away if it really became an issue. Or, you know, just summon mana shields or something.

On top of that, there were also the far simpler solutions of just not being hit at all, fighting them with ranged attacks, or using a mix of both like Jake was doing. The strategy also wouldn’t be that effective against larger groups of enemies.

Seeing their initial tactic fail, the three other D-grades also joined the fray. One of the three regular Tri-Lighttails kept sending the weird weight magic against Jake while the other two whipped their tails his way. He wondered what they were up to until he felt the air bend.

BOOM!

Two massive blasts of force were sent after him, exploding the branch he had just been standing on. One of the two that had just fired the blast after him then retreated and began using some kind of magic on the big boy: the Crusher.

They fought like a team, making it quite clear this group of monkeys had battled together before. Sadly… they stood before a foe far above their own level of strength.

Jake bent backward as a massive tail swipe from the Crusher passed over him and obliterated a tree to his side. Another tail quickly came down like a scorpion stinger as the hunter stepped on the air and retreated a bit with a flap of his wings.

First, that one.

He used the space he had opened up to fire a quick Arcane Powershot towards the Tri-Lighttail Monkey that was slowing him down. It tried to dodge at the last moment but found itself frozen by a glance from Jake, and was hit square in the chest.

The arrow didn’t explode, but rather pierced through it, leaving a large hole and sending it flying more than a hundred meters through the forest, pingponging between trees on the way. It wasn’t dead, but it was out of commission for now.

Next.

Chapter 2

Enhanced Splitting Arrow

The three remaining monkeys watched as their comrade was blasted away in shock, but it only made them more aggressive than before.

With one down, he turned his attention to the Crusher. It came at him with tails swinging and arms flailing, now even more berserk than before. It was pretty strong but not very fast, and Jake easily evaded its simple movements as he took out his melee weapons.

In a fluid motion, he ran his palms over both, drawing blood and coating them in Blood of the Malefic Viper. Venomfang felt oddly frail in his hand as he held it, and he knew the weapon would soon be unable to keep up with his progress. Speaking honestly, he had a feeling it would soon break anyway, him growing stronger or not. The weapon had been through a lot, and he would prefer for it not to break entirely.

But for this hunt you’ll be just fine, old buddy.

He blocked the clawed hand of the Crusher as he felt the weight on the blade. To Jake, it felt like the beast before him weighed tons, yet when it jumped on the trees or swung from a branch, the wood didn’t even budge, showing there was indeed some magic going on there.

Being this close, he also noticed what appeared to be a passive aura of sorts around the monkey, weighing him down even further. Even the regular D-ranks in the background had this aura active.

Jake angled himself a bit so the monkey releasing blasts couldn’t get a good shot as he landed small cuts on the body of the Crusher. Slowly the scimitar began glowing red, and Jake felt the curse within spin to life as its hunger permeated his body—luckily for it, today it would be sated.

With every landed cut, a small stream of red energy entered the blade and Jake himself, restoring a few health points to him while draining it from the Crusher. Simultaneously, the poison quickly accumulated in its system, and the monkey soon noticed that something was very wrong.

It didn’t know it yet, but it was practically already dead. The two other D-grade monkeys in the background tried to help as they also entered melee and began swinging their tails and hands. One of them even tried to grab and hold him down while increasing its own weight, but Jake was faster than all of them. While the Crusher had more pure strength than him, he had more than the regular ones.

All the E-grades attempted to throw more of their damn feces here and there, but it was difficult for them with Jake surrounded by the three D-grades.

Jake had to admit that the pressure building up from the three weight-increasing auras was beginning to get cumbersome as he moved to finish one of the beasts off. He laid eyes on all three of them and used Gaze of the Apex Hunter, making all of them freeze up. His scimitar was coated in a mix of arcane mana and the energy of the curse.

The blade extended as he swept it horizontally through the neck of the closest monkey, sending its head flying into the air.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Monkey – lvl 103] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

A moment after its head left its neck, the two surviving monkeys became able to move again, and their fury had spiked even more than before.

But it was all for naught. The Crusher was already sluggish from all the poison, and the other regular one wasn’t doing that much better itself, having taken a few solid stabs from Venomfang already.

Perhaps realizing they were both screwed, they held nothing back. It was as if the air shimmered, and Jake felt like he had just been thrown deep underwater. The pressure mounted and forced him to the ground with the two monkeys in tow. Their two auras overlapped as they tried to crush him, and Jake became unable to avoid even the attacks of the shit-slingers.

Without hesitation, he erected a barrier of mana around himself—courtesy of many hours of practice with Hawkie—and had all the feces land on that. He felt every impact drain some mana, and he even felt that the shit could hasten the mana’s corrosion, but if there was one thing Jake didn't lack currently, it was mana.

Also… while he couldn’t exactly jump around, he could still move a bit.

He took out his bow and, with great willpower, stood up straight as he began channeling. It felt like his bones creaked a bit doing so, but his body was durable enough to easily handle it.

The purple-pink mana swirled around him as the energy began building up. Both D-grade monkeys noticed this, and the Crusher moved in to attack, moving incredibly slow since it was also clearly affected by its own aura.

Jake smirked a bit as he lifted his foot and took a step forward, using his sphere to travel nearly a hundred meters backward. The ground where he had just stood exploded when the massive tail of the Crusher tried to do exactly what the creature was named for doing.

A small crater was formed as the soil was kicked up, the Crusher confused by its blow missing the human that shouldn’t be able to move.

Its surprise only doubled when an arcane arrow parted the cloud of dust and blew its head off.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Monkey Crusher – lvl 112] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Jake instantly felt the pressure on him almost disappear, and he turned his gaze to the last D-grade that was just standing there, looking like it was about to shit itself. Before it got the chance to throw that hypothetical shit, Jake put it down with another Arcane Powershot, freezing the monkey as it attempted to flee.

He barely had time to spot the very last D-grade monkey peek out from behind a tree before it quickly bolted away, rushing further into the forest. It was the one he had sent flying earlier, and it had only barely managed to get its bearings and return in time to see its comrades slaughtered.

With those gone… let’s figure out why Splitting Arrow isn’t working, Jake thought, moving on to more exciting things. The D-grades were honestly too weak for him… He reckoned those four together only managed to reach the level of a single Thunder Roc, even with their levels.

This wasn’t surprising, as solitary creatures were often more powerful individually. They had more skills to square up their own shortcomings and just more stats overall. This didn’t mean that beasts or monsters in groups were weaker, though. Often they had powerful leaders, even for their level, such as… well, pretty much all the dungeon bosses from the tutorial were examples of this.

On top of that, these leaders often had skills that allowed their subjects to level and grow faster. Jake didn’t doubt that these monkeys had some strong leaders hidden away in the core of their territory, and he was very much looking forward to paying them a visit.

It would only be polite to teach them some basic courtesy, wouldn’t it? Such as not allowing shit-throwing.

But before that… he had a skill to upgrade and more than a hundred E-grade monkeys still hiding in the trees all around him, thinking he couldn’t see them. The joke was on them, because Jake had more Perception than could ever be reasonable for a level 101 human.

He turned to the side with his bow in hand and fired towards a tree nearby, trying to use Splitting Arrow. When using the stable version of his arcane arrows, as before, they would persist for a bit longer. Yet again, the arrow appeared to split for a second, but just as the outline appeared, they dispersed.

Jake had only consumed a bit of stamina from the shot… and he instantly found the issue.

Arcane arrows use mana, you dummy.

The three fundamental energies for humans—vital energy (also called health points), mana, and stamina—were able to act like one another, but this required a bit of finesse on the user’s part. That was how he made his mana act like vital energy and created health potions, after all.

However, the transformation of energy was a time-consuming process, making it not at all viable in combat unless used with some specific technique. Self-healing spells, as an example, were often just a skill transforming a portion of mana or stamina into health points.

Jake had considered at one point if this was exploitable… You know, having a skill that effectively turned 500 mana into 1000 health, and then a skill that turned 500 health into 1000 mana. Couldn’t you go infinite with that? Sadly the Viper shot that down quickly. He learned that you didn’t truly transform the energy; you just allowed it to act as another kind of energy for a bit. You had to use it, or it would just disperse, like if Jake consumed a mana potion while full.

Going back to Splitting Arrow, that skill was entirely a "physical" skill. It required stamina to use, even if the stamina acted a lot like mana normally would as it duplicated the arrows. One could say the quiver was the same, too, as it summoned physical arrows. At least they were viewed as physical entities by the system. Jake’s arcane arrows, on the other hand, were considered entirely magical. Honestly… the easiest way to spot the difference was just what stats the skills benefitted from. If it benefitted from physical stats, it was a stamina move; if it benefitted from mental stats, it was a mana move, and if it used stats from both camps, it had a mixed cost—his own Arcane Powershot was an example of this.

The arcane arrows only benefitted from Wisdom and Intelligence for the exploding ones and Wisdom and Perception for the stable arrows. Perception was a stat that didn’t really fit into either camp as a physical or mental stat, but was a bit of both. That was because, objectively speaking—according to Jake—Perception was the best stat.

In summary, Jake needed to change the Splitting Arrow skill to work with his mana rather than his stamina.

However, this was easier said than done. Summoning an arcane arrow was naturally easy for Jake, considering that was the point of Arcane Hunter’s Arrows … No, the issue was doing it while in flight and at the same time allowing them to retain their innate power and momentum.

Any attack used had inherent power in it, and not just in the form of physical momentum or force. Jake’s attacks, especially, were different. All his arrows dealt damage based on distance and Perception because of his Archery of Vast Horizons, so he had to make sure the arrows were still considered archery—no matter how weird that sounds.

With all that in mind, Jake went to work.

He kept trying to use the skill, making small changes here and there. Dozens of Lighttail Monkeys fell during his experimentation, but even more of them were just perplexed at how bad the accuracy of their attacker was. A few of the shots were made with the intent of the arrow splitting, after all.

After half an hour, another small group of D-grades showed up. Two Crushers in this one, both around the level of the one he killed earlier, as well as four of the more regular D-grade Tri-Lighttail Monkeys. One of them was the straggler who’d run off earlier.

Another five minutes after that, there were two dead Crushers and four dead regular D-grade monkeys. Jake didn’t let any of them run off for reinforcements this time, as he wanted to spend some time figuring out the whole Splitting Arrow thing, and doing that while having two buffed-up, hulking monkeys try and smash him would be a bit distracting. He would come to them in due time.

The next few hours were spent with Jake trying different things. Around two hours in, he had some progress when he managed to split the arrow while in mid-air, but the new arrow just fell harmlessly to the ground instantly, having lost all momentum.

He needed the "physical" aspects of the skill to work, too, so he began experimenting with a mix of stamina and mana.

The hardest part was having it all work with the Splitting Arrow skill. He had an innate connection to any attack he used, and to activate his intent for the arrow to split using the Splitting Arrow skill took quite a bit of practice. If he tried to do it without using the skill as an anchor, he had no confidence at all in getting it to work. It was a good example of why skills were still valuable; they did stuff that was honestly far too complicated for Jake to do on his own, and it wasn’t even like Splitting Arrow was the most complex.

During his progress, only a single more D-grade showed up after that large group, and that one was swiftly put down. No levels yet, but he hadn’t really expected any either.

Five hours into his practice, most of his time was spent considering how to improve things while looking for more prey. He felt absolutely no regret about slaughtering a few hundred monkeys, and even if he questioned whether committing monkey genocide was acceptable, a single shit-flinging bastard was enough to deter that sentiment.

It was on the sixth hour that he met his first partial success as an arrow was summoned and lasted for a few seconds before flickering out. It even managed to strike a tree before doing so, penetrating deeply into the bark.

Fifteen minutes later, his improved version of Splitting Arrow passed the threshold of improvement set by the system, and a notification appeared.

[Splitting Arrow (Uncommon)] – One arrow becomes many; one fallen prey becomes a field of death. Fire an arrow that splits into several copies while in flight. Each arrow strikes with the power of the original. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility and Strength when using Splitting Arrow.

-->

[Enhanced Splitting Arrow (Rare)] – A skill most often used by archers, now usurped and reformed by the Avaricious Arcane Hunter. Allows you to clone your arrows while in flight, allowing them to retain innate magical properties. Each arrow strikes with the power of the original. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility and Wisdom when using Enhanced Splitting Arrow.

With the upgrade, the system assistance was entirely in place when he fired his Enhanced Splitting Arrow. It consumed both mana and stamina as he did so—quite a bit more mana than stamina.

It only split into three arrows—far fewer than before—but each struck with impressive power.

Three giant explosions sounded out as the forest shook, and monkey parts were sent flying everywhere.

Jake nodded in satisfaction as he dismissed his bow and began traveling further into the domain of the Lighttail Monkeys…

Leaving only more dead monkeys in his wake. One could even say that the monkey tribe was having quite the shitty day.

Chapter 3

Dervish

Sometimes in life, one must take the good with the bad, and disappointment was an unavoidable element of existence. To be honest, Jake shouldn’t really have been disappointed, though, as it was a bit unrealistic to expect it to work…

But damn it, Jake wanted his Splitting Arrow to also duplicate the poison. Was that really too much to ask?

Shortly after upgrading the skill, Jake had, with much excitement, tried putting his blood on the arrow—the type of poison most aligned with himself and his mana—and duplicating it with Enhanced Splitting Arrow. It did exactly the same as the normal Splitting Arrow, with only the "real" one retaining the poison.

No big deal, Jake had thought. He was already on a roll and had just upgraded the skill in rarity, so couldn’t he just keep working on it and upgrade it again? Allow it to also duplicate poison on it?

Jake wasn’t even going to be greedy… it was fine if it only worked with his blood. That shouldn’t be so hard, right?

Wrong.

It was damn impossible. No matter what Jake tried, nothing worked. The poison simply wasn’t at all considered part of the "arrow," so it didn’t duplicate. It wasn’t an issue of resources or methods… The skill just wasn’t compatible at all with what he wanted it to do. It was like trying to use his Brew Potion to make a shotgun…

Well, there was one consolation to it all, at least. A lot of dead monkeys. A lot. Even a good bunch of D-grades, allowing Jake to net his first real level in his class after reaching D-grade.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 101 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake checked the quest to see how much time he had before the World Congress and noticed that he still had a bit over four days left. It would take him a few hours to get back to the city with how far he had traveled, but that still meant he had plenty of time to explore the rest of the monkey-infested area of the forest he found himself in.

Where he was now, he nearly only saw D-grades, and almost all enemies were monkeys. The vast majority were the normal Tri-Lighttail Monkeys, but there were also plenty of Crushers and even another one called a Suppressor. Yeah… their names weren’t exactly subtle. To the surprise of no one, the Suppressors specialized in suppressing things with their weight magic.

Besides those two, there was also another variant. One Jake was looking at right at that moment.

[Tri-Lighttail Dervish – lvl 123]

It was tall and slender with three tails like all the other monkeys, but its tails themselves were different. While the Crusher had far bulkier ones, the Dervish had tails that looked almost flat. Jake had wondered why they looked like that, but he soon learned the reason.

When Jake came across the group of monkeys, they were in the middle of a battle against another beast: a large, bulky bear that was almost ten meters long and had to weigh many tons. Sadly for the bear, its large size became a detriment to it.

[Brownhide Ursine – lvl 131]

The beast was being pelted with literal shit by the D-grade monkeys, and was slowed down from its forcibly increased weight. Its hide grew harder as it tried to shield itself, but all it did was limit its own mobility further as it got covered in feces.

It tried roaring, sending a wave of force out, but the monkeys hid away up in the trees and just jeered and laughed at it. Jake didn’t like their way of fighting, but he still chose not to interfere. He didn’t like interfering in the fights of others even more, and besides, the Dervish looked like it was about to make its move.

After leaping from its tree, it instantly accelerated manyfold and plummeted the nearly one hundred and fifty meters separating it from the bear.

During its descent, it spun around itself, leaving its tails rotating at a tremendous speed by the time it landed right in front of the bear. The three tails tore into the bear, acting like three whip-like blades that sent blood flying everywhere and made the bear roar in pain and anger.

The suppressed beast instantly began burning with energy as it entered some kind of enraged state, and for a brief moment, it managed to shrug off the weight-increasing effect and move. It attacked the Dervish before it, and when Jake saw its paw land, he thought the monkey would be done for… but instead, it was just sent flying.

Like if the bear had punched a feather, the Dervish harmlessly flew away and landed on the ground. It had a few bloody marks left by the claws, but the impact itself seemed to have barely affected it. It decided to counterattack immediately.

It rushed towards the bear with frightening speed and, using a weird spinning technique, quickly cut into the far larger beast.

Definitely an Agility-focused beast, Jake thought as he saw the bear slowly get finished off. The Dervish inflicted many wounds in quick succession, but it wasn’t exactly a fast killer. In the end, two Crushers joined in when the bear became too weak to put up any resistance at all, quickly finishing the fight.

Just as the monkeys stood triumphantly and cheered, something descended from above.

BOOM!

An arcane arrow fell from atop one of the tallest trees, right through the skull of the one Suppressor that had been the primary force to immobilize the bear. It didn’t even have time to react before its life was ended, and with its demise, panic quickly spread among the monkeys.

A second arrow arrived a few moments later. It hit one of the regular D-grades right in its noggin, blowing its head off and ending yet another life. The remnant energy of the Arcane Powershot became evident as the air itself seemed to vibrate.

Sadly for Jake, that was the last easy kill. All the monkeys had now managed to take cover, and he didn't have time to charge another Powershot for a one-shot. He had previously wanted to fly above the forest to more easily bombard them from above, but found that the crowns of the trees made it impossible. It wasn’t just a question of his sight being physically obstructed, either, as clearly the crowns formed some kind of barrier sealing off the forest. Like a giant, naturally formed array or magic circle, the entire forest protected itself from attacks from above. Which, in retrospect, probably made a lot of sense with powerful flying beasts everywhere. Or, you know, winged humans with bows.

The trees themselves were also damn tough, especially the largest ones. Jake couldn’t even destroy them if he wanted to… It was like being back in the tutorial during the first days, where just penetrating the bark with a dagger had been a damn struggle.

It likely had something to do with the mana intensity being different here. Everything was just tougher, and D-grades were aplenty. Just how he wanted it.

With his wings out, he flew around the trunks of the trees and loosed arrow after arrow towards the monkeys below, every single one of them exploding whenever they hit an enemy or a tree. A few monkeys were even taken by surprise when the exploding arrow suddenly duplicated, and instead of one nearly lethal explosion, it became three very much lethal explosions.

To Jake, the regular D-grade monkeys just weren’t worth much. They were too slow and too weak to pose any real threat, and the entire Lighttail species hadn’t shown itself to be very robust yet. They were a race that focused on not getting hit to begin with, while Jake was quite good at hitting stuff.

He had to deal with a total of eleven normal Tri-Lighttail Monkeys, one Crusher, and one Dervish. After already killing one Crusher and a few of the normal ones, that is.

Jake had already decided to save the Dervish for last… if it allowed him to.

A single figure stood on the ground below, five hundred meters down. Bending its legs, it jumped.

Wha—? Jake barely managed to think before he had to do a flap of his wings to dodge two blade-like tails.

The Dervish tore through the air, and just as it hit the top of the forest, it turned and landed on only a few leaves of the long branches as if it was solid ground. With another mighty jump, it once more flew like a meteor towards Jake, but this time the hunter was ready.

Jake looked up at it and used Gaze of the Apex Predator as the Scimitar of Cursed Hunger appeared in his hand. It froze up just as Jake swung the blade and smashed it into the side of the beast. He felt his blade cut a bit into his target, but after barely managing to leave a wound, he felt all resistance disappear, as if he was striking something without any mass—or in this case, weight.

The Dervish was sent flying away, and just as Jake was about to take out his bow, he saw it purposefully bounce off a tree and behind another, clearly fearing the arrows that had killed several of its brethren earlier.

You don’t like magical attacks, eh? Jake thought, understanding their weakness. Blunt force or even cuts did little to the Dervish, but an exploding arcane arrow was a whole other story. Well, not like the other monkeys fared that much better. Very few things weren’t susceptible to being blown up.

With his target lost, Jake switched to killing off the regular D-grade Lighttails below, patiently waiting for the Dervish to make its next move. He could feel its attention on him as it looked for a chance to strike.

To make it a bit harder for the quick monkey, Jake made sure to fly around the different trees to never give it a straight line of attack while he whittled down the monkeys that were quickly rushing up towards him. He had to dodge quite a few blasts of force and shrug off several waves of weight-increasing mana, but he managed to get quite a few kills in return.

However, the monkeys soon managed to climb up the trees and reach him, and he had to contend with several of them leaping between the trees and trying to hit him. A single one was easy enough, but when five came at once, shit got difficult.

Luckily, he had a few tricks up his sleeve to handle it.

The wings on his back began glowing a dark green color as they emanated a dark, toxic gas. Jake had mixed a bit of dark-affinity mana into the poison, and soon large parts of the treetops were covered in a layer of dark smoke.

This made it significantly harder for the monkeys to strike back, while Jake barely noticed the dark cloud. He had learned quite a while ago that his Perception alone made him able to peer through many magical obstructions of sight, and even if it didn’t, he was accustomed to dark mana anyway.

Moreover, when the monkeys passed through the cloud, they were ever so slowly infected by the poison. The poison didn’t actually do much damage, and even the effects of the dark affinity weren’t noticeable to them… No, the real value lay in Jake being able to detect them far more easily.

Sense of the Malefic Viper allowed him to effortlessly detect poison he had inflicted, and the poison fumes from his wings naturally counted. It was technically just his burned blood, after all.

Jake used everything in his arsenal as he slaughtered the entire group of D-grades. He launched bolts of arcane mana, exploding arrows, and the occasional Powershot, which tore up entire sections of the forest he was in. None of them posed any threat besides the Dervish.

Well, the Crusher would hurt like hell if it managed to strike him, but Jake was never in any real danger of that happening. It was slower than even the regular monkeys and didn’t have much chance of pinning him down. They kept trying to ground him by sending their weight-increasing waves of mana, but Jake countered that by constantly releasing disruptive waves of mana around himself. Was this damn draining on his mana pool? Yes, it sure was, but Jake was a bit of a cheat when it came to that.

A single mana potion restored more than 10,000 mana with the bonus from Palate included, allowing his entire mana pool to effectively be above 40,000. His mask increasing his mana recovery to a large amount also sure helped.

Although Jake countered the beasts quite hard and they were all weak for D-grades, it still took a while to put them all down. D-grades were still D-grades, and unless he landed a lethal blow with Arcane Powershot, they took a fair amount of damage to put down for good.

The Crusher was the second-to-last to fall. In its final moments, the Crusher managed to make Jake dodge in a direction he would prefer not to, and it put him right in the crosshairs of the Dervish.

SWOOSH!

A figure zoomed by him, and Jake failed to fully dodge the blow. The two tails seemed to extend just as they were about to hit him, leaving him a nasty cut on his stomach and chest when the beast passed by. He barely had time to stabilize himself in the air before it struck again, this time finding itself countered like the first time it had tried this tactic.

Jake looked over at it and made it freeze with Gaze of the Apex Hunter. Yet the beast had learned a little—it was already spinning at high speed, effectively making itself a sawblade soaring through the air towards him.

The hunter dodged to the side and extended both his hands out beside him, a net of mana strings woven between them. The spinning tails cut through many of them, but a few remained as the monkey was stopped mid-air.

With a slight smile, Jake infused a bit more arcane mana into the strings. The stability broke and turned to destruction.

BOOM!

The entire net exploded, searing the Dervish as it screamed in pain. Jake himself wasn’t unscathed, as he was also hit by the large explosion, but the scales covering his body took most of the blow. Besides, it was his own arcane mana, and he had plenty of experience being hurt by that already.

Without any momentum and hurt pretty badly, the Dervish was forced to accelerate toward the ground to try and get away. Jake quickly followed by flying a few meters to the side and unto a tree.

Standing horizontally, he took a step and traveled down the length of the tree, appearing on the ground just below where the monkey would land as it accelerated down towards him.

He didn’t have time to fire an arrow, but he did have time to take out his sword and meet the descending beast. It had clearly managed to notice him, too, as it spun around itself and attacked.

With his scimitar, he blocked the spinning blade-like tails, finding himself forced back a bit. Taking another step back, he exchanged several blows with the tails. The monkey hissed, and Jake felt the weight of each blade rapidly increase. At the same time, he felt his own blade become heavier with every block.

Jake took a step forward and once more used Gaze of the Apex Hunter, a few droplets of blood flowing from his eyes from overusing the skill within a short amount of time. However, it was fine. He was about to finish the fight.

He moved in between two spinning tails, the monkey unable to move them as it stood frozen for a moment longer. With both hands on his blade, he raised it high and stabbed down towards the skull of the monkey, swirling dark mana around the edge.

Descending Dark Fang

Not unlike a giant spike of dark mana, his blade penetrated its skull and came out the other side at the base of the Dervish's neck.

The still-spinning blades managed to land a few more cuts on him and scratch his scales a bit in an instinctive reaction, but the monkey was unable to do anything more as its life ended.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Dervish – lvl 123] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Jake pulled out the blade and stumbled back, sitting down on the ground as he breathed out heavily with a smile on his face. Individually, these monkeys weren’t that hard to deal with, but damn, was there a lot of them.

Still smiling, he checked his notifications.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 102 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 102 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Another level. D-grade was quite a bit slower, but Jake knew he was doing exactly what he was meant to. He was hunting higher-leveled enemies, using Mark of the Ambitious Hunter on every enemy, and even killing foes more than twenty levels above himself.

Standing up once more, he did a few stretches before leaping up one of the trees and beginning his journey further into the domain of the Lighttails. With so many of them… something good was bound to be in the innermost area.

Chapter 4

Worthy Opponents

Jake opened his hand as he let the body fall, the dark green glow of Touch of the Malefic Viper fading. The body that fell was that of a monkey with a black handprint on its neck and its body already half-rotten. When it hit the ground, it squashed together as its insides were already decayed and turned to mush.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Dervish – lvl 128] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Its killer took out a healing potion and drank it. The dozens of deep cuts on his body rapidly began closing, leaving only a few of the worst ones, such as where a tail had penetrated his chest. Those would take a bit longer.

The entire section of the forest he was in was utterly wrecked. The trees had deep cuts in them, the ground was littered with craters, and everything had a horrible smell of death and decay, as he hadn’t held back on using his poisons at all. The bark of many trees was black from the poison mist or arrows coated in poison hitting them.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 103 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

He flew over to a branch, where he sat down and entered meditation. This was the third fight since he met the first Dervish and by far the hardest. The first fight had only been a small group of normal D-grades with a single Suppressor, so those were pretty easily put down.

The second fight had been a bit tougher and a lot like the first group with the Dervish, but with his increased experience fighting the monkeys, it had ended a bit faster.

As for the third and final fight he had just finished, there had been two dozen enemies with three Dervishes. It had been quite the battle, as the Dervishes honestly weren’t easy opponents at all. They were incredibly fast, no doubt Agility-focused, and, combined with their weight-increasing magic, their whip-blade-tails felt like heavy-as-fuck razors barraging you constantly.

Jake was fully aware that if he screwed up, he could lose his life to them—which was why he found them entertaining to battle.

He also made a decision. One that might be viewed as controversial by many… but Jake felt like it was necessary. As he made the command through the system, it hurt him down to the core of his soul… but he had to. He needed the speed to keep up with his foes, and he could feel his body unable to move as fast as he wanted, so he had done it.

Jake had used Free Points on something that wasn’t Perception.

The 105 Free Points he had saved up since entering D-grade were all put into Agility, taking him from 1595 to 1748 after all the bonuses were applied. It was around a ten percent increase, and he instantly felt the difference, as he could now move even faster than before, and perhaps now he could begin reacting to even the Dervishes above level 130. The one at 128 had been a bit too fast for him, and he’d had to freeze it, grab hold of it, and use Touch of the Malefic Viper to win the fight instead of just beating it with his blade. Fighting with his sword tended to be more fun, after all, so he preferred to do that.

Checking the time, he found he still had plenty to get to the inner area, and he had a feeling he was close.

Still, he had to spend a few hours getting himself back in top condition. Between his meditation and liberal potion use, Jake’s recovery was far faster than most other D-grades, allowing him to battle more than normal.

Once he was done sitting around meditating and chugging down potions, he moved on with his day of slaughtering monkeys.

He tried to avoid unnecessary fights and encounters with small squads, as those battles weren’t exactly entertaining.

Just as he made his way around a tree, he spotted a small group of D-grades heading his way from around three hundred meters ahead of him. Not feeling like battling four regular D-grade Lighttail Monkeys, he focused on staying hidden. He even used his cloak to camouflage himself a bit better.

It wasn’t something he aimed for or even expected… but that small action gave him a notification.

[Advanced Stealth (Common)] – The deadliest blow is the one not seen coming. A proven artisan in the arts of stealth, you have learned to stay undetected far better than a mere novice. You now find it even easier to blend into the environment, waiting for just the right moment to strike. Adds a minor bonus to the effect of Agility and Perception while successfully remaining undetected.

-->

[Expert Stealth (Uncommon)] – The deadliest blow is the one not seen coming. You have proven yourself an expert in the arts of stealth, as you have learned to become a shadow that is only seen when you wish to be so. You find it easier than ever to blend into the environment, making your presence, mana, and nearly all traces of your existence hidden as you wait for your prey to be vulnerable. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility and Perception while successfully remaining undetected.

Jake read it over and couldn’t help but just shrug. Staying hidden was never anything he really thought much about; it was just one of those things you did. The skill itself was the type that just existed and didn’t require any more thoughts than that. Not that he complained about getting it upgraded, as he knew it would make the hiding he already did just a little bit more effective.

Anyway, with a random skill upgrade out of the way, he continued his quest into the heart of the monkey-lands.

He estimated the entire domain controlled by the monkeys to be several hundred kilometers in diameter, making it a small country based on old-world standards. Still, Jake knew that compared to some other beasts, it really wasn’t that impressive.

The scale of everything in the multiverse was just bigger. It made sense, though, as an area did feel a lot smaller when you could fly faster than a fighter jet or practically teleport with every footstep. Populations growing to ridiculous levels and cities becoming absolutely massive were also just kind of natural.

Heck, trees could now naturally grow to be kilometers tall, and buildings could easily be constructed to be even taller. The logistical issues with large cities were primarily eliminated by magic, the population’s lower requirements for sustenance, and their natural ability to survive better independently due to stats and evolutions. E-grade required way less food than a normal pre-system human, after all, and so far in D-grade, Jake had yet to feel any hunger.

Well, except a hunger for good challenges, but that was a bit of a different thing.

Back in the real world, outside of Jake’s neverending random thoughts about things getting bigger, he had just made his way around a massive tree. It was one of the true behemoths in the area, and while he did consider flying to the top for fun, what he saw as he got to the other side of it dissuaded him.

Before Jake lay what could only be described as a small, ancient temple with a few stone buildings placed around it. The temple itself looked like one of those old, boxy Aztec pyramids, except without that entrance on the top. There was a small entrance at the bottom, though.

If that was the only thing worth noting, he would only be mildly interested, but what was living among those ancient-looking buildings made him quite excited. Hundreds of monkeys jumped around, a lot of them D-grade, but there were even more E-grades running about.

He saw dozens of Dervishes, Crushers, and Suppressors… but what was even more noteworthy were four huge monkeys, each sitting on top of their own small, ancient building.

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 142]

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 147]

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 146]

[Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 146]

The Matriarchs looked a bit like their brethren but were twice the size of an average monkey, with quite a bit of bulk and fat on their bodies. They looked like they could put up a decent fight, but it wasn’t their primary role. Many small monkeys with levels as low as 25 crawled all over their bodies, making Jake believe this was their primary breeding ground.

Just as Jake was trying to get a good count of how many baby monkeys there were, he felt something look his way. He barely managed to see a figure exit the ancient temple in the middle before he instinctively hid behind the tree he was on and focused on his newly upgraded stealth.

A few moments passed before he felt it was safe. He peeked out and saw what had just nearly spotted him from so far away.

It was another monkey, but it was rather different from the others.

Like the Dervishes, it was tall and slender, but it was bulkier than those. What truly set it apart was its pristine golden fur, the glowing silvery symbol on its forehead, and the five tails extending out behind it. Jake didn’t doubt for a second that this beast was the most powerful in the entire settlement and could in no way be considered weak. He used Identify on it as he hid, and the level didn’t actually surprise him.

[Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima – lvl 131]

It was lower than all the Matriarchs and even many of the Dervishes, but Jake knew level wasn’t everything. Shit, he just had to look at himself and the pile of dead monkeys in his wake, all of whom had been higher in level than himself.

A smile crept onto his lips as he, for the first time, spotted prey he found worth hunting after reaching D-grade.

Miyamoto was in his courtyard with his eyes closed, slowly swinging the blade through the air. As if dancing, he moved fluidly through the motions in a patient manner, his blade appearing to almost shimmer with every stroke as if it was made of water.

Every movement was calculated, every step predetermined, and every fiber of his being and soul invested as he trained. To Miyamoto, there was no world outside of him and his sword at that moment.

But all things have to come to an end. He stopped, opened his eyes, and softly looked down at his sword. The old heirloom that had been proudly displayed by their family for generations was no longer just a normal weapon. Oh, no, far from it.

One of the tutorial rewards he had spent his points on was making this old family blade awaken, allowing the spirits of his ancestors and their will to come to life and for the blade to become a true artifact. His request had been met, and the blade had been bound to his soul as it became his life companion.

Miyamoto was level 99 in his class and 95 in his profession. While it did hurt his pride a bit to not be the first D-grade as the patriarch of his clan, he would be the first to achieve the Perfect Evolution.

If he had chosen to become a City Lord, perhaps things would be different, but he knew he did not desire to be a leader of the people anymore. He was past that age, and he had passed the baton to the younger generation. No, he would focus on the blade and his passions as he helped protect his family as any good patriarch would do.

By following his own desires, he had spearheaded the expansion of the clan. He had fought and claimed the first Pylon, losing many family members in the process, but for the second Pylon, he had taken care of the foe by his lonesome. He hadn’t even needed to be present for the third Pylon, as his grandson and great-granddaughter had handled that just a week prior.

As an old soul, he had little to complain about. He spent most of his time focusing on improving himself to be a pillar of strength for the clan. He had just gone through a session of Sword Meditation, a skill he valued quite highly.

[Supreme Sword Meditation (Ancient)] – The sword is you, and you are your sword. While in meditation, regenerate stamina and mana significantly faster, more easily find inspiration, and experience enlightenment in relation to all sword-related skills. Allows you to earn far more experience points while using Supreme Sword Meditation. While in Supreme Sword Meditation, you must perform a compatible Sword Dance flawlessly. Any mistakes will lead to forcefully exiting meditation and being unable to reenter it again for a short period of time. May you find your truth through your blade.

It was a great skill, and he had gotten it to its current rarity shortly after returning to Earth. It had only been epic rarity upon his exit of the tutorial.

He had gotten it to rare rarity the day he reached level 25 and earned the meditation skill.

Taking a deep breath, the old man extended his sword and began drawing in the air, painting with his sword. It was an ephemeral painting of water that would disperse the moment he stopped the skill, a mere snapshot of reality that only he would ever lay eyes on.

Finesse had many forms, be it swordsmanship or painting. Ultimately, both were about control, conviction, and the ability to execute techniques accurately. All these things had only become more true when the system arrived.

Miyamoto had seen many others of the older generations—people still his juniors—fail to adapt to this everchanging world. They relied on the ways of old, or their mindsets were simply not adaptive enough. It was difficult for him to understand.

Life was but a series of shifting seasons. Every new season would bring about change as the world developed, not one day the same as the last. Throughout his life, he had seen so much change, so many shifts in society.

If he had been unable to adapt, how could he ever have hoped to achieve success? If he could not embrace new technology and even be willing to try and get ahead and prepare for the coming winter as fall arrived, how could he ever hope to excel?

To him, the arrival of the system was just yet another changing season. As he’d lain there in his bed, he’d believed that it was his winter, and that that season would be his last. Yet spring had arrived and brought about new life and new opportunities.

And as nature cheered and blossomed to welcome the sun and the end of winter, so would he blossom and grow to make his clan experience the most fruitful summer imaginable.

The World Congress would be the first step in achieving that, the first time where he would finally meet the other leaders and patriarchs of the planet—including he who had claimed the first Pylon.

Chapter 5

Rules of Monkey Hunting

There were a few rules one had to remember when invading an ancient temple and the surrounding area run by supernatural, many-tailed monkeys that can use weird weight magic. Forgetting these rules could lead to being covered in unnaturally heavy feces or just being smashed or cut up by a monkey tail.

The first rule was to stay high and avoid the ground. Being able to move in three dimensions against enemies unable to fly was an incredible advantage and made it far easier to deal with issues arising from breaking the second rule.

Lighttail Monkeys weren’t the strongest individually, but fighting a crowd of them was what, in the hunting industry, was called a very bad time. They buffed each other up while slowing you down, allowing their strikers in the form of Crushers or Dervishes to finish you off. So the second rule was to always only engage small groups at a time, and if possible, isolated prey.

The third rule was to always make sure the Prima wasn’t around, because the Prima was clearly the big boss. One should always save the big boss for last—this is just basic hunting protocol and best practice. Always remember: kill from weakest to strongest. It’s a bit like how you don’t eat your dessert before the main dish, no matter how tasty it looks. He would have to make do with all the Beastcores he collected from their corpses after the fight so far.

Then there was the fourth rule, one quite unique to Jake. It was a rule that invalidated the prior three if followed adequately every time, even if it often was a bit difficult to follow. The rule was actually quite straightforward: always kill with a single shot.

A rule Jake was doing incredibly well not breaking at the moment.

An arrow tore through the terrain, narrowly passing in between trees in its flight. Its target was just relaxing on a branch, keeping an eye out for any potential invaders to swiftly strike down. It was a Dervish, a creature that rarely found worthy challenges this far into their domain. It was too relaxed, too unaware… though it was doubtful if its preparedness would have made a difference.

It noticed the arrow too late and tried to move. Tried, because it suddenly felt like it had been thrown into an icy pit with a predator—nay, hunter—staring down at it, penetrating into its soul. The nearly one-meter-long arrow arrived and penetrated deep into the creature without any issues, releasing intense amounts of destructive energy. If that wasn’t enough, the arrow was even coated with incredibly potent poison and fired with the ridiculously powerful Arcane Powershot.

To strike down a beast nearly thirty levels above yourself in a single strike was a rarity, especially in D-grade, where every level mattered even more. But coupled with the low resilience of the Agility-focused Dervish and the power of the attack, it was made possible.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Dervish – lvl 131] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

The arrow he had used was naturally his Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, and it had been quite easily summoned the moment he tried. He had hoped the summoning time would reduce after reaching D-grade, but it had stayed the same… which couldn’t be said about the power.

Without noticing, the already-overpowered arrow had gotten better. A large element of the arrow was the destructive energy it contained, and through Jake’s arcane affinity, he had come to understand that type of energy quite a bit better. While it wasn’t exactly the same type of concept, it was close enough that the arrow simply accepted it when he poured in a bit of arcane mana.

Not too much, or it would destabilize the arrow, but just a little—a far cry from ever being enough to upgrade the skill, but more than enough to make it just a little better.

With the Dervish dead, it led Jake one to consider the fifth and final rule of hunting Lighttail Monkeys, one very important to remember in conjunction with rules four and two. This rule was that, after making a kill, you should fucking run. Because the tribe would be coming.

Jake swiftly flew away, making sure to hide behind trees and stay high as he could hear the screeching monkeys off in the distance. His way of killing wasn’t the most subtle, since Arcane Powershot was quite flashy by nature, so he had to quickly get away. There was even a faint trail of mana in the air beginning where he had fired from, and some of the more acute monkeys detected and followed that trail.

By the time they arrived, Jake was already long gone.

He watched them as they kept searching, the monkeys naturally split up to look for the intruder that had killed one of their brethren, perhaps too dumb or too confident to believe they wouldn’t meet the same fate. Either way, that belief was clearly not well founded. Less than ten minutes after the first Dervish died, a Crusher found an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter striking it from behind, killing it instantly.

Another kill kicked up another uproar as even more monkeys joined the search, yet it was all for naught, as Jake was already way ahead of them. He flew high among the crowns of the trees, constantly hidden behind thick branches and relying on his cloak’s extra camouflage.

The only times he went down the trunks of the trees were to fire a Powershot using the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. Before going up the tree, he would place a Mark of the Ambitious Hunter on his next chosen target and use that to summon the arrow, much like he’d done with the Indigo Mushroom.

Jake had to be honest—while this method wasn’t that fast, it was relatively safe. The Prima spent nearly all its time in the temple itself and didn’t appear to care at all what was going on around it, while the Matriarchs spent most of their time trying to hold back the weak monkeys in their care from joining the search.

At times, the monkeys got quite close to Jake, but he had a few more tricks up his sleeve to stay hidden.

Nearly three kilometers from where he was, the top of one of the smaller trees exploded with arcane mana, and the monkey that had come to investigate the source of mana it detected was sent flying. Not long after, another explosion shook the ground even further away, drawing more attention.

Finally, a third explosion occurred right in the middle of a group of D-grade monkeys, but this one was far larger than the ones prior. The reason for this was simple… the ones before had been created by conjuring Arcane Bolts and stabbing them into trees, knowing they would explode within a few minutes with their unstable mana, while the last explosion was caused by three exploding Arcane Hunter’s Arrows, fired with a Splitting Arrow.

The monkeys were injured but not dead, though that was just a temporary issue for Jake. An issue that was further alleviated as arrows rained down on them from a tree far away, the D-grade Monkey’s bodies occasionally freezing when they tried to dodge but still got pierced. All four of them died within less than a dozen seconds, far from long enough for the more powerful monkeys to trace the human firing the shots.

This entire dynamic of Jake striking like a shadow from atop the trees continued for over a day. He consumed a potion every single hour, nearly on the second, to keep his resources stable. Jake quickly found that the extra regeneration from his mask was even more effective than back in his city, boosting his combat endurance to a ridiculous level.

It was after this full day of killing that one of the big pillars of the monkey community made a move. The four Matriarchs always had at least a dozen Dervishes, Crushers, and Suppressors around them to ensure their safety, making Jake choose to ignore them for now.

Besides, for every hour that passed, he got stronger—both by being more familiar with his strength and making even more rapid progress with his archery and mana control, but also just in pure, tangible levels. His notification menu was easy proof of that.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 104 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 103 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 105 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

After reaching level 105 in his class and putting all the Free Points he had gained into Agility, the stat became his second-highest, naturally still far behind Perception. Jake felt like it was worth it for now. He had also begun noticing some other peculiarities of the entire area.

The temple and everything around it felt… old. Ancient. It wasn’t just that it was likely architecture taken from old Earth either; it was something about the mana in the air. The entire aura of the place just felt off.

But back to the whole Matriarch on the move thing… Yeah, one of those massive monkeys had chosen to personally try and hunt down whatever was killing all its children. Jake at least assumed that was the case, as, for some reason, it looked even more pissed than any of the other beasts, as though it had been holding itself back for far too long.

Followed by its entourage of guards, it made its way into the forest, away from the safety of the main temple and the one foe Jake was truly wary of. Jake did a careful count and saw seven Dervishes, four Crushers, and three Suppressors with it at all times.

This was too many enemies for Jake to handle at once, so he would have to do a bit of picking off before engaging the Matriarch herself. He was actually thankful that she had left the small monkeys behind at the temple area, as Jake really didn’t feel like killing them. He would have been able to just swiftly remove them with Gaze of the Apex Hunter… but that would just feel wrong.

Jake began carefully preparing himself as the Matriarch moved further and further away from the temple, moving slower than even the bulky Crushers.

His preparations consisted of preparing his arrows after overcoming an issue that had proven itself to not really be an issue at all. Jake had summoned all his Arcane Hunter’s Arrows while drawing his bow before, which made poisoning them quite tricky for obvious reasons.

He had considered how to fix this, since he’d previously been able to just prepare the arrows and put them back in his quiver… which made him wonder why he couldn’t just keep doing that. While it didn’t work with his explosive arrows—they would explode within a few minutes of summoning, no matter what—his stable arrows could stay summoned for a while with no problem.

So all he had to do was just not conjure any arrows in his old, uncommon-rarity quiver, instead filling it with his pre-poisoned arcane arrows. Shit, he even found that the quiver helped them not leak as much mana as before, allowing them to stay summoned even longer if he stored them in it. There was the one issue of not being able to keep them in his spatial storage like his old arrows, but that was honestly such a minor thing.

The upgrade to Malefic Viper’s Poison had even made it so his poisoned arrows would now stay nice and toxic even longer than before. When the skill was rare rarity, its coating had only stayed effective for around half an hour. Now it would last over an hour.

This resulted in Jake carrying a quiver with around fifty stable arcane arrows coated with his best Necrotic Poison. His blood was nearly as good, but not quite, so he went with the best he had for maximum killing efficiency.

The reason for all this preparation was that he knew he couldn’t pick off all the monkeys around the Matriarch one by one… but he would make it into a long fight to his advantage. He had confidence in his own endurance, and even more confidence in his ability to slowly poison his foes and bring them down in a prolonged battle.

Of course, as always, the first shot would be an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter—also nicely coated in his poison. His goal for that arrow was the Matriarch herself. Not to kill her, but because he had noticed how defensive the monkeys were of her… so if he could heavily injure her, he was one hundred percent sure some of them would stay behind and not chase him. Maybe they would even try and jump in to block blows meant for her later on… Either way, he thought it was a sound strategy.

With the arrow summoned and everything ready, he did something he hadn’t felt a need to do so far in D-grade. Energy began building up deep inside as the flow of internal energy sped up, and his body began overflowing with strength.

At the same time, all effects of his hiding were gone as he practically projected his presence far and wide around him. Limit Break was only active at the safe and not-so-tiring 10%, but it was a massive boost nevertheless.

With Limit Break active, the monkeys noticed him, but he was still not within their line of sight… He had calculated his timing enough to avoid that. Jake raised his bow as Arcane Powershot began charging, and he released the string only when he felt the bow about to reach the limits of its durability.

The arrow tore through the terrain towards the group of monkeys, now many kilometers from their home temple. When it was about to arrive, Jake strained himself to freeze not only the Matriarch, but also four of the seven Dervishes as they tried to block the attack with their bodies. Jake knew Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter would only work on the Matriarch, as she was the target, so hitting her was essential to his plan.

His eyes hurt as he found the Matriarch especially hard to freeze, and when she became able to move again, she was far faster than any of the Dervishes. Sadly, she was too slow and still ended up being hit in the belly with the arrow. She screamed in pain as it tore into her, leaving an extensive, gaping, poisoned wound.

From there, the real fight began. Jake instantly drew the string again and used Arcane Powershot with one of the poisoned arrows from his quiver. He didn’t do much charging, instead just firing and using Gaze on a Dervish. His arrow struck it in the chest, sending it flying and poisoning it.

He repeated this, blood already running down his cheeks from overusing Gaze, but it was necessary.

Once all seven Dervishes were hit… he ran. His wings spread open behind him, a cloud of poison spreading in his wake. The occasional poisoned arrow or explosive arcane arrow pelted those that chased him. A blade struck from behind a tree as they thought they had caught up to him. A hand grasped a neck, teleporting next to one sitting tired on a branch.

To the monkeys, this entire area was still their domain, their home, where they stood at the apex and the human that had come was just another invader to slay. But this foolish assumption would prove fatal… because what had come was not just another invader, but a hunter. And unbeknownst to them, they were nothing more than prey.

Chapter 6

Matriarchs

A massive crash echoed through the forest as a tree nearly three hundred meters tall toppled over. The wooden behemoth that would ordinarily be borderline impossible to take down looked old and worn, its bark peppered with many black rotten spots throughout, especially in the section that had been broken as a massive tail smashed into it.

Dust and soil flew up everywhere before being cleared by an explosion caused by a blast of force and an arcane arrow colliding. Blood sizzled on the ground in many places, mixed in with nontoxic blood and flesh left by over a dozen dead monkeys scattered everywhere.

Jake rolled and kicked up a bit of this blood-covered ground as he dodged the flyby of a sluggish-looking Dervish. As it flew past, the long cuts on both his arms spewed out blood drops that hit it while it was also diving through the ever-present poisonous mist from his wings.

He smirked as he saw it collide with a tree nearby, its senses severely weakened due to its many injuries and constant exposure to his toxins.

Nearly three hours ago, Jake had first engaged the Matriarch.

One slightly annoying thing he had noticed was that the damn Matriarch was actually more of a mix between a Crusher and a healer than just a pure support beast. It had managed to heal its own wounds and even counteract some of the poison he had spread, making the fight even more prolonged than he would have hoped.

To his advantage, though, he did discover that the Matriarch had quite the lacking mana pool. Or maybe it was just because it had used all its magic too liberally, not hesitating to try and cure the poison Jake inflicted on its children, even healing many of their wounds.

This had led to Jake shifting to a hemotoxin-based fighting style, poisoning and bleeding them out while always staying a step ahead.

Because he was a well-rounded fighter with high stats across the board, he could constantly adapt. He was durable enough to tank a blow when necessary, his resource pools large enough that he would not run out of magic or physical strength, his Vitality high enough so that he could keep his body healthy, and his offensive power powerful, be it through magic or physical blows.

The Suppressors needed to be swiftly struck down, as they had weak defenses but could debilitate even Jake if he allowed them to stack up their weight-increasing magic for too long. Those were the ones he focused on first, killing them with potent poison and Arcane Powershots while preventing the Matriarch from saving them.

Crushers were relatively tanky and dealt significant damage, but they were the slowest of the bunch, not counting the Matriarch herself. For the most part, he could ignore them and just slowly poison and bleed them out. With the Suppressors gone, they simply had no way to ever catch him. At that point, they just became walking mana-drainers for the Matriarch.

Dervishes were overall the most annoying to handle. While they were indeed weak defensively, they were incredibly fast and hit insanely hard, making them ideal strikers. With seven of them on his tail, Jake was forced to fight them directly at times, as kiting them was simply out of the question. The only good thing was that they couldn’t fly and were so fast that they could pretty much only attack in a straight line when they leaped for him.

He had already gone over the Matriarch, the one he was saving for absolutely last. She was incredibly tanky, could heal herself and others, hit even harder than the Crushers—the fallen tree was evidence of that—and could even do a bit of supportive magic. The downside was that… holy damn was she slow. Coupled with a few monkeys, always staying close to defend her made it far easier to kite them.

If Jake was honest, the group of monkeys would be more dangerous if they just abandoned the Matriarch and all went straight for him. Sadly for them, they hadn’t done that but allowed him to poison them all over several hours.

The fight was now in its final stages, with only a single Crusher, two Dervishes, and the Matriarch left standing. All incredibly injured.

Jake himself wasn’t all fine and dandy either, between his ripped clothes and the several long cuts all over his body, including one a few centimeters deep across his entire chest—the result of a Dervish getting him real good.

His health was already below half, and that was after drinking a health potion just ten minutes ago. He had also consumed two mana potions throughout the fight to keep up his constant bombardment of arcane arrows, poison mist, and even the occasional blood-covered Arcane Bolt for good measure.

He smiled as he blocked a tail from a Dervish with his Venomfang while swinging the Scimitar of Cursed Hunger with the other hand. He cut the one remaining Crusher by extending the blade with an arcane edge, tearing open its stomach.

As he did the damage, a flow of energy was absorbed from the beast and delivered into him, restoring a bit of his health and healing some minor wounds on his body. The blade had proven very valuable in these kinds of prolonged battles.

The Crusher fell back from the blow, the Matriach trying to push out a bit more mana to heal it. At the same time, Jake took a step forward, then teleported back with One Step Mile, avoiding the blow of yet another Dervish that came flying in.

It was a desperate battle for the side of the monkeys. Jake had outlasted all of them, and none could put up even half of their total power by now. Their insides were more mush than flesh, and blood was flowing from all their orifices. Yet none retreated.

That was a tendency Jake had noticed many beasts had when heavily poisoned. They didn’t flee but instead just tried to kill him even more desperately. He had previously theorized it was because they believed the poison would stop if he died, and he was only getting more and more sure of that. It was actually a good indicator that these monkeys were incredibly dumb—if them deciding to chase a poison-spreading human for hours wasn’t proof enough of that.

The monkeys had also given up their last-ditch suicide tactic where they amplified their auras. Jake had already found a way to break that and just One Step Mile away, leading to a Crusher and two Dervishes effectively just killing themselves with their own auras. A bit funny, actually, depending on how black your humor is.

Dodging yet another whirling blow of tails from a Dervish, Jake managed to cut off one of them before the monkey could reinforce it with energy. While it was distracted by the pain, he grabbed hold of it with his other hand and held it down on the ground. Touch of the Malefic Viper activated as the poison spread in the beast, and with a good squeeze, he heard a crack as the Dervish’s neck broke. Now the only two foes left were a heavily injured Matriarch and one kind-of-already-dead Crusher.

Jake didn’t even need to cut the Crusher directly anymore, and finished it off merely using Gaze of the Apex Hunter. Finally, only two living beings remained to stare each other down—one a heavily injured but spirited human and the other a Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch that looked utterly unable to decide what to do.

Its indecision quickly turned to despair as it began screeching in anger, but instead of attacking, it sprinted back towards the old temple grounds.

It didn’t get far. An Arcane Powershot hit from behind, blowing off one of its legs. It began trying to crawl before Jake leaped from above and smashed his scimitar down through its skull, ending its life for good.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 146] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 106 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 104 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 107 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake looked down on the Matriarch and the hellscape he had left behind, and couldn’t help but chuckle a bit to himself. Note to self: do not have big battles inside or too close to Haven, or we will require some serious landscaping afterward.

He left the area in a very nice and dead state, relocating in case more monkeys came to investigate. Then he found a good tree and sat down to recuperate while doing a bit of alchemy. He wanted to create better hemotoxic poison now that he had reached D-grade and discovered how good it was against the Matriarchs, as well as a single batch of health, mana, and stamina potions.

And if all went well, he would be able to wipe out those shitty monkeys before it was World Congress time.

In a rather large house in an even larger city, two women and a baby sat around a table, talking as the older one of them rocked the sleeping child back and forth.

"I still find it quite weird, if not a little unsettling," the older woman said as she held the child. "Babies aren’t supposed to be this quiet and relaxed when this young."

Another woman sat to the side, observing the grandmother hold her grandson, and smiled as she tried explaining what her husband had said. "Caleb says it has something to do with no longer having the same needs… You know, no longer as hungry anymore. Many of the other ailments usually affecting kids also aren’t really a worry either… Gosh, did I waste a lot of time reading books on parenting that are now irrelevant."

"I won’t say they were wasted; I am sure a lot of what was in them is still very relevant for a new parent," Debra said as she played with her grandson. "How is Caleb doing these days? I feel like he is less and less home."

"He and Robert are busy preparing for the upcoming World Congress with all of the other administrators. With nearly all the influential forces brought together in one room, they want to be ready for any scenario and are making way more plans than they could ever need."

"Well, I guess it must be hard being both the leader of some assassination guild fashioning themselves a court and a father at the same time," Debra said, clearly not approving of the entire situation.

"Caleb is doing the best he can," Maja said, shaking her head. "Things are a lot more complicated now than before, and I also find it hard to adapt. I am just thankful that at least we are all safe and together. For the most part, at least."

Caleb Thayne, the current Judge of the Court of Shadows placed on Earth, had not held back from using his authority to help his family at all. He understood that not being selfish to some extent was viewed more as a sign of weakness than strength. It was also just an advantage that the Judge was not burdened by worries outside the Court.

He had used this influence to help gather not just his entire family, but even Maja’s parents, who had lived not that far away before the integration. They had gotten a similar experience to Jake and Caleb’s parents by suddenly having a squad of shadow-wielding assassins appear, explain the situation, and offer to escort them to the city claimed by the Court.

Jake and Caleb’s parents had it worse. A notorious figure in their tutorial had one day appeared before them, all nice and sweet, saying he had been given the job to make sure they safely made it through the tutorial by some shadow god.

Maja had been in a very different tutorial from any of the others. Hers had only consisted of children, pregnant women, and people who worked with children or in the medical profession before the system. Barely any fighting had been going on in hers, and she’d been escorted to the city after the tutorial by Caleb himself, who had split off with a few others to get her.

He had talked about how that had apparently earned him even more respect from the second-in-command of the Court, Matteo, as he now viewed Caleb as a man who "valued family above all else.” The former assassin-turned-magic assassin approved of that.

"Yeah… nearly everyone,” Debra said. “Has Caleb said more about Jake? How come he isn’t having some of his men help him get here?" It was clear she didn’t understand why Caleb just kept insisting that Jake was fine and that there was no reason to go get him.

"Jake doesn’t need our help, from what Caleb said… He is doing just fine on his own. He even has his own thing going on with another settlement," Maja explained, trying not to give too many details. It would be easier just for Jake to explain himself, and honestly, even Maja found it hard to really understand.

Caleb shared everything he knew with his wife, but that only made Maja understand how different this world really was. Her parents and her mother and father-in-law were all just regular people in this new world. They weren’t standout performers, and their only outstanding quality was their relation to outstanding people in the eyes of the higher powers.

That Jake was doing well wasn’t that surprising to Maja, though. He had always been able to do well for himself when he put his mind to it, but she and Debra did share one fear…

"Do you think he is being dragged into something he shouldn’t? You know how he is," Debra said, sighing. "He always just goes with the flow and gets dragged into things… hangs around with crowds he really shouldn’t… Wouldn’t it be better if he just came here already? He hasn’t even seen his nephew yet. Does he even know he has become an uncle?"

"He’ll be fine," a new voice said as Caleb landed in the small garden outside of the house, obviously having heard what they said towards the end through the open window.

Debra looked out the window and at her son with no amusement. "You keep saying that, but are you really sure he hasn’t been influenced by some bad people? And also, how come you are back already? Where is Robert?"

"Dad is busy trying to figure out how to design that new high-rise he is working on and told me to just go back by myself first,” Caleb said. “We don’t really have much more planning to do—at least, nothing I want to be involved in—so I’ll have to head out for a bit more training before the Congress.” He then finally addressed the first question that Debra had asked. "And while I can’t really say anything about if Jake is being influenced by bad people, we will find out soon. I am ninety-nine percent sure he will be part of the World Congress."

"Really?" Debra said, a bit more relieved. They all knew she wouldn’t go to the World Congress itself, but at least Caleb should be able to check-in with him.

After that, they relaxed a bit together, Caleb playing with his son and giving his wife a kiss before taking flight once more. He then headed outside the city to the closest suitable hunting ground.

Because no matter what faction one was from, power was still the most important factor, which was also why Caleb and Maja weren’t that concerned about Jake.

Chapter 7

City/Monkey Management

Jake sat on the ground as he breathed in heavily, waiting for his left arm to regrow. His right eye was also still a bit blurry after being regenerated, as it turned out that taking a blast of force to the face resulted in quite a lot of it being funneled into the holes in the mask. He was lucky his head was tilted so he’d only lost one of them.

He was also, of course, half-naked from most of his armor being shredded or blown apart, a lot of the damage done by his own explosions of arcane mana. He had to be honest; he‘d come close to biting off a bit more than he could chew towards the end.

It was now only a bit over twenty-two hours away from the beginning of the World Congress, and Jake was still in the forest hunting monkeys. After the first Matriarch, the second one to move had been the highest-level one, but it had gone down quite easily. Mainly because Jake had the tactic down, and more and better hemotoxins than before.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 147] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 108 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 105 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

He’d regenerated to full with that one down and had then gone to pull another one of the Matriarchs, hoping to finish it off quickly. Oh, boy. That hadn’t turned out as planned. Not at all.

When he shot an arrow at the third Matriarch, the fourth one had decided to join in too, with all the young monkeys being ushered into the buildings surrounding the ancient temple. Jake had already found out they led to some small underground caves that were pretty much safety shelters.

Jake had no interest in going after the young ones. He was no sand-hating youngling slayer, after all. Besides, he didn’t have a laser sword.

Anyway, Jake had pulled the third Matriarch, the fourth had decided to follow, and eventually, this had resulted in the majority of D-grade monkeys in the entire temple area chasing him. The only lucky thing was that the Prima was still chilling within the center temple, not taking part. It appeared to honestly not give a shit what the rest of its tribe was doing, and all the other monkeys were just afraid of it, from what Jake could tell.

All of this had resulted in Jake on the run from an entire fucking army of D-grade monkeys, including two Matriarchs, more than twenty Dervishes, even more Crushers, and a dozen or so Suppressors. The number of normal, D-grade Tri-Lighttail Monkeys was above a hundred total. Very much not a good time.

The first hour had been the hardest by far, with Jake trying to slow down and injure the horde as much as possible as he ran. He’d killed and ripped and poisoned with everything he had, with both his blades absolutely covered in blood towards the end.

He did discover that the health-draining effect of his Scimitar of Cursed Hunger was extremely valuable against the normal D-grades. It meant he did not have to consume health potions as much, as he could regenerate by beheading monkeys.

With his sphere and Sense of the Malefic Viper detecting all the poisoned monkeys, he managed to avoid getting surrounded and outnumbered too much, allowing him to always fight back or escape when things got a bit too spicy.

In the end, the entire ordeal had still taken more than an entire goddamn day. An entire day of running, fighting, killing, and slowly whittling down his foes. A few more monkeys had even joined the hunt when they noticed what was going on, making Jake feel like he was facing a neverending tide of simians.

He’d had to chug down a potion every hour on the dot to keep himself at least a bit healthy, most of them stamina potions. He’d also had to use Limit Break at 10% nearly the entire time, but had, towards the end, activated it at 20% to finish off the final Matriarch.

Jake had discovered over the course of that goddamn marathon of a fight that he could indeed still get tired. Not because he lacked stamina or mana or anything like that—it was just pure mental exhaustion. His mind wanted to rest; he needed to just not think or do anything intense for a while. Not even sleep, necessarily. Just something without requiring focus.

After reaching D-grade, you never had to sleep anymore. You barely had to at E-grade and required only a few hours a week tops, most of it just being done with meditating anyway. But as he had discovered, that didn’t mean rest was unnecessary.

Ultimately, this mental exhaustion hadn’t had much effect aside from causing Jake to fight less tactically towards the end. He was lucky in the sense that he didn’t have to truly focus when fighting; it was actually quite the opposite: the less he focused, the more he could just move instinctively.

Of course, that wasn’t always optimal and worked best in melee. It also wasn’t perfect—far from it. Hence Jake’s lack of an arm, newly regenerated eye, and massive amount of wounds on his body. But it had helped him to never suffer any truly lethal blow… though he did have to trigger Moment of the Primal Hunter in the very end to finish off the last Matriarch.

So now, Jake just sat there, completely exhausted, his health, stamina, and mana all below 20%, and the negative aftereffects of Limit Break taking their toll. Luckily, nothing was alive anywhere close to him, and the destroyed area, miasma of poison, and stench of decayed and still-rotting corpses was sure to keep most anything away.

He felt tired as fuck, but also very accomplished as he went through his wall of notifications. The first of which were the many monkeys, but most importantly, the two Matriarchs. Though he did see that there were Dervishes all the way to 140 also mixed in.

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 142] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*You have slain [Tri-Lighttail Monkey Matriarch – lvl 146] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

And the best part: Levels.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 109 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 110 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 106 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 111 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 112 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 107 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Getting levels always just felt great. So, with deep satisfaction, he lay down on the bloody grass, ignored the toxic miasma all around him, and fell asleep.

Usually, she would be a bit annoyed or even question where he was, but quite honestly, she had become immune to his whims and constant absence and just resolved to do things herself. It worked out fine that way anyhow, and in the moments when it truly mattered, Jake would be there. There was no way he would miss the World Congress because he was too busy hunting, right? Yeah, definitely not. Definitely.

Miranda had just woken up from another journey to the Verdant Lagoon, where she had ended up spending most of the time going through paperwork and dealing with stuff through the system menus, making use of the time distortion to get work done. Creating new quests, taking stocks, and all that. The system even had interfaces for everything, and Lillian had recently unlocked a skill that allowed her to send and receive messages through the powers of the Pylon. This meant she could send information to anyone connected to it, such as Miranda, Phillip, Hank, or anyone else with an official position granted by Miranda or someone she had given the authority to grant positions to. A position-giving position, if you will.

This should also have worked for the owner, but Lillian had tried and found that it failed every time. It was like the skill couldn’t find its destination. Miranda just chalked that up to him having some kind of skill to block it, or maybe he was just too strong. Both seemed like reasonable explanations.

They’d had a meeting earlier that day—they being herself and most of the people with positions of leadership in the city—and agreed on a few things concerning the World Congress. One of the largest subjects of discussion was related to immigration.

Through interaction with merchants and travelers from Sanctdomo, they had become aware that the other city was truly massive and that other, far larger settlements also existed out there. Many of Haven’s current citizens had family or friends elsewhere, and were only in Haven right now because it was the only settlement they had come across that offered at least a modicum of safety.

Many guesses about what the World Congress was all about had been made, and the only real thing Miranda was certain of was that it would allow the different world leaders to interact. The quest had made that quite clear.

Haven didn’t intend to make themselves antagonistic to any forces, but she was damn sure that some other faction would try to cause strife or perhaps even attempt to lay claim and annex the city. Their population appeared to be a weakness, which was why another choice they had made seemed to not make a lot of sense: limiting immigration.

Due to the city’s geography, Haven would never become a metropolis unless they chose to abandon what made it special and ruin the entire atmosphere of the forest. Nobody wanted that, and Miranda was also fairly certain Jake would prefer not to have high-rises surrounding his valley.

At the Fort and the area surrounding the Fort, a proper city could be constructed, and Miranda was even working on having the area influenced by the Pylon extend to there. Once she reached D-grade, that should be possible.

No, they would keep Haven as an area more specialized and—as arrogant as it may seem—reserved for the "elite" and their immediate family. Nobody currently living there would be thrown out, but they would limit how many newcomers could become official citizens.

Haven was placed in the outer parts of a beast-filled forest, and just a few hundred meters outside the area influenced by the Pylon, one could run into beasts. If one delved further in, high level E-grades were aplenty, with D-grades eventually appearing. Miranda was pretty sure Jake was currently out fighting those.

The owner had even mentioned a nearby D-grade dungeon. It was currently closed off, with warning signs still at the cave entrance, and Miranda had even placed down a small alarm spell around the cave to make sure no one entered. Jake clearly wanted to be the first to do the dungeon, and there was no way Miranda would deny him that right. It was also just safer to have someone scout it out and get some general information for subsequent parties. She knew no one better than him to do it.

There wasn’t really any threat of others going to the dungeon currently, though. There were no D-grades in the city other than Jake and the birds. They just stayed in the valley most of the time, and while she knew beasts could enter and do dungeons, they apparently very rarely did. Besides them, no one was really even close to D-grade. Miranda herself was now the second-highest-leveled individual with a race level of 86, with Neil and his party all sitting between 75 and 85, with Neil being the one at 85. She was actually impressed by the continued zeal of the party to keep progressing. She did believe a part of it was due to what had happened at the Fort, as the entire party appeared both ashamed and motivated after being utterly embarrassed by Jake and Mystsong Hawk.

Besides all those decisions, they had also discussed who should go to the World Congress. Based on what she could tell, only two additional people aside from the City Owner and City Lord could enter the Congress per Pylon. The wording was a bit weird, making her wonder if perhaps both she and the owner could bring two people each, but she was now certain that wasn’t true.

As for who they would bring? She wasn’t sure yet. Maybe Phillip would be smart, or perhaps Lillian due to how loyal she was and because she had already signed a system-enforced contract. Neil could also be a good idea, as he was making rapid progress with creating a functional teleportation circle. It would be good if he could meet other space mages to maybe create a teleportation network—something Miranda had learned was quite commonplace on most other civilized planets.

Either way, it all came down to if Jake had any plans himself… assuming he would actually come. He’d said last time he would. Miranda felt a bit bad for doubting him; she knew she really shouldn’t, since she was his inferior in every way, but a small part of her still held doubt.

He still has half a day.

Jake awoke with a great yawn as he sat up and scratched his head. Actually, his body was itching quite a bit all over. It was probably the coagulated blood. Yep, definitely the blood. Who knew blood could be itchy? Jake sure knew now.

He got up and quickly took out a large barrel of water to clean himself up. He had a date with a monkey a bit later, so he would need to look presentable for that, wouldn’t he?

After cleaning himself up, he did a bit of light stretching to get all his sore and newly regenerated muscles up to speed. His entire body felt great, and his resources were maxed out once more. It was actually a bit funny—he found a bunch of empty potions on the ground, but he couldn’t at all remember drinking those. Drinking in my sleep… Am I becoming a potion-holic?

Checking the time, he still had more than twelve hours left until it was time for the World Congress. He had slept for a good ten hours, and he felt fresh as a cucumber.

With everything ready, he began making his way back towards the temple. He noticed how he barely encountered any monkeys on the way, and those he did see were solitary, regular D-grades, or even E-grades.

Jake landed on top of a tree, then stared down at the temple grounds and saw how it was now entirely desolate. There was only a single living being atop the highest point of the ancient temple, waiting, almost baiting him.

[Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima – lvl 134]

Grown three levels since last time I checked, Jake noted. Perhaps it had seen its interference in whatever Jake was doing as unnecessary, as it progressed its own strength at a rapid pace.

Alright, pal… let’s see what you can do, he thought as he focused on the monkey in the distance, an Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter slowly being summoned.

Chapter 8

Monkey Business

The arrow emerged from his palm as he focused on the monkey in the distance. He had a feeling that it knew he was there, just not where exactly he was hiding. It was just sitting on top of its temple, inviting him to attack—something Jake would gladly do, and even begin with his most decisive blow possible.

On a side note, Jake had tried to use Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter with his new Splitting Arrow, and it still didn’t work. He couldn’t split an arrow fired with Arcane Powershot either. Then again… it would be pretty silly if he could effectively triple the power of a powerful, epic-rarity skill with a rare skill. No, copying the Arcane Hunter’s Arrows didn’t really feel like he was copying an entire "skill."

With the arrow fully summoned, Jake carefully took aim at the monkey. He was far away—several kilometers—and its back was turned, yet he felt like he knew. He couldn’t help but use Identify to once more confirm it was indeed the Prima.

[Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima – lvl 134]

Yep, that’s the one…

His instincts also made it clear it was the real one… that it wasn’t some mental magic trick or an illusion or anything like that. It genuinely was just sitting there, waiting for him to strike. Was it stupid, overconfident, or did it have a plan in mind? Perhaps all three? Jake didn’t know.

But he was sure as hell about to find out.

He didn’t hesitate to activate Limit Break to 10% as he charged his Arcane Powershot. He released the string just as he felt the Windsoar Bow no longer able to endure it anymore, and with an explosion of arcane mana and stamina, the giant arrow flew forth.

Just before he let go of the string, the Prima sitting atop the building turned around and looked his way. Jake instantly froze it, and just as he did, he noticed how he had frozen it mid-smile.

CRASH!

The two upper floors of the ancient temple collapsed in an accelerated manner, as if the entire building and Prima had suddenly gotten dozens of times heavier. That damn smile was still on the monkey’s face when the arrow passed over its head and harmlessly struck a tree on the other side of the temple grounds.

You little shit.

Able to move again, the monkey didn’t jump or do anything in particular; it just slowly stood up on top of the ruined upper parts of the temple and stared at Jake, who still stood far away on a tree branch. Their eyes met for a moment, and Jake felt the provocation and confidence in the gaze of the Prima—a sentiment he returned in kind.

Neither of them felt like they could lose.

Jake quickly drew a pre-poisoned arrow from his quiver and began charging another Arcane Powershot. In response, the monkey pointed one of its five tails in his direction—a move he had seen the other D-grades make many times before, but never at this range.

The immediate surroundings of the tail distorted for a second, and Jake was forced to jump. A massive shockwave hit the tree below him as he fired his arrow while in mid-air.

His Powershot was intercepted by another wave of force, but clearly one attack was superior to the other. The wave of force was broken as a sonic boom sounded out midway through the arrow’s flight, caused by a small explosion from the clash. The Prima was forced to dodge the powerful arcane shot with a frown and an angry screech, still being scratched even then.

It responded by firing off blasts of force from its three tails, and Jake happily dodged all of them as he returned an arrow for every tree that had a large part of its bark blown off. It was a ranged battle with several kilometers between the fighters. Jake came out on top initially, as the monkey took a few minor injuries. Unluckily, Jake hadn’t managed to land much of his poison quite yet. It was still infected, though.

This whole exchange clearly didn’t sit well with the monkey, which had clearly had its pride hurt. It screeched angrily once more as its golden hair began standing up, and it flew towards Jake. Not jumping or floating or whatever, but truly flying.

Weight and force magic combined? Jake thought as the monkey soared towards him, even faster than Hawkie. It was a speed that would have stumped him before, but Jake had a trick up his sleeve… called having thrown all his Free Points into Agility.

He reacted by summoning his wings of poison and death as he fired another arrow after the charging monkey. It didn’t even attempt to dodge. The exploding arcane arrow split in three, and arcane energy appeared to consume the Prima in a raging flood of destruction as they clashed.

For a second, at least. Then the figure exited the explosion, not a scratch on it. But Jake saw the reason right away. It had a rippling sphere around it that appeared to have perfectly blocked the attack and kept the destructive energy out.

A powerful barrier… but… compared to the King…

Their levels were similar. Both were clearly not average beasts. Every single D-grade Jake met, he compared to the King… He just couldn’t help it. Especially not after the mask on his head had started hinting at some ominous return.

And when he compared any creature to the King, he just found them… lacking. Perhaps it was due to a part of him having inherently overestimated the King, as he, for all intents and purposes, was the only foe Jake had fought that he felt he hadn’t truly "beaten.”

The Prima is not to be underestimated, however.

That barrier was strong, and its speed impressive. He managed to fire one more quickly charged Powershot before it arrived, and he had a stable version of his arrows for that blow. The shot managed to pierce the barrier but missed the monkey itself, as it was deflected slightly by the barrier.

As he had no intentions of entering a melee brawl right away, Jake swiftly took a step to teleport down from the tree he was standing on. The monkey was clearly even better than him at flying, and if it could increase his weight like its brethren, then mid-air fighting wasn’t advised. He could totally see himself being forced down and smashed into the forest below.

The monkey didn’t hesitate to follow, descending like a meteor straight towards him. It looked like it intended to just crush him outright with the sphere around it. Jake wasn’t sure exactly how a direct clash with the monkey would go, and he really didn’t see any reason to find out.

Just before the monkey hit the ground, he took another step away, arcane bolts spinning to life and floating where he had just stepped away from.

BOOM!

Once more, the forest shook as the ground exploded with even more arcane mana, followed by a quick Arcane Powershot straight towards where Mark of the Ambitious Hunter told him the monkey was.

If the screech of pain didn’t tell him he had hit, the new response from Sense of the Malefic Viper sure did. Hemotoxin successfully delivered.

With a swipe of one of its tails, the Prima dispelled the cloud of dust and soil, making Jake see that it had an arrow sticking out of its shoulder. It looked more annoyed than angry as it ripped it out, stared a bit at the poison, and then tossed it aside. It stood in a weird pose, with one hand on the wound and another over its forehead, just looking at Jake.

"Can’t talk, can you?" he asked the beast, as it looked to have calmed down a bit after being infected by the poison. At least Jake thought so, until he felt its real intent. Fucker was just buying time.

It saw that he noticed and smiled at him, removing its hand from its forehead to reveal a glowing, silvery motif. The motif didn’t at all fit the rest of the monkey’s golden hide… and neither did its effects, as just a moment later…

The Prima disappeared.

Not invisibility either, as his Sphere of Perception made him know it truly was gone… Even the Mark was gone, and so was any response from Sense of the Malefic Viper. Jake was stumped. Had it decided to flee?

He stood there, confused for a bit, wondering what the hell to do… then dodged to the side, narrowly avoiding a whip-like tail that would have taken his head off.

Where the monkey had disappeared from, a new figure now stood. It looked a lot like the Prima, but its hide was white, almost silvery, and its tails looked more like those of a Dervish than a regular Lighttail Monkey.

But… Jake’s Identify and instincts made him aware it was the same beast.

[Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima – lvl 134]

Jake was confused, as this figure was completely unharmed. All the small wounds from earlier were gone, there was no poison in its system, and even his Mark was no longer there… Some kind of double-body skill? Or is it just its long-lost brother?

Ultimately, it didn’t matter… What mattered more was that this new figure was quite different—not just in appearance, but style.

Dervishes were tough due to their three tails constantly attacking… Unsurprisingly, five was a lot worse.

Jake dodged and weaved, blocking with his Scimitar and Venomfang all the time yet still getting hit here and there. The wings on his back were pumping out poison, making the Prima now target those. It moved in closer and momentarily stunned Jake by suddenly making it feel like a mountain was pressing down on his shoulders. He used both weapons to protect his vitals, but this allowed the monkey to go for its true targets.

Like two snakes clamping down, two tails moved and stabbed through the fleshy parts of the wings. With Jake now being unable to move them and distracted, two other tails swept down and severed both wings entirely, making Jake hiss in pain.

Yet he couldn’t be outdone; he took the four tails being busy as a chance to attack. He pushed himself forward and found that, while the beast was faster than him, he won out on pure strength. He stabbed Venomfang into the arm used to block his blow and had his Scimitar blocked by the fifth tail, which left just his final weapon: his teeth.

The monkey looked surprised when it raised its other arm to attack and Jake happily chomped down. His canines were already coated in a highly potent toxin. Yes, while Jake had said he really didn’t think he would ever use that part of Fangs of the Malefic Viper… the opportunity was just too good, and his instinctive way of fighting didn’t really take into account any potential embarrassment after the fact.

BOOM!

Jake was instantly impacted by a massive wave of force that aimed to send him flying back, but he had predicted it. He released his own wave of disruptive mana from his pores, resulting in both him and the monkey just exploding mana into the other’s face.

Their whole stalemate was disrupted when the hunter was forced to let go with his mouth due to two tails coming down to smash his skull. At the same time, it also allowed him to sweep up with his scimitar and land a long cut across the chest of the monkey as he took a step back, poisoning the Prima even more while draining a bit of health.

The Prima attacked back, and they proceeded to brawl a little in melee, Jake taking the occasional wound but landing two in return. His opponent tried many different techniques, all variations of what other monkeys had used on him before. This allowed Jake to predict many attacks, and it eventually allowed him to dodge under an attack and, with a swipe, cut off one of the monkey’s tails in a moment where the Prima failed to strengthen it with mana.

However, he wasn’t done. He swiftly took a small step forward and teleported back, summoning his bow. He quickly nocked an arrow, drew the string, and loosed the arrow for the beast that was already preparing to dodge to the side but found itself frozen by Gaze yet again.

Another arrow penetrated the monkey’s stomach and sent it flying back, blood flowing from several wounds on its body and the poison spreading throughout. It was far less durable in its silvery form, and Jake happily took advantage of that fact.

He didn’t let it relax but instead kept attacking, at which point the Prima became nearly suicidal. It stormed him, slashing with its four remaining tails, clawing with its hands, and even trying to bite him a few times. It released a constant pressure that increased his weight, and every slap of the tail felt like he was hit by a sledgehammer. Clearly, it held nothing back.

Jake felt like the entire situation was off, but he couldn’t exactly just stop fighting. However, he did try to minimize his own wounds and just buy time, as he suspected not everything was as it seemed. Besides, the Prima was growing weaker by the second as the poison spread in its body. The injection from his bite was doing a hell of a lot.

In a final clash, Jake took a nasty stab from a tail to his shoulder, but in return, he severed the entire right arm of the Prima and sent it flying back with a kick. It coughed up blood when it smashed into a tree and looked to be on the brink of death, yet Jake still felt like something was off.

A sense of wrongness only amplified when the monkey looked listlessly up at him and laughed, a huge grin on its face. It raised its one remaining arm to the golden symbol on its forehead as it disappeared.

"Oh, fuck me, this is bullshit," Jake said, already knowing what would happen. He took out a health potion and chugged it down to prepare for round three.

A second later, the monkey reappeared with its golden fur back in near-pristine condition. At least Jake still felt a faint trace of poison—the hemotoxin he had inflicted before it switched to its silver form.

At least it doesn’t just fully heal itself when it does that bullshit… Jake bitterly thought as he cracked his neck and stared down the Prima, which just looked tauntingly back at him.

But what can you do…? Jake had no intention to back down as he teleported back, drew his bow, and continued the fight. He just hoped there wasn’t going to be any more monkey business going on.

Chapter 9

Enjoyment

There was going to be more monkey business going on.

Once more, the Prima was fighting in a way that just didn’t make any logical sense. It took far more damage than Jake with every exchange; in fact, it was even worse for the Prima now that it had changed back to its golden form. It relied on magic and ranged combat, which was A-okay with Jake.

Its magic was something he was getting very used to, even if it did spice it up sometimes. At times, random areas around him would suddenly increase in weight, only making half of his body heavier, while at other times, the monkey threw a small stone that probably weighed a few tons post-weight amplification.

The waves of force were also something he easily dodged by now, as he had learned most of the Prima’s tells, and yet despite it all, he still couldn’t help frowning. A few injuries here and there against a foe of equal or slightly greater strength was expected, so Jake did take quite a few blows, while the monkey looked to not give a damn about taking several poisoned arrows just to return a blow that did far less damage.

Can it do that transformation again? Jake asked himself, genuinely unsure. He believed it shouldn’t be able to, based on how the golden version of the monkey had still been a bit wounded after it transformed back, and the silver version had been left close to death.

Besides that, the silver symbol on its forehead currently wasn’t glowing. It was still there and gave off an odd gray color with a bit of black mixed in. Jake even thought for a second it was due to toxins, as it looked almost deathly, but Sense of the Malefic Viper didn’t give off any response.

However… he was sure the symbol meant something. Maybe it truly was just a sign to show the silver version was out of commission? But then why did the monkey fight as it did? Had it given up or something? Decided to try and take him down with it? It was doubtful… because it looked to be in pretty high spirits, and even if it did try for mutual destruction, clearly the monkey would fall first, based on how things were going.

Does it not know I drank the health potion, and now believes my health points to be lower than they actually are?

So many thoughts, just searching for an explanation, went through his head as he kept fighting and exchanging blows. Jake dodged under a blast and fired off one of three arcane bolts floating above him, making a hole in the monkey’s barrier as the arcane mana tore it apart. He followed up with a quick arrow, penetrating the monkey’s stomach and sending even more blood flying.

The Prima retaliated by pointing all five tails forward and releasing a massive wave of force that expanded in a giant cone in front of it. In a display that must have consumed ridiculous amounts of mana, it managed to make Jake lose his footing for a second, allowing the monkey to land a quick blast of force that sent him flying back.

He felt a few ribs get pushed in, but nothing was broken. It did worsen his wounds a bit, but currently Jake was fine with not moving too fast. While he was confident the monkey had more tricks up its sleeves, Jake also had a trick. Or, well, a potion cooldown.

Perhaps the monkey noticed he was just dragging the fight out, too, as it finally decided to use its final card and change up the fight. It kind of had to do something, as it was dying of poison pretty damn rapidly. It released a few gigantic blasts, likely running itself out of mana, and it was only when it looked barely able to fight that it made its move.

Jake was unsure what it would do… until he saw it raise its hand towards its forehead once more.

You’ve got to be fucking kidding me.

The moment it touched the mark, the Prima disappeared, just like all the times before.

He just took out his bow and began charging an Arcane Powershot, hoping to give it a good opening blow when it appeared again. Which it did, a few seconds later.

Jake instantly fired his arrow before even seeing the figure fully appear. The Arcane Powershot tore through the air towards the Prima, but the monkey was already dodging before it was fully visible.

Well, fuck, Jake thought as he recalled something he had experienced before… the concept of altered time. Even if time had somehow been reversed, or perhaps the timeline changed, he still remembered all of it. It wasn’t due to any Bloodline shenanigans; the monkey just wasn’t good enough at the concept to truly control time. He quickly used Identify on the monkey to truly inspect its changed form.

[Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima – lvl 134]

Its level was unchanged, but its form was not. Before, it had been hunched over, while now it stood with a straight back. It had even grown nearly half a meter to be as big as Jake. Its fur was now dull and gray and it had several scars all over its body, including one across its forehead. The symbol there was gone, destroyed by whatever had caused the scar. Even more surprising was its back… Where five tails usually were, there was now only one with four stumps surrounding it.

The Prima looked older. Far older. Like it had gone from a young, arrogant master to an old veteran. Its demeanor had followed suit, as it stood there silently observing him. Yet there was still a trace of impatience, not born of stupidity or inexperience, but from an inherent time pressure… It’s a limited transformation, he instantly concluded.

That was all he had time to think about before the monkey made its move—or, well, had already made its move. It was in front of Jake the same moment he reacted, doing some more time-magic bullshit to allow it to move extremely fast, if Jake had to guess.

It swung not with its tail but its clawed hand. Those hands, which the monkey could barely use competently before, now soared towards Jake’s throat like an eagle’s talons, forcing him to bend back and dodge as he kicked the monkey in the abdomen.

With grace, it dodged back as he did so, sliding across the ground before swiftly attacking again. Jake had his scimitar and dagger out now and blocked the first swipe with ease. He had expected to cut a bit into the bare arm of the beast but found its fur as hard as metal, no doubt caused by a skill of some sort.

Jake moved forward as he compared his strength with the beast's. He was slightly pushed back as it retaliated, proving he was inferior in pure stats. Its speed was slightly above his, too. In a purely physical melee fight, it was a difficult foe to face… but Jake wasn’t a purely physical melee fighter.

He dodged back and swiftly began condensing two arcane bolts floating above him. The monkey hesitated for a second, allowing Jake to summon his bow. The moment he did so, the beast surely knew it had to attack if it wished to avoid facing the hunter in a ranged battle.

It only managed to take a single step before it froze up for a second. By the time it was able to move, an arrow struck its chest, finally delivering a good dose of poison.

Or at least, that was what Jake first experienced happening. Suddenly the monkey became able to move a fraction of a second earlier than expected and dodged the arrow by the narrowest of margins. With Jake momentarily stumped by his own immense annoyance, he barely managed to block its next claw attack. This one was different.

Like it had hit him with a fucking sledgehammer, he felt his arm buckle and the claw sink into his chest before sending him flying back into a tree. It was only after being sent flying that he noticed the faint white energy surrounding the hand. Jake nearly slapped himself.

How the fuck could I forget the weight magic…?

Just because it now did time bullshit didn’t mean it had lost its other school of magic.

Jake did hurt a bit from the blow and had five small holes in his chest from the fingers of the monkey… but honestly, that wasn’t a big deal. His entire body was already a mess from the drawn-out fight, and he was in many ways at a disadvantage.

Yet… in an almost ironic twist of fate, time was on his side. The monkey could only remain in its current form a limited amount of time, and Jake had his "trick" coming up.

The monkey obviously knew it had limited time as it continued its assault, while Jake stayed purely on the defensive. He blocked with his blade at every turn, his scales already summoned all over his body to lessen the damage a bit more. Throughout it all, he could feel the monkey building something up deep within itself. Like something was slowly being conjured and prepared.

It gave Jake a small sense of dread, as he knew that the monkey before him was no longer as dumb as before. It had a plan to finish him off before its transformation ran out. A plan Jake naturally would prefer to do without.

Their clash continued as they exchanged blows. They were far more even than one would expect, and Jake’s many levels from committing monkey genocide came in tight. His Agility allowed him to keep up, and even if his strength was subpar, he could make up for it with his magic.

The Prima seemed pressured yet sure of itself. It dodged his blows with grace and counterattacked only when opportune, never overextending. A few clashes did end with both taking a heavy hit, yet just as Jake felt that happen, it became a feeling of deja vu. Another obvious weakness of that time-magic trick: it worked on both parties. It truly was like it turned back time.

Finally, the two clashed again, and Jake stabbed the monkey in the chest with his scimitar since he believed it had fucked up and finally overextended a step too far. He was proven wrong when the monkey suddenly flew backward. Only then did he notice its tail embedded in the ground behind it, acting as a rope to drag it back.

At the same time, it chopped down on Jake’s wrist with both its hands, making him momentarily lose all strength in it and allowing the monkey to effectively disarm him.

Well…

The monkey ripped the sword out of its own chest and tossed it into the air before catching it with its tail.

…this is annoying.

With a swing of the tail, Jake was forced to dodge his own damn scimitar. While he was fully aware the blade wasn’t actually "active" in the hands of the monkey, that didn’t mean it wouldn’t hurt to be hit by what was now practicality just a metal rod.

Fuck me, Jake thought as he got smacked in the side, the blow barely hurting but still throwing him off balance. The tail’s power in its older veteran form was weaker than both its golden and silver form, but it made up for that in pure upper-body strength and experience.

On the backfoot, Jake did what he could to avoid taking too much damage while trying to get some range between him and his foe. Without his best weapon, it was far too dangerous to fight the Prima in a straight battle.

He leaped back and used One Step Mile the moment he landed. Teleporting away, he swiftly summoned his bow and turned in the air to fire a shot towards the monkey. It responded by punching the air and sending a wave of force out that broke all three exploding arrows mid-air, far too close to Jake for comfort.

The resulting explosion sent the human flying back. While in motion, he became aware that it was time for the big turnaround. And just in time, as he saw that the Prima was about ready to do whatever the fuck it was planning.

With great vigor, he took out the small bottle and chugged it down as if his life depended on it—because it likely did.

The warm liquid spread through his body and rapidly healed it. His sore arms began to feel more flexible, his aching bones regenerated and became tough and resilient once more. All of it happened within seconds as the potion did its job, and for the first time, Jake saw the Prima look truly surprised after its transformation.

It was also the first time he saw it show anger and annoyance as it activated what it had prepared.

Jake felt it before he saw it. An odd sense of pressure overtook the entire area as the symbol covered by the scar lit up on the Prima’s forehead. Its light was intense enough to shine through the scar tissue and be fully visible.

The symbol’s color started as gray , then bisected. One side turned golden and the other silver. This energy spread down the upper body of the Prima as Jake saw the symbol itself split in two directions and also begin moving. He saw it glide across the skin of the monkey due to it shining until, finally, both symbols found their home on the back of the Prima’s hands.

And then… then it attacked.

The first hand’s punch released a massive wave of force towards Jake. At the same time, it took a step forward and practically teleported to him as it swung the other in an overhead punch.

The shockwave hit exactly at the same time as the punch, as if it had somehow been delayed. Jake raised both his arms to block the hit and the blast simultaneously, even summoning a barrier of arcane mana as quickly as he could.

BOOM!

Scales and blood flew out everywhere as the punch landed, and Jake felt both his arms hurt like hell. He was pretty sure his left one was broken. The arm with the silver symbol on it was like the pinnacle of a melee weapon, while the golden one was now a master of releasing its magic.

Jake was sent flying back, but he had managed to get a bit of a counterattack in at the final moment.

The Prima stumbled back in a loud screech, now covered in a liquid that it had been the cause of releasing: blood. More accurately, blood infused with Blood of the Malefic Viper.

It looked at the human furiously, its eyes red from sprayed blood and burning with rage. Jake just slowly stood up from the tree he had hit, cracking the bone on his left arm back in place as he stared back at the Prima.

Their eyes met, and they moved simultaneously.

Jake jumped and dodged a blast of force that blew a huge hole in the tree he’d just been at, a bow already in hand as he fired an arrow at the Prima. It reacted by swatting it away with his own scimitar, making Jake grumble a bit before firing another shot.

The Prima only had its current form due to a temporary powerup. Now it had used another powerup that also felt very temporary. By all accounts, Jake should just try to open up space, buy some time, and play it safe. It would be the smartest thing to do.

So, of course, Jake charged a fast Arcane Powershot as he took a step at the same moment, appearing straight before the surprised Prima that had expected him to make the smarter choice. It was even more surprised when it was punched in the face.

Because the thing is… there was something Jake valued far more than being efficient and smart in a fight:

Enjoying it.

Chapter 10

Fragmented

Boom!

The Prima was sent flying back as Jake’s hand exploded in an assault of arcane mana the same moment he punched it. Its silly belief in Jake playing it smart had clearly backfired on it, as Jake was more than happy to be risky. The reason he had held back before was due to the uncertainty of what it was cooking up, but now… now he knew he could face it head-on.

His opponent got up with a nosebleed, looking more than a little pissed as it zoomed forward. Jake was ready as he met it; he had also decided to now hold nothing back.

More energy than ever began streaming from his pores until the ground cracked beneath his feet. The internal flow of his energy sped up to new levels as his body began overflowing with power. He hadn’t done it many times since reaching D-grade, but damn, did he love the feeling.

Limit break at 10% had been active the entire fight, but now he pushed it to 20%. All his capabilities instantly increased as he clashed with the beast.

He had lost his primary melee weapon… but that didn’t mean he didn’t have any. In fact, he had a whole lot of them.

In the hand not holding Venomfang, an arrow appeared—one he had no intentions of using with a bow. It did mean that the arrow wouldn’t benefit from a lot of what made it good, but it could still be used to stab stuff.

The monkey clawed at him with its swift hand, leaving a silver trail after every swipe that burned with energy and cut into Jake’s Scales of the Malefic Viper. In return, he stabbed an arrow into the shoulder of the beast and, in just as swift a motion, pulled one from his quiver and slammed it down too. His Venomfang was used to deflect the golden hand that the monkey extended in a palm-hit, firing off a massive shockwave.

Jake followed up with another quick jab and a kick to the monkey’s leg, which made it decide that enough was enough. It slammed its hands together. Yet another shockwave of golden and silver light hit him, and Jake felt his body lighten for a moment as he was sent flying back, only to become heavy and slam straight down.

Another explosion created yet another crater as Jake was forced to quickly roll away from the monkey. It had jumped and slammed its foot down where his head had just been. Jake felt quite a bit of aching all over his body from that last one.

Not that the Prima was doing any better. It had two arrows sticking out of it, one of them coated in his hemotoxin. It had tried to avoid being too poisoned, but fighting someone like Jake, it was truly impossible to altogether prevent it.

Without waiting for the beast to make the first move again, Jake moved in closer and tried to stab it with another arrow. The monkey was having none of that; its silver claw flew up and just straight up ripped the tip of the arrow off, making the entire arrow disperse.

The golden claw flew up and tried to blast his head off, but Jake tilted it by dodging the blow and landing an uppercut on the monkey. It grit its teeth as it was lifted off the ground for a moment before it suddenly slammed straight back down, also slamming its tail into Jake with the full might of its weight magic behind the blow.

His own scimitar crashed into his shoulder from above, bringing him to his knee as he felt like something broke. Yet he also took the opportunity to grasp out with his other hand and push the monkey to the ground, the hand glowing a dark green.

The Prima stabbed its silver hand into Jake’s guts as he held it down, but he didn’t let up. Instead, he kept pumping Touch of the Malefic Viper into its body. Jake even knelt down a bit and flexed his muscles to make the monkey unable to retract its hand from inside his body. He used his other hand to hold the golden hand away so it couldn’t blast him off an—

Just then, it blasted him from an awkward angle.

This is getting damn annoying, Jake thought as he landed softly on the ground, a trail of blood in his wake that sizzled as it hit the ground. The monkey also screeched angrily, as its silver hand looked like it had just been put into a vat of acid—which it kind of had, considering Jake’s use of the Blood of the Malefic Viper on all the blood around where the monkey had stabbed its hand in.

But… he was beginning to learn. He got a faint tingling in his mind as it cast its time magic—a sense of wrongness. He got it after, while, and before it happened, as weird as that sounds. Jake felt that if he could feel it, he could impact it somehow.

Both parties clashed once more, landing blow after blow on the other. The confidence of the Prima had begun waning long ago, as it seemingly found the human before it far more resilient and resourceful than expected. Jake, too, was surprised. Despite its weak-looking state, the monkey was tough and durable. Its ability to avoid most blows to vital areas helped it immensely.

In the end, the big difference-maker was once more the poison. Its time magic could help it heal immediate wounds, but the accumulated poison was still too much. The monkey was clearly aware it had to finish things now, or it wouldn’t end well.

And while Jake didn’t have to, he chose to face it in a final clash. Be it due to arrogance or well-founded self-confidence, he genuinely believed he had no way to lose.

They flew at each other, and Jake saw the symbol on the half-rotten and broken silver hand move to its other one. At the same time, the entire arm began glowing with newfound energy, but Jake was also fully aware the monkey’s entire arm could only handle a single blow before breaking apart from the sheer stress caused by the power.

Jake himself placed both his hands on Venomfang, focusing every fiber of his being on the weapon. He pumped mana into it to strengthen it and even coated it in a bit of excess mana. At the same time, he tried to use Descending Dark Fang. He instantly felt his intended action fail… but he wasn’t taking no for an answer.

He forced his will upon the blade until the arcane mana swirled and extended as an edge, the dark mana burning into it meanwhile. In the end, the energies were forced to mix and mingle, destroying one another until they finally reached equilibrium and split away from each other.

The arcane mana formed a coating around the entire dagger, looking almost like the weapon was made of crystal, while the dark mana swirled around that. The whole blade was volatile as he, with both hands, stabbed it down towards the head of the Prima.

At the final moment, it dodged to the side, prepared to strike—only to find that Jake had also halted his blow, not doing as he was supposed to. It was too late for the Prima, which smashed its fist towards Jake’s face in an attack that would undoubtedly blow his entire head off.

An attack that resulted in the Prima learning that, while it certainly was a talented user of time magic…

It wasn’t the only one who could use the concept.

Moment of the Primal Hunter

Time slowed as Jake saw the fist about to impact his head. He swiftly moved around it and stabbed his dagger down towards the head of the Prima. The moment he did so, he felt it try to once more interfere, and for a fraction of a second, he saw the despair in the eyes of the monkey as it realized… this was a moment that didn’t belong to it. A moment where it was utterly suppressed by a superior concept of time.

Everything returned to usual as the clash happened.

One fist missed the human and sent a wave of golden and silver light flying out, tearing up a huge part of the forest as the Prima’s entire arm was mangled by its own power. However, it failed to hit the human with anything but a bit of the remnant energy.

The other attack came from the dagger that swirled with a mix of arcane and darkness, plunging down into the skull of the Prima and releasing two loud cracks—one from the broken skull and the other from the dagger itself.

A torrent of arcane and darkness penetrated the entire body of the Prima as the edge extended, and its screech of pain turned to silence.

*You have slain [Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima – lvl 134] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 113 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 114 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 108 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 115 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake stood almost frozen as his arm shook from the impact of his own attack. The energy around the dagger faded away and revealed the form of Venomfang. It had a large crack down the middle with many small fractures throughout. He instantly knew this battle would be the last for the good-old reliable fang.

As for the attack he had unleashed at the end… it was yet another skill upgrade that had come in clutch. One that shouldn’t really have come as a surprise, given how much he had been practicing using his arcane mana. He’d even made a few arcane edges here and there.

[Descending Dark Fang (Rare)] – A fang coated in dark mana descending like the clamping mouth of a snake. Do a downward strike with a melee weapon, significantly increasing penetrative power and damage inflicted. Dark mana makes the wound harder to heal and drains energy until dispelled. Damage improved further if the weapon is benefitting from Twin Fang Style. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility, Strength, and Intelligence when using Descending Dark Fang.

-->

[Descending Dark Arcane Fang (Epic)] – A fang that strikes from the darkness, clamping down with the fury of your arcane. Infuse your blade with a mixture of dark and arcane mana as you do a downward strike, significantly increasing damage done and penetrative power. Dark mana makes the wound harder to heal and drains energy until dispelled. Arcane mana creates a powerful coating and extends the edge while increasing all its basic capabilities. Damage improved further if the weapon is benefitting from Twin Fang Style. Adds a bonus to the effect of Agility, Strength, and Intelligence when using Descending Dark Arcane Fang.

The skill had gotten stronger in every way, even if its name was beginning to look a bit silly. Either way, Jake couldn’t help feeling accomplished. He had won. Gotten a skill upgrade and three whole levels for the effort too. Even with how slow leveling was supposed to get in D-grade, Jake had an extreme pace, likely due to the difficulty of the foes he faced. He was truly living up to the name of his class, and surely increasing his speed even further.

Jake stood and smiled as he looked down on the dead monkey. He was slightly perplexed when he saw the Prima slowly turn to dust, its eyes still wide open with surprise, but he nevertheless spoke his genuine thoughts to the figure moments before it disappeared.

"Good fight."

Jake saw the entire figure of the Prima disappear, leaving nothing behind but a small piece of golden metal and a core. He quickly used Identify on the golden fragment, and it left him more confused than anything else.

[Key Fragment of the Exalted Prima (Unique)] – A key fragment to the Seat of the Exalted Prima. Collect three fragments to form the Key of the Exalted Prima to gain access.

I guess it is good to know the system can still be like a videogame sometimes, Jake thought with a small chuckle. Maybe collecting the key would unlock a secret boss or a treasure vault? Either way, it sounded like something he was definitely gonna do.

As for the second item, it was, of course, the Beastcore.

[Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima Beastcore (D-grade)] – – A Beastcore left behind by a D-grade Penta-Lighttail Monkey Prima, containing remnants of its Records within. Can be used as an alchemical ingredient for many types of creations but is most often found in elixirs. Contains powerful energy related to the concept of time.

Jake looked at it for a bit, then picked it up together with the fragment and, of course, his dropped scimitar. It was good to have that back. While getting a key fragment and a Beastcore may have seemed a bit shitty for the tough fight, Jake totally got it. It would be weird if creatures out in the wild just dropped random high-rarity items. It would break the economy and make most crafters obsolete for sure. Maybe dungeons still do a bit of that? Hmmm….

It was also a bit weird that the monkey just turned to dust and left a key behind, sure, but what can ya do? Jake wouldn’t really feel comfortable running around in an old monkey’s hide anyway. That would just be weird.

As he stood there, looking at the core and thinking of what he could possibly make with it in the future—or what someone else could make—he remembered something slightly important.

"Oh, yeah. World Congress."

He checked the time and saw that he still had… a bit less than ten hours. Plenty of time, plenty of time.

Jake could get back in three hours tops. He was more than good on time.

Well, he did feel like shit, so maybe a bit more than an hour, as he needed to wait for his potion cooldown to be up. The fight with the monkey had lasted nearly two hours, the vast majority of it spent just on the ranged parts of the fight. It was actually a damn long time for two D-grades to battle.

With all that in mind, Jake had plenty of time to check out that ancient central temple the Prima had been guarding and going into while Jake was busy slaughtering the entire local Lighttail Monkey population. Maybe it was hiding all its shiny stuff there?

In a dark cell, the chains hung from above. Ancient magic marked every part of the walls and floors. Within, a single being was trapped.

The figure opened its eyes as the chains that bound it rattled to the movement. A mighty beast. It barely had time to realize why it had been awakened before one of its chains broke, and the spike that had been inserted in its body vanished.

A single seal was now broken.

A single stub where something had once been now regrowing.

A single stub of 999.

998 chains remained—998 spikes sealing the beast.

The figure closed its eyes once more as it waited for release.

Chapter 11

The Calm Before the Politics

He wasn’t sure if he should be disappointed or not as he entered the central temple. The inside sloped down a bit as he entered a small underground chamber—a perfect place for a secret treasure vault.

What he found instead was just a damn bush… tree… thing. As he looked at it, he actually found it a bit odd that his Sagacity of the Malefic Viper didn’t toss out a snippet of knowledge. His Herbology skill was also not giving him any idea what the hell he was looking at.

Luckily, the system still came in tight and offered a nice explanation as he used Identify.

[Ancient Celerita Musa (Ancient)] – This plant has been grown from an ancient Musa seed and brought new life by the advent of the system. Also commonly called a banana tree, this plant produces different sorts of bananas, a type of fruit unique to the newly integrated planet Earth. This tree has become intimately connected to the concept of time through unknown means, making its growth pattern highly unpredictable. Destroying this tree will have unpredictable effects, and using it in any kind of alchemical creation will require one to first anchor it in time. Can only grow in certain areas with intense amounts of mana.

You learn something new every day. Jake actually thought bananas grew on trees, something the system acknowledged. Maybe it was just being extra-nice with these new things and giving all of that sweet info? Either way, it was much appreciated. As for the banana Musa itself…

Well, this was without a doubt the rarest and most powerful herb Jake had ever come across. He felt the pressure just standing before it as he observed the weird plant.

It looked like it was growing in real time. At least, it was… until suddenly it wasn’t. A minute or so later, a part of it suddenly began growing in the opposite direction—in other words, began retracting into itself as if time reversed. That was likely because time kind of did reverse… This was a time tree… time Musa. Whatever. Anyway… kinda awesome, not gonna lie.

It wasn’t very big—only about five meters tall—though it was pretty wide with its large leaves. There was nothing else in the entire underground chamber aside from a few other minor herbs that Jake decided he may as well just pick up.

As he stood there, considering that, something happened on the plant. One of the flower-like growths suddenly appeared to bloom as four small bumps began growing out. Within less than a minute, the bumps took the shape of bananas and the growth stopped.

The bumps were—to the surprise of no one—bananas. Yellow and ripe, looking just like what Jake was used to buying in the supermarket. Jake was pretty sure modern bananas were selectively bred or something like that, but who was gonna complain about delicious-looking bananas?

He went up to the tree—yes, Jake had decided to just call it a tree because it looked a bit like a tree—and felt like he passed a weird barrier as he got close. He felt like time was being ever so slightly affected in the area a few meters around it.

Using Identify on the bananas, Jake was honestly a bit taken aback.

[Celerita Banana (Rare)] – As a banana from the Ancient Celerita Musa, this fruit contains intense amounts of Celerita-affinity mana with Agility-enhancing effects. This fruit can be used in many different creations and is especially suited for flasks and elixirs. Due to this banana’s origin, it will be returned to the rivers of time if it is moved too far from the tree. Consuming or transforming the fruit will anchor the energies in time, removing this effect. +3 Agility upon consumption.

This was the second natural treasure he had seen that just stated how many stat points it gave, the first being the Argentum Vitae Mushrooms all the way back in the Challenge Dungeon. These bananas were clearly a step better, giving 3 stat points each.

With four of them, that was just 12 free Agility. Well, not entirely free. As with most things, there was a cap.

Jake had considered at one point if the rich and entitled kids of the multiverse couldn’t just have their mama and papa give them a mountain of elixirs and whatnot to instantly make them absolutely overpowered for their level, but that—luckily—wasn’t a thing.

Villy had explained to him that the cap was actually quite low and based entirely on race level. For levels 1 to 24, AKA F-grade, you could get 3 stat points per race level; for E-grade, you could get 5 per level, and D-grade, 15 per level. This ultimately resulted in Jake having a maximum cap of stat bonuses from consuming stuff that sat at 585. Of course, he had already used a bit of that.

Jake had eaten his way to a total of 86 stat points gained—51 of it in Vitality, 25 in Toughness, and 10 in Willpower. The stats were coming from the elixir he had chugged down after clearing the Valley of Tusks dungeon, the fucked-up concoction he had made to clear the Challenge Dungeon, and the mural with the history of the Malefic Viper in that same dungeon. Yes, things like that "glimpse" counted towards this cap too. This cap was pretty much everything you could get from outside sources.

There was one big difference between this and something like equipment, though. First of all, it counted towards base values, and secondly, there was no limit to increasing any one stat. This meant Jake could go drink Perception-increasing elixirs and get 499 Perception at his current level if he so wanted. Which he kind of did want, but that wasn’t the current issue.

The current issue was that he was under time pressure in front of a giant time tree-thingie that he really wanted, and based on all the descriptions going around, there was some magic going on he didn’t really understand.

He did understand that he couldn’t just take the bananas that were growing on the tree. Maybe he could put them in his storage, but he had a feeling they wouldn’t come out the way he wanted them. The barrier around the tree was likely what kept them ripe as they currently were, and he would have to find a way to "anchor" them before using them in any alchemical creation.

Well, with the four bananas that had just grown, he anchored one the easiest way possible by grabbing and peeling it.

You have assimilated a powerful energy of Agility.

+3 Agility

"Damn, these are good," he spoke out loud as he munched on it. He had always liked bananas. They were like the candy of fruit and fit in any good smoothie. Banana cake was also good.

Jake didn’t hesitate to eat all four of them, getting a sweet +12 Agility total. If all things went well, this would only be the beginning. Jake then took out an item he hadn’t used for a long time: his Omnitool.

[Omnitool (Rare)] – A favorite for nearly all professions. This tool is made of a liquid metal that can take on any preprogrammed shape that the user desires. While unsuitable for combat, it has incredible application when it comes to performing nearly any recreational task. Enchantments: Self-Repair.

It was an item he forgot about ninety-nine percent of the time, and should have totally given to some of the crafters back at Haven so it didn’t just sit uselessly in his spatial storage like so many other things. Anyway, with that in hand, he transformed it into a giant shovel.

Now, did Jake have any idea if he could even steal the banana tree? No, not at all.

How to properly move it? Of course not.

Was it possible it could only grow within this temple, and he would just kill it? It sure was.

Did he one hundred percent bank on his valley counting as an area with "intense amounts of mana" due to the Pylon? He sure did.

Was Jake one hundred percent taking a chance as he decided to dig up the entire tree and relocate it to outside his lodge just to get a cool-ass banana tree? Yes. Yes, he was.

Shit, what is the worst that can happen? I kill a tree and still get some weird-ass time-tree-Musa-thing I can play around with, Jake thought as he began digging it up, finding it a bit annoying that the soil randomly moved back from where he had just dug it up from. Time magic and all that.

Jake was just going to risk it all and try to steal it. He knew it was a high-risk, high-reward move, but if he was candid, he wasn’t sure he would ever come back here. This temple was in an area that would be swarmed with new D-grades within a day or two once they noticed the Prima was dead, and a new alpha would claim the tree. Could Jake just kill that new alpha? Sure, but he was also confident it wouldn’t be nice to him and save the bananas.

So Jake would have had to cut it down or try something similar to that anyway. No way he would just leave it here. It was also damn far away from Haven, and it wasn’t like he could position anyone here. Even Mystie and Hawkie wouldn’t be safe at the temple with the kinds of beasts he’d seen around the place.

Eventually, Jake realized he had to dig around the barrier of the tree to prevent the soil from replacing itself all the time. Stupid tree. He dug around the tree at a radius of three meters or so away. It did take around two hours, which still left plenty of time to go back.

Him missing the World Congress had never been an option. He would rather say "fuck this tree" and fly back right away if getting it meant missing the meeting. Because while he didn’t give much of a shit for all the political bullshit that would be going on—that was for Miranda to handle—there was something he had genuinely been looking forward to: meeting his family.

He was only willing to spend this time to bring the tree back because he did have time. There was just one minor issue left.

"Now, how do I carry this…?"

Miyamoto cleaned his blade as he waited—not because he expected to use it, but to clear his mind as he got more used to his reforged body. His blue robe was in impeccable condition, and he was ready. His great-granddaughter was already waiting at the Pylon together with his grandson and one of the managers.

He had also gotten word that the two other Pylons had prepared, each bringing in four people. This meant the Noboru clan would have twelve representatives present at the World Congress. Their preparations had been excellent, and Miyamoto was especially looking forward to finally laying his eyes on Earth’s elites.

Jacob drank a cup of coffee as he read over the latest reports and prepared for their final meeting before the World Congress. The Pylons had the ability to link up and connect to each other, which was undoubtedly one of the major reasons for the World Congress, as it required either the owner, lord, or someone with an assistant profession to meet another representative.

Naturally, the Holy Church had already linked up their three Pylons to better facilitate cooperation. The hope of this World Congress was not just to link with a few of the remaining factions—they aimed to at least reach some kind of agreement with ninety percent of other Pylon holders.

Caleb rocked back and forth with his son, taking the time to clear his mind and relax before the World Congress. Maja was with him and discussing the upcoming meeting—not just between the many faction leaders around Earth, but also the reunion with Jake.

There were many powerful people on Earth, and while Caleb did believe in Jake, he was still as worried as any family member would be. They hadn’t met in over half a year, and to say that a lot had happened during that time would be an understatement.

His only consolation was the divine message he’d received from Umbra saying his brother was fine. Besides that, he had only heard some vague rumors that may or may not pertain to Jake. He had to be honest; it would be good seeing his big bro again.

"Remember, we do not seek any hostile relationships with any factions," Priscilla said with a big smile to the three people in the room with her. “Play it safe, be courteous, and recognize that some may be scared, at least to begin with. This will be the first time for many to see a Risen; it is our job to make the first impression a pleasant one.”

One of those in attendance was Casper, who looked like he was listening but was actually more busy thinking about how much he really didn’t want to attend the World Congress—and at the same time, how much he would hate to miss it. On the one hand, it would mean meeting many people who would hate him by default just because he was an undead—his general aura, amplified by his powerful curse skills, didn’t help either—but on the other… it would be good to see Jake and even Jacob again. At least, he hoped it would…

"I am not wearing a fucking dress," Carmen said as she looked at the other woman entering the room.

"No one says you have to," the older woman answered with a shrug. "Just remember we aren’t going to fight. Who even knows if we will be able to fight? It would be quite silly if the first World Congress ended in a bloodbath."

"That does sound more fun than sitting around a table with dim lights, discussing trade," Carmen sighed, annoyed she even had to attend.

The woman in front of her was the current City Lord, while she had taken the title of City Owner. She was called Pam, and the only reason Carmen had picked her was that she was the only one she had gotten along with of all the annoying survivors she’d come across so far. Oh, and she was her old boxing coach.

"Who knows? Maybe something fun will happen," Pam said with a smile as she sniffed the air. "However, one thing you are doing before the meeting is taking a shower. No discussion."

Many other factions around Earth prepared for the approach of this key geopolitical event. A meeting between the most prominent factions of the planet. It would be the time to forge alliances that could last for ages to come.

No faction dared take it lightly. All with just the slightest hint of competency knew this, and even if they didn’t have the smarts, most at least still had intuition skills related to being a City Lord that made them aware of how important it was.

"Jake, what the hell are you doing!?" Miranda yelled as she stood half-panicked at the Pylon, watching a figure descend carrying what looked like a small fucking island with a plant on it.

Jake’s response was to throw Neil, who stood beside her, a glance and a smile. "Big hole there, now," he said as he pointed at the ground beside the lodge.

"You want to—" Neil started before Jake just threw him a glance. Neil sighed and used his space magic to create a hole in the ground by teleporting a cube of dirt away—a task he had done quite a lot these days while helping with the construction efforts at the Fort.

Jake happily plopped the tree down, then began filling the hole with dirt and trying to make sure it would survive.

The flight back had sure as hell taken a bit longer than expected. Who would have thought that flying with an ancient-rarity natural treasure would attract attention? Well, he should have guessed it… Either way, the banana tree was safely returned with… nine minutes remaining.

"I need a shower," he said as he stood there, covered in dirt. At least he had managed to pump enough mana into the self-repair enchant during the flight back to restore his clothes to top condition.

"Then hurry up!" Miranda yelled, her panic overpowering her usual restraint.

"Geez, I’m on it, I’m on it…" Jake said as he jumped over to the pond. He entered it, then swam around a little before jumping out and, with his mana, pushing off all the water to dry himself. A final Alchemist’s Purification was used on himself for good measure.

"Alright, ready to go!" he said as he stood there, staring at them.

All of them looked at him a bit hesitantly before Lillian finally spoke up. "We did kind of plan on going with more… formal attire."

To which Jake had the perfect response."Excuse me, this is premier dungeon boss fur and leather…"

Which was about as far as they got before a system message popped up in front of Jake and Miranda, warning them there was one minute left. Jake had also gotten one at the one-hour mark, which had been a bit stressful.

With everything ready, the four of them prepared for the start of the first World Congress.

Chapter 12

The World Congress Begins

Jake, Miranda, Lillian, and Neil all stood at the lodge as the timer ticked down.

The question of who would attend the World Congress had never been an issue for Jake. In fact, he didn’t have any input at all; he’d left it all up to Miranda to handle. The only ones he could possibly bring along were birds, and birds weren’t known to be great political negotiators. Or maybe they were? Mystie did come off as very smart, even by human standards…

Either way, Miranda managed to fire off a few quick bullet points in the final seconds. Mainly: avoid fighting, politics and good relations first, no starting wars, let her take charge of the primary negotiations, no killing other City Lords and/or owners, and other such essential things.

When the timer reached zero, Jake and Miranda both got the option to join along with the ability to invite up to two people total. Neil and Lillian were naturally chosen.

With everything in order, they accepted and disappeared from the valley.

Jake appeared with the three others inside a large, circular room that was much akin to a conference room of the old world. He stood on a small platform with a table and four chairs in front of him. He also immediately noticed similar platforms to his sides, except the one he was on was slightly raised compared to the others, and the design of the table was also a bit different. The most significant difference was a sign saying "Haven – Earl."

The one to his immediate right had the name "Saya – Viscount," while the one to his left said "Sanctdomo – Viscount." Jake counted nine of these Viscount platforms total, with theirs being the only one with the Earl tag.

Ten or so meters separated each platform, and Jake felt that each had a barrier of sorts surrounding it, one Jake naturally ignored with his Sphere of Perception. Well, that wasn’t so significant a thing, as the barriers were invisible and didn’t affect sight at all.

"Do we take a sea—" Neil tried to ask before figures appeared to their sides. Before Jake even had time to inspect anyone in his sphere, he felt the auras.

To his left, a serene presence appeared that sought to soothe all around it. It inherently had magical and mind-affecting properties, and was one Jake recognized instantly as his old superior: Jacob. There was another presence mixed in—that of a middle-aged man—but it was nothing compared to Jacob’s. Besides those two, there was also Bertram and a woman.

To his right, the aura he felt was far different. It was the reason that the first direction he looked wasn’t towards his old boss, Casper, or even his own brother, whom he had already noticed with his sphere. No, he looked straight at an old man who met his gaze with a smile.

This was the first human that Jake had ever met that made his instincts warn him so directly. That old man… wasn’t simple. Not at all.

The old man looked towards Jake, and they both sized up the other until, finally, the man bowed. Jake returned his greeting with a deep nod. Their eye contact never broke, as both saw something similar in the gaze of the other: a desire to fight.

Yet they both knew now wasn’t the time, and they broke their staring contest just as they began attracting the attention of their companions. Jake saw the old man speak but couldn’t hear his voice. Guess I just found out what the barriers do.

"Who is that?" Miranda asked, also feeling the aura—though she appeared more affected by Jacob, based on how she kept throwing glances his way.

"Someone strong," Jake answered as he also looked to his left, toward Jacob. Jacob regarded him with a nod in turn, which Jake gladly reciprocated. Well, Jacob seems normal… As normal as someone with that Augur stuff going on can be.

"Alright," Miranda said as she also now truly inspected the platform with Jacob on it. "Sanctdomo… and the Augur… how do you know him?"

Miranda had read the notebook Jacob had given Jake, which included a description of the Augur class. From the looks of it, she had put two and two together, especially after meeting Neil and talking about having met the man. That she wasn’t entirely clear on their relationship was only natural.

"He used to be my boss," Jake answered nonchalantly as he turned his attention towards the two other people in the large hall that he knew had looked his way. Miranda just shook her head, not even bothering to deal with the bomb Jake had just dropped.

"That’s the guy?" Matteo asked as he looked over to the highest platform in the entire room—that of the singular Earl on Earth.

He saw a masked figure wearing nearly all-black clothes, giving off quite a mysterious and unapproachable aura. Thinking about it, the guy would fit in quite well with the rest of the Court of Shadows.

"I can’t Identify him," Nadia said as she shook her head, getting a glance from Matteo and the current manager of trade of Skyggen, the sole city controlled by the Court.

Nadia had an upgraded version of Identify that allowed her to better pierce normal obscurations, so if she failed to Identify him, he had to have some great skill or technique behind it. As for the City Lord of Skyggen himself…

Caleb looked over and saw Jake look back towards him. He met his yellow eyes, and despite their outward change, found his brother’s gaze as familiar as ever. He saw the mix of relief and happiness in his eyes, and Caleb could only return the sentiment as a wave of relief washed over him.

Good to see you again, Jake.

So far, only ten platforms were filled. It looked like the system brought in people based on nobility, with one Earl and nine Viscounts present so far. And while Jake’s platform attracted a lot of attention because it was the only one that was Earl-tier, one attracted even more.

It was the only platform that wasn’t occupied by humans… At least, not the usual definition of humans.

The aura given off by that platform was different from all the others. It had an inherent concept of death seeped into it, making it automatically repulsive to most living beings who didn’t possess the affinity themselves. Needless to say, this was more noteworthy than the three far stronger auras present, as it was simply too foreign.

No one could speak to each other yet, but there were many whispers around the chamber—especially by the ones with the old man, as they were placed right beside the undead faction. The same was true for the faction on their other side, which consisted of a bunch of burly men and women who looked straight out of a medieval festival. All of them held axes or maces for some reason. Well, it wasn’t that weird to have a weapon—most did—and the majority at least had them sheathed.

Jake threw a look the way of the undead and saw Casper on the platform along with three others. The one in the lead was a woman with long white hair and equally white skin. She smiled like the negative attention didn’t bother her and seemingly tried to appear as inoffensive as possible.

Casper looked like he wanted to make himself invisible. Should have gotten a mask, Jake joked to himself, honestly feeling bad for his old friend. There was power in wearing a mask, and Jake knew he would in no way feel comfortable with the attention currently on him without it. It was like a powerful shield that put a barrier between him and everyone else.

Hang in there, buddy.

After a few minutes of everyone sizing each other up and a bit of a dick-measuring contest in the form of auras, it was time for the rest of the chamber to fill up.

People began appearing on the platforms one by one, nearly all of them with four people, but there were a few with less than that. In total, ninety-four new platforms were occupied, meaning a total of one hundred and four Pylons of Civilization had been captured. Four more than the day it announced a week was left till it was World Congress time.

A flood of auras overtook the room once more. Of the first ten factions, six of them had at least one D-grade on them: the old man, Jacob, Jake, the white-haired undead woman, the leader of those bulky cosplayers, and the tenth platform’s middle-aged woman.

As for these new arrivals, all of them were E-grade except for three. All of them were automatically noteworthy for their strength, but one was more noteworthy than anyone else in the entire room—the dangerous, old swordsman included.

The two less noteworthy D-grades were a young, red-haired woman who already looked annoyed at being there, and a man wearing full plate armor. As for the last one...

It was the only individual who had shown up only with two and not the allowed three companions.

He looked to be in his mid-thirties, with deep brown eyes, combed-back hair, and a small mustache. Jake’s first impression was that he looked relatively harmless; the aura he gave off did not threaten him either… but what he felt in the aura did.

Jake felt an emotion he hadn't experienced before… an innate recognition of sorts. They both held something unique, something no one else possessed in the room beside them. A power that was theirs and theirs alone.

A Bloodline.

The two men stared at each other for a while before the other guy raised his finger to his lips and made a shushing motion. Jake answered back with a toothy smile as he understood. No sharing secrets, eh?

He could get on board with that.

Jake spent the next minute or so observing others while being closely studied back by the various factions of Earth. Most attention on their platform was due to him, as he was the sole D-grade, but Miranda, Neil, and Lillian also suffered quite the scrutiny. Miranda looked unfazed, Lillian like she didn’t care, and Neil a bit uncomfortable. Jake himself hated every moment as he hoped for the system to do something.

Which, luckily, it did.

Welcome to the first World Congress of Earth.

The World Congress is an opportunity for the newly integrated Earthlings to establish political connections and an arena for discussion, voting, and international politics that can impact the planet as a whole. Note that no fighting will be allowed during the World Congress. Each booth has an aura that will offer privacy to each city.

During the first World Congress, three votes will be held with one three-hour intermission between each to discuss the proposal. The total length of the World Congress will be ten hours.

The first vote will be held in one hour and pertain to the election of a World Leader. The World Leader will automatically have their noble rank advance one stage. Becoming a World Leader requires more than 60% of the total votes.

Jake and everyone else got the notification. This was easily concluded, as everyone suddenly stopped for a moment to take in the information. To be honest, it was a lot more... formal than he had expected.

A small part of Jake had expected this entire World Congress to be a big room they were all tossed into like the tutorial, where Jake would have to dunk on some morons to set them straight. Luckily—or perhaps unluckily—this wasn’t that kind of event.

Though he would like to fight that old man with the sword… Maybe later.

The whole World Leader thing was a bit of a surprise, and not something Jake expected was relevant here and now. Seriously, even if Jacob went full-on mental interference with his Augur stuff, he couldn’t convince sixty percent of the attending to vote for him. The task only became more daunting with the next message that popped up.

Voting rules of the World Congress:

The number of available votes is based on the nobility rank of the attending members. The number of votes per nobility rank is as follows:

Earl: 10

Viscount: 5

Baron: 3

Lord: 1

The noble in question may distribute their votes as they choose if there are multiple options. The noble may abstain from voting. Votes are final and cannot be appealed. Any agreements will remain in effect until the next World Congress or if all included parties choose to revoke it. All tie-breakers will be decided by the highest-ranking noble present at the World Congress.

Going through that, it only became clearer how much harder it would be to be voted World Leader. The more prominent nobles had more votes, so you would have to convince the big factions to vote for you. It was without a doubt a feature not for this first World Congress, but for future ones after the political landscape had formed and strong alliances were established.

As for all the rules… Jake didn’t like them. He already felt a few more eyes upon him now, likely due to that last sentence about the highest-ranking noble deciding at tie-breakers… Seriously, no way there was even going to be tie-breakers.

Also, why did he need 10 votes? Heck, Miranda had 5, Lillian 3, and Neil 1… Their small group of four had 19 votes total. They were, without a doubt, the group with the most votes. If Jake had given Neil a Baron title, it would be even more. Actually… maybe he should give out titles. That would be something to talk with Miranda about.

With the final message out, a countdown appeared.

Vote for first World Leader will begin in: 59:59

And with that, the barriers around each platform faded. They could still be reactivated, but now everyone was free to move. Everyone seemed hesitant until one person moved.

A figure teleported from the tallest platform, first towards the middle of the chamber, then before the four people from Skygge and the Court of Shadows.

Three of them tensed up as the figure spoke to the only calm member of their group.

"Hey, Cal, how are Mom and Dad doing?” Jake asked. “Did everything go well with Maja?"

"Yeah, they are doing quite well, considering the circumstances. As for Maja… congratulations. You’re an uncle now." Caleb gave a big, proud smile as he thought about his son.

"Damn, good to know the system didn’t do anything weird in that department, at least," Jake said, genuinely relieved but also feeling a bit weird. He had suspected he was an uncle now, but it was still something else to have it confirmed. Well, he was also kind of an uncle to Sylphie, but Sylphie was a bird, so that was different.

"Anyway, how have you been doing? Heard through the grapevine that you went and did some impressive stuff," Caleb said with a raised eyebrow. Umbra hadn’t given that many details, and confirmation from primary sources were always best.

"Oh, yeah, it’s been fun. You haven’t slacked too much either, though you should really hurry up and get to D-grade; the evolution is damn nice."

Jake was so embroiled in his reunion that he didn’t care about the entire hall’s focus being on him and Caleb. Miranda staring at him in confusion barely registered, and the three people with Caleb also just looked utterly baffled, as their boss clearly hadn’t told them that the mystical Progenitor they had been warned to stay away from was the brother of the Judge.

The two of them lit the spark and broke the ice of the entire hall. The tense competition of auras died down, and while many were still wary—especially towards the undead faction—they eventually began moving about. Soon, a dozen or so attendees began to group around Miranda, Lillian, and Neil.

The reunion of two brothers split by the integration to the multiverse was something everyone could relate to. Many had lost touch with family, and so much uncertainty still remained for so many. The sight of two influential faction leaders just talking about family was… human.

It was an element that had been sorely lacking for many of those present. Many had spent the last few months just struggling, but perhaps this Congress was a time to return to something more… civilized. Without Jake knowing it, his spontaneous action of impatiently approaching his brother had set the entire mood of the World Congress.

Chapter 13

World Congress: Friendly Talks

"Should we not be out attempting to sway the vote for World Leader?" Jacob was asked by the middle-aged trade manager he had brought along for the Congress. Maria and Bertram also looked at him questioningly.

They controlled several Pylons already, and had many votes between them—not to mention an Augur with frankly overpowered skills for convincing people. Yet Jacob did not look like he carried any intentions towards securing votes for World Leader.

"It’s too soon, and there are far too many unknowns,” he said. “Becoming World Leader will undoubtedly come with a lot of power, but also a lot of responsibility. In addition, fear that it may put a target on our back from those who disagree. Finally… I see no possibility of us securing sixty percent of the votes. At least, not yet."

"I am confused… I find it doubtful that any faction will dare move against us directly. We represent the Holy Church on this planet, and any powerful forces with divine connections will surely want to join hands with us or, at a minimum, not dare stand in opposition. While I understand that the Court of Shadows and the undead are not to be taken lightly, I do not see—"

"Exactly,” Jacob said. “You don’t see it. The problem is that I don’t either. This entire World Congress is an utter enigma to not just me, but the gods too. Not just due to the inability of skills to predict the system itself, but also due to the presence of the leader of Haven and the Sword Saints.”

Jacob would have loved to be able to divine what the best choices for this World Congress were. To see the fates that the voting would result in, and in concert, the future of their entire planet. Sadly, things didn’t work that way.

The individuals present formed a maelstrom of destiny that threw all predictions off. Jake was the primary issue due to whatever fate-bending skill he had been given. If Jacob was honest, he knew the mere fact that Jake was a Chosen was enough to toss off all predictions, even if he didn’t have a skill. A single sentence from the Malefic One would throw off all certainties.

Anyone being blessed made it harder to predict anything related to them, but not to the level of Jake. Not even close. He could at least get a general feel for things with most people, but with Jake and Haven, it was just a black hole.

Additionally… usually the Holy Pantheon or even the Grand Master who was in charge of their section of planets would throw in a tip here and there… but in regards to Jake, it had been radio silence except the warning of not interacting with the Malefic Viper’s Chosen at all, and if he had to for some reason, limit it as much as humanly possible.

A warning Jacob had no intentions of following.

Stronger than me.

That was the assessment Miyamoto had when he saw the masked man for the first time—the enigmatic Earl that had claimed the very first Pylon.

Miyamoto was prideful and, in the eyes of many, arrogant, but when he locked eyes with the man, he understood he wasn’t the only one. He saw the arrogance and inherent challenge in the eyes of the man. He was an old man, but at that moment, he could barely contain his childlike excitement. One of his biggest fears had been alleviated.

A fear that he would have to wait for the multiverse to open up to meet peers with the same drive and desire as himself. A tiny part of him had feared that the first to claim a Pylon had done it simply as a fluke and not due to his own power… something that clearly wasn’t the case.

Their duel would come… but not today. Today was not a day of fighting, but one of forming bonds.

The masked man clearly understood this too, as his first choice was to greet his brother. Miyamoto smiled upon seeing this, and his respect for the hunter grew. That he also possessed such a profound movement skill only made it all the better.

"Grandfather, should we still move according to plan?" his grandson, a middle-aged man, asked him.

"Yes. Focus on getting a good feel for the state of things, and as for this whole World Leader business… we shall abstain as our default choice. To make such a choice this early would be an act of foolishness." Miyamoto threw a glance towards the Augur.

"What about… those?" an assistant to his grandson asked. The man didn’t even bother hiding his contempt as he looked at the undead.

Miyamoto frowned and shook his head. "Do as you would with anyone else. Do not make enemies because you fear the unknown. The system has brought us here as equals—as humans—so treat them as such. The world is changing, and the Noboru Clan will change with it."

The last words were said as he looked the assistant straight in the eye, making him freeze up from the implied threat.

"Mistress Carmen, it’s an honor to finally meet you in person," the large, burly man said as he smiled at the far smaller woman.

"Sven… you look utterly ridiculous… and don’t call me mistress again. Ever. Carmen is fine." Carmen looked the man up and down.

Standing at nearly two and a half meters tall, Sven had clearly grown with his evolutions. The shift to D-grade had no doubt come in tight to make him the tallest man in the entire World Congress. He was built like an absolute tank, but his outfit…

He was wearing fur clothes and a bearskin cap on his head, with the three following him looking equally ridiculous. Of course, Carmen knew it was actually equipment that was likely as good as her own, but that didn’t make them look any less silly.

While the majority had shown up in clothes ready for battle, that still meant most looked presentable. You could never go wrong in plate armor or the robes worn by nearly all casters and healers. In fact, many of those present also just wore large cloaks, making it entirely possible that they looked ridiculous beneath it.

"Bah, who cares about something as trivial as that?" Sven dismissively said as he waved his hand. "Here, let us first establish an official alliance before anything else."

Would you like to enter an Alliance with Midtgaard?

Carmen got the notification as the City Owner, but just shook her head and directed Sven towards the actual City Lord, who was busy talking to their neighboring city. As one of the rare groups outside of the first ten with a D-grade in it, they instantly attracted quite a bit more attention.

"Handle it with that guy," she said, pointing to the City Lord behind her. "Got any other orders from the big shots?"

"None recently. I am sure the gods of Valhal believe we can handle ourselves and are judging our ability to make our own decisions. We have backing of the highest level, so let’s use that and find likeminded individuals to join our ranks, and—"

Sven kept talking proudly as Carmen slowly zoned out and looked around the room a bit more. D-grade’s ability to split your attention between different things was awesome when it came to listening to a boring speech and doing something actually interesting without the other party noticing.

Needless to say, Sven was blessed by a god related to Valhal too. Valhal was a pantheon of gods founded by the Primordial named Valdemar. Unlike many others, it focused far more heavily on combat over everything else and didn’t care much for higher goals or complicated ideals. It was just about finding strong people who liked fighting and bringing them together with likeminded individuals, and Carmen liked that.

Well, it did have a few tenets of sorts—mainly related to getting proper fights—and was, in Carmen’s view, more common sense than anything. It talked about how there was no honor in mindless murder of those weaker than yourself, and how one should fight foes in a straight-on fight.

This wasn’t to say one should fight stupidly. It was fine to use any advantages you had, research your foes, and use all your skills to their full extent. An assassin sneak-attacking was a part of their strength and not something to look down upon. Well, it likely also had something to do with how instantly killing anyone of equal strength was pretty damn hard in the post-system world—a sentiment that only got more and more true as one advanced through the grades. So a powerful sneak attack just meant the fight started with one party injured.

The entire organization didn’t recruit as actively as the Holy Church, yet it had a lot of faith. Many warlords or career warriors of the multiverse found themselves recruited to Valhal, where they would interact with their peers, which lead to another difference.

Valhal didn’t recruit factions, empires, or kingdoms; it focused on people. That those people then made Valdemar and Valhal the figurehead of their entire faction was another thing entirely—one that, quite frankly, not a single god Carmen had met cared about.

This had led to Valhal not being a large "faction" of the multiverse in the truest sense… yet it was still one of the most feared. Even a faction as massive as the Holy Church didn’t dare fight the massive amount of war-crazed powerhouses belonging to Valhal.

These experts could even be found within other factions. Many members of the Holy Church or large empires were part of Valhal while also belonging to another faction. In the truest sense, Valhal was neutral and so far had only taken sides in conflicts a few times throughout the history of the multiverse. And those times were often just because Valdemar really didn’t like something and personally went on a warpath, and the warriors of Valhal just followed him on his quest.

Carmen began to feel bored watching the hall’s occupants talk, but she soon picked up something interesting from Sven.

"—between the Sword Saint and the hunter that guards Haven, I am unsure who is the most powerful human currently on the planet, but if I had to guess, it would be the hunter. Of course, it is entirely possible some hidden powerhouse exists, but beating out a Progenitor is no easy feat."

"How would you compare me to them?" Carmen asked.

Sven was many things, and a competent warrior and leader were undoubtedly two of them. With his axe in hand, he had reached D-grade about the same time as her and was strong, even for a D-grade at his level.

"Without an actual bout, it is hard to say… but I get the feeling that the two of us wouldn’t win if we fought either of those two together. Of course, my senses may be off, but I am getting some serious vibes from both of them." Sven shook his head. He was a proud man, but he wasn’t stupidly overconfident.

"We’ll see," Carmen said as she threw another look at the masked man, who was talking with that shadow-assassin leader who was apparently his brother, before shifting it to the ancient-looking man who was currently moving with his entourage towards meeting people she assumed were his allies… mainly based on how they all called him Patriarch.

"That King sounds like an absolute monster." Caleb frowned as Jake finished going through a few key points of his own tutorial. He didn’t really bother to keep things a secret, as he was pretty damn sure Umbra already knew, and if she hadn’t told anyone… well, a bit of bragging never hurt.

"Yeah… I blame all those gods messing with shit to get their way. Well, it turned out pretty well in the end, if you ignore how nearly everyone died…" Jake said, shaking his head.

Thinking about it, four out of five survivors of the tutorial were present in this meeting. Jacob and Casper were both part of two of the largest factions of the multiverse. Which left the question… What is that psychotic metal mage up to? Actually, who cares…

Caleb had also told of his own tutorial, and Jake had already learned about some cool stuff, like that virtual fighting arena they had where one could safely fight to the death without actually dying. He needed one of those for Haven—that was for sure.

"Being immortal beings of untold power must be boring with how much they bothered messing with your tutorial," Caleb said with a chuckle. “At least Umbra and the Court of Shadows seem pretty decent. Pretty sure they subscribe to the whole freedom-under-responsibility doctrine.”

Caleb’s comrades just stood silently behind him, not uttering a word as they observed Jake and Caleb’s interaction.

"Villy is also pretty chill, too, especially considering how stuck up gods tend to be, from what I can tell," Jake said.

That got a confused frown from the three observers behind Caleb. The woman, though, suddenly seemed to realize what Jake meant, and asked before his brother had a chance to.

"Are you speaking about the Malefic Viper?" she asked a bit cautiously.

"Who are you?" Jake asked, annoyed that someone was butting in on his family time.

Caleb came to her rescue, not knowing what he had just unleashed. "This is Nadia, one of the higher-ranking members of the Court and a real meanie with a sniper.”

"A sniper?" Jake frowned. He felt a bit bad for her, using inferior weaponry like that, but he nevertheless gave her a chance. "What’s your longest kill?"

"One hundred and twelve kilometers," she answered without hesitation, clearly quite proud of it.

Okay, that was longer than expected… but I still win. I guess snipers are technically better at extreme ranges… Bah.

"Not bad," Jake acknowledged, somewhat reluctantly. "And yeah, Villy is the Malefic Viper. I just call him Villy because all his other names are just too long or feel weird… like calling him a Viper all the time. It would be like if he called me Human."

"Is the Malefic Viper fine with that?" Caleb asked with a hint of worry.

Jake knew that his brother was worried about him getting into problems with authority again, which was totally unfair to expect just because he had a history of it. Jake couldn’t even remember how many teachers he had pissed off by being stubborn with authority throughout his life.

"As I said, he’s a chill dude. Have Mom or Dad received any blessings? How are their levels, by the way?"

"No blessings, but they are both getting levels slowly. Dad more so than Mom… but they shouldn’t have any issues getting to D-grade, at least," Caleb said with an assuring smile, knowing what Jake was truly asking.

It was an uncomfortable conversation they would have at some point… but not yet. It was too early. Either way, his parents’ ability to reach D-grade quite easily was exemplary proof of how relations and connections to others could positively impact your Records.

Their two sons were both extraordinary beings of Earth already. Jake had no worries about his brother reaching D-grade soon, and was sure he could go even further than that. While his current level of power was far from Jake’s—or any other D-grade present—he was still one of the strongest E-grades present, if not the strongest. Moreover… he had Jake.

A lot can be said about nepotism, but Jake sure as hell would deploy that aplenty. He would gladly help his family out, and he was already planning on getting them a bunch of potions and hopefully even elixirs and such in the future.

While, of course, also making it clear everywhere that he would hunt down anyone who touched them. Was he fully aware this would cause some political issues with his brother literally being the leader of some semi-corporate assassin organization? Sure, but he didn’t really give a fuck.

"I’m going to come by and visit once I get the chance… but I need some directions," Jake said with a goofy smile.

"Oh, I’m sure we can figure something out," Caleb said, returning the smile.

The first half an hour of the World Congress turned out to mainly be networking and reuniting with allies or friends. The factions that possessed more pylons teamed up and made their size and influence clear, while the smaller ones began talking to their neighbors. Eventually, alliances began slowly forming.

Some conversations were very businesslike, but with the original mood set by Jake, the entire atmosphere turned out to be way more relaxed than one might expect from the first clash of the majority of the strongest humans on Earth.

Chapter 14

World Congress: Reunion

After the first half an hour, four people found themselves within one of the closed-off platforms that belonged to a city. It was at the table belonging to Haven with the sound-proofing barrier active. Even sight into the area was disrupted, making anything less than a Sphere of Perception unable to pierce inside. One could still see out, but not in.

In there was a reunion of sorts. Bertram and Jacob sat together with Casper and Jake, making it quite the unlikely group. Them entering the barrier had already grabbed plenty of attention.

Undead and the Augur of the Holy Church meeting together with the first man to claim a Pylon? Very suspicious, and undoubtedly many theories were already being conjured up. Theories instantly debunked if anyone actually managed to peer inside…

"I think the use of Credits will become far more normal with time, especially as we open up to the wider multiverse,” Jacob said amid their usual bantering. “The merchants naturally also push it as their skills incentivize and use it, and from what I have gathered, using Credits is also beneficial to their progression."

"A digital currency that is universally accepted and endorsed by the system will also more easily be adopted by people,” Casper chimed in. “It is also far safer than anything of the old world, as I have yet to hear of any way of stealing Credits from someone without their knowledge. Except, of course, good old blackmail or extortion or stuff like that.” His entirely black eyes had a glint to them when he mentioned the last part.

Jake just chuckled a bit inwardly as he sat back and enjoyed the conversation. Casper had worked in the R&D department before and had always been a bit of a geek—one of the big reasons he and Jake had gotten along so well.

Casper had been passionate about digital currencies, especially cryptocurrencies and how they were the way of the future… and he’d kinda gotten it right, hadn’t he? Credits were kind of a digital currency, though Jake would more call it a magic currency. Or a system-fuckery currency?

"From what I have gathered, the establishments of banks and such is only a matter of time,” Jacob said. “They appear to be common across the multiverse, and it is quite understandable to want to ensure your assets away from yourself. Losing all Credits upon death and leaving nothing to your family or comrades is a harrowing thought.” He shook his head.

"Considering how Credits can be bound to a city, I am sure there are other skills or methods to create organizations independent of a single individual that can store funds, effectively acting as banks, as you said," Casper agreed.

Jake butted in with a very stupid question. "Wild thought—is the Holy Church on the stock market?"

"I am pretty sure stocks aren’t really a thing," Jacob chuckled in response. "At least, not in the way we know them. There likely are methods to invest in organizations and get a return, but I doubt it will be through a stock market or anything like that."

"Well, I would invest in Haven if it was me, Lord Progenitor," Casper joked with a snicker before he turned a bit more serious. "By the way, I never got to thank you… so thanks for killing that fucker William. He had it coming, even if it does suck that he ended up being revived in the end."

"No problem, dude was a fucking lunatic," Jake said, shaking his head at the appearance of a few bad memories as he looked at Jacob questionably. "Any news on what the psycho is up to? I reckon the Holy Church has quite the information network, and you are an Augur and all that."

"No information that I can confirm pertains to him… but from what I can tell from the most credible cases, he seems almost… normal?” Jacob said. “Altruistic, even. At least, I have heard no rumors of a metal-manipulating psychopath committing mass murder, and it isn’t like our planet is lacking people like that." He looked up towards the ceiling of the hall with a sad gaze.

"Oh, yeah, on that note… are you guys gonna try to do some large magic ritual and turn the entire planet into a land of death?" Jake asked Casper. He was happy to know that at least William wasn’t running around being a dirtbag openly, but that didn’t mean he wanted to offer the guy any more attention than he deserved.

"Nah, at least I haven’t heard of any plans of that,” Casper said. “We do have things set up so people can turn into Risen and become undead if they want to, though, and the areas we control are being affected with a bit more death affinity than anywhere else. Already had quite a few converts, mainly family or friends of Risen or those that just want a longer lifespan, even if that isn’t that relevant yet. Being dead does come with some other perks and drawbacks, but honestly, it is mostly just cosmetic. I barely feel the difference myself." Casper shrugged.

"Good to know," Jake said. “Both that you aren’t planning on any mass purge of the living races and that you seem to be fine with technically being dead and all that.” They had kind of danced around the elephant in the room of Casper being more or less dead.

"I should ask you the same," his undead pal said. “The Order of the Malefic Viper isn’t exactly known as being part of the good guys.”

"Gonna be honest—I wouldn’t really know. I haven’t joined it, as far as I can tell. I will go visit in the future, but no plans of any planetary sacrificial rituals currently."

"No one mentioned planetary sacrificial rituals..." Casper said with a mix of humor and just a tinge of suspicion.

"And no one is going to make one," Jake agreed, giving a joking smile.

"Not that it matters; our Sacred Purification Ritual will wipe out all you heathens before any of that can come to pass," Jacob said with a grand gesture.

Bertram looked at Jacob with confusion and doubt before catching on, at which point he gave a big smile and declared: "The unholy ones will never see it coming."

The four men looked at each other with stupid smiles as they joked about things that, to any outsider, did seem like serious topics.

Jake also knew that they maybe would be put on opposing sides due to their affiliations in the future, especially Jacob and Casper. Jake himself had no intentions of picking any sides, as he honestly hated politics, but if either came to threaten what was his, he would protect it.

But that day wasn’t today. They continued to chat about minor things, with Casper talking about how he was learning about dungeons and even making his own, Jacob primarily complaining about the difficulties of dealing with ass-lickers and managing a city, and Jake talking about the dangers of shit-flinging monkeys.

"On a more serious note, what are your thoughts on the election of a World Leader?” Jacob asked, changing the subject and reminding them of what they were actually supposed to discuss. “That is what this intermission was for, after all, and the vote begins in… oh, four minutes.”

"We are going to abstain; no way anyone would vote for us anyway," Casper said, his tone making it clear he truly didn’t care about the subject. “I doubt anyone is going, ‘Oh, yeah, let’s vote for the undead!’ during the very first Congress, if ever.”

"Dunno, man, I am just going to listen what the City Lord says; it ain’t my job," Jake said dismissively.

"The Holy Church will abstain too," Jacob said, shaking his head at Jake. "I find it amazing that the highest-tiered noble of Earth appears to be the least interested noble of Earth."

"I don’t care either?" Casper said, feigning offense.

"Yeah, sounds annoying as hell," Jake agreed. "Anyway, get out of my system-box-thing; people are waiting."

Miranda had been standing with Lillian and Neil outside the barrier for a minute or so now. She and the others were looking troubled as to whether they should enter or not, seeing as how the leader of Sanctdomo and a high-ranking member of the undead faction were within. None of them could see inside either, so they were likely afraid of interrupting.

"Harsh," Casper laughed as he got up. "Good to see you again; you should come by sometime. I promise not to eat your brains."

"Likewise,” Jacob said with a nod as he also stood up. “The good-to-see-you-again part. You are welcome to visit Sanctdomo if you wish, but do be a bit discreet not to cause a ruckus."

"I say you should cause a ruckus; it would make things more interesting," Bertram added, mirroring Jacob’s nod. "Keep doing what you’re doing. Clearly, it’s working out for you."

"No one knows what the future may bring," Jake said as he saw them out. "I promise not to purposefully fuck things up too much."

"We only got eighty seconds left," Lillian reminded Miranda, who was already tapping her feet.

"I know, I know, but we can’t just barge in," she said, despite really wanting just to barge in. Luckily, she wouldn’t have to.

Three figures walked out of the barrier, the first two being the Augur and his bodyguard. The Risen left in the direction of his own city, practically rushing there.

The Augur stopped just as he walked out and greeted her. "I apologize for the inconvenience, Ms. Miranda. I was just catching up with an old friend."

He spoke loud enough for everyone around to hear, which was pretty much everyone who tried due to senses improving and all that. Miranda knew it was on purpose. With a simple sentence, he’d made it clear that he was related to, and on friendly terms with, the Progenitor and didn’t hold any antagonistic relationship with the only Earl of the planet, despite being competing forces on paper.

While Sanctdomo was large, people also knew their one D-grade in this meeting wasn’t a fighter, so the move also helped inadvertently plant a seed of doubt about their true power. Especially if Jake was willing to move to their defense and take their side in a conflict.

"It’s of no consequence; I hope you had a pleasant time," Miranda said with a courteous tone.

No way she would complain if the largest city on Earth showed good intentions towards their small Haven.

"I did," Jacob said as he walked by, adding a few more words that only she could hear. "Do take care of Jake. I know he can be a handful, but he is good at what he does."

Miranda felt the magic deployed as he spoke, making her shudder inwardly. It was just a simple skill to obscure his words, but the amount of pure power packed into it was intense, showing that while the Augur looked harmless, he was far from it. While he couldn’t beat anyone in a fight of fists, he could crush nearly anyone in a bout of words.

She nodded at him in understanding as she entered the barrier with Neil and Lillian, who’d both read the mood and stayed silent throughout the exchange.

However, Miranda was inwardly fuming about those words. They reminded her of the last hour of her life and the infuriating comments she’d gotten from half the groups.

The notion that women were treated as "lesser" in many cultures was something she was used to, and was something she had experienced plenty of times throughout her professional life. After the system, it seemed a bit better, from what she could tell, though there were still issues.

During the initial meeting, her level and position had been enough for most to recognize her as the City Lord of Haven, but what made her furious was why people thought she was the City Lord. After Jake had taken off to talk to his brother, the first of her meetings had been with the trade manager of Sanctdomo, and that had set a precedent for the bullshit that was to come.

For some fucking reason, everyone thought she had her position because she was the mistress of Jake. No one dared say it to her directly, but the implied words and motions were so damn obvious it was nauseating. They talked to her as if she was the wife of the household that was Haven, and couldn’t truly make any decisions—at least, not any of the important ones.

Granted, she could, in retrospect, see how some of these rumors had come to exist. She had spent entire nights at Jake’s lodge, but that was all for work… Okay, sometimes it was more leisure, but nothing untoward had ever happened.

Anyway, this meant that she had to spend the beginning of every negotiation making clear that she wasn’t just some figurehead put in place because she was sleeping with the "true" lord of the city, but that she could make nearly all decisions independently. Sure, Jake was technically the true leader of the city, but considering how she was the one in charge, she was still the de-facto leader.

This was why the Augur’s comment pissed her off, even if he didn’t mean anything bad by it. She walked through the barrier with a sour mood and saw at least part of her grief sitting there on one of the chairs, staring up at the ceiling.

His mask was gone, and from the looks of it, he hadn’t worn it during the meeting with the Augur and the Undead.

He turned to her as she entered and smiled. "Sorry about that; time ran away from us. Anyway, quick thoughts on voting?"

Miranda instantly felt her anger towards him reduce to nothing… Yeah, the thoughts of those idiots aren’t his fault. Jake was in the department of people who seemed to honestly not care about such things. At least he’d killed Abby as mercilessly as anyone else, despite being a woman. A champion of equality right there.

"My focus has been on creating relations, and quite honestly, this one hour is far from enough to adequately identify anyone qualified as World Leader, so I believe most if not all will skip or just vote for themselves," she said just as the system popped up before them.

Please place your vote for World Leader of Earth. You have 5 votes and can distribute them as you desire or choose to abstain with any or all of your votes. Voting time is set to 5 minutes.

Votes remaining: 5/5

Time remaining: 4:59

"So, we skip? From what I can tell, Jacob and Casper plan on doing the same," Jake said, casually mentioning two names she didn’t know.

"Can you place some titles or at least races on those names?" Miranda asked, not mincing words. She had learned that just being straightforward worked best with her boss long ago.

"Oh, yeah. Jacob is the priesty guy, and the big guy with him is Bertram, his butler of sorts. Rich person stuff. The Risen is Casper, another former coworker. We used to hang out quite a bit before the system. He did some weird ritual to turn himself into an undead during our tutorial to help his girlfriend, who is now a ghost.”

Miranda wanted to hit him over the head due to the utter insanity he was spewing. These were the kinds of moments where she forgot the constant reminders from the Sisters of the Verdant Lagoon to remain super courteous.

"You will have to give me a quick summary of your relations to the major factions you apparently have personal relations with. You know, such as the Judge of the Court of Shadows being your brother. A prominent figure of the undead faction, your old pal. And the Augur, your old boss. The Sword Saint wouldn’t happen to be your grandpa? Or do you have an ex-girlfriend or former roommate among the other city leaders?" Her voice was just a tiny, little bit soaked in annoyance.

She just really hoped that the rest of the World Congress wouldn’t be filled with as many surprises… But hey, on a positive note, her annoyance at Jake failing to inform her about vital information had completely overshadowed and made her forget about all the other annoying stuff.

Chapter 15

World Congress: A Quick Vote

Jake didn’t know why, but he got a faint feeling that he maybe should have told Miranda that a good third of the first ten Pylons had been claimed by family or old friends. Perhaps it was her very sarcastic tone… Nah, it can’t be that.

Alright, I did kind of drop the ball on that one, Jake had to admit as he scratched the back of his head, a bit embarrassed. It had been a slightly dickish move not to inform her beforehand, but in Jake’s defense, he hadn’t known that Casper would be a big shot in the undead faction or that his brother would attend the World Congress. He really should have mentioned Jacob, though.

Either way…

“Yeah, sorry about that. But no, I don’t know any other people than them here, though I did half-expect one other guy to attend here today. Luckily he hasn’t. His attendance would make it hard to follow the no-fighting rule.” The person that he had kind of expected to attend was, of course, William.

Jake hadn’t really thought about the metal-caster at all since the tutorial ended before today, but in retrospect, he had to wonder why he wasn’t present. He was blessed by Eversmile, after all.

“Just… don’t spring any more surprises,” Miranda sighed before switching the subject. “While you were meeting old friends, we managed to make contact with quite a few other factions, mainly to gather information and to try and understand the state of the planet. Haven has yet to enter any official alliances yet, though there are a few good prospects… but I wanted to get your thoughts first.”

“Do what you think is best, Miranda. Make as many alliances as you want, and if you make a few enemies along the way, just let me know. Ah, but don’t go around making people mad on purpose; that could get a bit annoying to deal with…” Jake quickly backpedaled as the mental image of a dozen small factions descending on Haven emerged. He would hate having to waste time on getting them to fuck off…

“I have no plans on making enemies for no good reasons, geez,” Miranda said with a small laugh, clearly finding the notion preposterous.

“Just saying,” Jake clarified.

“Needlessly,” Miranda interjected.

“Importantly,” Jake countered.

“Wastefully,” Miranda shot back.

“Clarifyingly,” Jake double-clarified.

“Neil and I managed to talk to the trade manager of Sanctdomo and begin early talks of establishing a trade network using spatial formations,” Lillian came in, totally ruining the critical discussion with actually helpful information. “Something the Holy Church is already working on themselves to connect their own cities.”

“Guys… shouldn’t we vote?” Neil asked, clearly feeling a bit out of place.

Jake turned to the space mage in confusion. “You haven’t already? Weren’t we just going to abstain?”

“I hadn’t voted either,” Lillian said.

Miranda also shook her head. “Me neither… but yeah, we skip this one.”

A minute later, the notification popped up before all of them.

The election of World Leader has now concluded!

Results: No individual obtained at least 60% of the total votes. No World Leader will be elected during this World Congress. Note that a World Leader must be elected within the first 3 World Congresses.

Jake read the message and tried to locate a breakdown of votes, but couldn’t find any way to do that.

“Miranda, can you see who voted for what?” he asked, hoping maybe she could somehow.

“No, I can only see what it says,” she explained as she shook her head, also clearly wanting to see a breakdown.

“Well, that sucks. Then again, it isn’t like the system is known for being overly transparent when it comes to details… Imagine if you could get a breakdown after getting a skill upgrade telling you exactly what you di—"

Sadly, he didn’t get any further than that before he was interrupted by a new system message.

The second vote of the World Congress will relate to accelerating the growth of the planet and its inhabitants.

A System Store with limited wares will be offered for a period to assist the enlightened races of Earth. This store will both buy and sell wares, with any sold item then becoming available to other cities through the store at a price set by the seller. All items can also be sold directly to the store with compensation determined by the System Store.

To determine what wares the store will offer, a vote will be held.

The store can only be used by the City Lord and individuals designated by the City Lord. The stores will use Credits as their currency and will contain, in addition to items being sold by other cities, three types of crafting materials depending on what receives the most votes. Votes may be distributed as the noble desires between any number of options.

The voting options are as follows:

1. Herbs

2. Ores & Metals

3. Gems & Crystals

4. Mixed Monster Leather, Hides, & Bones

5. Mixed Monster Body Parts, Meat, & Innards

6. Wood

7. Stone

8. Chemicals

9. Fruit, Grain, & other Foodstuffs

10. Cloth, Thread, & other Textiles.

The stores will only be available for a limited time. All unsold items will be returned to the seller once the period expires. The Pylon can be accessed from anywhere within the city’s borders, and materials will appear at the buyer’s location.

Voting will begin in: 2:59:59

Jake stood there for a bit as he took it all in, Miranda, Neil, and Lillian doing the same. A System Store… Jake hadn’t expected such a thing to appear, as the Viper had made it clear that the tutorial store wasn’t something he should expect as a regular occurrence.

Then again, this one was quite a bit different from a store that offered legendary skills and pretty much whatever the heart desired as long as you had enough points. This store was just a store for materials to help craft stuff… and as Jake read over the options, he already knew what he wanted.

“Herbs for sure,” he declared.

It was a no-brainer. Jake was starting to get low on many herbs, so wouldn’t it be awesome if he could just buy them? He had so many Credits, after all. Maybe he could even get a small garden started… or stock up so much he wouldn’t need one.

“That does seem like the clear choice for us,” Miranda said, nodding. “As we don’t particularly plan on expanding, we aren’t in dire need of building materials. Besides, we are in a massive forest, so it isn’t like we need wood, and as we only really build using wood, the stone isn’t needed. Everything is basically a luxury to us and to help grow the professions of our inhabitants.”

“Which means we want the herbs,” Jake fully concurred.

“I believe we have a task ahead of ourselves, then, “Lillian added. “I doubt many others will vote for herbs. Most larger factions are, at the moment, focusing on expanding their populations, so I am ninety percent sure either stone, wood, or both will be voted for en masse.”

“Yeah, and I also think many will want ores and metals,” Neil said. “There seems to be a perpetual lack of proper materials for the blacksmiths, and it is also a barrier of entry to making the teleportation circles. Personally, I would prefer gems and crystals, but I don’t see that happening.”

“Anything is fine, as long as herbs is one of them,” Jake said.

He really didn’t care what else was picked. He doubted any leatherworker or blacksmith could make him any good equipment right now, even if he did seriously need a second melee weapon after Venomfang taking irreparable damage.

Before Jake could mourn the loss of his long-time weapon some more, another person spoke up—someone not from the first ten, but a level 85 E-grade who was the lord or at least apparent leader of a city. He was the highest-leveled individual of his city, at least.

“Ladies and gentlemen,” the young-looking man began, “would it not be wise to agree on what we will vote for before we split up once more so we can focus on creating connections rather than needlessly discussing this vote?”

“I agree,” a neighboring City Lord said, clearly already on good terms with the first one who’d spoken. “If we determine what Earth needs most now, we can focus on other important topics during this intermission.”

A few others voiced their opinions, none of them in the top ten. It was kind of a show of solidarity, perhaps because they felt like they needed more time than the larger factions. The Holy Church had no issues forging alliances, but those who didn’t have a single D-grade and had yet to make contact with another city outside of the World Congress were quite strapped for some good diplomatic relations. If not, they risked being absorbed by larger forces quite swiftly.

Jake threw Miranda a look as she turned their barrier transparent. Jake had already summoned his mask. The barrier around each city’s area had quite a few functions, and many were still locked off as people no doubt discussed what to do within. He used the term “no doubt” because… well, he could see them in his sphere discussing… cheat-like Bloodline for the win.

With some actual negotiation about to begin, Jake happily let Miranda take full charge. He just stood by her side, being the scary Progenitor he was.

“Haven’s first priority will be herbs," Miranda said loudly, instantly turning the attention of everyone in the hall to their platform.

What Miranda said wasn’t an invitation to negotiate or a proposition; it was a declaration. She was informing them what Haven was planning on doing—nothing less and nothing more. But there was quite a bit to it.

Miranda knew that everyone else knew that Jake, the weird masked man, was on good terms with several of the larger factions in the top ten. He even had familial relations to the Court of Shadows, a faction that was quite honestly an unsettling presence for many. Who would have thought that a Court of assassins would unnerve people? Not to speak of the undead…

It played to Haven’s advantage, as many now had an opportunity before them… one that was instantly grasped by another of the low-tiered City Lords.

"New Heartland will also support Haven’s selection of herbs as one of the options," the woman said.

It was a good political move that Miranda had counted on. Soon, a few others also voiced their intent to vote for herbs.

Honestly, it was just a cheap way for them to curry favor with the one Earl of Earth. While many of them would likely prefer wood or stone, they didn’t need it as much as they needed strong allies. Also… there were three options total. They could still get what they truly wanted and make a great political move. A win-win, if you may.

The only thing was… she could clearly see Jake’s eye twitch at the many city names. Four of the seven contained the word "new.” Miranda also had to admit that the imagination of most lords certainly wasn’t the best. Not that Haven was the most original, but at least it wasn’t New Haven.

Finally, another of the top ten also spoke up, this one from the group that Jake had referred to as the "Stone-Age cosplayers." “We have no objections to voting for herbs, and we nominate monster leather, hides, and bones to be selected," the overly tall D-grade leader of the city called Midtgaard said. “Defensive equipment is one of the most important things at this stage, given the constant battle against beasts at our doorsteps. A secure source of high-quality crafting materials will be incredibly beneficial. The bones can also be used for weapons, with leather having a use for many other professions too, making this option overall perhaps the most valuable package.”

Miranda barely held back a scoff, as she knew most of his reasoning was only half-truths at best… He just wanted leather and hides for his own city since, based on their equipment, they evidently had quite a few talented leatherworkers.

She wasn’t the only one to call it out either.

"While I agree that there is much truth in your assessment, I don’t think it is our best choice,” a woman said. “Scarce building material leads to many lacking homes and cities being unable to properly ensure the safety of their citizens. We believe it would be best to focus on constructing our cities before prioritizing personal equipment. Therefore I believe we should select both wood and stone. If only one, I think stone would be best.”

She was one of the D-grades from the top ten that hadn’t drawn that much attention yet. Jake had told Miranda she was exactly level 100, having clearly just evolved, but that still meant she was one of the stronger people present. Jake had mentioned that she felt weak, though, so Miranda doubted she had achieved the Perfect Evolution.

"Do you need tall walls if the warriors can stand firm and make no beast come near?" the man in fur countered, looking a bit annoyed that he wasn’t instantly offered the same support that Miranda had gained.

"Your axe will not place a roof over anyone’s head if you spend all day slaying beasts and not chopping wood," the woman said, clearly also annoyed.

The discussion continued for a while, others frequently adding their opinions, and it quickly became clear that at least either wood or stone would be chosen. Now the choice was which one…

Jake looked wholly uninterested, and quite frankly, Miranda didn’t care much either. Haven was already somewhat strapped for Credits, so it wasn’t like they were going to buy a lot, and pretty much all resources chosen would benefit the citizens in some way.

Phillip would love ores and metals for the large smithy at the Fort, Haven had many wood-working professions, and a source of high-quality stone was always welcome for construction. Again, the same held true for everything.

It quickly became obvious that the other cities didn’t have the same opinion, however. Jacob, the Augur, didn’t engage this time. He instead had the trade manager advocate for both stone and wood, noting that foodstuffs surely had to be another valuable option if they could only get one.

A few tried to question if herbs were truly necessary, but Miranda found that other forces also supported it, and not just to kiss ass. Herbs were generally harder to get than most other resources, and most settlements had at least some alchemists. Even if they didn’t, many cooks or other types of artisans could still use herbs. This ignored that some herbs were also beneficial to just eat raw; they mostly functioned as suboptimal healing or mana potions, but they were better than nothing.

In the end, the proposition to quickly decide what shops to get turned out not to be that quick.

Chapter 16

World Congress: "Confrontations"

Jake had always liked to play strategy games, mainly those of the good old 4X genre. 4X was an abbreviation of Explore, Expand, Exploit and Exterminate, and featured, in ninety percent of cases, macro-gameplay and economics in a leading role. While they weren’t the most realistic, he and Casper had spent many hours nerding out over making optimal builds and strategies, and one of the most important factors was always location.

In these games, the resources you had available were nearly entirely dependent on the starting location. In any given session, you might start near valuable metals or expensive crystals, a forest for logging, or a seaside with great fishing possibilities.

The placement of the Pylons was a bit of the same. Most, if not all citizens preferred to be within the scope of the Pylon for obvious reasons. It increased experience gain for noncombat-related activities, and the City Lord also wanted it for all their skills to work properly.

This meant that unless you had valuable resources extremely close by, you would have to travel outside of the safety of the city to get them—something very few liked to do. There was always the risk of some high-level asshole bird descending and killing you, or some huge earthworm suddenly coming up and gobbling you down.

Haven, as an example, had a mine placed within the area of the city with some ores and metals. Perhaps a few gems and crystals too, but nothing worth writing home about, and far from enough to call it a strategic resource. According to Miranda, they had already spent all the metal they’d mined, so it wasn’t like getting more would be bad.

There was plenty of wood to go around, being placed in a forest and all, with stones also aplenty—primarily because they didn’t feel the need to expand senselessly.

Jake was already fairly confident that they wouldn’t lack monster material—again, forest—and fruits and foodstuffs, they also had plenty of. Heck, even herbs weren’t that hard to get, and Jake had collected a few during his hunts deeper into the forest, but it still took time, and most herbs he found had unknown uses.

As far as Jake knew, Haven outright lacked some materials, such as chemicals and cloth. Due to them having nearly nothing natively, Haven would be fine with all the offered materials except for wood or anything from monsters as at least they had those. As it was, they kind of needed everything but didn’t severely need anything. Except for herbs… because Jake wanted that.

The same wasn’t true for other cities. Sanctdomo appeared to lack nearly everything due to their large population, but apparently had plenty of gems and crystals. Other cities had one or two resources that they all seemed adamant on not needing a store for.

All of this is to say… no one could fucking agree on anything.

Jake really wanted to just leave or go chat with one of his many acquaintances present, but that was a bit hard with all the borderline yelling going on between the City Lords. It would also just be rude to tell Miranda, Neil, and Lillian to leave the platform for him to invite friends over… so Jake had to wait. The only positive thing was that you really got a good feel for the other cities based on this entire thing.

A "quick discussion so we can move on to other things" ended up taking nearly two hours, leaving only a single hour remaining before the actual vote would begin. Jake wasn’t even sure any definite agreement was reached; it just sounded like people would vote for their own thing. A massive waste of time. Everything except for the first five minutes where everyone agreed on herbs, that is.

Finally free, Jake considered if he should go over and ask the undead a bit more about how their stats now worked, but he noticed a figure approaching before he could do that. He was from one of the lower-ranking cities and was a person Jake recognized by aura over appearance.

It was the sleek-looking man with a Bloodline.

He had deep brown eyes, with what looked like a small flame burning within, and his gaze seemed to pick up something no one else could perceive. Jake felt uncomfortable under his stare, like his eyes bore into his body, and he was certain of one thing… the man had a Perception-based skill like himself. At least, it had aspects that allowed him to "see" something. No… it wasn’t a skill… it was his Bloodline.

What does he see? Jake wondered as the man got closer. The man’s eyes flickered between Jake’s chest and face as an intrigued smile adorned his face.

"Pleasure to meet you, Hunter. I am Eron.” He extended a hand towards Jake.

Jake looked at him for a bit. Miranda and the two others stood uncomfortably behind him, not sure what to do or say. Before Miranda had a chance to come to the rescue, Jake just smiled and shook his hand.

"Nice to meet you… Patriarch," Jake said, his voice infused with a bit of will to make it harder for anyone but Eron to hear it. It wasn’t foolproof, and Miranda and the others still heard it—as well as anyone using a skill or technique to snoop—but it was good enough to mask it for the casual listener.

As for why he’d used that term…

Eron returned his smile with an even larger one of his own. "A rarity, those like us. It would be my pleasure to host you in the city of Cardius if you find the time and wish to speak further. I believe we have much to learn from one another, and it would be my honor. You have a certain… spark in you."

The last words were said a bit weirdly, and Jake squinted. "I’ll think about it," he said, honestly just wanting the creepy guy gone. He got the heeby jeebies from him... but he also got another strange emotion.

Everything within Jake was telling him that the man, Eron, wasn’t a danger to him. He was a D-grade, and he did have a certain aura to him, but it was far from enough to threaten Jake. Yet Jake felt like if they fought… he couldn’t win.

It was an odd feeling… He somehow sensed that fighting the man would be a meaningless endeavor. He kinda wanted to try fighting all the D-grades present just to try and battle a fellow human at D-grade. All except for Eron. Odd indeed.

Eron, hearing Jake’s tentative affirmation, just smiled once more and nodded. "Know that you are welcome." He looked at Jake’s face… Not his eyes, but face… or perhaps what was on it. "Both of you."

With those words, he walked off, leaving a frowning Jake behind.

Casper stood with his eyes closed, ignoring the entire discussion about what resources to get and all that. He knew his opinion wouldn’t add any value, and he would rather spend his time focusing on something more important.

Such as talking with his ghost girlfriend.

"Your friends seem nice," Lyra said, her voice echoing in his head.

They had tried and discovered that Lyra couldn’t be summoned inside the World Congress, much to the annoyance of Priscilla and the schadenfreude of Casper. He didn’t want to put her out there just because Priscilla wanted to flex their strength a bit.

Lyra had evolved to D-grade a week or so before the World Congress and was already damn strong for one her level. Her blight magic was damn intense, and she seemed to like fighting, which was a relief to Casper. They had even worked on ways for her to help enhance his traps to have better synergy in the future.

While it was expected that someone of the enlightened species was stronger than monsters, it wasn’t a rule—far from it. Priscilla didn’t like to admit it, but Lyra was stronger than her in pretty much every way when it came to a straight-up confrontation. Her race was incredibly powerful, and something equally important was something Casper hadn’t even considered… She was practically immortal.

As long as the locket existed, she would always be able to reform her body. The locket itself contained at least parts of her soul… To be honest, Casper wasn’t sure exactly how it worked; he was just happy that his girlfriend would be safe in most circumstances. A bit like a lich, actually. It was weird how an item could be both functional equipment and essentially the body of a "living" creature. He had been warned that certain soul-affecting attacks could still hurt her and that she was even a bit susceptible to them due to her state, but it wasn’t something they had to worry about against regular beasts.

Even if he didn’t care overly much about this whole negotiation, Priscilla and the others were sure going at it. They didn’t really need stone but actually really wanted wood. Many trees couldn’t grow within their area or wouldn’t last long, and they hoped that the store would have types of wood fit for areas with high death affinity.

He himself desired some gems and crystals, but he wasn’t desperate.

They were for his profession as a Dungeon Engineer, and he needed many crystals, gems, and other energy sources to power stuff. Casper was called a Dungeon Engineer, but that didn’t mean he could actually make dungeons… at least, not yet. He could make certain areas with desired properties, and with his class as a Cursed Trapper, he could make some damn nice defensive fortifications. Together with Lyra, they had taken down quite a few D-grades already.

Well, Casper had taken them down alone after she reached D-grade, after which she just kept close to keep him safe. It hurt his experience gain a lot and wasn’t great for his Records either, but he saw that as a small sacrifice to spend more time with her.

"Yeah, they’re good people," he replied. Communicating telepathically with her had been a lot easier than he thought, and it helped him to not look ridiculous by standing there and talking to himself.

"But… your friend Jake is a bit… how do I say it… unsettling. I felt like he knew I was listening," Lyra said, a bit unsure.

"Wouldn’t surprise me. Also, can I point out how funny it is that a ghost is scared of a human and not the other way around?"

"I am not scared! I said unsettled, not scared. Geez. If anyone is scary, it is that Augur. I feel like half of his words somehow touch my soul or something. I don’t think we should interact too much with him, at least not too frequently and only in small doses. I have a feeling that kind of passive mental magic can seriously affect someone.”

"True. I don’t think Jacob would do anything on purpose, but better safe than sorry. It also isn’t like people can’t change… and I wouldn’t have thought Caroline able to do what she did, so I guess I am not the best judge of character."

They kept talking for a while, mainly discussing non-World Congress-related topics.

It was soothing, and they did have to touch a bit upon some sad facts of reality. This would likely be the last time Casper could meet this casually with Jacob and quite a few others. The political stage had yet to form into circles and alliances, but more defined lines would begin separating the factions once that was established. And there was no way the undead and the Holy Church would ever be in an official alliance.

They were only interrupted when the talks died down and people began wandering. Casper didn’t think about going anywhere, as his attention was still grabbed by the "confrontation" many had looked forward to.

Progenitor vs. Sword Saint.

Jake stood before the man as they looked each other in the eyes. Quite a few other parties, including the Holy Church, were interested to see what would come of this, as the two had just stood there for a good five seconds now.

Blue eyes, deep as the ocean, stared into beastly, soul-piercing eyes. Their gazes could nearly not be any more different, yet they both held the same challenging intent.

At the same time, they raised their arms to shake hands, both giving a good squeeze. The old man winced as they both let go, while Jake smiled triumphantly. He’d won out in pure strength.

He could see in the Sword Saint’s eyes… and knew for himself… that if not for the rules of the World Congress, the old man would have drawn his sword, and he would have summoned his bow at this very moment. Sadly, there were rules, and this wasn’t the time or place for a fight between what were likely the two strongest humans on Earth.

"The Noboru clan wishes to enter a formal non-aggression pact with Haven, with the goal of a true alliance," the Sword Saint spoke, finally breaking the silence with curt words no one had expected him to say. "I do not believe our two cities have any reason to fight. We can discuss more… personal arrangements for the future at a later time. What say you?"

"Sure," Jake agreed. "You can have your people discuss it with my people."

"We are in agreement, then. Pleasure meeting you," the old man said as he bowed and moved away. Jake returned a nod, ending their second interaction the same as the first.

This interaction had been brief but impactful. Many eyes had been on them, some of them hoping for the two to enter an actual conflict.

And while Jake would love to have a fight, he didn’t see any reason to involve Haven or the other guy’s cities. Jake also had a feeling that they would get their chance eventually, even if a vast distance separated them… And quite frankly, while Jake was vain, he wasn’t silly enough to spend so much time traveling to another city just to fight an old man. At least, not before he got faster.

Jake wasn’t sure what to do with the rest of the time before the next vote and just returned to his seat on their platform. Everyone else was gone again, Miranda and Lillian having taken the chance to talk to the representatives from Saya and Neil chatting with some space mage woman from a lower-ranking city.

With a mental command, he obscured the platform and took the mask off his face.

He stared down at the wooden mask. It looked entirely the same as the day he’d gotten it… but he knew it was not. Things had changed. During his race evolution, it had absorbed some of the weird energy in that space, and he had a feeling that while it increased his mana regeneration, it also constantly pulled in energy for itself.

"Hey Villy, wou—" Jake began, but instantly felt something was wrong. He closed his eyes and focused, and only noticed now that he couldn’t feel that small, subtle connection he usually felt. He also only now discovered that he couldn’t feel the Viper’s presence at all.

Usually, he just zoned out the occasional peek the god took, but he hadn’t peeked for this entire World Congress… and it turned out it had been because he couldn’t. All connection to outside sources, at least divine sources, appeared to be cut off while inside this weird World Congress space.

I guess that means all the other factions are cut off too… Good riddance.

It was good to know that this entire World Congress, in actuality, wasn’t a bunch of gods discussing with mouthpieces. It was also once more proof that the system was the real OG on the power scale. That it could fully cut off the connection like that so flawlessly was quite a powerplay.

Anyway, what he wanted to ask Villy was pretty simple… so he decided to ask the one other "person" on the platform with him.

He looked down at the mask once more.

"So… do you think I could beat you now?"

Jake got no response… but he was sure the King was there. Still alive. Eron had seen something… it had taken energy… the description had slightly changed… and Jake couldn’t wait for a proper rematch. Of course, it was entirely possible he had misread the situation, but one could always hope…

Chapter 17

World Congress: On the Flip of a Coin

The second vote quickly approached its end, and by now, there was quite a bit of nervousness going around. The last hour had contained plenty of closed-door deals and under-the-table agreements on what to vote for.

Miranda told Jake that she and Lillian had gone to reaffirm the vote for herbs with those who’d promised it before. She even went as far as making binding system agreements with them, not allowing them just to make empty promises.

With the many votes of Haven and at least a few from some of the other top ten ones, herbs was pretty much secured as one of the chosen options. Honestly, no one was sure what the other options would be, but wood and stone had apparently become less popular over the last hour.

This was due to the ability to sell to other cities using the store, and the different factions had begun just making deals with those who had plenty of a particular resource. Of course, there was the issue that you couldn’t sell to designated buyers based on the description of the store, but it would at least mean some wood or stone was up for sale.

Haven would likely sell some wood, too, logging from around the outskirts of the forest towards the Fort. They didn’t want to ruin the city of Haven itself, but no one really cared about the outskirts closer to the Fort. All it would do was make less forest between the Fort and Haven… and there was plenty of forest to take from. More than they could possibly log for many years.

There were some worries, though. Such as… what did the system consider an item? Or a material? Many types of wood apparently weren’t Identifiable without some mild processing or until transformed into an item, just like some herbs and fruits didn’t register as an item before they matured. Could you just throw a pile of trees into the store? How would the system communicate what you were selling?

He was also aware that he didn’t have full information on this. Identify only worked on items you could actually Identify… like how he couldn’t Identify herbs back before becoming an alchemist. Miranda also hadn’t seen the properties of herbs before she got some general appraising skill for magical catalysts from her class that allowed her to Identify some herbs. On a side note, everyone could apparently Identify stuff like equipment or consumables, but the details varied. Like how Jake could see how much a potion would restore and others couldn’t, and how a blacksmith could see details if Identifying a weapon or armor.

The only ones that could kind of Identify everything were merchants. According to Miranda, rather than an Identify skill, they often got it upgraded or received a similar new skill called Appraisal or something like that. That made sense to Jake… as a merchant kind of had to know what the hell he was handling.

Actually, would merchants be able to do something special with the System Store? Maybe some additional options? An easier way to sell items?

All of these were questions Jake was glad he didn’t have to really think about, outside of interesting consideration about what an item was. He could just ask Miranda or someone else about it after the fact.

Jake had also considered if he should try and flex some potions and promise to put some up for sale if everyone voted for herbs… but he didn’t really want to put himself out there like that. He would also seriously need to commission some more bottles soon.

He’d had Miranda give him back quite a few, and she had even scrounged up some additional ones from a merchant, but Jake still needed a lot. He had this bad habit of sometimes throwing and breaking poison or potion bottles after drinking them.

Hmm, will potion bottles be a part of gems and crystals, or maybe stone? Jake wondered. Glass was made from sand, and sand was technically small, annoying, underwear-invading stones. Which begged another question… Were they even made of glass? He didn’t actually know. Maybe it was just some special kind of crystal?

As these thoughts passed through his head, Neil entered the barrier, and Jake also noticed that the vote for the System Store would begin in around five minutes.

Jake nodded at Neil and asked, "Any progress on getting some teleportation network up and running?"

Neil looked a bit surprised that the unmasked Jake had asked, then smiled. "A bit, but it isn’t easy. We need to properly link things up, which will require us to travel to other cities and set them up as it is now. We are hoping to find a way to sync them up without having to travel…"

"How would that work?" Jake asked, genuinely curious. He loved figuring out how all the magic stuff worked.

Neil was clearly happy to see someone interested. "Hm, it is a bit like finding a radio frequency that we can tap into. One not currently used. You can say that the usual space we occupy is the stable wavelength, and any deviations to it result in spatial distortion. Space magic, as I understand it, is basically just fiddling with the frequency in a localized area.

"So, what we are trying to do is to create matching spatial radios of sorts, all running on the exact same wavelength to make the entire journey between the two stable. We need it to be a frequency that is also properly compressed and warps the space between the two locations, like that old movie trope where the science guy folds a piece of paper in half and pokes a pencil through. We need to make sure the frequency properly bends the paper, and then for the teleportation to poke the hole with whatever we transport on the edge of the pencil."

"Wait, won’t you need the spatial radios, as you call them, to be able to differ in frequency depending on where you want to go?” Jake asked. “And what if that space is distorted by other means during travel?"

Neil just looked at him for a few moments. The surprise on his face from Jake actually having listened was palpable. "It is indeed a challenge. Outside interference isn’t really that big of a deal, as we can stabilize it, so unless another expert messes with it or someone booby traps the teleportation circle, the teleportation itself should be safe and one hundred percent reliable. You are also right that the teleportation circles will need to link up to each other. Luckily, we think we have found a solution to that.”

"Do tell."

"We will use the System Store to sell items with spatial signatures imprinted on them as well as confidential codes only known and understandable by us space mages. It will take a while, but with it, we should be able to establish a good network of participating cities. This does require the teleportations circles to be absolutely stable, and they cannot be moved around after being established and linked. Luckily, planets heavily stabilize the frequency of space, but we would still need regular maintenance for the circles to not have them desync due to the planet moving and stuff like that."

"Well, sounds like you have quite the task ahead of you," Jake chuckled. "How will you power the circles?"

"Yeah… that is another issue. The circles will require a lot of spatial mana to work. More dependent on the distance. It will also get more expensive as the strength of the person being teleported increases. By the way, these teleportation circles aren’t our inventions at all, but common knowledge in the multiverse, confirmed by how we pretty much all have the same understanding based on the study resources we had access to. I still have quite a few books stored in the Orb."

Neil was getting sidetracked. Jake already knew these teleportations weren’t their invention, as so many damn books he’d read talked about them as being regular business across the multiverse.

"Didn’t answer my question. How will you power it?" Jake asked again.

"Right. To begin with, it will absolutely require one of us space mages being present to power it, and even then, it will require consumables. If gems and crystals gets voted for, there might be useable energy sources there, but it is honestly a big maybe, as items with space affinity are rare. No, it makes more sense for us to make it such that regular mana can be transformed into space mana to power the circle, but that will take a while to get up and running. Even then, it will result in it needing even more maintenance, as these catalysts to transform mana will wear out quickly. Again, this is how it is often done throughout the multiverse in the early stages of these networks. There are better ways, but they will take even longer and even more power to get up and running. Of course, if we suddenly had a B-grade space mage, he could just toss up super-advanced circles running on atmospheric mana and tap into high-level concepts to power it, but I don’t see that happening any time soon."

"Sounds like you have a major task ahead of you," a female voice said.

Miranda and Lillian entered the barrier, making Neil look a bit embarrassed. He was really getting into it, and Jake found it quite interesting. Sadly, the time to vote was approaching. But more importantly…

"Hey, that’s what I said," Jake said, cracking a smile.

"Great minds think alike." Miranda smiled before turning a bit more serious. "I have done what I can, and I believe herbs should be locked down, but it would still be risky for us not to pour our votes into it. Based on the talks, I also strongly believe that ore and metal will be voted in. As for the last option… it is honestly up in the air."

"I reckon it will still be stone or wood, though I did hear some talk of foodstuffs in some of the rapidly expanding settlements," Lillian pitched in. “Food has a lot of value in regenerating resources faster. People still have to eat a bit… I can’t talk about D-grade, but even at E-grade, we can’t go entirely without food.”

Jake had to admit… he had barely thought of food as one of the things that could possibly get voted for. There was so much to find, and people needed far less. Yet people still needed a little... Jake had just never noticed it.

Did he really get his fill from herbs and stuff? Actually, about the time he stopped eating as many herbs, Miranda had begun bringing him food. Was he really just a spoiled brat who got all the food handed to him on a platter—literally?

I guess I shouldn’t judge others like that, and I am sure chefs and cooks can make some awesome stuff; if not, they wouldn’t get their own entire profession. The food Miranda brings is also godly… If foodstuffs was voted, maybe they could make even better things and level faster. Haven needs a D-grade chef sooner rather than later.

Anyway, the timer slowly ticked down, and by now, everyone had returned to their own platforms. Nearly all of them were fully obscured as the factions went through a last-second discussion on what to vote for.

Voting has begun!

Please distribute your votes.

Votes remaining: 10/10

Time to vote: 4:59

Options for store offerings:

1. Herbs

2. Or

Jake stopped reading there and poured all ten votes into herbs. Miranda, Lillian, and Neil did the same, then just waited and made some small talk to pass the time. He felt somewhat nervous about herbs possibly not being voted for, as it was really the only option he cared about. Should I have done more to convince people? No… put trust in Miranda. You would just have made things worse.

The vote for the Limited System Store has concluded!

Voting breakdown (ordered based on the number of votes received):

1. Ores & Metals

You got to be fucking kidding me. I swear to fucking Villy, I will—

2. Herbs

Okay, all good. Phew.

3. Stone

So stone won out, eh?

3. Fruit, Grain, & other Foodstuffs

Wait, what? Two threes?

4. Wood

5. Mixed Monster Leather, Hides & Bones

6. Cloth, Thread, and other Textiles

7. Gems & Crystals

8. Chemicals

9. Mixed Monster Body Parts, Meat, & Innards

Does two threes mean there is a tie? Wait, doesn’t that mean—

The vote has resulted in a tie. The highest-ranking noble shall function as the tiebreaker. The highest-ranking noble present is the Earl [?] from Haven, who will have 10 minutes to decide.

This isn’t all good anymore. Not at all.

As the high-ranking noble, it is your privilege and responsibility to take charge during a political impasse. You must exercise your power and choose either Fruit, Grain, & other Foodstuffs, or Stone as the third resource to enter the Limited System Store.

Time to choose: 9:57

WARNING: If you fail to select, the decision will default to the second-highest-ranking noble present, chosen based on who obtained the Viscount Title first.

Well, fuck me.

Jake was the only one that could read the last few system messages, which had followed the news that the decision was now up to him... and he felt it. Every single fucking pair of eyes turned his way, and the damn barrier was always made see-through just as a vote ended, making everyone look straight at him.

He wanted to make it obscure him, but he grit his teeth as he prepared himself for what was coming.

"Excuse me—"

"Sir, I believe—"

"For the sake of—"

"I implore you to—"

A dozen voices spoke up, all directed towards Jake to try and make him choose their preferred option. Jake found it all a tad overwhelming but kept his cool. He focused on the mask on his face and the fact that he was the one in charge here… but more importantly, he chose to believe in the person he had appointed City Lord.

Jake raised his hand to silence everyone. Saya—the city of the Sword Saint—the undead, Sanctdomo, the Court, and many of the other major factions hadn’t said anything; it was mainly all the smaller factions. Soon, everyone quieted down as Jake spoke.

"Let’s do this fairly."

With a motion, a small item appeared in his hand: a coin. He noticed a few people’s eyes go wide. His brother made a big grin on his platform, one mirrored by Jacob, Casper, Bertram, and even the Sword Saint, who clearly found his decision amusing.

Jake placed the coin in his hand and, with a flick, tossed it into the air. It spun at incredible speed before it landed on top of his hand, where it was instantly covered by his other hand.

He looked out into the hall and spotted a random City Lord from one of the lower-ranking cities. "You there. If you’re right, stone; if you’re wrong, foodstuffs. Choose—heads or tails?"

The poor City Lord took a few moments to notice he was talking to her, and all the attention switched her way. She was clearly surprised to be put on the spot, but managed to collect herself as she asked, "How do we know you aren’t doing some trick?" She clearly didn’t want to choose.

"You don’t, and I don’t care what you think. If I wanted, I could just pick a random one myself. So… heads or tails?"

She stood there, hesitating, before Jake just shook his head and looked to her neighbor, another low-ranking noble. "You, then. Heads or tails?

The man looked a bit more assured as he shrugged, gladly playing along. Perhaps he didn’t care that much himself. "Heads, I guess."

Jake smiled as he lifted his hand and revealed the coin. Tails.

"Foodstuffs it is."

He didn’t even give the objections time to come. He chose it, and the system notification went out to everyone.

Voting for the Limited System Store has concluded.

The store will include an assortment of Ores & Metals, Herbs, and Fruit, Grain, & other Foodstuffs. The store will be available upon the conclusion of the World Congress.

Jake heard a few yells of people claiming it was unfair and other silly objections, but he didn’t care. Nothing was fairer than a coinflip. Sure, it would’ve been cheating if he’d picked himself with his intuition, which was why he’d made someone else pick. Still, the complaints annoyed him. Miranda had even given him an approving smile, so it couldn’t be that bad.

Luckily, the next system message quickly came to make people shut up.

The third and final vote of the World Congress will pertain to the upcoming System Event to help the enlightened races of Earth.

Chapter 18

World Congress: System Events

"System Events are exactly as the name suggests—events put on by the system itself," the Malefic Viper had explained to Jake long ago. “More often than not, they offer great rewards but equally great risks. Well, as a new universe, you may get some safer versions. Events can be pretty much anything and are great ways to challenge yourself and achieve a breakthrough to the next level for many mortals and even gods. They can even offer things one cannot find out in the multiverse. As I told you, I got my Bloodline through an Event, so that should put things into perspective. They can also offer titles, items, and all sorts of things. I wouldn’t count on any Events you experience in your early days to offer anything overly great, as I have yet to hear of any Bloodline-granting Events for anyone below C-grade. Also, as your events will likely be of the safer variant, it won’t offer the best there is. Danger and opportunity are intrinsically linked, after all.”

Actually, the tutorial had been considered a System Event, though still special even by System Event standards.

Jake was certain most, if not all factions related to higher powers were aware of these things. At least, he saw their eyes light up at the mention of a System Event, and most seemed to nearly instantly forgive and forget his coin-flipping antics.

The third and final vote of the World Congress will pertain to the upcoming System Event to help the enlightened races of Earth. All System Events will primarily feature combat, and any participants are advised to recognize this.

All events will offer unique rewards and opportunities.

Options for the System Event:

1. Tournament (Singles)

2. Tournament (Groups)

3. Town Defense

4. Treasure Hunt

5. Event Dungeons

The Tournaments will include both battles against monsters as well as other enlightened beings of Earth. If Singles are chosen, the battles will primarily consist of 1 vs. 1 fights between monsters and enlightened ones, while Groups will include group battles and larger combat scenarios against monsters. The monsters will be rare variants from across the multiverse, both powerful and valuable. Groups can consist of up to 10 members. For Singles, all rewards will be given individually, while for Groups, it will be split evenly among Group members.

The Town Defense event will see the enlightened beings of Earth in a city of old, and they will have to defend it from ever-increasing waves of invading monsters. Every Pylon will be granted their own minor settlement to defend. However, an alliance of up to 5 Pylons may be established before the event and allow them only to defend a single City instead. The invaders will carry much bounty for you to claim. All rewards will be split among the defenders, partly based on contributions.

The Event Dungeons will offer 3 distinct dungeons that can be challenged in parties of up to 5, and 2 Challenge Dungeons that can only be attempted by individuals. Rewards will be split according to standard dungeon rules, with a final reward given depending on overall performance.

The Treasure Hunt will see the participants travel to a foreign land filled with treasures to be unearthed and discovered or hidden away by a lost civilization in their safest and well-defended chambers. Beat challenges and claim your spoils. During the Treasure Hunt, the participants will encounter other creatures attempting to claim the items, as well as the ever-present threat of the other enlightened ones and the environment itself. The Treasure Hunt will be entered individually, and all rewards are individually earned.

All events will take a total of 10 days and will begin in 3 months (90 days). Beware that death is a risk, but all participants will have the possibility of surrendering and exiting any ongoing Event at the cost of a reduced reward. All participants must be D-grade or above or be granted an exception to participate by the system. Anyone who meets the requirements to participate will be given an invitation upon initiation of the chosen System Event.

Three days after the chosen event concludes, there will be an Auction where the participants and cities may auction off their spoils as well as any other valuables they hold. More details regarding the Auction will come after the conclusion of the System Event.

Only one option may be chosen.

Voting will begin in: 3:59:59

It was a massive notification, and everyone in the entire hall was silent for a moment as they all took it in. Jake also carefully took it all in, already considering what option he liked the most. Actually… it was a bit like when he was choosing skills. Five options, too. Of course, the difference here was that he would have to discuss it with a massive group of other interested parties.

Miranda didn’t hesitate as she obscured their platform—and just in time, as Jake saw many other factions do the same. There were a few that didn’t, but the vast majority did. They needed to discuss the new information and reach an internal consensus.

"Thoughts?" Miranda asked openly.

"I think the solo tournament would be best for Haven," Lillian said, being the practical person she was. “We don’t have a lot of powerful groups besides Neil’s party, and most of the other events seem more catered towards groups. However, if it is purely solo battles, I believe we have the strongest person on Earth.”

There was just one issue with that. "No, thanks," Jake answered, shaking his head.

A tournament honestly just sounded… boring. Besides a handful of the people present, he didn’t see anyone even capable of putting up an entertaining fight. The Sword Saint and maybe one or two others could likely offer a good bout, so the entire tournament would just be him fighting monsters. And while that did sound quite entertaining, he liked many of the other options more.

Lillian looked a bit confused, but Miranda seemed to understand his thoughts as she nodded in acknowledgment.

"I think Town Defense would be the worst option for us,” she said. “That event seems heavily focused on the power of cities as a whole, and Haven simply isn’t big enough for that to seem like a good idea. Also, the rewards seem to be heavily biased towards large parties, and even if one has an exemplary performance, they will very likely have to share a lot of the bounty with others. As Haven is more focused on singular, powerful individuals, that entire option seems like a bad idea.”

Jake agreed. Also, it said waves, which likely meant hordes, which meant a lot of busywork killing weaker enemies.

"I am personally leaning towards Dungeons or that Treasure Hunt," Jake said.

While Haven already had a D-grade dungeon close by, that wasn’t the part of the event he focused on. It was the two Challenge Dungeons. Jake had only ever been in one Challenge Dungeon, and that had awarded him his current profession and put him on the Path of the Malefic Viper. It had been a major turning point for his progress and an invaluable experience. The gains outside of the profession were also good for a dungeon you couldn’t even be level 10 to enter, having provided stat-gaining items, that mural that gave 10 Willpower, and, of course, the entire garden and living area he’d cleaned up. Oh, and on top of it all, he’d even gained usual dungeon rewards, AKA the spatial necklace and fabulous boots.

He wouldn’t discount the regular dungeons either. If they gave loot similar to that of the tutorial, he would come out with quite a haul if he managed to clear just twoof them during the ten days. It was all a gamble, of course, but he should be able to make solid progress, considering his relative strength compared to the rest of the planet.

The other option he liked was the Treasure Hunt. Why? Well, it was in the name. Jake liked treasures, and he liked hunting. How could he not like an event centered around hunting down treasures? Moreover… he felt like he was quite suited for it.

He had Hunter’s Tracking, Sense of the Malefic Viper, and an insanely high Perception stat—not to mention all the benefits from his Bloodline, such as improved intuition, his danger sense when breaking into well-defended chambers, and his Sphere of Perception, which had grown immensely since his evolution. If anyone was good at finding cool stuff and getting to it, he felt like it was him.

Also… of all the options, Treasure Hunt seemed the most "open." The rest looked way more regulated, with set challenges to overcome. Based on the description, the Treasure Hunt would be an area perhaps a bit like the tutorial, allowing those who truly stood out to exemplify themselves. That meant Jake could spend the entire ten days going for the good stuff and not waste the first few days slogging through the easy parts.

Heck, it even mentioned competing with other humans and the Risen, so he would even get a chance to test his mettle against the other powerhouses of Earth.

Out of all the options, he also felt like it synergized best with the subsequent Auction.

Thinking about it, the idea of an Auction was quite interesting, especially considering it would be in three months. With a System Store now available for at least a while, many would be able to craft more and better stuff than ever before, and surely they would save the best for the Auction.

Jake voiced his opinion to the others, as well as his reasoning. They seemed to get it, but Miranda did have a point of concern.

"Based on the rules, there is nothing stopping factions from grouping up during the Treasure Hunt. While the minimum requirement of D-grade will mean you can’t enter with an army, I can still see most of the major factions entering with quite a group in three months. Haven won’t have as many, so we may be outmanned severely and be taken advantage of."

"I am very confident Eleanor, Christen, Levi, Silas, and I will achieve D-grade for the event," Neil chimed in.

"Me too, but that will still leave us severely behind pretty much every faction besides some of the smaller ones," Miranda said, shaking her head.

"You are only making it sound more enticing," Jake said with a toothy smile. "While I can empathize with you guys being ganged up on, I personally welcome it. Besides, I doubt they will dare grouping up on me. The system said death is still a risk."

"Yeah… but needlessly killing anyone will be a diplomatic disaster," Miranda said, shaking her head again.

"If they try to start shit, it isn’t needless. While I would prefer not to have to, I am not averse to making a few examples." Jake mirrored her shaking head.

He truly didn’t want to kill humans if he could avoid it, as he knew how complicated it was. It was the same reason he’d tried to avoid killing even invaders like Abby and Donald, but just like Abby and Donald, he wouldn’t hesitate to kill if he decided it was necessary.

Jake still vividly remembered the ambush that had nearly killed him back in the tutorial. If he were ever put in a similar spot, he wouldn’t hesitate to kill every single fucking person involved, consequences be damned.

If he were worried that there would be retaliation, Jake would just rely on the nugget of wisdom from the Viper… Become strong enough for them not to dare and try anything. Of course, he knew that as humans, they were emotional creatures and didn’t always act logically, but the stronger one gets, the more they tend to value their lives. Well, Jake was a hard exception to that, considering the near-suicidal behavior he was still willing to exhibit if he could get a good fight.

"Just don’t overdo it, and tell me if you kill a scion of some faction or the son of a City Lord or something like that," Miranda answered. She looked like she knew she couldn’t convince him otherwise… and she was right.

"I don’t think most factions will try anything either. Is it really worth the risk to attack those from Haven?" Jake asked, trying to convince her.

"Not with you around, no, but the rest of us? While some might still be rebuffed, just as many won’t care. Anyway, dungeons or Treasure Hunt. Got it. Which one would you prefer?"

"Treasure Hunt," Jake answered, having convinced himself thoroughly via reflection and the subsequent discussion.

"Alright."

Their platform was made visible, and they just stood there for a while and waited. Soon, Sanctdomo to one side and Saya to the other also became visible. Jake looked towards Jacob, who returned his gaze, and Jake threw him a questioning look.

Jacob smiled as he mouthed the word, "Treasure."

Jake smiled and subtly nodded. He wasn’t surprised at all. He had expected Jacob and the Holy Church to either want Treasure Hunt or the Town Defense one. Town Defense because they were the largest city Jake knew of, and Treasure Hunt because they had a living cheat with the power to divine where valuable things could be found.

As Miranda had noted, high city populations weren't necessarily that big of an advantage. This event would only be for the elites, no matter what. Three months seemed like a long time, but one had to remember that D-grade wasn’t that easy to reach. Neil and his party were all regarded as powerful experts, yet he couldn’t promise they would all reach D-grade before the deadline.

One by one, all the platforms became visible. No one stepped forth right away to voice their opinions, but instead waited patiently for the entire hall to be ready.

This vote was a bit different from all those prior. This vote wasn’t one that truly concerned the trade managers or even political figures. It was a decision only those who had reached D-grade or had the confidence to be D-grade by the deadline should really be involved in making.

As the silence permeated the room, Jake soon noticed that most were looking up towards him and the platforms to his sides, waiting for them to start it. Something they didn’t get a chance to do, as one of the few factions nearly entirely based on combat spoke first.

"The Court of Shadows proposes we vote for the Singles Tournament," Caleb said.

Many frowned across the hall, but Jake’s brother didn’t give them time to comment before he came with his explanation.

"Properly establishing the power rankings of the strongest on Earth will surely be a valuable thing and will allow the strongest to battle each other in relative safety. From my understanding, as long as you surrender, you won’t die, and the system has a tendency to heal people as they exit trials, so this would allow us all to go all out and best learn from each other. Additionally, the tournaments differentiate themselves by a winner being guaranteed, and hence bountiful rewards being guaranteed. In all other events, we may get unlucky and end up with nearly nothing if we fail to complete enough of the event."

Even more frowns filled the room, and many glances were also thrown towards Jake and the Sword Saint. Everyone knew that either the old man or the masked man would win if a tournament were to begin here and now, and chances were that dynamic wouldn’t change unless either of them began slacking off.

As to why the Court would choose to vote for the singles tournament when they didn’t have the winner on their team?

It was something even Jake could quickly figure out. First of all, Caleb believed Jake would likely win, and secondly, while the Court wouldn’t win, they would probably have a few good placements. Assassins tended to be quite good at one-versus-one fights, after all.

"Would it not be equally valuable to know which city ranks the highest?" a female voice sounded out from the platform with the undead. "We propose the Town Defense event to help cities and experts prove they can truly defend their citizens while at the same time allowing us to work together and form stronger bonds among our fellow Earthlings and alliances. If we fear missing out, would it not be an idea for some of the top settlements to group together? Haven, Sanctdomo, Saya, Midtgaard, Skyggen… If such cities banded together, wouldn’t we surely be able to lay claim to the best the system has to offer by putting our best experts together?"

And thus… another long discussion began.

Chapter 19

World Congress: Challenge

If one called the discussions for those damn materials heated—a vote where herbs truly was the only worthy choice—then the current discussion revolving around the System Event was absolutely blazing.

At least many cities had needed some of the same materials, plus the angle of potential trading. It meant that there had been a strong desire for consensus. However, for this vote, everyone went straight for what played into the strengths and desires of their own city.

The undead wanted Town Defense—or City Defense, really—for several reasons. First of all, Jake had the feeling they were quite good at defensive stuff. Heck, Casper had an insanely defensive class and profession combo, and as the undead had many enemies throughout the multiverse, it made sense they had developed many means when it came to defensive battles.

On top of that, they had the angle of teaming up with other powerful cities. It would give them ten days to prove they were valuable allies and form strong alliances. They were clearly desperate to form at least some strong alliances or even defensive pacts to offer them some protection.

During their chat, Casper had briefly mentioned that sometimes the Risen in new universes got wiped out on the planet quite quickly, as they were seen as undead abominations. Filthy creatures to be purged. Jake thought it was just silly prejudice and bigotry. Being somewhat dead didn’t make one any less of a person.

People tended to fear what they didn’t know, so being put in an environment with them for ten days to work together and get to know each other would allow humanity to become more adapted to their existence. As has been said, the best way to battle bigotry is to actually get to know those you are bigoted against.

So their angle made a lot of sense.

Meanwhile, Midtgaard really advocated for the dungeons. As in, really hard, though they did say they could also support the group tournament. It was pretty damn obvious that their city had many powerful parties, or perhaps the leader was just a selfish guy in a powerful party.

The Sword Saint seemed intrigued at the dungeons, but his faction appeared the most open-minded out of everyone in the top ten. He looked confident in handling anything, which kind of made sense.

He had a powerful faction and was also strong as an individual. No matter what they ended up doing, they would end up on top… which was why their next move made a lot of sense.

"The Noboru clan is open to negotiations for our votes. All four cities’ worth," one of the people on the Sword Saint’s platform said.

It was the guy Jake assumed to be the City Lord, and he also looked related to the old man. Which he one hundred percent assumed they were, since they were from the same clan and all.

The declaration threw the entire hall for quite a loop. The Noboru clan was behind a tenth of the total votes, making their offer quite enticing for everyone. Yet surprisingly enough, the first response wasn’t someone trying to get the votes, but denouncing them.

"To openly sell your votes like that… Have some shame."

It was one of the lower-ranking cities—one Jake couldn’t even remember speaking up before. Actually, there were a few cities that had barely talked, if at all. That Eron guy and his city were one of them, though the two people with him did go around doing stuff during the intermissions.

Jake had to admit that it seemed a bit corrupt—if that was even the right word—to just pretty much put their votes up for sale like that. Then again… who really gave a shit? And weren’t these political discussions pretty much just selling votes and promising stuff for benefits? People just tended to be more subtle about it.

"Oh? What does your clan want in return?" the woman from the undead faction asked, completely ignoring the complaint.

The man from the Noboru clan frowned a bit but responded nevertheless. "Such things are better discussed in a smaller setting. The Noboru clan will abstain from the discussion till an opportunity to talk more closely with the interested factions presents itself."

From there… the entire discussion kind of spiraled, as Jake came to learn that most factions honestly didn’t care about what event was chosen, while those that did care were just very vocal about it. What they did care about were gains they could get from others for their vote.

After an hour of open discussion, people began spreading out. Negotiations became face-to-face and behind closed doors. The first thing Jake did was to go over to Jacob and confirm that the Holy Church did indeed intend to vote for the Treasure Hunt. One could only confirm so much with mouthed words and questioning glances.

"Yeah, we discussed it and agreed on the Treasure Hunt being the best," Jacob explained. “There are several reasons for this, but the primary one is that we feel it fits our strengths the most.”

"We are in agreement, then.” Jake smiled. “How do you feel the chances are to lock it down?”

“Quite good. With our and Haven’s votes and a few of the allies we have already made agreements with, we are close. If we manage to secure the votes of the Noboru clan, I believe it is pretty much secured.”

“Better get moving, then," Jake said as he and Jacob together went towards the Noboru clan.

Miranda had already gone over to one of the other top ten factions who seemed indecisive. Neil hadn’t hesitated to go straight to the other space mages present to keep discussing their teleportation circle network. In retrospect, it had been an excellent move to bring him. Miranda deserved a pat on the back for that one.

When the City Lord of the Noboru clan saw Jake and Jacob approach, he quickly finished up with the one he was currently talking to and engaged them—completely ignoring the undead woman who stood to the side, already waiting her turn. Jake had to admit, her level of patience and tolerance was impeccable. He didn’t even see her react to the blatant disrespect.

She did do something, though. She motioned backward towards Casper to have him come over. Jake saw his old friend wince a bit, but once he saw Jacob and Jake also there, he relented and made his way over.

"Those two may as well come along," Jake said, nodding towards Casper and the undead woman. "Would make negotiations a bit easier just to have everyone present, don’t you agree?"

"Alright…"

The Noboru City Lord clearly disapproved but still allowed them all to go up to the platform. However, he did throw out one comment just as he obscured them from outside view—a comment heard only by the four of them and the Sword Saint who sat inside with his eyes closed.

"I didn’t think the Holy Church usually associates with the undead?"

His words didn’t seem that bad on the surface, but the meaning behind them was clear: He wanted Jacob to denounce them, take his side, and make them leave again. Jacob was ready, however.

"I cannot choose the associates of my friends. If the Progenitor wishes them present, then neither the Holy Church nor I have any right to tell him to make them leave. That we happen to interact through him is simply unavoidable.”

Jake nearly wanted to choke as he heard that explanation. "Oh, no, I am not here with the undead heathen! I am here with my friend who happens to be with an undead heathen, and if I happen to be friendly with the undead heathen, it is just to play nice with my friend!" To Jake, it was total BS, but Jake could empathize with Jacob’s position. He couldn’t openly say that Casper was his friend due to the Holy Church and their stance on the undead… It honestly sucked.

"Who cares?” Jake asked, shaking his head. “We’re all just Earthlings and mortals; why care that someone has another eye color and a bit better death affinity?"

Sure, it was oversimplified, but he really didn’t give a shit. Heck, his best friend was a snake, and his two other good friends were birds. Oh, and his kind-of niece was the cutest baby hawk. Well, soon-to-be teenage hawk.

"Ah, I meant no offense…" the City Lord said, looking a bit embarrassed. Clearly not by his actions, but Jake’s reaction. He was that kind of guy.

On the other hand, the undead woman made a huge smile as she went over and bowed deeply towards Jake. She then extended her hand to shake, being a bit too obvious as he looked straight down her cleavage.

"I am Priscilla, and it is an honor to finally meet the Progenitor and Viper’s Chosen face-to-face," she said, her eyes looking deeply into Jake’s.

No matter how ignorant Jake was at times, even he could pick up the apparent signals and her shameless flirting. Sadly for her, Jake wasn’t interested.

He grabbed her hand and shook it. "Jake Thayne. Nice to meet you too. I heard a lot about you from Casper."

Indeed he had. Casper had spent a lot of his recounting of becoming undead and the rest of his time in the tutorial talking about her. About how insufferable she was and how she had tried to "honeytrap" him all the damn time, even when he already had a girlfriend. She had even flirted just as they went to the World Congress…

"Only good things, I hope," she answered, her smile only growing.

"Sure."

That made her smile fade a bit.

As for why he used his name so openly, despite hiding himself with a mask throughout the entire World Congress… it was because he saw no reason to hide it. In fact, he preferred if people knew who he was.

It was already known that Caleb was his brother, of course, and by extension, it would be easy to figure out who his parents were. With his brother around to defend them, he didn’t fear that they would suffer any harm; he actually believed that the knowledge of not only pissing off the Court of Shadows but him too would serve more as a deterrent.

And as sad as it was to admit, Jake hadn’t really been close to anyone in the pre-system world other than his family and colleagues. He had more friends and comrades now than before. Miranda, Hawkie, Mystie, Sylphie, Villy, et cetera. All were new friends he had made after the system. He also still had Casper and Jacob, whom he considered friends.

All of these had in common that everyone already knew he was close to them and/or could take care of themselves.

However, most importantly… he didn’t really have any cool nickname. Sure, some called him the Hunter or just Hunter, but he didn’t really want to be called that all the time, as a hunter wasn’t as unique as an Augur, Judge, Sword Saint, or other cool names like that. Yes, Jake was a tiny bit jealous.

Well, he was sure he would get a cool one in the future, and he did kind of have Progenitor, but introducing himself as the Progenitor would just be weird. It would be like introducing himself as a Prodigious Arcanist or another of his titles. Also, what if he got a better title in the future? Would he have to switch it up then? Way too much work. Jake Thayne worked just fine.

Anyway, back at the negotiations that Jake had just made damn awkward, Jacob was luckily there to pick up the slack. Casper just snickered at Jake’s response as Priscilla looked scornfully back at her undead comrade… still containing a touch of her coy demeanor. Yep, she is an S-tier gold digger. Or influence digger? Blessed by a Primordial digger?

"Both Jake and Haven as well as the Holy Church are interested in the Treasure Hunt event, and we naturally hope for your support in this endeavor," Jacob said, leaving the other side open to voice their requirements.

"I am sure we can figure something out," the City Lord of Saya said. "I believe the Holy Church has much to offer, information being one such thing."

"I am listening," Jacob replied as they slowly began talking. There was plenty of time, so Jake did some negotiating of his own.

Jake walked over, took a seat on one of the chairs, and looked at the Sword Saint, who had now opened his eyes and regarded him.

"What do you want?" Jake asked curtly.

"What makes you think I want anything in particular?" the Sword Saint asked in return, raising his eyebrows.

"Because people like us always have something we want, and you look just as bored being here as I do."

Jake had observed the old man enough to see his impatience. They were both here for similar reasons too. Jake had come to reconnect with his family and friends and support Miranda, while the Sword Saint had come here to support his clan.

The old man smiled and chuckled a bit. "What are you offering?"

"I’m an alchemist," Jake answered, summoning three bottles: a health, mana, and stamina potion, respectively.

Jake knew from Miranda he couldn’t actually hand them over in here. He had tried to have Casper give him some small thing from his own spatial locket, and Jake had found himself unable to deposit it. Chances were, the system wouldn’t allow anyone to trade any material goods during the World Congress. A bit sad, honestly, as Jake would have loved to give his pals and family some good potions.

The Sword Saint’s eyes sharpened as he looked at the bottles. He picked one up and observed it more closely, even opening another to take a whiff.

"Certainly better than any made by our resident alchemists or pharmacists. However, while I am interested, I am unsure what the point is in offering such things to me personally… I am not the one you have to convince.” This was clearly in reference to the City Lord, who looked wholly absorbed in his discussion with Jacob.

"Are you saying that if you say to vote for something, he won’t listen?" Jake asked. From how the City Lord had constantly looked at the Sword Saint for approval, Jake was quite clear he didn’t have it wrong.

"Even so, my personal wants and those of Saya are two separate entities," he answered, shaking his head.

"How so? Your success and power mean more power to your faction. Your death or stagnation is a loss or could possibly lead to the collapse of your entire clan.” It was becoming clear that they had a bit of a fundamental disagreement about how things were supposed to work.

"You look at it far too simply… To lay everything on this old man is not the way. The Noboru clan is not strong because I am strong. We are strong together. I am merely our sword—nothing less, nothing more.”

"While I admire that mindset… will a dulled sword be enough for you to stand on top when you refuse to invest in bettering yourself?" Jake asked, looking the Sword Saint straight in the eye.

"I guess time shall tell," he answered with another shake of the head.

"Either way… that is another reason I say go for the Treasure Hunt. Dungeons or the Town Defense one will not allow us humans to spar… The tournaments will be structured and annoying, and who is to say the format will even allow those who wish to battle to meet? No, the Treasure Hunt is the only open event where we can all meet. At that time, let’s see who wins…" Jake looked challengingly into the eyes of the Saint. "Me, or the Noboru clan."

With those words, Jake just exited the barrier. Both Jacob and the City Lord watched him leave with puzzlement on their faces. Jake hadn’t gotten to negotiate for anything, but just left… Still, he felt like the Noboru clan would vote for the Treasure Hunt.

The big smile on the old man’s face—and the way he’d shaken his head at Jake’s audacity—were the sources of his confidence. No matter how much he talked about doing everything for the clan… he wanted to know who was strongest just as much as Jake.

Chapter 20

World Congress: Master Negotiator

Okay, Jake did fuck up one thing during—or after, really—the discussion with the Sword Saint. Jake liked walking off after getting the last word in, as he felt it was the easiest way to come out on top of a discussion—and because it halted any future arguments.

This resulted in Jake leaving behind two undead with no one really talking to them, as Jacob and the City Lord were already doing their own thing.

It wasn’t like he could walk back in either—both because the barrier blocked him, but more importantly, because that would be totally uncool. Luckily, Casper didn’t want to be in there either and also walked out… Priscilla followed a few moments later, looking quite conflicted, perhaps wondering if she should have stayed or not. In the end, she seemed to have decided to go with the city that didn’t either openly hate the undead or show bigotry towards them.

When Jake saw them following… well, he decided that he might as well also get them on board. With them, the Treasure Hunt would be damn near ensured. He would also go by Caleb and do as any good big brother would: Use their familial relation to convince him to go with Treasure Hunt by bringing up old memories, like how Jake always allowed Caleb to use the good controller.

Anyway, the undead faction wanted the Town Defense event because it would allow them to form better relations with other factions of Earth. Jake felt like as long as he could alleviate their fear of humanity suddenly banding together to wipe out the evil undead, they would be more open to voting for the Treasure Hunt.

Jake felt pretty sure about his assessment, but it was always good to confirm. He went up to Casper and asked, "You guys want the Town Defense mainly to make humanity less assholish towards the undead, right?" He said it as straightforwardly as he could.

"Yep," Casper answered with a shrug. "Can’t see most of the others doing anything good for our image. Could you imagine if we actually did well in the tournament and got a good reward? The ‘righteous crusade to wipe out the unclean’ would be just around the corner if that happened. It would have nothing to do with just wanting to take our stuff… not at all."

"People like justifying their own shitty behavior—nothing new there," Jake said, shaking his head in his disappointment with the human race.

On a side note, all of this was said outside any of the platforms, allowing anyone interested to listen in.

Priscilla—despite Jake’s cold reception to her earlier—still caught on. She nodded in agreement, her eyes practically shining at the opportunity. "Indeed, we just want to form good relations with everyone and make valuable allies for the future. We carry no animosity towards anyone; we simply are what we are. Most of us didn’t choose to become Risen. I died a few hours before the integration myself, and I was one of the people brought back to life by the system as a Risen along with thousands of others. With anyone who died less than twenty-four hours before the system integration, in fact.

"We Risen are barely different than anyone else… We have classes, professions, families, and friends. Casper here is a rare exception as someone who chose to become a Risen, and the Progenitor knew him beforehand. Has he truly changed?"

Her last words were naturally directed towards Jake.

It was clear she wanted validation, even if some of it was bullshit. Casper hadn’t “chosen” to become a Risen so much as he’d been blackmailed into it with his dead girlfriend’s soul. He also was a bit different than before, though that was primarily due to the constant dark energy that he kept bottled up—no doubt related to his curse magic. Personality-wise, he was pretty much the same, except for those suppressed emotions.

"Yeah, he is still the same downer he always has been," Jake answered, throwing a cheeky smile towards Casper. "Probably still sucks at poker too."

"Fuck you; I’m still convinced you cheated," Casper answered with an accusatory smile.

"I deny all such accusations."

Wait, did I cheat? Considering I always had a muted version of the Bloodline even before the system, it is entirely possible. I did like betting based on intuition more than anything. I should have gone to casinos… Also, sorry, not sorry, Casper.

Priscilla just stood there, smiling as the two talked, clearly elated over Jake doing all the PR work for them. If being a bit nice to them could help his friend in the long run, he was all for it.

"Should we go discuss this more thoroughly behind closed doors?" Priscilla asked.

"Sure," Jake agreed, following them towards the undead faction’s platform.

Actually, it was only now he noticed the name of the city. Jake would have personally thrown money on it being called either Necropolis or The Graveyard or something else cool—or stupid, depending on who you asked—like that.

Instead, he was met with the boring, vanilla name Deepshire. Nothing related to death at all except maybe the deep part—something Jake would later learn actually just referred to how they were geographically placed low and how they had many mines and underground networks.

Before he stepped on the platform, he noticed his brother off to the side, leaving another platform. Jake took the chance to yell, "Hey, Cal, we are having a small meeting—wanna join?"

He was a good big brother like that, always trying to involve his little brother when he did fun stuff. Jake totally didn’t have any ulterior motives… not at all.

Caleb looked his way, threw a quick look at the two people with him, then nodded. "Shouldn’t be an issue."

He went over, and together all four of them stepped up on the platform. From what Jake knew, it was the first time his brother had met Priscilla face-to-face, and he was already looking forward to how his brother would react to her "friendly" behavior.

So when she went to greet him after they all stepped on the platform, he had to hide his childish giddiness a bit.

"Greetings, Judge. It is an honor to meet you," she said, performing a curtsy towards him respectfully. "I apologize for not seeking you out earlier, but I am glad we finally got a chance to speak."

"Likewise, the Court and the Risen tend to do well by each other in the multiverse; let’s not make Earth any different," Caleb said in his own greeting.

Jake stood back, disappointed as hell. He had expected Priscilla to act like she did with him and Casper, only to make a fool of herself when Caleb shot back "I’m married" or something like that, allowing Jake to laugh at the awkwardness of it all.

Yet Priscilla acted perfectly decent, not even trying to be slightly flirty. She just seemed like a competent leader and not a gold digger trying to get into the pants of anyone with strong backing. Was it because his brother wasn’t blessed by a Primordial? No, Umbra was also pretty awesome in her own right, according to Villy… so maybe… just maybe…

She actually was competent. Yeah, she had to know that Caleb was taken, so she didn’t even try any of her shit… Damn, I was looking forward to it.

It was sad that Jake would have to actually do political stuff instead of messing with Cal.

"Cal, you’ll vote with your big bro for the Treasure Hunt, right?" he asked with a big smile.

"No, of course not—we are going with the tournament," Caleb answered, returning the smile with an even bigger one.

Jake acted hurt. "What happened to my obedient little brother, who always did as his awesome older brother asked him?"

"He became the leader of a shadow assassin organization," Caleb said curtly. "My question is why you wouldn’t like a one-versus-one tournament. Not confident you’ll win?”

"It’s not that; I just wouldn’t enjoy slogging through ten days of battles against weaker foes for a handful of good fights… I can find plenty of good fights outside of events," Jake answered, really trying to convince his brother. “The Treasure Hunt, on the other hand, will likely offer unique and cool challenges to get the treasures… and you can do the fun stuff from day one. No need to wait for some stupid tournament brackets or things like that.

"Also, who says shadow assassins aren’t good at hunting treasures? You can sneak around and steal stuff from others or quickly swipe things and run away! I am sure you would all love it too!"

"But shadow assassins are even better at assassinating people," Caleb countered.

Reasonable… however…

"You can also assassinate people during the Treasure Hunt. It will actually be way easier then, as they will be distracted. You can snipe them from long distance unnoticed, emerge from a shadow right as they least expect it, or attack after they just finish fighting a tough foe for a treasure. Then you can both beat them and get the loot. Win-win for everyone but the poor sap who gets robbed and possibly killed."

"While that does sound convincing, people also tend to group up when it is possible, and it tends to be harder to assassinate people surrounded by allies."

"Not if you bring even more assassins. Group assassinations. Sounds like a great teambuilding exercise, doesn’t it?"

"Not as great as the afterparty for when we do great in the tournament.”

"Boring." Jake shook his head before turning to Priscilla and Casper. "You guys support the Treasure Hunt, right? No one likes Town Defense anyway."

"I am not certain what we will choose," Priscilla answered noncommittally. "It depends on what is best for the Risen as a whole… not just a few of our experts."

"If you don’t, I am going out there right now and yelling loudly about how we need a crusade," Jake announced. His mask hid his emotions a bit too well, as Priscilla didn’t pick up on the sarcasm and began to panic.

"Wait! I don’t think that’s necessary. What if w—"

"He’s fucking with you," Casper chimed in with a big grin. "But if you do go for it, can I come with you and toss out some curse magic to really solidify the image that we are evil, life-hating monsters?"

"It would be my pleasure," Jake chuckled. "But in all seriousness, the Holy Church and Haven will both vote for Treasure Hunt, and we are collecting more votes as it is. Pretty sure Jacob will get the Noboru clan vote locked down, and Miranda is working on another of the first ten cities. With you guys, the Treasure Hunt will be pretty much assured."

"So you’re telling us to be on the right side of history?" Caleb asked.

"That, and also… Cal… would Mom and Dad really want to see their children fight?" Jake asked, going full-throttle on the emotional manipulation. "The tournament might force us to battle. What would Mom say?"

"Don’t worry—I swear I will surrender if that ever happens, so that won’t be a problem… I doubt I can win anyway," Caleb said, not taking Jake seriously at all. "But it does sound like we’re screwed. The group we just came from seemed pretty damn disingenuous when they said they would strongly consider the tournament. It might be an idea to voice that we will vote for the Treasure Hunt just to be one of the ‘cool guys,’ I guess."

"Treasure Hunt voters are the cool guys," Jake fully agreed, once more regarding the undead. "The Risen are cool, right?"

"Our body temperatures are indeed lower than you humans," Casper confirmed.

"So, you’re on board?"

"I don’t really care either way, so sure. On one condition: you’re gonna come visit and help me with some stuff. Work-related stuff. Oh, and bring some alchemy stuff along; you must have some cool stuff. I want all the stuff. That sounds fine, right, Priscilla?"

"I’ll also promise to walk out of here smiling and looking happy, like I just had a swell time," Jake added on, looking at the slightly troubled Priscilla. "The Risen are gonna look like the nicest people around."

"You’re wearing a mask; no one can see you smile," Caleb commented, not at all supporting his big brother as a good little brother should.

"Irrelevant." Jake shook his head. "But sure, I’ll come by, though it will be after the Treasure Hunt. I am sure we’re all going to be busy in the next few months grinding out levels. I guess I’ll go on an adventure after the event, so stopping by and seeing the evil stronghold of the undead faction makes sense."

"Alright, we’ll support the Treasure Hunt vote," Priscilla finally relented. "I hope that you will also support us if we run into difficulties in the future."

"Of course. As long as you guys don’t do anything weird, that is. No mass-undeadification rituals—we clear?"

"Alright, we’ll pause the construction when we get back," Casper said, smiling. "Thanks, mate."

Casper surely knew that Jake had only agreed to help them because of him, which was true. Jake didn’t care much about the undead faction—he didn’t care much about factions at all, period. Instead, he cared about people. Casper was a friend, and of course, he would help his friend. He had fucked up in the tutorial… He wasn’t going to repeat that.

"You’re also on board?" Jake asked Caleb, trying to get his brother to confirm the vote for the Treasure Hunt.

"Alright, but I expect a damn nice stack of presents when you come to visit. Oh, and it’s fine to wait till after the event.”

"Of course—I planned on bringing good stuff anyway," Jake happily said. “Also, while we’re here, I can even toss in that I promise not to beat any of you up during the Treasure Hunt. I won’t even rob you!”

"So you would beat me up if I didn’t agree?" Caleb asked, raising an eyebrow.

"Of course. You’ve gotten a bit too cheeky lately. So be happy… you won out big time." Jake gave him a pat on the back to finish off his joking.

"Lucky me."

They sat down and kept talking. Priscilla was a bit hesitant in the beginning but soon joined in. While Jake’s first impression of her wasn’t that good, she seemed like an okay lass once you got to know her.

Miranda sighed as she returned to Haven’s platform. She had spent the last nearly three hours trying to get votes for the Treasure Hunt, but honestly, it wasn’t easy. Many of them wanted unreasonable compensation or promises, some of them even requiring a system-enforced defensive pact just for a damn vote.

She wasn’t even sure if she had secured a single vote… At least, no one willing to sign an agreement. Heck, the majority didn’t even let her know what they wanted to vote for.

Soon, Neil and Lillian joined her on the platform, and she finally saw Jake walk from the platform right next to them—the one belonging to the city Saya. The Augur exited soon after, and from the looks of it, things had gone well.

Jake entered the barrier and smiled. "Oh, hey everyone,” he said casually. “How did things go? I managed to get Caleb and his city as well as the undead on board, and Jacob—with a solid assist from me—also landed the Noboru clan vote, so we should be good.”

This truly made Miranda feel like she had just wasted the last three hours of her life.

Chapter 21

World Congress: Final Talks

The vote for the System Event came and went, all the different factions once more back on their respective platforms. There were a few last-moment speeches, but everyone knew that people had already decided by now on what they wanted, or had made other commitments.

In the end, the vote for the System Event quietly came to an end. Jake just hoped that things would indeed go as he planned. Treasure Hunt, let’s gooo!

The vote for the System Event has concluded!

With 63% of the total votes, the chosen System Event is the Treasure Hunt.

The Event will begin in 3 months (90 days), and all eligible participants will be invited at that time.

Jake read it over and did a mini-cheer inside. Sixty-three percent of the total votes was damn nice. Some people had been stubborn, and he was also fairly confident that some had just abstained. In retrospect, they likely didn’t need one or two of the factions they’d made deals with, but hey, better safe than sorry.

All in all: Treasure Hunt!

With the final vote of the World Congress done, the last message popped up.

The final vote has concluded. The First World Congress will end in: 1:29:59

One and a half hours to go around and talk to people. Jake felt like it was a bit much, but Neil was already gone by the time Jake began pondering what he wanted to do. As he hadn’t really thought about there being much time remaining after the vote, he had already said his farewells to Caleb, Casper, and Jacob, making it super awkward if he waltzed back now to keep chatting.

Just as Jake considered what to do, someone approached him. She was from one of the lower-ranked cities, and Jake hadn’t seen her around at all, really.

She was pretty small with long black hair. Her level was only 51, which made Jake wonder why she was even here. It was entirely possible she was the lowest-leveled person present.

"Excuse me, you are Jake, right?" she asked him. "My name is Kim Eunseo; I would like to ask if you have time to talk a bit privately?"

Jake frowned beneath the mask. The woman looked to be in her mid-thirties and wore an outfit that was not at all fit for adventuring. It looked far closer to business-casual, actually. More importantly, though… she knew his name.

While he hadn’t kept it a secret during the World Congress, it hadn’t been publicized either. She didn’t strike him as some Priscilla-type gold digger, either, so he was honestly confused about what she wanted.

"Do we know each other?" he asked. He couldn’t recall her, but maybe they had met? They might have met pre-system, and he just couldn’t remember.

"No, this is our first meeting. I would explain more, but I think it’s better to do it in a more private setting. It’s related to a mutual acquaintance of ours.”

"Fine," Jake answered.

Hmm, maybe she was related to some god the Viper knew? Maybe even a member of the Order of the Malefic Viper? Or was it related to a mortal friend? It would have to be one not present here, wouldn’t it?

No one was on Haven’s platform, as everyone had already left—Miranda and Lillian were busy trying to do some more political stuff he didn’t care about, and Neil was busy with his space stuff.

They got on the platform, and Jake invited her to take a seat. "So, who is this mutual acquaintance of ours?

"From what I know, there aren’t any positive relations between you, but I would like to ask you some questions related to him and what transpired between you two anyway," Kim Eunseo said. "He has not been able or willing to do so himself."

"Who?" Jake asked… but deep down, he felt a bit of anger churn up as a name sprang to mind.

"William."

Carmen leaned back, tossing the small orb she normally used for dodge-training up and down as she just waited for it all to end. She had tried to go out and help with things, but honestly, she felt like she had just embarrassed herself. But she had tried. She really had. She had gone with Sven or the City Lord she had appointed and tried to play nice, but she’d just felt sick to her stomach while doing it. The fake smiles, the empty promises… Everything just sucked.

She hated being there and thoroughly regretted coming. She felt so out of place it was like going to one of her old family gatherings. It was even similar in that she’d just been brought along to show off. In this case, because she had reached D-grade and not because she was the daughter of her father, so that was at least marginally better. Anyone else could have made a quick alliance with Sven, as that was truly all she had done, so she didn't really have any reason to be there.

Sven looked like a meathead, but he wasn’t stupid at all. Carmen had never considered herself a moron, but she sure as hell wasn’t smart. She had sucked in school, and the only thing she had ever been good at was boxing. Meanwhile, she felt like so many of the other people present weren’t just strong fighters, but also damn smart in their own right.

Spending the last few years in prison had stunted her quite a bit, and she felt like she would never truly fit in with all these "elites." This was the last World Congress she had any intentions of participating in...

The only bright spot was that things had turned out fine, as she liked the idea of a Treasure Hunt, and ores and metals were quite useful for her profession. It did also help that most didn’t dare approach her, as she didn’t look particularly interested in talking with anyone, and her D-grade strength also served as a natural deterrent.

In comparison, the tutorial had been so easy. Even after Carmen returned to Earth, it was easy. She could just spend all her time fighting and doing something she actually felt good at, as opposed to being the incompetent piece of shit she currently felt like.

As she sat there, a person approached. Carmen really didn’t want to talk to anyone, but she nearly felt forced not to turn them away when she saw who it was. She didn’t want to fuck things up more than she already had by turning away the City Lord of Haven.

Why the fuck didn’t I turn on the barrier? she bemoaned as the woman walked up and stood right below the platform.

"Would it be alright if I joined you?" the City Lord asked. Carmen was pretty sure she was called Miranda, and she looked to be around thirty, if even that. Older than herself—that was for sure—but with the system, things got a bit hard to tell.

"Alright," Carmen answered, unsure of what the hell she was supposed to say.

Miranda walked up and took a seat beside Carmen. A few seconds passed before Miranda asked, "Can you make it a bit more private?"

"Alright…" Carmen answered, feeling dumb for not having done it already.

The moment the barrier hummed into effect and the platform was hidden from outside view, Miranda let out a huge sigh and slumped back in the chair.

"I am fucking exhausted," she blurted out. "Days like these are what lead to an early retirement due to stress, I tell you."

Carmen was taken aback, not sure how to respond to the woman. It was like she’d flipped like a coin. Her welcoming and friendly demeanor was utterly gone, and she now just looked… normal.

"Yeah, today sucks," Carmen agreed. She could handle normal.

"I wouldn’t say suck as much as being a bit tedious and annoyingly hard work. Everyone wants something if they feel like every term isn’t one hundred percent to their advantage, and even then, most of the time, they only think they’re superior because they’re idiots.”

"What makes you any different?" Carmen asked, feeling a bit more comfortable. Her own hate and annoyance of fake morons overtook her self-doubt.

"Oh, nothing really. I am sure I am equally exhausting to deal with. It’s our job to try and take a mile when given an inch. That’s why I was appointed City Lord. Well, that, and because the one who claimed the Pylon seriously didn’t want to do the job. I just like telling myself it was due to how competent I was and not because I got lucky.”

Carmen studied the woman, unsure what she wanted. Why had she come here? She battled a bit internally but decided just to ask… she appeared to have been honest so far.

"Why did you want to talk to me?" Carmen asked, honestly not sure if she should expect a genuine answer or not.

Carmen wasn’t stupid enough to think it was because the woman was just nice and friendly. She had seen her negotiate. Miranda always wanted something; she always did things because she thought it would benefit her or her city… because that was her job. And while Carmen respected that, she didn’t have to respect the underhanded ways people went about things.

"Because you’re the highest-ranked member of a faction related to a Primordial on Earth," Miranda answered with a small shrug. "A lot of people seem to think you work for Sven due to the difference in nobility rank and such, but I happen to have a more reliable source of information than most."

"So you do want something from me," Carmen shot back, somewhat disappointed.

She should have known… that damn blessing would only cause issues in the long run. She had only said yes to it for the stats and the skill, not because she actually wanted to go around playing priest—or worse, politician.

"Sure, I want to form a good relationship, so if we ever have a disagreement, it doesn’t instantly result in a fight to the death. I don’t see someone so highly regarded by Gudrun as being weak in any way, and based on the Progenitor’s assessment, you are one of the strongest here by a good margin.”

"Sounds like you want an awfully lot of nothing," Carmen answered, sharpening her gaze.

How the hell did she know who had blessed her? Was she also blessed by some god? Well, it made sense; Gudrun had said that many of the powerful people on Earth would be blessed, and had even warned her about the Progenitor being blessed by some giant snake god.

Was this Miranda also blessed by that snake?

"I didn’t come wanting anything today; I just hope to lay the foundation for the future," Miranda said, smiling. "I like to at least introduce myself to the important people of Earth."

Carmen scoffed. Right…

"Should stop wasting your time, then, and go talk to Sven," she said while shaking her head.

"Don’t underestimate yourself… How much do you know about Gudrun and Valhal in general?" Miranda asked.

It was a bit… embarrassing, but Carmen honestly didn’t know much. She had only ever met Gudrun, and she had seemed nice enough. Gudrun felt very motherly and had kept making comments that Carmen was just like her husband in many ways. She had even taught Carmen some stuff, but not much related to Valhal itself. Just some general stuff. Much of that Carmen had found out herself, but to be fair, the information had been scarce.

“Not as much as you, it seems,” Carmen once again scoffed, but inwardly she did want to know. She hated how everyone seemed to know more than her about everything. Sven was far more knowledgeable regarding everything Valhal-related, and Carmen was too damn proud and embarrassed to admit that in front of him.

"Valhal is a weird place, mainly created due to the admiration many felt towards the Primordial Valdemar" Miranda began. “Eventually, it turned into a powerful organization with a vast number of experts, both among mortals and gods alike… but things never really got started before she came.

"There was no rhyme or reason behind blessings given, no attempt to bring together those who technically belonged to Valhal, and nothing but a loose code of honor uniting them. Valdemar had no desire to fix any of this because, quite frankly, he never cared for any of it. He had his brothers in arms and rarely thought of anyone not in his immediate surroundings.

"Gudrun was one of those comrades in arms he got during the Second Era—a powerful god in her own right, but also one with ambition and guile. She also managed to do something no other warrior had done before: conquer the heart of Valdemar. They became bonded, and now she is effectively his wife and has been ever since… And in actuality, she is the true leader of Valhal. On paper and in spirit, it was still, and always will be Valdemar simply due to his utterly insane amount of power, but what he had in brawns, Gudrun had in brains.

"And if there is one thing I am one hundred percent confident Gudrun is good at, it's recognizing talent. So don’t put yourself down… If there is anyone great warriors of the multiverse wish to be recognized by, it’s her."

Carmen looked a bit oddly at Miranda, not sure what to say. Gudrun hadn’t talked much about herself… not at all… and if Carmen reminded her of her husband…

"So when she said I am like her husband, she called me simple-minded…" Carmen said self-deprecatingly.

"Valdemar isn’t known for being simple-minded,” Miranda said with a smile. “He is known for his strength. He didn’t need anything but his axe to sit where he is today, and what he couldn’t do himself, he had the foresight to find qualified people to handle for him. His innate charisma and drive were enough to attract them. He is a genius, no way about it. Knowing that Gudrun compared you to him… It only makes me happier I came to meet you today.”

Once more, Carmen was unsure what to say. Miranda didn’t look like she had anything more to add either, but she just sat there in silence with her. She looked like she actually enjoyed the quiet break away from all the discussions… Carmen could relate to that.

Like that, the minutes just ticked by until the timer finally was about to expire.

Miranda got up and stretched, cracking her neck and even doing a small yawn. "Gotta head back now. Nice meeting you."

"Same," Carmen answered without even thinking.

Miranda just smiled in return as she left.

She seems nice enough, Carmen thought as she saw her walk out.

Miranda made her way back towards Haven’s platform, as there were only a few minutes left and she wanted to check in with everyone just before it all ended. While walking over, she saw a woman exit the barrier, making her frown.

A frown that only deepened when she actually made her way inside and saw that it had just been her and Jake. She hadn’t seen Jake around at all… Did that mean he had just spent nearly one and a half hours with that woman? Moreover… he had a weird look on his face.

He was both frowning and looking puzzled, as if deep in thought. Miranda couldn’t help but ask, "Who was that?"

"A psychiatrist," Jake answered, shaking his head. "One whose patient I’ve already killed once during the tutorial and, among other things, she asked me not to kill on sight on our next meeting."

"Sounds like there is a story there I haven’t heard," Miranda said, smiling.

He had talked a lot about fights in the tutorial, sure. He had mentioned how some psycho had killed most of the survivors and then… wait. Was it him?

"Will you do as she asked?" Miranda said.

"Maybe… If what she said is true… maybe. She wanted to learn about him more than anything… What had happened between us," Jake said, looking a bit conflicted before turning to her with the same puzzlement. "Apparently, I gave him some kind of PTSD?"

Shortly after that, Lillian returned and barely had time to throw them both a nod before the final message of the World Congress came. Neil never came back, but instead stayed to discuss teleportation with other space mages till the very last second.

The First World Congress has concluded. The Second World Congress will commence in 1 year (365 days).

Chapter 22

Shopping Spree

The World Congress had only lasted about ten hours total, but had without a doubt been a defining moment for the enlightened races of Earth. Most of the powerhouses of the planet had met, and alliances, truces, trade agreements, defensive pacts, or just generally friendly relations had been established between many factions.

To distinguish a "winner," if one may, would be difficult. While Jake and Haven had gotten all the voting results they wanted and managed to secure both herbs and the Treasure Hunt event, that didn’t mean they had somehow won out over everyone else. They were far from the only ones, as it wasn’t like the Treasure Hunt was unpopular, and ores and metals had been the first option voted in, along with the foodstuffs one.

The only way to truly say there had been a winner was if a World Leader had been selected, but such an option was far off. Perhaps it would happen in a year, or perhaps later than that. Many theorized ways the system would one day enforce that one had to be selected, but that day hadn’t arrived yet.

In the end, it could be said that all of humanity had won out. No wars or conflicts were started, as the World Congress had in general been a pleasant event that only led to a stronger bond between the enlightened races, and everyone came out on top—even the undead who had feared for the worst.

Jake, Lillian, Miranda, and Neil appeared back at the good old lodge inside Jake’s valley. They had only been gone for ten hours, but all of them—besides Neil, who actually seemed quite energetic—were exhausted.

It took a lot out of you to always be on your toes, and even if Jake hadn’t been under as much pressure as Lillian and Miranda when it came to discussions, he was still tired. Jake tended to find social interactions, even those he enjoyed, exhausting in the long run. But the most exhausting thing had been the talk with that Kim Eunseo woman—or Kimmie, as she’d told him to call her.

She had told him quite a bit about what she and William had been up to, and while Jake had let her talk and he had listened, he honestly didn’t care very much about that metal mage anymore. Jake didn’t truly know him, as he had only spent a few moments with the guy. He knew the metal mage more as an idea or a concept than a person.

To Jake, he was a representation of his own failures during the tutorial. Nothing less and nothing more. He had been a living reminder that Jake had fucked up and not even tried to help people he honestly did care about—no matter how much he sucked at showing it. In that sense, Jake wouldn’t say he hated William; he hated what he represented. The only real feeling he felt towards him was apathy.

This ultimately led to the question: Would Jake kill him the next time they met? He couldn’t answer that. He did feel a strange mix of puzzlement, doubt, and even humor in how William had apparently been traumatized by Jake smashing him into the ground. But if he would kill him… time would tell.

If Jake were honest, he would prefer to simply never meet the guy again. The psychiatrist had talked about how he was "improving" and moving towards forgiveness, if that was at all possible, but Jake really didn’t feel like he had anything to forgive him for. If anyone truly had a bone to pick with William, it wasn’t Jake… it was Casper, and even more so than that, his girlfriend. William had either been the direct or indirect cause of her death. Jake wasn’t sure which, and he hadn’t been insensitive enough to ask for details.

And one thing was for sure… If Casper decided that little shit needed to be squashed, Jake sure as hell wouldn’t interfere.

"So… what’s the plan now?" Jake asked, shaking his head to clear some of those annoying thoughts.

What was important now was preparing for the Treasure Hunt, and nothing else.

Both Miranda and Lillian, who stood there like they were in a daze, just looked at him weirdly. Then Miranda suggested, "Check out the System Store?"

"Oh, shit," Jake exclaimed. He swiftly opened it, and a store opened up before him.

Limited System Store

Categories:

Ore & Metal

Herbs

Jake didn’t need to go any further than that. He opened up the Herbs category and instantly felt a bit… disappointed. He had a lot of Credits just burning in his metaphysical pocket. A lot.

Credits available: 133,972,000

Jake had even spent a good 700,000 on things. Mainly all the weapons he had destroyed, his order of the mushroom-killing poison devices, and a lot of other minor matters he wanted to be done. He was also fully aware that he had overpaid for pretty much everything—at least, he thought so. He had given Miranda 500,000 to buy weapons with, and she had mentioned he still had some money with the city…

Anyway, all of this was to say that Jake was loaded, and he knew he was loaded and wanted to instantly buy out all the best stuff. Yet the best he could find was a scarce few uncommon-rarity herbs, and the rest were common or inferior rarity.

Well, it wasn’t all bad, and Jake instantly jumped in and checked what the store had in stock. Before that, though, he quickly skimmed some rules.

The System Store only accepts Credits.

The System Store restocks every 3 days.

Items put up for sale must have a list price and can be bought by anyone with access to the store.

Items bought will appear in your immediate surroundings. (If you have spatial storage, it will appear within there).

Items sold directly to the System Store are appraised, and you will be paid immediately based on their estimated worth (determined dynamically, with the current development of Earth taken into account). These items will not become available to others with access to the store.

There were a few other notes, but these were the important ones. The restock thing especially was a relief to Jake due to what he planned on doing next.

Without any hesitation, Jake went into the store and bought half of the common-rarity Red Lavender, Blue Lavender, and Green Lavender. Each portion of lavender only had a cost of 250 Credits, with the inferior-rarity version costing 25. Jake left the inferior-rarity versions alone, as he quite frankly didn’t need them. However, he did see that the inferior-rarity lavender was disappearing rapidly, likely being bought up by all the different cities.

Luckily for them, the system had clearly taken this into account, and there was a near-infinite supply of inferior-rarity lavender. As for the common-rarity stuff, not so much.

Once he bought it—nearly a thousand plants of each version, making him spend nearly a million Credits right away—he felt it instantly appear within his spatial storage, neatly packed in bundles. 10/10 delivery service. He also quickly bought some Evergreen grass to go with the lavender, immediately gaining enough materials for several thousand potion batches.

Jake didn’t hesitate as he dove in and began buying up some more stuff, such as all the Bluebright Mushrooms—which were only about 70 total—and more than half of the uncommon-rarity toxins available. That was more than a million Credits down the drain again. He didn’t really sweat it, though, because he quickly tried to do something else fun.

He took out a potion and willed the system to offer to purchase it.

Would you like to sell [Health Potion (Common)] for 6412 Credits?

Well, ain’t that a deal? Jake smiled. It was one of his newest potions, and it was quite potent for sure… but damn, that was some good value. One had to remember that every brewing didn’t result in a single potion but a batch of potions, and at this point, Jake could easily have several potions in every batch.

This meant that Jake could effectively amplify the value of the ingredients by turning them into a potion by about a hundredfold. The only limitation was his own time and boredom. Of course, he had a strong feeling the price would decrease the more he sold—a feeling he tested out.

He had five potions from the same batch, restoring the same amount of health each. He sold the first one and saw it disappear from his hand. He quickly did the same two more times and noticed the price reduce slightly—a change that only intensified each time he sold a potion.

Would you like to sell [Health Potion (Common)] for 6331 Credits?

The last one, he would get around 80 less for.

Finally, he took one of the potions and put it up for sale so other cities could buy it. He decided to start high and put it at 15,000 Credits, more than double what the system offered. He didn’t actually think anyone would buy it right away, bu—

Your [Health Potion (Common)] has been sold.

Okay, people really like potions, Jake thought, shaking his head in mild disbelief. 15,000 Credits was a lot to normal people… but then again, a potion restoring nearly your entire health pool was close to a second life. Jake sure as hell wouldn’t be where he was today without chugging down what he now realized were millions of Credits’ worth of potions.

"Would it be fine if I just offloaded a shitload of potions?" Jake asked Miranda, who also stood in a trance going through the store.

"Sure," she answered as a weird nugget of metal appeared beside her. "It’s your Credits." Another weird piece of metal popped into existence, followed by what looked like an old root soon after, and finally another small chunk of ore.

Jake took that approval and rolled with it, putting up all the potions he’d made to prepare for the fight against the Prima as well as most of his old, common-rarity ones. He had already given out the inferior-rarity ones, so he now put up ninety-nine percent of the potions he had left.

Which only left one issue… bottles… Jake was nearly out of—

Just as the thoughts appeared, so did the bottles. Hundreds, no, thousands of small potion and poison bottles appeared on the ground just beside Lillian, who stood there with her neutral expression.

"I made a deal to have a supply of bottles sold right after returning at a reduced price, and I was waiting to snipe the postings," she explained, a small smile creeping onto her lips. "You did mention how you needed bottles, and I assume that need is now bigger than ever."

"Lillian, you are a goddamn hero!" Jake said, giving her a huge thumbs-up.

She looked a bit embarrassed, making Jake happy he hadn’t jumped to his first choice, which was to give her a big bear hug. Jake was feeling damn good, practically shoveling in crafting material, and even getting a bunch of uncommon ingredients for some poison he had researched.

On a side note, most often you didn’t actually need a specific kind of herb for a recipe; you just needed something that fit the criteria. The lavender archetypes, as an example, were just one kind of herb that innately stored energy especially suited to the resource potions, and they were incredibly easy to grow and numerous—hence, they tended to be the go-to. They were such good herbs because they truly only did that one thing.

So, Jake had needed some more strong poison with powerful necrotic energy to begin making some uncommon-rarity poison in earnest. The super-fungicide had used up far more valuable ingredients than it should have, and it wasn’t something he could mass-produce—far from it.

Apropos the mushroom, Jake also picked up some herbs he hoped to combine with the Lifevines. Maybe even the Lifecore he still had absorbed with Palate of the Malefic Viper, which was actually the source behind knowing what he needed. At least he had a solid general sense of what could be good to combo it with.

Finally, Jake tried to look for something he could mix with the weird time-bananas from his time tree. Because one had to remember that Jake now had a time tree. Well, not a tree, but Jake called it a tree anyway.

However, it turned out that finding compatible herbs for time bananas wasn’t that easy. Who would have thought? Apparently, time bananas that permanently increased Agility weren’t that common… In fact, one could even call them rare… rarity.

Bad jokes aside, Jake spent the next hour or so shopping. All the potions he put up for sale were sold within the first fifteen minutes, making Jake realize he had likely undercharged significantly. But wouldn’t it be kind of an asshole move to overcharge people for what was essentially emergency care? Yeah, overcharging people for stuff like that was some solid asshole behavior.

All of them actually just stood there, likely looking absolutely moronic from an outsider’s point of view. The only thing really happening was items appearing on the ground around Miranda and Lillian once in a while. For Neil and Jake, it just appeared in their spatial storages.

Jake even ended up picking up a few things from the foodstuffs store. They were mostly things he just wanted to experiment with, as they contained types of energies he thought beneficial during a brew. It could totally end up being a dead-end, but who knew?

"So, any interesting news?" a voice echoed in Jake’s head. He smiled as he felt the connection’s full return. Well, it had been intact ever since he left the Congress, but Villy had been nice enough to give him some time to look at menus.

"I’ll tell ya in a bit when the others leave—deal? I wanna ask you some stuff too," Jake answered. He could have spoken the words out loud, but that would’ve just been weird, as he was surrounded by other people.

"Lillian, we should head back to the office and call a meeting with the council to discuss these new developments," Miranda finally said.

"I’ll tag along; I need to get back with my party,” Neil said. “We got some work to do in the next three months to make sure we’re all ready for the Treasure Hunt and won’t embarrass Haven.”

"Right, that will certainly be one of the points of discussion. Identify how many citizens we have that are able to reach D-grade in time, and support them in doing so." Miranda turned to Jake. "You wanna come along?"

She looked like she already knew the answer and had only asked to be polite. And, well, she did know the answer.

"Nah, I got some stuff to handle," Jake said dismissively.

He had just spent ten hours in a Congress surrounded by hundreds of people. No fucking way he was going to another meeting. Besides, he had to wait for the hawks to get back. They tended to spend a lot of time hunting these days, with even Sylphie tagging along.

"Alright, take care. I’ll come by and inform you later." Miranda capped this off with a nod, quickly adding, “Tomorrow, that is."

Giving an affirming nod, Jake watched them all walk out of the valley, leaving him alone as the area’s sole occupant. Alone with himself, his thoughts, and an impatient god he had put on hold.

Chapter 23

A Question of Morality

Jake sat on the steps leading up to his lodge, looking at the weird banana time tree as he spoke with Villy.

His theory that gods truly had no idea what happened inside the World Congress turned out to be accurate. The system simply didn’t allow them to peek or communicate with their blessed ones in any way during the Congress, and the only way for them to find out afterward was to be told. That, or use some serious mental magic on the person, but gods couldn’t do that currently due to the other set of system limitations on the entire 93rd Universe.

"A Treasure Hunt… A bit unoriginal, but not bad," Villy chimed in, genuinely interested in all of the system stuff going around related to the integration. “It’s honestly hard to say what would be best due to the lack of information. There is no way of knowing what kinds of treasures will appear, so it could end up just being piles of junk. I doubt it, but it could happen. Personally, I would have gone for dungeons due to the two Challenge Dungeons and the fact that they tend to be safe bets. On a side note, if you ever find one, do it. They are all done alone and often come with some sweet rewards, and you could’ve likely done both within the allotted time.”

"True," Jake said, seeing no reason not to speak out loud. It was easier than sending it mentally. "But a Treasure Hunt can also be great, and it also feels more… new. Exciting. It will also allow me to finally butt heads with some of the other humans of Earth."

"As I said, it isn’t a bad choice, and honestly, it would be impossible to determine what the best one would be. I am actually prone to trusting your gut over anything else right now, including my own empty guesses.”

"Huh? Why?" Jake asked, a bit confused.

"The system restricted everything about these events. That includes all skills or other types of divination, intuition skills, soothsaying—all of that stuff didn’t do jack shit to give hints. But your Bloodline isn’t bound by any such rules."

"I reckon if the system blocks even gods, it would also block me. Sure, it’s strong as fuck, but—"

"No buts. It isn’t a question of strength either, but one of rules and absolutes. A Bloodline operates on a different spectrum than skills or regular magic. It ignores all rules and acts as it is meant to act in all circumstances. You have a spherical perception ability of sorts, right?" Jake quickly confirmed with a nod. "Well, that’s an absolute. AKA, it doesn’t give a flying fuck about anything. A god could use their strongest stealth skill, and you would be able to see them like nothing was obscuring you. Of course, it isn’t perfect, and there are always ways to still mess you up. In the end, the Bloodline still relies on you, so don’t get complacent, but do realize exactly how powerful a tool it is."

Jake sat a while in contemplation. It was true he could see through those barriers during the World Congress, though he had tried to avoid doing so, so as to not be a peeping tom. He also did remember how he could see "outside" the dungeons he was in, basically just seeing large black voids beyond the walls. Villy had also mentioned something similar before. He was pretty sure it was something about how only two things operated outside the system.

"I get it… So my gut feeling originating from my Bloodline is better than nothing… This is related to when you talked about Bloodlines operating outside the system, right? You mentioned two things do that… What is the second thing?"

"Something you’ll learn about in the future. It isn’t anything relevant to you yet, and you’ll know the moment you encounter it. Just know that the difference between these two things is that while a Bloodline is something bound to your being and comes from your Origin… the other thing is claimed. Surrendered to you by the system. What they do have in common is that neither is inherently about strength or power."

"Alright," Jake answered. He was fine with figuring stuff out himself. Now, as for what Jake himself wanted to talk about… "So… Villy… I need some advice. I told you about the news related to that metal caster William who fucked up my tutorial, and I am just wondering… what would you suggest?"

"Hm, depends on what you want to do. If you want to kill the guy, go ahead, but if you want to leave him be, I doubt he will cause you much trouble. As I told you before, Eversmile likely doesn’t give a fuck either way.”

That wasn’t really what Jake wanted to know. "No... I mean… should I kill him the next time we meet? Would that be the right thing to do? Morally, that is. The dude has done some seriously fucked-up stuff, but… honestly… it isn’t that bad in the grand scheme of things, is it? Sure, he is bad, but compared to that Donald fellow or some of the other fucked-up people I have heard about, he doesn’t seem as evil. Also, it feels a bit weird for me to act like some arbiter of justice," Jake said, shaking his head.

"I am not the best to receive moral advice from, as most would classify me as evil. And I wouldn’t disagree either. Honestly, if you look at how many humans he has killed, you have done far worse than him since returning to Earth. He hasn’t even killed in the double digits, while you have. You have also slain even more intelligent beasts than him. In the eyes of humanity, he might be evil, but in the eyes of the multiverse, no one cares.”

"Not to get into a too-in-depth moral discussion, but doesn’t it also have something to do with intent and cause?" Jake asked.

"Sure, one can say it does. So let me ask you, why did you go and hunt down all those shit-flinging monkeys right after you evolved to D-grade?"

"Well, to test myself, get some levels, explore the forest, et cetera. I wanted a bit more progress before the World Congress, and I was curious what was out there.”

"And the reason why William did as he did during the tutorial was that he thought that was the best thing to do for himself. He thought it would give him a higher final reward if he were the only survivor, so he tried to make that happen.”

Jake had heard it all before from both Villy and his two buddies during the World Congress, so it wasn’t anything new, and he knew where the Viper was going with it, but he disagreed.

"But the difference is that he took pleasure and enjoyment in doing what he did," Jake shot back. “He enjoyed killing people and causing all that mayhem.”

"Because you hated every second of hunting down monkeys, didn’t you? You both enjoy it, albeit for different reasons. William had, and likely still has, a fragile ego and psyche; he was stunted developmentally in every way and acted like a stupid teenager with too much power, so he began believing himself the chosen one, not knowing he was actually facing a Chosen. To him, there was no greater feeling than having power over others when he himself had felt so powerless his entire life. Eversmile was continually cultivating this mindset till the day you punted him into the ground. My actions back then should make it clear I hold no love for the little fuck, but that had nothing to do with me believing he is the bad guy or something. I thought you would enjoy putting him down."

"So, you’re doing the whole ‘you aren’t so different’ speech?" Jake shook his head. "Also, you make him sound like the victim here."

"Oh, no, not at all—the dude deserved getting his head smashed in. Also, I like you way better. I am just saying that trying to judge William by some grand moral doctrine is bullshit, as everyone is evil in the eyes of someone else. I personally don’t like him because he is weak-minded and so easily manipulated. I don’t like him because he messed with you, and I don’t like him because I like fucking with Eversmile. I don’t like him selfishly. So what I am saying is… if you want to kill him, do it because you want to, not because you feel obligated to. In the end, we’re all monsters leaving mountains of corpses in our wake, so trying to judge who has the least bad corpse-mountain is just moronic in my opinion."

"I know you’re partly playing devil’s advocate and stuff, but you do have a point… I guess we all suck now. Mystie, Hawkie, and Sylphie are as much people to me as any human… and you’re technically a snake. So I guess by monkey-law, I am now a wanted war criminal?"

He asked it with some humor, but in all honesty, Jake just felt a bit… off about his entire mindset regarding things like revenge and bearing grudges. When he looked deep inside himself, he didn’t have anyone he really hated. Even those who had betrayed him in the past all seemed so meaningless now. Unless they posed an active threat, he didn’t see any need to hunt them down or do anything.

Yet, he was still not sure if he wanted to kill William. A part of him did, just to "finish the job," and another part of him thought, "Is he even worth thinking about?"

That isn’t to say Jake wouldn’t kill people he judged deserved it. If people like Donald waltzed in, Jake would happily put them down. But that was solely because Jake selfishly hated them, not because he was trying to be some hero. Meanwhile, William was just… sad.

I’ll just leave the judgment entirely up to Casper. Jacob clearly doesn’t care about it and even seems to think what he did was "fine," as it was just him following his path or whatever, but Casper has every right to finish the job. As for the question of whether Jake would help Casper track down and kill William? Of course he would—that’s what friends are for.

"If the monkey empire had a court, you would surely be put on trial," Villy replied to Jake’s bad joke, which he’d made primarily to lighten the mood. Villy instantly caught on with his godlike ability to read social cues.

“Anyway, thanks as always for the talk, Villy,” Jake said with a smile. “You can always ping me if there is something.”

"Sure thing. Work hard, and win that Treasure Hunt. I don’t care if it isn’t winnable, win it anyway." Villy chuckled, then Jake felt the presence of the snake god fade away, and he was once more alone in the valley.

He took a deep breath and stood as he stretched a bit. He had ninety days, or three months, till the Treasure Hunt, and he would spend all that time preparing. During these three months, he had a number of goals.

Firstly, he wanted to make a supply of uncommon-rarity poison. He knew it wasn’t easy and that it would take a while to craft it reliably, but he felt confident.

Secondly, he also wanted to make an uncommon-rarity beneficial consumable. He wasn’t sure if it would be a potion, as, quite frankly, it would be impossible for him to make mana, health, or stamina potions of uncommon rarity any time soon.

Due to the way rarity worked for the resource potions, the only way to increase the rarity was to increase the potency. There was only depth and no width to expand upon. The fungicide was uncommon due to the sheer complexity of how it worked, not necessarily how effective it was. Which is to say, if Jake wanted to make an uncommon-rarity potion, it would have to do more than just restore a resource. An uncommon-rarity health potion would restore several times his health pool anyway, so it would be kind of useless.

One way to do this was to make a rejuvenation potion that restored all three resources, though even that would likely not be possible. He could also try his hand at making regeneration potions that boosted passive regeneration for a time, or something like that. However, another option was to just make something entirely else… like flasks.

Flasks were something Jake had kind of neglected, but that didn’t mean they weren’t great. Flasks could give temporary bonuses, such as stat increases, heightened concentration, or even some more exotic effects, like making a good portion of your mana into a certain affinity for a time. They were temporarily boosting items and functioned a lot like his Limit Break, and like Limit Break, they would lead to a period of weakness or other side effects when they expired.

As for elixirs… he would put that off for now. Three months just wasn’t enough time to do everything.

Third, Jake wanted to check out the dungeon, maybe even clear it. He did want to spend most of this period on his profession due to the System Store, but that didn’t mean he would entirely neglect his class. Jake also seriously doubted he could make himself sit still for that long. At the very least, he wanted his level 120 skill selection.

Fourth, and perhaps the most important of them all, he wanted to cuddle the cute bird currently making a beeline for him.

"Reee!" Sylphie screeched as she descended towards him excitedly. It hadn’t been that long, but she was always excited, and Jake had absolutely no complaints about that.

"Had a good hunt?" he asked, Sylphie happily landing on his shoulder and rubbing her head against the side of his head. He raised his hand and scratched her, taking that as a yes.

Sylphie was really beginning to look a lot more like a real adult hawk, but she was still somewhat small, and all her feathers weren’t out yet.

[Syplhian Eyas – lvl 41]

She was growing up fast, and her level was already beginning to get quite impressive. She was leveling a lot faster these days, and when Jake saw her parents also enter the valley, he realized she wasn’t the only one.

[Stormsong Hawk – lvl 109]

[Mystsong Hawk – lvl 116]

The two of them had grown many levels since he evolved too. He remembered them being 102 and 111 respectively when he evolved his class, and he was pretty sure he was at least partly responsible for their leveling frenzy. He had kind of owned them both in their little fight.

As for Sylphie, she seemed to be going through a growth spurt too. Maybe it was because she was now actively practicing more and even hunting, and based on Jake’s assessment, she could easily beat beasts quite a few levels above herself. Her wind magic was both weird and powerful, easily shredding most anything it touched.

After rubbing the bird a bit more, he finally got to work by summoning his cauldron. He had a lot of stuff to do, but his first task would be to get grooving—which meant mass-producing potions and selling them for ridiculous prices.

Hence, with great vigor, he began yet another alchemy grind.

Intermission 8 - William (1/3)

Kim Eunseo. Commonly just called Kim or Kimmie by her friends. To him, however, she was Ms. Kim.

In his life, William had only ever suffered defeat at the hands of three people. Himself, due to his own ignorance; Ms. Kim, who was the only psychologist to ever truly figure him out; and… that guy.

Anyway, this was why she was the first one he’d wanted to find upon his return to Earth. A return that had gone as one expected.

His new “master” sent him off from whatever void he had been trapped in for the last few months. Yes, months, because the fucker had bent time or some shit. He had been forced to practice every hour of every day, only relaxing whenever he fell asleep from exhaustion.

At first, he’d wanted to kill the old man, but he began to see his gains in time. When he was offered a new weapon and help with his other pieces of equipment, he began to really see his gains.

The final thing he requested before leaving was directions. Directions to find his target. And his “master” obliged, smiling creepily like always.

When he returned, all was as expected. He found himself within the now ruined mental hospital where he’d entered the tutorial—at the entrance area, surrounded by other patients and personel.

The old him would have slaughtered the lot of them… He held a lot of hate for a good number of them, and he even saw that shitty nurse who forced him to take his medication. Sadly… he had been told to consider if the killing was worth it, and honestly… they were all too weak. They wouldn’t even give any experience or tutorial points anymore, so it was all a bit pointless.

Oh, but he still took out his new weapon.

Less than a minute later, he walked out of the hospital, juggling the severed head of some weird-looking monster that had been trying to sneak up on them.

“Damn, does it feel good to be back," he said to the bloody head in his hand.

"Now, where were you again?" he said as he closed his eyes. A mental image of the city appeared in his mind, including the location of his target. His goal was in a house in the suburbs leading into the city.

Manipulating the breastplate he had gotten from his first friend Herrmann, he lifted himself off the ground and took flight. He ignored distractions on the way, as he didn’t want to risk his target slipping away or falling prey to any unfortunate incident.

Luckily, she lived close to the hospital. In quite a nice neighborhood well above the middle class. Big houses, big lawns, and driveways that once, without a doubt, had had big cars in them. Now they were all vacant, and many of the homes broken messes.

The house he was interested in, number 76, was rather whole, actually. Sure, the windows were all broken, and the entire first floor was gone, but besides that, it looked fine.

He couldn’t help smiling when he heard noises within. But soon, he frowned as he detected several loud ones.

Walking in, he made his way towards the noise in the basement. He could hear them very clearly now.

"I know you have one; just give it to us already, you stupid bitch," one voice said.

"I already told you it is gone! Like the cars… please just leave us be!" a familiar female voice pleaded.

"Don’t fucking lie—I know you have it," the first voice said again.

William didn’t even need to get closer; he could easily feel it already. Why had his master made these morons come here? His touch upon them was so obvious…

"Then give us something else," a second male voice said.

William was now just standing right above him, peering down into the floorboards.

"I don’t have anything! Please, there is no reason for this, we—"

"This is a waste of time," a third voice said. "Just stop the damn foreplay and fuck her already so we can move on."

"Fine," the second man said. "Always in such a rush."

"What are you—"

"Shut the fuck up. Ya know, I always had a thing for you, so if you play along real nice, I promise to let you and the kid go. After we've had some fun." William heard the man chuckle. He was still standing, unmoving, right above them.

"I… please, don—" the woman cried.

"I told you to shut up! One more word and the kid’s first!"

"Hurry up, but do that sick shit somewhere else. We need to leave so—"

"Got room for one more?" the three men heard a voice above them say, footsteps now clearly audible as someone walked down the stairs.

William saw the situation was quite as he had foreseen.

In the corner was a small woman in her early thirties. Her shirt had been partly ripped by a large, burly man standing over her. In William’s opinion, he had always rated her objectively good-looking. Large eyes, long black hair, and a good bone structure.

What he didn’t expect, however, was the smaller version of her lying unconscious on the ground. She didn’t look any older than five or six. For some reason, the sight of her—coupled with the words of the men earlier—made him a bit mad, but he quickly suppressed it and spoke with a huge smile.

"Wow, Ms. Kim, I didn’t know you had a daughter," William commented as he looked the men in the eye, all of them sizing him up.

Kim, on the other hand, looked at him with terror. He wasn’t sure if it was directed at him or her current situation.

"Who the fu—"

"Now, now, gentlemen," William said, putting his hands up in front of his chest. "Is this the way to treat a lady?"

"What do you want?" the third man said—the only one not currently standing over someone threateningly. He wore a clearly upgraded medium warrior set, and, looking at his level, he was likely the leader here.

[Human – lvl 29]

None of the others were even above 25. While William, on the other hand…

Status

Name: William Hanson

Race: [Human (E) – lvl 48]

Class: [Metal Savant – lvl 66]

Profession: [Disciple of Eversmile – lvl 31]

He didn’t feel the slightest threat. The men were mere background to his beautiful reunion.

"Allow me to introduce myself. William Hanson, nineteen years old, no work experience except my very successful career being a psychotic mass murderer. I am a fast learner, though!” He let out a snicker. “So, can I join in on the fun?"

He briefly saw the look of terror on Ms. Kim’s face deepen, but soon it turned more somber. He couldn’t help but smile internally. He hadn’t gone wrong indeed.

"Listen here, you litt—"

Before the man could finish the sentence, his head was severed from his body.

The leader and the man closer to the child both changed their attitude really quickly because of that. Weird how that works.

"What? He was rude, was he not?" William casually said as the two men exchanged a quick glance before charging towards him. Neither of them made it two steps before both their bodies were eviscerated into dozens of pieces, falling to the floor in bloody messes.

At this point, Ms. Kim had a bit of that terror returning.

William walked up to her as she sat there, unmoving. Her shirt was slightly ripped, and the marks on her face clearly indicated that she had been hit. Her level was no higher than 17. She was a lamb in this new world. Worse was the little girl, who boasted a level of only 10. He didn’t even know how she’d gotten any levels.

Honestly, she looked… unsightly. Her demeanor was very different from the authoritative woman he remembered from their session. Yet William didn’t feel the slightest inclination toward killing her. He needed her, and clearly, she needed him.

"I take it you remember me, Ms. Kim?" William asked, already knowing the answer.

"William… or do you prefer Mr. Hanson?"

"William is fine, Miss," he said, giving her the same fake smile he’d used in every one of their sessions. "You are my psychologist or therapist or whatever they called it. And I require your professional guidance once more."

She looked at him, her terror now mainly replaced by confusion. Until he saw her gaze land on her smaller version not far away. Without even hesitating, she got up and ran to the little girl, cradling her.

"Relax, she’s alive," William muttered, but she didn’t stop hugging her. "Okay, then…"

Sitting down on the stairs, he began playing with his new weapon. Cuts appeared randomly on the ground and walls here and there.

After what felt like ages, she finally began talking. "What are you going to do to me?"

He kept playing around as he chuckled. "You misunderstand. This is about what you can do for me."

"This is my daughter, Seo-Yun," she said. "She will be six in only a few days. Her father died shortly after she was born. Moving from overseas, I don’t have any other relatives on this side of the world. So it has just been the two of us since then.

"We went to that tutorial together. It was pretty safe, so we didn’t do much fighting. She didn’t do any at all, of course. We… Without you, I fear what would have happened. To both of us. Thank you, William."

William just smiled and didn’t interrupt her. He enjoyed this new sensation. He actually felt a bit of interest in her situation—from a standpoint that didn’t revolve around benefits or objectivity, no less. A foolish, subjective interest in another human being.

So he tried something else he had never truly tried before.

"Sorry to hear. Sounds like it sucked, but glad to see you two made it."

He showed actual sympathy. Not a lot, but just a sliver. Still, for once, it wasn’t just empty words or platitudes, but genuine. He was happy she had made it, as, while she had been a hard-ass, she had also always been one of the better people in that shitty hospital. And she didn’t disappoint him as her eyes opened wide.

"William… you…" she said, stunned.

"Let’s get out of here," he said, getting up from the stairs. “The blood is beginning to stink, and we don’t want little Seo to start crying when she wakes up, now, do we?”

Kim only nodded as she got up and followed after him, holding her child. William couldn’t help but look. For reasons he still couldn’t explain, he liked the look of the scene. He didn’t understand why at all—something Ms. Kim was sure to help him with.

Getting outside, he stretched in an exaggerated motion and looked back at the woman. "Much better out here, isn’t it?"

"William… what happened to you?" she asked, still holding her child.

"Oh, this and that. I killed a bunch of people, made a friend, killed a bunch more people, and got my head smashed in and killed by some monster in human skin. You know, the usual tutorial stuff.” He was still smiling, but his face did crack a bit at the last part.

"One step at a time, William. But what is this about making a friend?"

"Wow, between killing people and getting killed myself, you think making a friend is the big takeaway?"

"Isn’t it? It is an event important enough to be put beside your own killing and you supposedly getting killed. Which must indicate it meant a lot to you.”

William smiled, as he was beginning to see his good old “friend” once more in her. Attempting to change the subject, he said, "Enough about me for now. So, a daughter, eh? Never mentioned that.”

"Our talks weren’t about me; they were about you. Besides, would you have cared for that information before? Or would it just have been ammo to try and get under my skin and throw me off?"

"Wow. Harsh. But totally true." William chuckled a bit.

Silence overtook the two for a while as William just observed her looking down on her daughter, wiping some grime off her cheek. He found it eerie how they looked so incredibly similar. The kid was like a mini-Ms. Kim.

"So what is it you really want?" she finally asked, breaking the silence.

"I am sure you have noticed by now, but I experienced quite the enlightenment on certain subjects during our time apart," he explained. “Certain changes, if you will. I want you to do what you did before. Help me understand these things by having our ‘talks.’”

"William, what are these changes? In your own words."

"Hm… do you know how evolution works through the system?" he asked. Seeing her shake her head, he explained, "You see, I wanted to try and understand emotion better subconsciously, it seems. Comprehend them somehow. I had some encounters that gnawed at me, made me reconsider certain things. Evolution through the system is exactly as described. It allows one to get closer to the perfection that is divinity. But perfection is subjective, so one of the things it does is change the one evolving according to their own deep wishes. Mine appeared to be to comprehend these emotions better, so… here I am."

"That is… So you are… better?” she asked, very much doubting her own words.

“Oh, no, far from it. Don’t get me wrong—I don’t believe there was ever anything to fix, just ways to improve myself. I don’t need emotions, but I recognize the value in many of them. Empathy, as an example, is quite a dual-edged sword. On the one hand, it can help you better read people, but on the other hand, it can make you less efficient in killing. I want to learn to control it.”

"You know that isn’t how emotions work. You cannot pick and choose, like a cable package. They are all connected.” Ms. Kim sighed.

"First of all, outdated metaphor. Secondly, I would agree if it was anyone else. But you see, I am indeed quite a bit different. Unique, if you may. My new ‘master,’ as he calls himself, helped me understand certain things about myself.”

He smiled, thinking back to the creepy old man. Not even realizing how he had inadvertently began picking up a habit of also smiling a bit too much.

"You will have to explain everything to me in great detail, or I won’t be able to help. But… I am not sure how you want to do this… thing. The world is different."

"This is my proposition. I will help and protect you, and at the same time, you will help me. A partnership, if you will. It’s a pure win-win, so what do you say?" William extended his arm for a handshake.

Kim just looked at the child in her arms and asked, "What about Seo-Yun?"

William’s dismissive wave seemed to worry her until he said, "I get it; you’re a package deal. So, not a partnership, but the three musketeers instead? Something like that. On that note, how is she still out cold?"

"I… I put her to sleep with a skill of mine. It revolves around hypnosis, and I had to make her calm as we tried to hide," she said, a bit ashamed.

"Neat. Anyway, what do you say?"

"I don’t feel like I have much of a choice in the matter," she sighed. "Okay, William, but we must set some ground rules."

"Eh, like what?"

"Firstly, you must promise to protect my daughter and me, of course. Secondly, you are never allowed to use intimidation, force me to do anything against my own volition, or resort to violence due to our talks. Third, you must always answer me honestly. Lastly… you are not allowed to kill any people in front of Seo-Yun."

"I kind of expected a rule against killing altogether," he said, honestly a bit surprised.

"We both know that isn’t realistic."

"Because of me or the current state of the world? Also, what is up with the second rule?"

"Both. And the purpose of the second rule is to make sure this is a partnership. I cannot do my job if I am in fear of anything I say. I will without a doubt need to push you and risk angering you…"

"Fine," he said, nodding. “But I will add a bit to the rules. First of all, confidentiality about anything I don’t give you express permission to say or that you believe can benefit me by sharing. And to make the third rule go two ways… you also have to be honest with me at all times. Of course, I will also keep everything confidential.”

"Naturally, I won’t share anything," Kim said. "I also agree to your terms."

"Great," William said as he took out a small object the size of a coin from his pocket. "From this deal, our new karma shall be born."

The coin flew upward and exploded into several golden letters in mid-air, describing the terms they had just made, exactly as stated.

"Now, let us shake on it, and the bond be created," he said, motioning for her to shake his hand. "Oh, and the kid too."

That day they shook hands, and a very unusual trio was born.

Intermission 8 - William (2/3)

A few weeks later, a trio composed of a small girl, a young man, and a woman walked through the streets of the now broken city. The girl ran around far faster than a typical child normally could, showing that her physique would clearly be considered supernatural by pre-system standards.

The teenager was smiling cheekily as he chatted with the woman. That is, until the girl ran up to him holding a small object in her hand. Upon second look, it was clearly a broken dagger handle.

"Look, look! I found this! Do magic!" she said, proudly presenting the weapon to her mom and the teenager.

"Woah, nice find. Now watch this," the young man said as the dagger began floating and spinning in the air.

As with every other time he’d done it, the small girl began giggling while trying to grab hold of the dagger. Her mother stepped in before she could get a chance.

"Seo, you know you aren’t allowed to play with sharp things," Kim said, having noticed a few of the sharp edges on the handle.

"But mooom!" she cried.

"Ms. Kim is right; only big kids like me are allowed to play with them," William said as he floated the dagger into his hand and, with a swift motion, made it disappear into himself. "Tada!"

The girl giggled as William returned the smile. It didn’t take long before Seo rushed off again to explore the small city they had just entered.

It had been just over two weeks since they returned to Earth and began their partnership. William had thoroughly enjoyed their time, though they’d had a few awkward conversations about certain emotions. Two days ago, they’d had a particular one he vividly remembered.

"Are you sure I am not a damn… You know?"

"William, thinking a child is cute does not make you attracted to them," Ms. Kim said comfortingly. “It just means that your natural empathy exists. It is a biological trait developed for you to want to defend a child and care for them. Also, you just experienced a phenomenon called ‘cute aggression’ earlier. It is very normal to want to squeeze cute things. I have it too.”

"And you are one hundred percent sure?" he asked, shivering a bit at the thought. “A psychopath is one thing, but a goddamn child predator? Yeah, rather just cut off those emotions permanently again if that’s the case.”

"Is it not more interesting why you find the thought so abhorrent?"

"What?" he asked, confused.

"What logical reason do you have to find the thought of it so terrible? Where does your disgust stem from?"

"It’s… thinking of someone doing twisted shit to someone like mini-you just seems fucked up. As for why… hmm… It just is? Like, she’s a little kid and all.”

"Once more—why, though? You have no remorse or hesitation when killing people, and your brother was even younger. What makes doing ‘that’ with a child more disgusting than murdering that child outright?" She spoke provocatively, and William clearly saw that she was uncomfortable even asking the question.

"I… It just fucking isn’t cool, alright? Killing is different. You know, like when you go hunting. There is no reason to extend the animals’ suffering more than necessary. Killing is quick, and then it is done. It is an act that has utility. While…that… is just fucked up.” He seriously wanted to change the subject—but she didn’t let him.

"But what if they take pleasure from it? Like you take pleasure in extending the suffering of your targets? Do you not like to play around with your victims before you end their lives? What makes what you do so different?"

"Okay, I get it… no killing kids. Sheesh.” He sighed, unable to help looking at Seo running around happily in front of them. Yeah, not like kids have proper levels and give any experience anyway… No reason to.

"I know this isn’t easy to talk about; I am not particularly fond of it either. But it is important for you to understand why you do things and what kind of emotions push you to do these things. Even before your change, you found playing with your prey fun, from what you told me. It is clear that it stems from your innate desire for power, but why doesn’t this desire extend to all aspects of your life?"

"Who says it doesn’t?" William answered half-jokingly.

"Why didn’t you force me to help you instead of offering to create what you yourself identify as a partnership? Why agree to take Seo along and protect her too? You didn’t need to, but you did so anyway. You can’t tell me there were purely utilitarian reasons behind it."

"True… I knew I wanted you to help me due to our prior interactions, and when I saw Seo, I didn’t really feel like I had much of a choice but to take the both of you. As for why I wanted a partnership… well, I doubt you could do your job without also having a measure of power in the relationship, and because… well, I respect you, I guess.” He felt a tad embarrassed by his answer. Damn that honesty rule.

"I see," she said after a while. "Thank you."

He couldn’t help but look at her as she smiled at him. Her hair had long since been washed and was now the long, silky hair he remembered. She no longer had torn clothes, but a robe he had “acquired” from someone he made sure didn’t need it anymore.

It was a good memory, despite only being two days old—and despite the rather harrowing conversation before it, that is.

One might wonder how their relationship could truly be considered a partnership, as William currently appeared to hold all the power. Still, the reason was exactly due to their contract—a karmic contract, to be more accurate.

Karmic contracts were an interesting thing. William had been given a token from Eversmile to make it, as he hadn’t learned how to properly do it himself yet. The contract was the kind that couldn’t be broken easily without both party’s consent. And if one did break it… well, it wouldn’t end well.

A good case would be getting a bad karmic curse. A bad case would be instant death. He still wasn’t quite sure how it worked, but it didn’t really matter much. Even if he broke the contract, he didn’t give a damn.

Because as William had said: he was unique. Enough so for even the system to recognize it.

[Bloodline of the Bondless One (Ancient)] – Grants resistance to passively creating karmic bonds. Increases ability to comprehend bonds and manipulate them.

A Bloodline. The reason his master had been so willing to make him a student. As to what exactly it did… well, the first part about passive karmic bonds was apparently the overpowered part, while he’d mainly noticed the second one during his practice after he had awakened it.

William didn’t know that he had apparently always had it, but he had been told it was only awakened when Eversmile blessed him. He’d even gotten the Bloodline ability as part of the blessing-title-thing. His master had warned him not to mention his Bloodline, and that most information out there in the multiverse was fake, spread on purpose by those with powerful Bloodlines like him. He totally got that; he would have done the same thing.

Anyway, back to karma. What he had learned about karma was that karmic bonds between two people were a two-way street. Normally when a bond was created, there was a connection going from person A to person B and from B back to A. But what happened if one of those was missing?

Well, according to his master, that would be nearly impossible without an incredibly powerful skill, coupled with great insight into the concept of karma. If the bond went from A to B, there would always automatically be a bond back the other way.

This was also the reason why a single party couldn’t simply sever karma. One could cut off their own part, but the karmic bond would always exist if the other party declined to also sever all karma. And even if it was severed, to truly, one hundred percent sever it was, once again, nearly impossible.

Which was where his Bloodline came in. If he was person B in the other example, then while person A established a karmic bond with him, he wouldn’t just automatically return that bond or have a weaker bond. Which effectively meant that he could more easily sever his own karmic connections.

Now, what did that help with? First of all, he could sever any contract—such as the karmic contract—simply by working on not actively forming his part. To make it even better, the other party was still bound by the agreement as though he was too. Well, unless the person had just a sliver of insight into karma… It only worked with weaker people, but it was still nice.

Eversmile had told him that his Bloodline meant so much more than simply that, but honestly, that part was good enough for him already. It meant he wasn’t shackled down by some otherworldly law, or worse, his own promises.

Which isn’t to say he had any plans on breaking his deal with Ms. Kim. He just didn’t like the thought of being unable to break it.

"So, where to now?" he asked her.

As said, it was a partnership. And since William didn’t have any particular target or location in mind, he just let her direct them. Because while he didn’t have any family or friends he gave a damn about, she did.

"They lived in the inner city, just through here. Though I must admit it is a bit hard to recognize a lot of the area due to the destruction.” She sighed.

"Want some help?" he asked, offering his karmic expertise. “If they’re close, I should be able to locate them.”

"Really? How?"

"An ability of mine. Quite effective at finding people you have a connection with. It was the same skill I used to find you.” He didn’t intend to share any real details beyond that.

"It would certainly be useful. What do you need me to do?"

"Just take my hands, and I am gonna give it a go," he said, offering up his hands. "It is my first time doing it, though, so not sure if it will actually work."

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

She grabbed his hands without hesitation, and William couldn’t help but notice how soft her hands were. Shaking his head, he closed his eyes and began reading the threads of karma.

In his mind’s eye, he saw thousands upon thousands of threads extend out from Kim. Most of them so ethereal that he wasn’t even a hundred percent sure they were actually there. The threads didn’t actually go anywhere but simply hung in the air.

All except for five. One of them was directly connected to William himself. Its strength and intensity were relatively strong, but it was nothing compared to the thread right beside it. A powerful, almost golden thread extended to the child playing behind them. It was the most powerful karmic connection he had seen since he started practicing this whole karma thing.

But neither of those were what he sought. Instead, it was the three threads extending towards the inner city she’d pointed to before. One of them was significantly stronger than the two others. Likely only one friend or family member, and two she wasn’t quite as close to.

Opening his eyes, he smiled. "Let’s go."

"You found them?" she asked, not quite believing him. He had just taken her hands and closed his eyes for ten seconds before letting go again.

"Three people you have some kind of connection with right this way, milady," he said, making an exaggerated motion towards where she’d pointed before.

"Do you know who?" she asked, a fair amount of expectation in her voice.

"No clue."

"Let us hurry, then!"

"Alright." He turned towards the girl and yelled, "Seo, time to go! It’s flying time!"

With an excited scream, she bolted back towards him.

At the same time, he took out a large disc of metal from his armor and quickly enlarged it until it was long enough for all of them to stand on. The disc also had small appendages to hold feet in place, making it safe-ish.

"I still can’t believe you convinced me to fly on that thing. Much less Seo," Kim said as she stepped on the giant disc.

"Come on—you secretly like it, don’t ya?" he teased, getting only a small smile in return. No denial, though.

Seo, of course, absolutely loved flying on the disc.

The two of them laughed as they took flight and whooshed through the air towards where he had tracked the karmic threads. The speed of the disc was limited more by the child on board than William’s own capacity for speed. However, he had to admit that keeping it afloat was quite expensive mana-wise.

As they got closer, William saw far more people than just the three they were looking for. An entire camp had been built in what was once a park, with several makeshift tents and other structures scattered about.

Turning to Ms. Kim, he said, "I think Seo needs to sleep."

She nodded as she picked up the oblivious child. Putting her mouth to the girl’s ear, she said in a weird, ethereal voice, "Sleepytime."

With those words, the small girl fell over in her mother’s arms, already asleep. It was the standard procedure they had agreed upon when meeting other humans. The situation was unpredictable by default, after all.

Their intrusion did cause quite the commotion. Several people spotted them flying towards the camp, and he could hear several yells as they tried to muster a response to a possible attack.

At the behest of Ms. Kim, he landed outside of their camp, several watchful gazes drilling into them. And like the last time they’d met other humans, he let her take the lead once more. On a side note, he had learned that being a group carrying around a sleeping kid didn’t exactly add to their intimidation factor.

"I am sorry for the scare; my companion and I are here looking for a close friend of mine," Kim said, practically yelling at the six men who stood cautiously watching them at the edge of the camp.

"Who?" one of them yelled back.

"Her name is Mary; she is my friend. But would it not be easier for us just to enter and look around ourselves? We have it on good authority she is here.”

The men turned to each other and muttered in hushed voices, scowling back towards Ms. Kim and William several times before finally turning back to them.

"Fine—you and the girl can come in, but the guy is staying out here," the man said.

"Why can’t he enter with us? We truly mean no harm, and—"

"He gives me the creeps, and we can’t see his level. That reason enough?" one of the other men said.

"But—"

"I don’t give a shit what you say; he ain’t comin’ in," the same guy said, cutting her off. "And if you keep up this bullshit, you can fuck right off too."

Ms. Kim was momentarily unsure what to say as William stepped forward. “Now, now, that is no way to speak to a lady, is it?" he said, a big smile on his face. "Besides, why are we even arguing? Are you boys not under a serious misconception here? What makes you think I give a flying fuck if you allow me to enter or not?"

Chapter 24

A Healthy Diet

Lavender, Evergreen Grass, a lot of mana, and a bit of love, and you have a perfectly healthy potion. It seemed simple on paper, but there was a bit of work going into it. The mana-control aspect of the crafting process was something that could always be improved, and the more you trained, the better your potions would inadvertently get. While there was a cap caused by the ingredients and your own stats, it wasn’t one Jake could ever feasibly reach.

He did improve a whole lot, though. His potions got better and better, and he honestly took quite a while to get proper pricing down but ended up just settling on 20,000 for each potion. While he certainly could charge more, he didn’t feel the need to. He didn’t craft them to make money, to begin with, but to level his profession and get as comfortable with his new D-grade mana-control prowess as he could before he would begin crafting some more interesting things.

Like some uncommon-rarity poison.

Well, his pricing scheme was like that for the first week—until he talked about it with Miranda.

"Why don’t you have someone else sell it for you?" she'd asked. “Merchants or others with compatible professions apparently get great experience selling items through the store to other cities and have even better methods to price goods with their skills. That way, they can gain levels, and you can gain Credits without thinking about putting them up for sale yourself.”

"Do you have anyone in mind?" he had replied.

This was when he learned that, apparently, being a City Lord’s assistant also included selling stuff as a part of the job—at least, the system agreed it did. Lillian came by later that day, and from the first week and moving forward, she handled all the commercial stuff for him. She just came by once a day or so and took all the potions he had already made while giving him any stuff he asked her to buy or look out for.

Jake still bought most of the items he wanted himself, as quite frankly, he only knew he wanted it when he saw it. Every item above common rarity was more or less an impulse buy, because he thought, “Hey, I guess I can use this for something."

It had now been two weeks total since the World Congress ended, and Jake was spending most of his time every day experimenting on making an uncommon-rarity poison, but he did still spend a few hours pumping out potions.

The experience was great when he mass-produced things, and he had gained two levels during this period. While that didn’t seem like a lot, one had to remember that leveling only got harder and harder as time went on. Villy had told him to sometimes expect going years between levels at higher grades.

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 103 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 109 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 104 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

As for what kind of poison he was trying to make an uncommon variant of? He had decided to start with the old trusty one: Necrotic Poison.

Necrotic Poison did have some drawbacks, but against any living being, it was just great. Against elementals, it was quite bad, but it even functioned okay-ish versus plant-based foes. It also happened to be the poison Jake had the most experience with.

Finally, he decided to go for this poison because of a certain herb. Or, more accurately, mushroom. An old friend of his, but in a new and improved form.

[Aged Bluebright Mushroom (Uncommon)] - A poisonous blue mushroom that emits blue light. The Aged Blue Mushroom has grown to a point where simply being touched by its light can bring you harm, and the juices found within are more toxic than ever.

Jake had discovered that the System Store was indeed a bit dynamic and adaptable. He had bought all the normal, common-rarity Bluebright Mushrooms that he could and found that the store stocked a few more every time, with it even giving out a few uncommon-rarity ones every time now.

For the first many mushrooms, he did as any reasonable person would do and ate them. All competent doctors would agree that death-shrooms were a part of a healthy diet.

They tasted a lot like the regular Bluebright Mushrooms but had a bit stronger flavor, and the juices within them sizzled in his mouth when he ate. He was perfectly aware that without Palate of the Malefic Viper, half his mouth would have rotted away, but with it, nothing really happened. Yay for a legendary skill granting poison resistance.

The first few mushrooms always gave the best insights, and it was far more valuable than just trying to experiment with them blindly. Jake did run into the issue of needing to get more, and he knew he would need these mushrooms in the long run, even after the System Store disappeared. Problem was… Jake had never actually done any proper gardening in his life, and he also really didn’t feel like starting now. It would require a lot of time to make a proper mushroom garden.

This was an issue he brought up with Lillian during one of her visits to get his potions, and she’d shrugged and said, "Why not just find someone to do it for you? Maybe train someone to do it properly. That should also get them a great profession or a great upgrade."

Jake had considered it, but that would also take time… There was also the issue that he couldn’t just take anyone random. They had to know the basics and be strong enough not to be killed by the mushrooms. He considered it for a while and decided to just postpone it for now. He would also need someplace to properly grow the Bluebright Mushrooms.

One would think that it would be smart to do the mushroom growing down in the cave by the dungeon due to the mana it leaked, but the issue was that the dungeon portal leaked life-affinity mana, while the mushrooms primarily had death-affinity or perhaps rot-affinity mana. Chances were the mushrooms would get worse if put down there, or possibly mutate if Jake got lucky and gave it enough time.

No, the cavern was far more suitable to grow other kinds of herbs and plants in. There were many different types of mushrooms too, and ones used in hemotoxins or many other types of toxins would still grow just fine down there.

Luckily he wasn’t in that much of a rush, as he could save all the herbs he wanted to plant later in his spatial storage.

Anywho, Jake spent a damn long time grinding alchemy, eating mushrooms, making bank, and having the occasional playtime with Sylphie or meeting with Miranda and/or Lillian. All in all, it was quite relaxing, and his goal was to get his first uncommon-rarity poison done within the first month. After that…

Dungeon time.

Miranda took a deep breath as the mana hummed to life. A green sheen overtook the entire area as the light danced and weaved in seemingly random patterns. But there was a method to the madness as she began chanting words in a language she truly didn’t understand. Her ignorance wasn’t a question of her translation skill; the words she spoke truly didn’t exist, or perhaps weren’t real words to begin with.

They did hold power, though.

A green top-down view appeared, and she saw her targets. It was an old enemy most in the city would recognize as an Oakwood Tiger—the kind of beast that had nearly killed her, Hank, Louise, and Mark before Jake saved them.

She saw nearly a hundred of them grouped together around a large, peculiar tree—likely a natural treasure of sorts. Out of all the tigers, one of them was special. It had a small mark on it that it could neither detect with its mana sense nor see with its eyes. It was a green sigil depicting a circular mark, looking a lot like a green lagoon. The Verdant Mark.

Miranda didn’t have a typical combat class, but was instead a witch. While they could fight with regular magic, flinging fire and ice like any other caster, their specialty lay in mysticism and ritual magic. Such as the ritual she was currently doing.

Around her was a magic circle over five meters in diameter. Candles burned around the perimeter, and several items were placed in key spots of the formation. Among these items were the heart of an Oakwood Tiger she had killed days prior, leaves from the forest, bark from many different kinds of trees, and several catalysts she had bought using her Credits from the Ore & Metal category, as well as some things from the Foodstuffs & Herbs categories.

Using the Verdant Mark, she weaved her spell. Through it, she would bring them death.

Concentrating, she evoked even more mana, and the items placed around the circle began burning with green fire as the spell activated.

"Verdant Feast Of the Lagoon’s Insatiable Depths."

--

The Oakwood Tiger rubbed its barkskin up against the bark of the magical tree. It was a natural treasure that served as a gathering point for all the Oakwood Tigers in the area. It was their domain, and no other beast had been able to go near for months without being torn apart.

Some beasts had tried, but most didn’t. Many types of natural treasures—this one included—functioned better for some beasts than others. This tree was highly beneficial to the tigers but wouldn’t help many other types of monsters or enlightened races.

None of them knew that today would be their doom, nor that this haven they had named their home would be their grave.

At first, it was subtle. A few of the tigers noticed a shift in the air as a green wind seemed to sweep through, with even less noticing the green grass below them growing an even deeper green.

By the time they knew anything was wrong, it was already too late.

Suddenly, a green hand sprang up from the ground and grabbed hold of the leg of one of the tigers. It struggled, but another arm came up, followed by a dozen more as they began dragging it down. Down to the depths of the lagoon.

All of the grass beneath their feet melted together to resemble a still lake. Every single tiger was assaulted at once by the greedy hands that sought to bring them down, and no matter how they cut or tore at the hands, a new one would just come to replace whatever they broke.

The ground then stopped simply looking like water and actually turned swampy, and the hands began succeeding in dragging the tigers down. The first to be grabbed was also the first to be fully submerged. It quickly failed to keep itself afloat and was pulled under.

Once it was entirely under… the tiger saw them: human-like creatures with maws for mouths, all closing in on it. They were all half-corporeal but physical enough to bite and tear into the tiger as it struggled. As a monster growing up in a forest, it had never fought in water, nor was it built to do so. Needless to say, it was heavily outmatched and outnumbered.

Its other comrades also joined it below and suffered the same fate. They did struggle, and they managed to "kill" many of the creatures trying to devour them, but there were just too many. They also noticed that these creatures didn’t respawn and no new ones appeared… so if they could somehow defeat them all…

The struggle ended up lasting for nearly half an hour before the depths below became calm, the silence broken only by the occasional munching sound.

Above, the grass surrounding the natural treasure turned back to its old color as the aura from the ritual faded. Not a single trace of what had happened, including the tigers’ bodies, remained. All had been devoured at the Feast.

Miranda collapsed to the ground, sweat pouring down her face as she breathed heavily. A bit of blood even flowed out her mouth, as she had taken a bit of damage towards the end from pushing herself too far. Even so, she had a light smile on her lips—she had succeeded in her most significant and powerful ritual yet.

The ritual circle around her had already died down, all the catalysts burned away by the green fire. It had been an expensive one, and it had taken quite a bit of work to set it all up and make all the preparations, but it had been worth it.

*You have slain [Oakwood Tiger – lvl 89] – Experience earned*

*You have slain [Oakwood Tiger – lvl 80] – Experience earned*

…

*You have slain [Oakwood Tiger – lvl 92] – Experience earned*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Neophyte Verdant Witch] has reached level 91 - Stat points allocated, +3 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Neophyte Verdant Witch] has reached level 92 - Stat points allocated, +3 Free Points*

It was some damn good experience to get two entire levels from a single ritual, and she chuckled through the pain as she began cleaning up the magic circle around her. She kept some of it, as it could be reused and was more or less an all-purpose ritual circle for Verdant magic. It had taken nearly all of her personal Credits to get that one built…

Miranda also didn’t get any race levels because, well, she was already capped at 99. Had been for a week now, due to the immense amount of profession experience she got from managing the city. She had even gained two levels from the World Congress.

She had decided to go for the Perfect Evolution due to the advice from the Sisters, and she didn’t dare go against it. Jake also agreed she should do it, as, in his words: "Everything counts."

Also, her class wasn’t that bad to level, and one of the best parts was that she could do it from the comforts of her home. The ritual she had just performed was done from the cellar of the mayor’s office/City Lord residence of Haven, more than a hundred kilometers away from where she had just killed a massive group of Oakwood Tigers.

That was the beauty of being a witch and doing rituals… It was all a bit more metaphysical, and distance didn’t always matter as much. She did have to mark a target in person, but once that was done, all she had to do was wait and then use the Verdant Mark as a casting point for the ritual.

There were some downsides, though, such as the fact that Miranda honestly found her own spells scary—at least, she had at first. Now, she had begun to be okay with them. Verdant Ritual Magic was its entirely own school of magic, recognized by the system itself. There even was a Verdant affinity—one Miranda didn’t at all understand and knew she wasn’t supposed to understand any time soon.

It was an affinity much like the holy affinity, which was bound to the Holy Mother, or the blight affinity, bound to the Blightfather.

Or, of course, the malefic affinity of the Malefic Viper.

Shaking her head, she finished cleaning up the basement, then went to a small room with a staircase and a sink. There, she quickly cleaned herself up before she headed upstairs again, passing through a myriad of wards on the way. Sadly, those only gave experience if someone actually interacted with them.

Miranda walked into her office, where Phillip was already waiting. The man himself had also gained quite a few levels over the last few weeks, as he was one of the people identified as able to reach D-grade by the time the Treasure Hunt began.

"Any news?" she asked.

"Well…" Phillip said, scratching his head. "Arnold keeps insisting he wants to talk with the owner. Apparently, only he can do what the madman wants. Should we ask Jake if he is fine with meeting him?"

"I’ll bring it up next meeting. Anything else?"

"There has been a single more application to the temple, and a few people unsatisfied with not being able to buy all they want from the System Store, but besides that, everything is going fine. Oh, yeah, one last thing—Neil expects to reach D-grade within the month, and I, for one, am looking forward to seeing what a D-grade space mage can do." Phillip looked a bit expectant while saying that last part.

Chapter 25

This Chapter Contains Alchemy

Sylphie had once again gotten mad when Jake sent her away to spend some time with her parents, but today was one of those days where having a bird sitting around just wasn’t feasible. The reason for this was simple… Today would be the day he would craft his first uncommon-rarity Necrotic Poison. He could feel it. At least, that was what he kept telling himself. He’d felt the same the day before.

Another two weeks had passed, and it had now been nearly a month since the World Congress ended, AKA two months away from the Treasure Hunt. He had gotten another profession level in the bag, bringing it to 105, and with it, a race level had also naturally come. Yet his stats had grown quite a bit more than one would expect. The reason for this was simple.

Jake had begun a new diet called SHIT, I GOTTA HURRY UP AND EAT THAT FUCKING BANANA BEFORE IT DISAPPEARS! DAMN YOU, TIME TREE THAT ISN’T ACTUALLY A TREE!

It was a very healthy diet, naturally consisting of magical time bananas.

[Celerita Banana (Rare)] – As a banana from the Ancient Celerita Musa, this fruit contains intense amounts of Celerita-affinity mana with Agility-enhancing effects. This fruit can be used in many different creations and is especially suited for flasks and elixirs. Due to this banana’s origin, it will be returned to the rivers of time if it is moved too far from the tree. Consuming or transforming the fruit will anchor the energies in time, removing this effect. +3 Agility upon consumption.

Jake constantly kept watch of the tree with his sphere, and whenever he saw a ripe banana appear, he stopped whatever he was doing to rush in and pick it off the tree. He had discovered the bananas could disappear and no longer be recognized as items in as little as a minute, while at other times, they remained on the tree for hours on end.

He suddenly understood far better why the Prima had never left the temple. It hadn’t wanted to miss out on bananas.

He had also tried not heeding the warning and taking the banana away and out of the time-distortion area surrounding the tree. That hadn’t gone well, as it had instantly begun rotting and turned to dust in his hand within seconds. Jake still had no idea how to anchor the banana besides eating it, but he did have one way of finding out.

Swallowing one. No, not eating it, but swallowing a banana with Palate of the Malefic Viper. Sadly, he could only have one item stored at a time, and currently, he still had the Lifecore within there. He could switch it up but didn’t really feel the need to. Eating the bananas normally was fine, too, as they were super tasty.

Also, while he made it sound like he ate a lot, he had only actually eaten thirteen more during this month, giving him an extra 39 Agility. He knew there was a cap to stats and all that, but he had decided that since Agility was one of his best stats, it was fine. Besides… it allowed him to do something he really wanted: throw every single free point into Perception again. Perception for the win.

Overall, his status had experienced quite the growth, especially in Agility and the stats his class gave. Not to downplay the ten race levels. That in itself was more than 100 to all stats due to his titles. Of course, Perception was still the one that had grown most—as it should be.

Status

Name: Jake Thayne

Race: [Human (D) – lvl 110]

Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter – lvl 115]

Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper – lvl 105]

Health Points (HP): 20070/20070

Mana Points (MP): 25941/26975

Stamina: 14571/16880

Stats

Strength: 1439

Agility: 2376

Endurance: 1688

Vitality: 2007

Toughness: 1392

Wisdom: 2158

Intelligence: 1709

Perception: 3902

Willpower: 1722

Free Points: 0

As for skills, not much had changed besides a few upgrades here and there, such as Enhanced Splitting Arrow and Descending Dark Arcane Fang. Quite a mouthful, that last one.

Anyway, bananas were tasty, Perception was the best stat, and he had grown quite a bit since reaching D-grade. He had made way more progress in the first week on his monkey hunt than during this month, but that was just the disparity between professions and classes. Jake liked both, and that was what mattered. Plus, right now, he wanted to make a cool new poison.

With his cauldron between his legs, he began his preparations. The first and most important ingredient he needed was, of course, the mushrooms themselves.

[Aged Bluebright Mushroom (Uncommon)] - A poisonous blue mushroom that emits blue light. The Aged Blue Mushroom has grown to a point where simply being touched by its light can bring you harm, and the juices found within are more toxic than ever.

Damn toxic, pretty tasty, and he had even discovered that he slowly got a bit of knowledge from Palate just by basking in their blue light. It was only a bit, though, and he quickly got "capped" on knowledge from doing that. Pretty much all he learned was that it emitted a kind of light that directly attacked the vital energies of anything it touched.

Second was the moss. One always needed to have moss as a side dish for their mushrooms. It was the butter to the bread or the rum to the coke. Of course, with a stronger mushroom, one needed more potent moss.

This was where another of the must-buys from the System Store came in. Another item that Jake just bought everything of whenever possible.

[Black Moss (Uncommon)] - A rare variant of the Green Moss found in places with absolutely no sunlight and a high level of death-affinity mana. This moss is extremely dangerous and will erode any Vitality-based substance it comes into contact with.

The moss was black, as the name suggested. It was an almost unnaturally dark color, and he even felt a bit of dark mana mixed into the overpowering death-affinity energy. Jake had naturally munched down quite a bit of this moss, too, having some good old moss soup that brought him back to his tutorial days.

With that and several failed crafting attempts under his belt, he was beginning to get quite confident.

The final ingredient was, as always, his blood. It replaced most of the water and was quite frankly instrumental to him making as much progress as he did. It just made everything far easier, and the synergy with all of his Malefic Viper skills just amplified it even more. As an example, Sense of the Malefic Viper allowed him to get a much better feel for the concoction, as his blood was already part of it.

With all of that in mind, he began.

First, he cut his own wrist to add blood to the mixture. (Don’t do this at home). He also added a bit of Purified Water to not have his blood be too overpowering in the concoction. With both hands on the cauldron, he slowly mixed the two until he was satisfied.

Next up was the moss.

Jake slowly took out a good handful of it, chopped it apart in mid-air with a few mana strings, and let all the small fragments enter the mix. The reaction was immediate when the two energies clashed, and he once more had to step in and be the guiding hand to make the two play nice.

Toxic fumes entered the air from the cauldron, and Jake was happy he was doing this outside and in a relatively open area. He did see that he was still a bit too close to a few trees, judging by the leaves turning black and withering, but what can ya do? He really needed to set up a proper lab.

After fully integrating the moss energy, he noticed that the entire concoction was still too weak, so he used Touch of the Malefic Viper and infused a bit more necrotic energy into it, just slightly topping it up. The moss fragments absorbed the energy, and it gave them a second wind of sorts, allowing them to squeeze out just a touch more until they fully disintegrated.

Nodding in satisfaction, he took out one of the mushrooms. Its blue light seemed all-encompassing, and the entire area he was sitting in had already been cleared of grass by one of its brethren earlier.

With the common-rarity mushrooms, he squeezed them for their juices first, but with this uncommon version, he just placed it straight into the mix. The reason for this was simple: it would allow him to not only squeeze out the juices but also absorb all the light energy first.

The "flesh" of the mushroom had been bathed in its own light and contained a lot of its energy. Jake wanted to get that out before he fully ripped the mushroom apart and began directly integrating its potent juices. Also, it allowed the concoction to more easily assimilate the mushroom if he first let it get used to the death-light.

He assumed that when he got more used to the crafting process, this part was one he could speed up significantly, but currently, that would only be a shortcut to having the entire concoction explode in his face. That had happened a few times already.

So he took it slow and let the mushroom exude its own energy for a bit before he willed it to speed up just a little. He couldn’t just sit there forever, or the concoction would be ruined, so he was forced to.

Deploying some more advanced techniques, he shielded parts of the concoction with his mana, even using a bit of his own arcane affinity to make the protective constructs stable so as not to interfere with the other energies of the concoction. That was the good thing about his own stable version of arcane mana: it didn’t give a fuck about other types of energies.

This technique allowed him to avoid a cascading effect when some of the energies didn’t play nice but also allowed him to isolate the issues and deal with them. Once more, this made the entire crafting process a lot harder and prolonged, but you gotta do what you gotta do to make it work.

He sat like that for a good five minutes before the passive light was nearly entirely absorbed. When he couldn’t delay any longer, he began extracting the toxic liquids from within the mushroom and braced himself.

A lot could be said about the blue mushrooms, most of it bad. One thing was certain, though: they were toxic as hell. The liquids instantly sought to overpower the rest of the concoction with their potency as the death-affinity energy spread throughout the mix.

Now, one may call it a bit counterproductive, but the death-affinity energy tried to kill the death-affinity energy from the Black Moss. Death affinity liked to make things dead—even other dead things, it appeared—so Jake had to play mediator and make sure the two didn’t just stupidly try to cancel each other out but instead mixed as they were supposed to.

With a guiding hand, he concentrated fully to keep the equilibrium stable as the energies slowly mixed and the synergistic effects began showing. Instead of killing each other, the two energies of death mixed, like they had agreed to team up and tag-team the next thing they met. This was exactly the state Jake had hoped for as he made a final push.

*You have successfully crafted [Potent Necrotic Poison (Uncommon)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

Jake had a massive smile on his face as he opened the lid of the cauldron and took a good whiff of his concoction. It smelled absolutely terrible—terrible enough to leave a bad taste in his mouth. From the looks of it, the trees around him and the ground below didn’t like it either.

Dead grass surrounded him in a fifteen-meter radius, and quite a few trees also had signs of rot on them, with the closest two trees now nearly completely withered.

Okay, I really fucking need a proper alchemy lab.

If he kept doing as he did now, his entire valley would just be a dead wasteland by the time he was done. With Sense of the Malefic Viper, he could feel that the area was nowhere close to being permanently affected, but he risked that happening if he kept doing as he did. AKA, the ground would resemble the site of a chemical spill or something.

Besides possibly ruining his home with toxic pollution, everything was great, and he had even gained two levels from the successful craft.

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 106 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 107 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 111 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake guessed he was already close to a level, and that was why he got two. It had been quite a while since his last profession level, after all. Anyway, more Free Points in Perception.

Finally, he was down to the meat of things… the poison itself. And honestly, it hadn’t changed much, description-wise.

[Potent Necrotic Poison (Uncommon)] – An extremely toxic poison with necrotic properties, infecting and killing off biological material in the affected area. Wounds caused by necrotic poison are extremely difficult to heal. The poison takes effect upon any contact with any biological material. The poison emits necrotic light that affects the area around where it is applied, making necrotic energy seep even further into the enemy.

It did mention things that clearly came from the mushroom, such as the whole necrotic light thing. Funny enough, this was the first time Jake had seen the official term for the death-affinity light.

Jake quickly scooped up the poison, only getting two bottles’ worth, which was to be expected. For reference, he now usually got around ten when making batches of common-rarity Necrotic Poison.

With it in the bag, Jake decided it was best to wait for Miranda to arrive. He had a few things to talk to her about—renovating the basement and turning it into an alchemy lab being the primary one. Also… he had eaten so many damn mushrooms and too much moss these days, and he would really appreciate a proper meal.

Chapter 26

Man Cave(s)

"We’ll need to build it deeper," Hank explained as he shook his head. “There is no way the ceiling of the cellar can take that kind of toxic exposure. Even if we put some serious enchants on the floorboards, they will eventually lose effect as they are slowly corroded, and the stronger you get, the faster we will need to keep reapplying the enchants.”

"How deep do you reckon?" Jake asked. "It would be best if we can still keep the lab within the area affected by the Pylon. It would function as a ward to keep people out if they, for some reason, try to dig in."

"Oh, that should be easy enough. We just need to put in some good layers between the lab and the rest of the lodge. I would be able to put in some wooden layers that can absorb a lot of the poison and other toxic energies released, but you will have to switch them out or extract the poison from them again occasionally. That, or you could just sell them. They may change into actual items.”

"That would be fine; I just don’t want my entire valley to turn into a wasteland from my own experiments," Jake responded.

"Great. Anyway, we will dig down to create a second floor to the cellar below the first one. I intend to leave at least five meters between the two floors with the wooden layers placed there. You will still need some magical warding on top of that, I reckon. I am sure Miranda can hook you up with someone, or maybe ask that bird friend of yours." Hank began roughly sketching his plans on a piece of paper.

Jake just looked on, nodding. Situating the lab that low also allowed them to make it a lot bigger, and… Wait.

"Say, could we somehow link it up with the cavern leading to the dungeon?" Jake asked, liking his own idea quite a lot. “The barrier by the Pylon should help isolate the lodge and keep any energies from flowing that way, and it would mean easy access for me when I make a garden down there.”

Hank scratched his beard and thought for a while. "That is a lot of digging, and we would need to place the lab a lot lower, most likely… How far down are you comfortable with it being? I would assume the lower it is, the more future-proof it will also be, but everything will add to how long it will take to get done. We are talking meters in the triple digits.”

"I am fine with any depth; it doesn’t matter much when you can walk on air and make your own staircase at any time, anywhere. Or, you know, just fly. It is more if you think you can do it, and of course, have the time to. I know you’re a busy man." Jake smiled.

He really didn’t wanna put too much on the father of two. Hank had been in charge of most of the construction in Haven, and the man had barely stopped working ever since Jake met him. Yet he actually looked a bit younger now and full of spirit, even if he still had that vibe of a grizzled old lumberjack.

Jake had heard he was getting close to his profession evolution. He was actually a bit surprised the man hadn’t gotten it yet with how much he worked, but then again, he still wasn’t sure exactly what determined why some leveled so much faster than others. In retrospect, his class actually leveled pretty fast. At lightning speed compared to his profession. Fifteen levels in a week was kind of insane, even if he had spent nearly every hour of every day fighting monkeys at higher levels than himself.

"Alright,” Hank said. “I’ll have to bring in quite the crew to get it done properly. Do you want proper ventilation down there too? I know you probably don’t need it; it’s more of a comfort thing.”

"Nah, no need. I already have a plan myself for the future. One that includes really sealing in the flavor." Jake smiled mischievously.

"Sounds like we’re making a real man cave here," Hank chuckled. "Do you want us to get started right away?"

"Not today—tomorrow at the earliest," Jake answered.

"When I said right away, I didn’t mean here and now… At the earliest, we can begin tomorrow afternoon. We need to finish the current project first. Miranda’s orders. The whole town is really coming together." Hank had a big, proud smile on his lips.

"How’s Mark and Louise doing?" Jake asked. He hadn’t seen the man’s kids around much lately, so he was a bit curious.

"Didn’t think you’d care," Hank answered honestly, surprised at the question. "Both of them are currently staying and working at the Fort. While we agreed to keep Haven itself small, the same can’t be said for the Fort. Sure, it technically counts as Haven, but the flat plains around the Fort are just perfect for building on. More people already live there than in the entirety of Haven. At least twenty thousand, last I heard, with more coming… Ah, I’m sure you already heard this from Miranda."

Hank scratched his beard again, and Jake smiled at the builder’s embarrassment. "Yeah, she already gave me the update. I didn’t know those kids went there, though."

"Kids," Hank scoffed. "You’re barely older than them, aren’t you?”

“Teenagers, then," Jake corrected.

"Still incorrect. Mark turned twenty last month; Louise is twenty-two," Hank answered, shaking his head as he chuckled.

"Alright, fully functional adults, geez," Jake finally relented. "Also… back on topic… won’t it more end up being an alchemy cave than an alchemy cellar?"

"Yeah. A man cave.”

Jake was unable to tell if he was serious or just fucking with him.

The two spent a bit more time discussing the details, and Jake got more and more hooked on the idea of making a deep cave beneath the lodge to use as his alchemy lab. Possibly an entire network of sorts. It would also allow them to make a long, vertical tunnel leading down to it, and they would be able to seal that off properly.

After Hank left, Jake did exactly as he had said he would avoid by continuing to make a few more uncommon-rarity Potent Necrotic Poison. While he most certainly knew it would fuck up the spot he used a bit more, he felt like as long as he didn’t overdo it, it would fix itself in time.

If not, it wasn’t like he couldn’t get someone with nature magic or something like that to come by and work on it.

The reason he was a bit impatient was that he wanted the poison ready for the dungeon. He also made a few batches of fungicide, as he guessed he had a high chance of running into mushrooms or other types of fungi down there, based on the Indigo Mushroom.

After crafting, he only had one more thing to take care of before heading into the dungeon.

Jake stepped through the plains, each step taking him over a hundred meters forward. His travel speed with One Step Mile was quite frankly insane at this point, and he worked to increase the range of each step just a little as he got more used to the skill.

He couldn’t wait for the day the skill would actually allow him to pass a mile in one step.

The reason for going to the Fort was twofold. First, he wanted to have a talk with Arnold, the weird guy who liked to make drones and stuff like that, as well as the timed injectors Jake had used for the Indigo Mushroom. Apparently the guy needed help from Jake with something. Plus, he wanted to show off some cool stuff Jake would potentially want.

On the way out of the forest towards the Fort, he noted that the Pylon’s area of influence had grown even more. The city of Haven was now technically over a hundred kilometers in radius, though it was a bit oval, and the area was directed towards the Fort.

It was a bit insane to imagine that the Fort could eventually come under its influence despite the long distance between the two. Then again, distances seemed to matter far less now, especially when you could travel hundreds of kilometers in less time than his commute to work had taken before the system. When Miranda reached D-grade, he reckoned it would expand to encompass the Fort.

Anyway, the second thing Jake went there for was the blacksmiths. Jake needed a second weapon for the dungeon. With Venomfang broken and his Shortsword of Icy Winds subpar to say the least, he wanted to check out if they had something decent. He didn’t even need it to be that good, just something he could transmute to improve a bit, though he hoped for a weapon he could just use.

During this one-month alchemy period, Jake had made time to do one task he knew he would have to at one point. It had hurt him to do… but his old bow needed some change. The old one was fine, but after reaching D-grade, it just didn’t cut it.

[Windsoar Bow (Rare)] – A bow made from a tree inhabited by wind elementals. The string is made from the sinew of the beast that dared destroy their home. Now restored to a form made for hunting down the beasts hated by the young elementals. The elementals’ spirit and mana have left their mark upon the wood, making it light and flexible. The remnant will of the spirits within blesses any arrow fired. Enchantments: Windsoar.

Requirements: Lvl 50+ in any humanoid race.

Jake had liked the Windsoar enchant a lot. It removed wind resistance and made the normal arrows fly a bit faster. It even made them a bit more stealthy. He had noticed that after he began using his Arcane Arrows, the enchant’s effect had lessened, and by now, he doubted he could even use a fully charged Powershot without the bow breaking or suffering irreparable damage.

So, he had transmuted it with a focus on one thing: stability. He just wanted it to be as tough and durable as possible to support his firepower.

[Windsorrow Bow (Rare)] – A bow made from a tree inhabited by wind elementals, now corrupted beyond recognition by powerful arcane energies. The string is made of the sinew of beasts long forgotten. The blessing of the spirits once laid upon this bow has been devoured and transformed by the arcane energies, their final wishes and will made into nothing more than nourishment. All that they were now serves only one purpose: to make the bow as immutable as possible so that it may remain unchanged or be destroyed in its attempt to do so. Enchantments: Arcane Immutability.

Requirements: Lvl 75+ in any humanoid race. Quasi-Soulbound.

Now, Jake had a lot to say about the description, mainly about how it really painted him as a bad guy. Seriously, all he had done was transmute it a bit, and now it made him feel like he had just snuffed out the final legacy of a family of wind elementals.

Anywho, new bow in the bag. It looked the same as before, for the most part, but did have some subtle pink-purple lines running through it. It was also damn durable now and was overall a better weapon. No wind enchant, though. It was just a tough bow.

When he made it to the Fort, the guards only panicked a little until one of them recognized him and poked his partner in the side, giving him that look you give to your coworker to make them shut the fuck up and act like nothing is wrong.

Jake quickly made his way towards the workshops and was quite impressed by how much the place had changed.

So many houses now filled the plains surrounding the Fort, forcing Jake to take flight and fly over them to reach the inner area where he knew Arnold was. The big room where Jake had first seen him was now exclusively for the use of Arnold and those he invited in. The man had really set himself apart and was still making new inventions all the time.

Also, while the other crafters had been pushed out, that didn’t mean they complained. A huge complex had been constructed immediately around the Fort, and Jake saw that the courtyard, which used to be filled with tents, was now a bustling market.

He even spotted a few large booths by traders who proudly advertised they were from Sanctdomo. They had some interesting and unique stuff, but nothing Jake cared about. Instead, he went straight for the center fort.

There, he once more encountered two guards at the entrance. They both jumped a bit when he landed a few meters in front of the door, his large black dragon wings perhaps looking a bit unsettling. Luckily, one of the guards was once more an old soldier of the Fort and just made a salute and opened the door. Jake felt a bit weird about that, as he had never been in the military or anything like that. You only saluted others in the military, right?

Inside the building itself, he could go to the left, right, or straight ahead. To the left was Arnold’s workshop, but the first thing he did was go straight ahead to look at something equally interesting: the teleportation circle being built.

Jake walked into a large, circular room that had clearly been remodeled. It now had a dome-shaped ceiling with lots of small magic scripts on it, and in the middle was a large magic circle more than six meters across.

While in the room, Jake felt the space affinity from everywhere, and the atmospheric mana was nearly entirely space mana. It actually felt a bit weird to be in the room.

No one was there currently, and Jake could see things were still halfway done. Neil came by often and worked on it when not out with his party. It had actually been active for a time and had a corresponding magic circle back in Haven they used to transport goods, but Neil had moved that outside and begun remodeling the one in here. What they wanted right now was to possibly transport living things.

He had to admit, it all looked very impressive, even if he didn’t really understand it. Leaving the room once more, he finally went towards his real target and turned into the hallway towards Arnold’s workshop. Even now, he could hear the sounds of what seemed like welding coming from in there.

Arnold didn’t even notice Jake when he entered, as the man was too busy working. Jake saw him working on what looked like a four-legged robot hound of some sort. At least, that was the only name he could immediately call to mind.

Besides that, he saw so many other constructs strewn about—different kinds of gun-like weapons, what looked like pieces of armor, a lot of small orbs and balls of sorts, and generally just a huge bunch of small electrical devices. Jake could see he wasn't the only one who would have a real man cave. Or man fort.

There was more of one thing than anything else, however, and that was drones. Jake saw so damn many of them, and clearly… they saw him too.

Five of them took to the air the moment he entered and moved to protect Arnold, it seemed. The only thing they really did was make the man aware of Jake’s presence.

He turned around. "Ah, you’re here. I need you to help make bombs."

Jake was pretty sure he’d just gotten placed on some kind of watch list.

Chapter 27

Nanoblade

Jake had been sure Arnold was just joking when he asked him to make bombs, especially with the deadpan delivery. It turned out the man was earnest, as he scurried over and picked up a box of tennis ball-sized metal orbs.

Jake also spotted something on the table he recognized. It was a sword with pink-purple lines running through it, and on closer inspection, it was indeed one of the many swords he had experimented on and had transmuted with Arcane Conductivity.

While he did remember handing some over to Miranda and Lillian to maybe break apart for scrap or find some other use, he hadn’t known Arnold had picked one up. Several, actually, as he saw a few more scattered across many different worktables. One could say a lot about Arnold, but organized sure wasn’t one of them.

Arnold walked up to Jake with the box of metal balls as he said, "I will need you to infuse that destructive type of mana you used to create the swords into these balls to—"

"Now, why would I do that?" Jake asked, raising an eyebrow.

Miranda had told him that Arnold needed his help with something and had something he wanted to show Jake, which was why he’d decided to go. Yet his first experience here was that of immediately being told to work without any context.

"Oh," Arnold just said, looking confused. "These orbs are made to more easily absorb and integrate any mana affinity and store it till it is released in the form of an explosion, and of all the mana affinities I have seen, the one in the swords seem to carry the most destructive potential."

"No, I mean, what’s in it for me?" Jake clarified, now also looking a bit confused.

"… You can keep some?"

The man scratched his head after putting the box down, clearly not prepared for that question. Jake reckoned the guy had gotten used to just having the things he asked for, and he struck Jake as quite the one-track-mind kind of guy. A bit like himself, actually.

It made sense in some ways, as Arnold clearly was one of the most influential people in the Fort, and he had even surpassed Phillip in levels. Not by a little, either, as the man was now in the D-grade. Something Jake hadn’t seen coming.

[Human – lvl 101]

"Fine, I’ll look at it, but I want something else too,” Jake answered, only agreeing because he did want to try and mess with the balls a bit. “Any idea where I can get a good sword or dagger?"

"Hm, I can make you one?" Arnold said, scratching his head again as he scurried off to one of the shelves and took down a case. "Energy-based weapons seem to be the most efficient against most entities, but I have found that sometimes you do need a tool more suited for close combat and dealing with enemies with tough defenses, so I have worked on blades that can be attached."

He opened the case, and inside, Jake saw three approximately sixty-centimeter-long blades, each black as night and looking incredibly thin. Jake used Identify on the first one and was surprised at the result.

[Carbon Fiber Nanoblade (Uncommon)] – An ultrathin Nanoblade made out of Carbon Fiber, making it both incredibly durable and sharp. The blade itself can cut most materials effortlessly but has little to no effectiveness against magical wards or defenses. Due to the materials used, enchanting this blade is incredibly difficult.

Requirements: Lvl 80+ in any humanoid race.

The rarity itself was surprising, but even more so was that these were just the blades, not the entire weapons. Jake knew from experience that if a good handle were made, it would be possible to make a rare sword… making him realize that Arnold was actually pretty damn talented. As if him being D-grade wasn’t enough.

He couldn’t help but ask, "Say, have you been blessed by a god yet?"

"Hmm?" he exclaimed, tilting his head. "Ah, yes, I got one when I evolved my profession last time. Quite frightening, those gods. Not at all something I want to repeat any time soon."

"So, it’s a new thing?" Jake inquired.

"Fifty-six days. I did not bother with that Perfect Evolution thing; I cannot see any value in delaying my work for a few more stats. I did not have any immediate field tests planned, so waiting for my class to evolve simply wasn’t worth it.”

Quite reasonable, in Jake’s opinion. Arnold clearly cared far more about his profession than his class, even if his class was also at a relatively high level. Jake also realized that Arnold had evolved his profession before Jake had evolved himself, making him feel a bit weird. Though, to be fair, he could have evolved his class way before anyone on Earth if he didn’t care about alchemy.

"I see," Jake answered with a nod. "If you can make a weapon using these blades, I am sure we can figure something out."

"Shouldn’t be an issue. I have some handles already, but I will need to modify them a bit. They weren’t made for human hands."

"Were you trying to make sword-wielding robots?" Jake couldn’t help but ask a bit jokingly.

"Naturally," he answered with the same somber, deadpan expression. "Sword-wielding robots are awesome."

Jake just nodded slowly, having severe issues determining if Arnold was joking or not… because, by all accounts, he looked serious.

"Alright, deal. So, I just need to infuse these orbs with my arcane affinity and make them into bombs?"

"Arcane affinity? Not the name I would have given it. But yes, that destructive variant, and please inject it till the pin is fully inserted into the orb and then stop.” He showed Jake a small pin with a ring on the end.

This is one hundred percent just a grenade.

"Got it," Jake answered as the two of them split up and got to work. Was it an entirely fair trade, with Jake getting a weapon for infusing some orbs with mana? Probably not, but Arnold seemed perfectly fine with it.

Jake went over to the table with the box, took up one of the orbs, and observed it.

[Aluabsorbant Metal Sphere (Common)] – A sphere made of a composite metal by an extremely talented craftsman. Due to the materials used, this sphere has incredibly high conductivity and can effortlessly absorb and store most types of mana affinities. Once the orb has absorbed enough mana, the trigger pin will be fully inserted. Pulling the pin will release all the stored mana at once after a slight delay. (Charge: 0%)

He didn’t hesitate to begin inserting his destructive arcane mana into the first one. He didn’t use Touch of the Malefic Viper, as he didn’t aim to transmute it and knew doing so would likely ruin the orb or make it Quasi-Soulbound like everything else. Arnold only needed the mana, nothing more.

After half a minute, he was amazed to see that the metal sphere kept absorbing mana. He was already 1000 deep. A minute later, he frowned. He had now infused 3000 mana and was afraid something would go wrong if he kept going. Just as he considered stopping, he heard a click as the pin fully inserted.

Jake held up the orb, which just looked like a near-perfect sphere with the pin sticking out the top. It had a bit of a purple tinge now, but otherwise, it looked the same as before. The description had only changed the Charge meter from 0% to 100%.

3800 mana was what it took to charge a single orb. Jake saw dozens of orbs in the box and knew he had a task ahead of him. He got to work as Arnold tinkered in the background.

--

Jake once more stepped through the plains, a smile on his lips as he thought about the loot. He had hoped for a rare-rarity blade, but that hadn’t happened. It wasn’t all bad, though, as the weapon was a lot better than before.

[Nanoblade Sword (Uncommon)] – The blade is an ultrathin Nanoblade made out of Carbon Fiber, making it both incredibly durable and sharp. The blade itself can cut most materials effortlessly but has little to no effectiveness against magical wards or defenses. The blade itself has little to no mana conductivity. Infusing mana into the handle will automatically coat the blade’s edge in mana. Enchantment: Modelled Coating.

Requirements: Lvl 100+ in any humanoid race.

Now, the description hadn’t changed much, but what had changed was the level requirement. The blade was now officially a D-grade weapon, and Arnold had said he gave it one final round of tempering before it was put together. The handle had the same enchant as the one the man had wanted for his robots, so it wasn’t that useful to Jake, as he already knew how to coat his weapons in mana. He could see it being effective for a robot, though.

Jake was interested in Arnold’s class and profession but hadn’t lingered to ask him about details. He hadn’t asked what god had blessed him either; Arnold had just said it was one related to making machines.

He had also gotten ten of the orbs, only on the promise that he would share their effectiveness when he got back. Jake had spent nearly an entire day at the man’s place infusing them, and only getting ten did sting a bit. Oh, and it wasn’t like he took a lot either, as it turned out that Arnold didn’t just have one box, but six. Yes, Jake went through a lot of mana potions.

The hundred and thirty kilometers back to Haven from the Fort were crossed even more swiftly on his return trip. He could take several steps a second easily, though he couldn’t make running steps; they were closer to powerwalking. It took quite a bit of concentration to use the skill consecutively like that. Also, he didn’t exactly make himself go faster by putting his hands behind his back and trying to look like a mysterious old master either. The skill required one to "walk" when making consecutive steps, though there was some leeway in what exactly counted as walking.

He made it back in less than twenty minutes. Jake could have gone faster for sure, but he found it more important to further improve his familiarity with One Step Mile after reaching D-grade.

Jake took flight when he got close and flew over the city directly to his valley. There, everything looked just as usual. This surprised him, as Hank should have started doing stuff by now, but as he got closer, his sphere picked up that there were indeed things happening below the lodge.

Hank and four other men were down there, and what he saw was just damn weird.

One of the men touched the ground, which caused a deep hole already being made to grow deeper before expelling large chunks of earth. Another man waved his hand and directed hundreds of kilos—if not tons—of soil and stone into a weird-looking cross between a bag and a trashcan.

Jake considered if he should go talk to them. Usually, he would avoid it… but he decided not to act as antisocial as he normally would so he could check in on the construction.

He entered the cellar with a smile—one no one could see, as he wore his mask. "Hello, there. How’re things going?" he asked in a casual tone, trying to be friendly.

All the men, including Hank, turned around, and a few of them yelped when they saw him. Hank didn’t heed it but answered, "Swimmingly. We are already over a hundred meters down now, and based on our estimates, we can begin forming the cave after thirty more."

"That is a bit further down than expected," Jake admitted as he frowned. "Will the Pylon be able to reach down that far?"

"I had Miranda check it, and there are no issues. In fact, the cavern with the dungeon is already under the influence of the Pylon. The aura it gives off is blocked by solid objects such as soil, but it can enter through that when there is an opening. It doesn’t go as far up or down as sideways, but Miranda said that is largely due to her own actions. She has chosen to focus all her energy on encompassing the Fort as soon as possible. It’s a waste they’re not getting the Pylon bonuses right now, and Miranda isn’t getting anything from their presence either.”

"Hm, thanks for the update," Jake answered, taking out a small bag of potions. "Take these and keep up the good work. I am going dungeon diving now."

"Alright, be careful. Hopefully things will be mostly done by the time you return, depending on how long you take."

"No worries if it isn’t—I am not in that much of a rush," Jake said, waving it off. "Oh, final thing. Saw the time tree up there? It would be best if you stationed someone close by to keep an eye on it, pick any banana that ripens, and eat it right away. 3 Agility per banana eaten. Do make sure it is someone who needs the stats, though.”

"Sure?" Hank answered, a bit confused.

"Bananas don’t grow on trees?" another worker mumbled, Jake completely ignoring him.

With that done, Jake didn’t have anything more on his bucket list. He went down the cave and into the once-a-biodome cavern.

He jumped down the hole and onto the platform as the message appeared:

Dungeon: Undergrowth of the Deepdwellers

Requirements to enter: D-grade

Requirements to enter met.

WARNING: Only 5 challengers are allowed per party attempting the dungeon.

Enter Dungeon?

Y/N

Jake only briefly considered that much of the bonus information and warnings from the tutorial days were gone. Well, it had been a tutorial, hadn’t it?

Without further ado, he accepted and was swept away to his first dungeon since the tutorial.

With a whoosh and a whish, the bad beast was cut into pieces by her awesome blades of wind. They weren’t as good as Dad’s, but they were still super-duper strong. Mom didn’t do wind as good as her and dad, but she did big beams that went BOOM, and she made big monsters appear to beat the bad guys. That was also pretty cool.

Sylphie was flying through the forest as she fought the bad guys. They looked a bit like Uncle but had a lot more hair and tails, and they kept jumping around between the trees using their tails or throwing stuff. She wondered how Uncle would look with a tail… She didn’t like it. A bit more hair would be okay, though, especially on the head. Hair was a lot fluffier than feathers.

"Scree!" she heard from the side as Mom flew over and told her to follow them further into the forest.

Sylphie wasn’t allowed to beat the bad guys with three tails. Only mom and dad could fight those, so she would just blow away the other ones. Beating those wasn’t that hard, even if they were a bit higher level. They were just weak, and her super winds were super strong, and the stupid beasts were too slow ever to hit her when they threw stuff, and their silly heavy-thing didn’t work against her Green Shield. Green Shield was super great.

Dad had also told her that Uncle had already been in the area before and killed the boss of the bad guys. Dad kept saying that Uncle was super strong, but Sylphie wasn’t sure. Uncle only ever sat on his butt and played with his weird pot, so how could he be super strong? Only his smelly pot was really strong. Maybe he’d thrown the smelly pot at the bad guy boss?

Sylphie did feel that Uncle was a bit strong himself, but compared to Mom and Dad? Nah, Mom and Dad were super much stronger. But it was okay, because Sylphie could always protect Uncle so he could play with his smelly pot as much as he wanted!

Sylphie was super kind like that.

Chapter 28

Evil Incarnate

You have entered the dungeon: Undergrowth of the Deepdwellers

Objective: Lay your hand upon the Heart of the Undergrowth.

Jake came to and opened his eyes just as the message appeared. He quickly skimmed it and frowned. This was the first time he entered a non-challenge dungeon that didn’t tell him to just go kill a big boss. Instead, he had to touch some Heart? He assumed it was a figurative thing, but with magic, he could totally see some massive beating mushroom or plant heart being a thing.

He found himself within a small, damp cave, and outside a vast underground cavern sprawled out before him. Walking out of the small cave, he finally saw the landscape—because it was truly a landscape.

The entire cavern looked to have a width of at least ten kilometers and a length that spanned longer than he could even see. A constant damp mist hung everywhere, making him unable to see all the way to the other end despite his insane Perception.

Jake found the biome quite interesting. There were many different kinds of mushrooms and fungi and other types of plants, including some full-on trees that looked like pine trees. It was very dense and reminded Jake of the biodome the Indigo Fungus had created, albeit with far more growth.

Sense of the Malefic Viper helped him feel the many affinities permeating the atmospheric mana, and he found the life affinity to be the most overpowering by far. Next up was the water affinity, as the humidity of the entire cavern was at a level where he feared mold growing on his cloak. Besides that, there was plenty of dark affinity, as the cavern didn’t have any proper lighting at all.

Besides a few glowing mushrooms or the occasional shifting light in the distance, there was nothing else. Luckily for Jake, he didn’t really need natural light to see anymore, and the darkness caused by the dark affinity wasn’t an issue either.

So far, he hadn’t seen any living things, and his sphere hadn’t picked up any movement, even more than three hundred meters in front of him. At least, it didn’t right away… but soon he saw movement. It was only when he exited the cavern where the door to leave the dungeon still stood that these creatures seemed to notice him.

Yes, there was a door to exit for some reason, even if he had entered through a big metal disc. The system seemed to have taken a liking to old wooden doors, and Jake wasn’t going to waste energy trying to find out why.

Focusing on his sphere, he zoned in on the movement and saw what it was. It looked like a hunched-over humanoid figure with long, bat-like ears and a mouth full of sharp teeth. It didn’t have any eyes but instead had what looked like two oversized nostril holes. It looked pretty bizarre, to be sure.

The creature was incredibly skinny, wore a loincloth, and carried a wooden spear. Its movements were fast, and Jake saw the nostrils move as he became certain it knew he was there. Finally, he used Identify on it.

[Deepdweller – lvl 109]

The Deepdweller, as it was called—the dungeon’s name now suddenly made a lot more sense—made a weird movement as it raised its head and opened its mouth.

Jake heard an almost inaudible sound that seemed to spread far and wide from the Deepdweller. He felt the mana spread through the air along with the sound, and it didn’t take a genius to put together what it had done: It was a call for assistance, or perhaps a warning call. In either case, it led to even more movement in the distance.

He cracked his neck from side to side as he prepared. His foes did look partly humanoid, but he didn’t feel a very high level of intellect from them. Sure, they could use tools in a very basic way, but so could pre-system chimpanzees when taught. No, more than anything else, he trusted his own intuition. These Deepdwellers were monsters, through and through.

His assessment only proved truer as more began pouring out. Some of them didn’t even wear any clothes. This variant was far bulkier and looked a lot stronger. Instead of the rather human-like hands that the first Deepdweller had, this one had four long, sharp claws instead of four fingers. As for its level, it was actually lower than the first one.

[Deepdweller – lvl 104]

Not that it mattered, as they were all so damn low level, in Jake’s opinion. So low he wouldn’t even gain any experience by killing them. So he wouldn’t unless he felt he needed to.

Jake walked forwards and let his aura rip. He didn’t bother even making an attempt at stealth. Instead, he would move forward till he met something worth fighting. He hoped that the dungeon wasn’t made for a level lower than him, and that it got more difficult the further in he went.

From talks with Villy, he knew dungeons could come in many forms. Some of them were super short, like the Badger’s Den, and others were practically their own small world. This one at least didn’t look that small, and he knew that the larger a dungeon was, the larger the level disparity there usually was.

The Deepdwellers didn’t react well to Jake ignoring them. They hissed as he got closer, and the brute ran straight for him with its sharp claws raised. It had three more comrades now—two with spears and one who wore an old, tattered robe. Only the brute was stupid enough to attack.

"You sure you wanna do that, buddy?" Jake asked as he looked at the Deepdweller.

Gaze of the Apex Hunter activated, and the big Deepdweller froze up for a second, stumbled a few more steps, and fell down to the ground with foam frothing at its mouth. Knocked unconscious.

Eh, a bit more effective than I anticipated, but I guess it did the job? Jake thought as he saw the three Deepdwellers, who’d been staring at him, bolt away into the undergrowth. He had decided to call the weird mixed biome of mushrooms, trees, and bushes the undergrowth, as that was what the dungeon was called.

Just as he was about to run further in, the big Deepdweller sprang up, looking around in confusion before it saw Jake. It screeched, and he was prepared to kill it if it was stupid enough to attack again. Instead, it ran directly away from him… in the direction he was heading.

With a chuckle, Jake decided to have some fun. He followed, much to the dismay of the Deepdweller.

It kept making hissing and screeching sounds as he tailed it. Jake primarily wondered how it even detected him being on its trail. As it didn’t have eyes, he assumed it used some other sensory organ. He had already noted the large ears, which made him assume they had excellent hearing, and the nostrils also indicated a great sense of smell. Besides that, he assumed they had some mana sense, as most monsters tended to have that.

Jake had learned such a sense had as much to do with sensing enemies and prey as it had with finding natural treasures. It was a part of the basic toolkit for pretty much all monsters, which was likely also why his stealth skill had included hiding from mana sense in one of the earliest upgrades.

Anyway, his friendly trip with the scared shitless Deepdweller didn’t end up taking that long. They were both fast, so a dozen kilometers was crossed in a jiffy. Jake didn’t know if it was due to the stupidity of the big Deepdweller or not, but it had decided to lead him straight to a village of sorts.

Quite a few of these Deepdwellers, he noted. He counted around a hundred in the village, and he began Identifying them to get a general feel for their levels using his sphere.

104.

106.

103.

110.

None of them were worth his time… at least he hadn’t thought so till he inspected those in the largest tent. There, four Deepdwellers in robes sat around a goddamn mushroom and looked to be in meditation. Not only that—when he Identified them, he saw true horror.

[Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 131]

[Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 125]

[Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 126]

[Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 134]

Jake was a person who didn’t believe in objective morality. He didn’t believe anything was inherently good or evil but knew those were definitions created by society. For those who studied social sciences or read a few too many blogs, good and evil would be referred to as social constructs. This is to say, good or evil were one hundred percent subjective terms.

Yet today, he was swayed in that belief.

Mushrooms were—according to him—evil. Villy liked mushrooms, but at least he liked to eat them. But these… Deepdwellers… These monsters… They didn’t just eat mushrooms, or control them as tools… They lived in synergy with them.

The Fungalmancers’ cloaks weren’t there just to cover their bare skin, but also the many fungi growing all over their bodies. They were living incubators of evil, abominations, a mix between Deepdweller and fungus. Jake knew it was his job—nay, responsibility—to purge this objective evil from the world.

Jake would not strike from the darkness this time. No, he would walk in and crush them in his malefic crusade.

Also, it would be a bit hard to sneak in with the panicking Deepdweller storming into the village, making loud screeching sounds and putting the entire settlement on edge with all its ruckus. The Fungalmancers reacted by getting up from their meditation and heading outside to see what was going on.

Jake just walked straight in, not caring as the Deepdwellers mobilized themselves. He would have expected more intelligent creatures to set up a perimeter, but these monsters weren’t that smart. They just charged out of the village towards Jake. Most of them were of the big-clawed or spear-wielding variants, but he did also see a few with slings and cloaks.

It was a bit weird to see D-grades that he still equated with power look so primitive. But they were truly D-grade, and he could feel they were strong… just far from strong enough. Before, Jake had wanted to show mercy, but no more. They were mushroom-loving monsters. Also, upon reflection, not wanting to kill dungeon creatures didn’t make much sense. In the grand scheme of things, it wouldn’t matter. All that mattered was if he wanted to kill them or not, and while they wouldn’t give him experience, killing them would give him a feeling of having made the world a slightly better place.

A blade appeared in each of his hands—one a scimitar that was already hungering, and the other a long, thin blade with a simple sheath. These heathens did not deserve the mercy of his bow. Instead, they would die by the sword.

The first one who reached him was a spear-wielding Deepdweller. It didn’t attack right away, appearing hesitant. Jake didn’t bother striking it down but instead waited for the second arrival. This one was one of the big brutes, and it didn’t have the same sense of self-preservation.

His scimitar flew up, the edge already covered in a purple sheen of arcane energy. The extended claw aiming for his head was cut in two as the blade dug deep into the flesh of the Deepdweller, nearly cutting it entirely in two.

Not that it mattered. The other blade flew up, mana already coating and extending its edge as he decapitated the D-grade in a swift slash. The Nanoblade cut through the neck like nothing. The blade was sharp as hell—that was for sure.

The headless Deepdweller didn’t die right away but stumbled and swayed a bit, its one remaining claw swiping the air until it finally fell to the ground. The notification came a moment later.

*You have slain [Deepdweller – lvl 101]*

Jake hadn’t moved, and after the kill, neither did the Deepdwellers. His swift execution of their comrade made even the bigger versions of the Deepdwellers hesitate and hang back.

Until the true harbingers of evil arrived, that was. The four Fungalmancers walked towards Jake. The Deepdwellers ranged in height from around a hundred and fifty centimeters to almost two and a half meters. The Fungalmancers were all far bigger than that, towering over everything else at nearly four meters each.

The biggest of them snarled and made a hissing sound, making all the Deepdwellers freeze up. A few of the closest to Jake reluctantly moved forward as four more Deepdwellers charged towards him.

*You have slain [Deepdweller – lvl 105]*

*You have slain [Deepdweller – lvl 107]*

*You have slain [Deepdweller – lvl 109]*

*You have slain [Deepdweller – lvl 105]*

"Stop fucking around," Jake said after swiftly executing the four of them. They were only about as strong as the monkeys individually—AKA, far too weak to pose any true threat to him. For him to kill a monster below his own level was just too easy. Unless they had some insane variant race or were a Unique Lifeform, he didn’t see himself losing.

He doubted the Fungalmancers understood his taunt, but they did understand his strength and his unabashed killing intent. Seemingly aware they could no longer hold back, they made their move.

All four of them threw off their cloaks to reveal their disgusting bodies. Small mushrooms were growing straight out of their flesh, and mold and other types of fungi covered nearly every inch, making them look half-rotten.

One of the Fungalmancers placed its palms on the ground and stuck its fingers in as Jake felt the mana in the area come alive. Another one began sinking into the ground, while a third howled. Jake, with his high Perception, saw the latter exhale millions of small spores all over the area. The final Fungalmancer did the most surprising thing as it took out a small crystal and ate it.

The spores released weren’t aimed at Jake, but at all of the Deepdwellers hesitantly staying back. Jake saw it touch their bodies, and it was as if something awakened within them. Mold began growing on their bodies, and Jake felt their auras spike as an extreme level of life-affinity energy was emitted from every last one of them.

As a single entity, they attacked, all hesitation now gone. The Deepdwellers mindlessly tried to stab him with spears or claw him to death, and even the ones who held slings tossed them aside as they attacked with their bare hands.

Jake couldn’t help but smirk as he moved. He completely ignored the hundred-plus crazed Deepdwellers, heading straight for the Fungalmancers. Wings appeared on his back, blood burning within, as he took his first flap towards the Manipulators of Evil with toxic mist in his wake.

He had aimed his blade at the one who had exhaled earlier, but just as the Nanoblade descended, several vines sprang up to defend it, and a hand nearly the size of Jake’s entire upper body moved to block.

Several vines were cut, and the Nanoblade got halfway through the hand. He looked at the creature it had come from: the Fungalmancer that had eaten the crystal and was now midway through quite the transformation.

Only its one arm had been affected so far, but massive, cancerous growths with mold and fungi growing from them popped up all over its body as it grew in size, adding tens of centimeters every second and making it into a hulking abomination. Jake would expect nothing less from a creature that dared call itself a Fungalmancer.

He was actually a bit glad… He could not only purge the world of evil, but possibly also get some good fights out of this dungeon.

Chapter 29

Questionable Choices

Jake bent his back as he avoided a wooden spear trying to impale him from behind, then, in a spinning motion, cut the Deepdweller that had attacked him in two with his scimitar. The kill didn’t even make any of the other Deepdwellers hesitate; they came bearing down on him.

He released a wave of arcane mana with a scoff, pushing back the closest Deepdwellers as he once more turned to kill the Fungalmancers. The hulking abomination Fungalmancer attacked him in response. It was now nearly eight meters tall, with its arms even longer than its entire body was high. They looked more like long vines with hands attached to their ends.

Jake dove under the first swipe and cut into the arm with both his blades as he ran alongside it. The Fungalmancer hissed in response and tried to squash him with its other hand, but the hunter was too fast; he jumped and went straight for the head.

Four large vines sprang up from the ground, but Jake had already seen them coming in his sphere and used Shadow Vault to move forward just a little bit faster to dodge them. It was a skill he didn’t use that often, and he quickly remembered why as he felt his mana and stamina drain significantly. It used more based on how strong his body was, as far as he could tell, and he even took note that the spores in the air needed to be "faded through," only increasing cost further.

But it got the job done, as Jake was free from interference. He stabbed his sword down towards the forehead of the Fungalmancer. Or, well, at least where he expected the forehead to be. It was so mutated with cancerous growths and fungi it was hard to recognize the hulking form as even remotely humanoid.

The sword penetrated straight into the head of the Fungalmancer, sinking to the hilt without any issue. Jake frowned. It felt wrong, and the movements of the abomination appeared unaffected, forcing Jake to withdraw his blade and jump back.

On the way, he saw the wound close up at a visible rate. Is it natural vitality or life magic of some kind? he questioned as he jumped to the side, avoiding another round of attacks. The small army of Deepdwellers was getting a bit annoying, but he would rather just kill the Fungalmancers. Also, it was an enjoyable new experience to fight while at the same time being hounded by a group of weaker enemies. Well, they would die eventually anyway… Even now, they bathed in his poison mist.

With the hulking monstrosity a bit too annoying to kill, he moved to the three others first. Well, two others, as one had sunken into the ground. Jake did see the guy sitting a good hundred meters below, as he was the one who manipulated all those vines.

The two he could target were the spore-spewer and the one with its hands in the ground—the one who seemed to slowly infuse the ground with his life-affinity mana. Was it strengthening them? Some kind of long-term ritual? Well, he would love to find out, so he went for the spore-spewer first.

It had yet to stop spewing them out, and Jake could see why. The entourage of weaker Deepdwellers got stronger by the second as more and more growths appeared on their bodies from the spores. Their plan had likely been for the vine guy and the big guy to keep Jake occupied while two of them powered up and overwhelmed him with the army.

Sadly for them, they were thoroughly outmatched.

Jake stepped through space and appeared right before the spore-spewer. It was the first time he had used One Step Mile in the fight, taking them all by complete surprise. The Nanoblade swept horizontally to deeply cut the Fungalmancer’s abdomen.

Before striking again, he jumped to the side, avoiding an incoming assault of vines, and attacked with the sword. This time he managed to cut off an arm as the Fungalmancer tried to block in vain. The monster spewed out even more spores towards Jake as retaliation, and he felt them invade his entire body and take root on his skin.

He felt the fungi dig into him, consuming his blood and the vital energy in his body. It was unpleasant, and he even felt that the spores carried a slight paralyzing poison—one that naturally didn’t have any effect.

Drink up, he thought, smiling as his blood turned toxic. All the spores withered instantly and turned to dust, and the Fungalmancer only had time to flash its nostrils in surprise before Jake landed a finishing blow. His blade burned with dark and arcane mana as he stabbed the monster right in the mouth.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 126] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

One down.

Jake stepped forward and teleported back as he avoided another attack of vines. He turned his attention to the hulking guy, as he didn’t want to deal with the one infusing energy into the ground. It was guarded by over a dozen Deepdwellers functioning as living walls, but even then, it would be the easier kill. The issue was… he really wanted to see what it was trying to do.

The monstrosity attacked him as he ran for it again, making simple and heavily telegraphed attacks. Each of its blows tore up the ground, and he had to admit that getting hit directly would hurt. If it could hit him.

Once more, he cut into its arm and danced around it, slicing and dicing its body. Each cut was incredibly deep and made pus and blood spew out, yet the hulking Fungalmancer seemed unaffected, and the wounds continued to heal at a visible rate. He also noted that the blood and pus that spewed out was coated in spores, meaning even its bodily fluids were now weapons.

Jake did notice how fragile its entire body seemed and frowned at how annoying it was to put down. He decided to get just a tiny bit more serious as he jumped back and summoned a bottle. It contained common-rarity Necrotic Poison that he had made during his practice to create the uncommon-rarity version, which meant it was top-tier. He didn’t want to waste his precious uncommon-rarity poison on these Fungalmancers. He had a lot of dungeon to go, after all.

After coating both blades while dodging the Deepdwellers and vine attacks, he moved in to attack the monstrosity once more. All of his sword cuts from before had already healed, but he had a feeling the next wounds wouldn’t be fixed as easily.

His blades tore into it, and this time it didn’t go as before, as it failed to heal. The wounds blackened and decayed as the hulking abomination screamed in pain while the poisoned swords dug into it again and again. Jake could feel the constant fight between his poison and the life energy of the Fungalmancer. It tried to hold on, but Jake went in for the finishing blow.

Dodging yet another round of annoying vines, he stabbed the blades deeply into the abomination and quickly placed both palms on it as Touch of the Malefic Viper activated.

The poison spread from his touch, invading every inch of it and further amplifying the Necrotic Poison. It didn’t even have time to move before Jake was done and dodged back again to avoid another vine attack. Two dark green handprints remained as it collapsed to the ground, dead. Then, with a wave of Jake’s hands, the swords flew out of the corpse and into his hands.

With the big guy down, only two remained. The one with its hands on the ground huffed a bit more with its nose holes, and Jake assumed it was stressed or scared. Unfortunately, it was a bit hard to tell, as they weren’t exactly the most human-looking creatures.

Jake wondered how he should kill the one hiding so deep underground. He didn’t have any effective attack that could go down there, except maybe forming beams of arcane mana or something? Could he even do that?

He thought about these things as he elegantly dodged all the Deepdwellers attacking him to keep him busy, not caring that much about them at all. Their weapons of choice were even coated with venom, he had come to learn, making him care even less. The spears and claws were all covered in some mushroom venom, and while Jake was a bit surprised he hadn’t felt it with Sense of the Malefic Viper, he just chalked that up to the venom being parts of their bodies or something.

With little effort, he cut down the Deepdwellers one by one as he waited for the grand finale. He could now feel that the life affinity in the air had grown to an extreme level, and he felt it was soon time.

Finally, it happened. The Fungalmancer wore what he assumed was a cheerful smile as it made one last push.

A green explosion of mana came out of it, washing over all the Deepdwellers and Jake alike. At the same time, he saw the Fungalmancer begin sinking into the ground like its comrade, making him frown for a moment… but he didn’t have time to address it here and now.

The green wave hadn’t been aimed to damage Jake—at least, not directly. A bit of mold had grown on his shitty cloak, and he saw the fungi begin to glow green as it absorbed the green energy. The same thing happened to all the moss-covered Deepwellers that surrounded him as they all pounced… and for the first time that day, Jake felt his sense of danger give a noteworthy response.

Oh… I guess I should have seen that coming? Jake thought as the intensity of the green light they all gave off amplified. He barely had time to save the cloak by burning the fungi off with arcane mana and throwing it in his storage before the attack came.

Well, shit. In the final moment, he covered his body in scales, summoned a bubble of arcane mana around himself, and then knelt down and covered his head with his arms.

Fucking mushrooms.

*BOOM!*

An entire area, several kilometers in diameter, exploded in an intense green light that sought to destroy everything by leveling an entire section of the dungeon—one with Jake smack in the middle.

Sanctdomo had been busier than ever since the World Congress, and like most other cities and factions, they had begun a push to have as many D-grades as possible available for the Treasure Hunt. Of course, Jacob and the rest of the leaders were fully aware that the strongest participants would obtain the best rewards, but that didn’t mean numbers were useless. Especially as the system had dropped hints that the event wouldn’t just be a pure death game, but one that could be pulled out of when one’s life was in danger.

Jacob sat in his small office, going over some reports of possible prospects with hundreds of pages flying all around him. Mana control had never come easy for him but had gotten a bit more refined after reaching D-grade. It had taken many weeks of practice, but in the end, he had finally gotten a good grasp of it.

The papers detailed people determined to have the potential to reach D-grade within the next two months to attend the Treasure Hunt. He did this every day, as he liked to know the names and identities of the future elite of the city, and sometimes he even got lucky and got a revelation when he saw a specific person.

One of the papers caught his eye—a blacksmith. One he recognized. It was one of many he hadn’t talked to in a long time, and the last time they spoke, he had been stuck at level 68, and Jacob had advised him to go into teaching.

Jacob smiled. He had failed to break through back then because he was too stuck in his own old-world ways. With forty years of experience, he had heavily ingrained habits, and he had his own way of doing things and wasn’t that open to change. He thought he was already as good as he could get, and that had held him back. Jacob had thus advised him to give up… so that he could start over.

He'd evolved his profession a week ago, Jacob could see. When he had given up and gone into teaching, he had seen things he had never even considering doing before, and in his attempt to teach better, he had found inspiration and broken through. His mindset had changed, and his barrier was overcome. Now he was open to improvement and no longer set in his old ways, but still with four decades of experience to pull from. He had transformed from someone who likely wouldn’t ever level again in his life to an elite prospect with an assured path to D-grade, if not beyond.

That was one part Jacob disliked about being an Augur—he couldn’t just tell people what to do if he wanted the best result. The Records from figuring things out and experiencing enlightenment were worth infinitely more than just being told what one should do. This meant that Jacob sometimes had to be a bit roundabout and couldn’t directly tell people, only set them on a better path; they would have to walk it independently.

Jacob had done so many times, and he remembered every single one like it was yesterday. It was his calling to lead people towards their most ideal fate, after all.

Of the people he had done it with, some had more sure paths than others, and some he did were borderline pure gambles. One of those examples was a certain space mage he had just seen again for the first time during the World Congress. Neil was his name, and Jacob had sent him and his comrades towards Haven so long ago.

That one had been a bit selfish. As a whole, Jacob and the Holy Church had a strong ambition to establish a teleportation network on Earth quickly so they could unite their many cities and more promptly make diplomatic relations.

Jacob had known Neil was incredibly talented when it came to space magic formations and teleportation, so he’d sent him towards his old friend to make sure he had a space mage in his city. Did Jacob know it would work? No. What could he predict related to Haven? Nothing at all. Jake’s mere presence as the City Owner blocked all that.

Yet Jacob had chosen to have faith. Sometimes that was all he could have. Jake himself was a black hole when it came to fate, and he screwed everything he was related to divination-wise. Jacob hadn’t even known Neil was in Haven till the World Congress began, though he had heard reports of Haven having a space mage.

In some ways, it was a bit exciting, and in others, absolutely terrifying. Jacob was just glad that Jake was his friend. He knew he was—not due to magic or divination or whatever, but because he trusted his own judgment of character. Sometimes even more than he trusted fate itself.

He still remembered his experience in the tutorial. It had been the most painful and hardest thing he had ever done, and he knew it had made him look like the bad guy, as he had essentially herded his own comrades towards their deaths while lying to them… but it truly had been the best choice at the time, in his mind.

As an Augur, he was to realize fate, and killing William would have gone against that. Jacob realized his choice not to kill him that day had as much to do with him somehow following fate’s plan as with him being merciful. Those two together somehow pushed him over the edge to qualify as an Augur, even if he still wasn’t sure if that should really be enough. He had decided to just not think about it…

Back in the tutorial, he had lied to them and given them hope for them to keep pushing themselves. To keep leveling and keep getting race levels for one goal only: reach E-grade before William awakened. And he had succeeded with every single one of them.

The reason for that was simple… It would allow them to "live" longer.

A soul’s absolute maximum lifespan was determined by grade due to the qualitative change a race evolution brought. When a soul was sent to the Holyland, it would exist as a Holy Spirit for the maximum lifespan possible of their grade. Him having gotten them to E-grade had bought all of them hundreds of years.

Yet he could not tell them that was what he’d done till the last day. So he had to make them hold onto a false hope to keep them progressing. It had made him feel like shit, but the result was truly the best it could have been. Except, perhaps, having had Jake interfere… but that fate was not one he had seen or even been aware of then. Perhaps his biggest regret.

While a Holy Spirit did live as a human did—they still had the same form and everything—they did have the fatal flaw of never being able to leave the Holyland. They also could never level. It was just a place to live out their lives.

It was one of the big pulls of the Holy Church. Anyone blessed or even Baptized could go to the Holyland and live out the rest of their maximum lifespan there. This was even worth it for those who died a natural death, as the maximum lifespan of a grade was something few races ever reached, save for a few such as the undead—yet another reason the Holy Church didn’t like them.

All in all… Jacob tried his best; he truly did. He wanted what was best for everyone and for people to be the best they could be. He didn’t like that, sometimes, the individual would have to suffer for the masses, or the masses suffer for one extraordinary individual, so he tried to go for win-wins whenever possible.

But… sometimes that wasn’t possible. This was one reason William had to be left alive… He was too important to kill. His fate was too grand to stomp out just to save the lives of a few dozen humans who would likely never reach D-grade, no matter how harsh that sounded.

Things had worked out this time with the smith, but he couldn’t expect it to always go well. Like with William. He could only do his best and believe in others. Thus was the fate of an Augur of Hope.

Chapter 30

Golden Mushroom

One can have too much of a good thing. Something that would usually be highly beneficial could become unstable and even destructive in too large of amounts or too high a concentration. Life energy was no exception.

The Deepdwellers were infused with so much life that their entire bodies couldn’t take it anymore, and all had to be released. This resulted in the explosion that infused everything caught in it with so much life it died—only to rise again.

The massive area infected by the explosion suddenly sprang to life once more, with massive plants and mushrooms growing rapidly. The only ones that didn’t rise were the Deepdwellers, who had been the cause of the explosion. Their lives had been fuel for growth, as the life energy had to come from somewhere.

Yet this growth would only be temporary, a single cycle before the innate life energy in the entire area was used up. It would take years for it to return to a stable state once more. It was a sacrifice the Fungalmancers had been willing to make to strike down the invader.

But… once more, they had been under a severe misunderstanding.

The suicide attack was undoubtedly powerful and could kill most early D-grades without any issues. At a minimum, it would leave them crippled from the overflow of life energy and make their own bodies turn against them. An influx of too much vital energy was incredibly dangerous, as Jake had already experienced before during the Challenge Dungeon when he consumed his amalgamation. The energy back then had even been neutral and not actively trying to harm him. This time, he was struck with life mana actively seeking to end him, but such a thing was easier said than done.

In the middle of the huge area that was currently experiencing explosive growth, a single area stood unaffected.

A figure was kneeling on the ground, covered in dark green scales. Blood flowed from the tiny gaps between the scales as he gritted his teeth and stood up. A pink-purple current ran across his body as any small, annoying growths were instantly eliminated.

More noteworthy was the blade sticking out of his chest. The scimitar glowed in an almost cheerful red light as it drank the foreign life energy from its owner. Standing up, Jake observed the area in his sphere and noted the peculiar effects of the explosion.

"Should have learned to focus the effect a bit more," he chuckled, shaking his head.

See, this was why big, fancy explosions weren’t always the best way to go. So much life energy had been wasted by simply soaking into the ground and leading to growth instead of harming Jake.

Now, if one really wanted the best effect of big explosions, the optimal way would be to make stuff explode from within the target. Jake was certain the King would agree. This entire ordeal was actually a bit reminiscent of back then. It even included the entire contaminated area and stuff like that, except for one big difference—the explosion back then had been even more powerful. The King surviving it to keep fighting had been a testament to his durability.

Jake had only survived back then because his energy was the source of the explosion, and all he’d been hit by was the impact. That was also after the vast majority had been focused within the King, and the energy back then had also been far more focused in the immediate area around the King. Jake had survived the explosion this time because he was simply too durable for such a thing to take him down.

Between his arcane barrier, Scales of the Malefic Viper, and his subsequent application of arcane mana to destroy any mana getting too close, he’d eliminated the vast majority of energy. What he failed to stop, he had the Scimitar of Cursed Hunger absorb. Granted, stabbing yourself in the gut to absorb overflowing life energy wasn’t the optimal choice, but it was better than dealing with tumors.

Jake hadn’t handled the fight as well as he could, but he believed it was still a valuable experience in the long run. He had just started the dungeon, so learning what enemies were capable of was beneficial. Also, it was a new experience for sure. While Jake had tried to be supercharged with life energy before, it had never been by a foreign, antagonistic type that held clear intent to kill him.

Now, Jake only had one issue remaining… Those fungal-loving fuckers hiding below.

"Either you come up… or I make you come up," Jake said.

Could he ignore them and lose nearly nothing? Sure, he could. But he wouldn’t. Justice had to be carried out, after all.

Jake re-summoned his wings—they had been destroyed in the explosion earlier, as he couldn’t adequately protect them—and took to the air. On his way up, he summoned his bow. He didn’t fly up very high to keep both Fungalmancers within his sphere.

They were just sitting down there, a hundred meters below the ground. Neither of them had even tried to attack, making Jake wonder if they were even able to. Maybe they could no longer see him? Well, they could never see him, but they could still detect him somehow.

Jake summoned an explosive arcane arrow and nocked it. He didn’t bother using Powershot but just shot it down and watched it explode. It made a big hole, and a moment later, another arrow fell, followed by another. This continued as Jake rapid-fired arrows of pure destruction.

Like a jackhammer—or Jakehammer, if you will—of arcane destruction, he dug. The two Fungalmancers were still unmoving below. The ground was hard due to mana and the earth-affinity mana within, making it even more dense and solid, but he would be able to dig all the way down with enough time.

When he was seventy meters down, one of them finally reacted, but not as Jake expected. The one who had entered the ground first began coming up towards the surface in a very unexpected and one hundred percent moronic move. Unless it had been forced to come up for some reason?

Either way… it was in for a bad time. Jake aimed his bow, and before the head even had a chance to pop up, it was hit by an explosion of arcane mana. He heard it scream and struggle. It tried to summon vines, but it failed, as the ground it was on was no longer under its control.

It turned out that when you use half your mana pool to explode an area with arcane mana, it left a lasting effect. Who would have known? The Fungalmancer sure knew now.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 125] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

Jake didn’t do much after that but just waited patiently. After a bit, the last Fungalmancer also began coming up, making him now confident that the hiding skill had a duration of sorts. Maybe it was even dungeon-imposed so enemies couldn’t just hide belowground forever. Either way, the Fungalmancer got absolutely slaughtered once it showed its ugly, mushroom-filled head aboveground.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Fungalmancer – lvl 134] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

With both dead, Jake went to the one place still standing after the green explosion: the large tent the Fungalmancers had come from. Well, the tent wasn’t really there anymore, but a smashed-together bubble of rubble remained, making it obvious some kind of barrier existed. The mushroom he had seen them sit and meditate around was still in there.

Jake flew down and landed in front of it. With a wave of his hand, he blew away all the debris and saw a green barrier surrounding the mushroom. As he didn’t feel any sense of danger, he walked closer and found that he could walk through it with no problems.

The barrier was just a few meters in diameter, created to protect the mushroom—which had without a doubt been created by the Fungalmancers. Jake used Identify on the mushroom to see what all the fuss was about.

[Infused Golden Mushroom (Unique)] – A golden mushroom grown in the unique environment of the Undergrowth. This mushroom contains energies cultivated over a long period by Fungalmancers of the Undergrowth with the hope of gaining access to the Heart of the Undergrowth. Has been further infused with the life energy released from the Deepdwellers that inhabit the village built to guard it. Collect Golden Mushrooms to open up the Heart of the Undergrowth. WARNING: Golden Mushrooms cannot leave the dungeon. If the dungeon is left with any mushrooms, they will appear at the entrance upon re-entry.

Definitely a quest item, Jake thought as he promptly picked it up and threw it in his spatial storage. It was only the size of his palm, which meant it had only looked all the more ridiculous as the Fungalmancers sat meditating around it.

The item instantly gave him a lot of context to the Undergrowth. First of all, the Heart of the Undergrowth could be opened, yet Jake needed only to touch it to complete the dungeon. What did this mean? That’s right—bonus objective for better rewards.

Collecting mushrooms was clearly an important aspect of the dungeon. It even included the fact that one couldn’t take the mushrooms out of the dungeon. The fact that you wouldn’t lose them permanently meant that one required a specific amount. Jake also assumed there was a limited amount and that you needed as many as possible to open the Heart.

That his first mushroom was infused hadn’t been expected, but he hoped it was a good thing. It had to be. Jake loved when his own stupid recklessness was rewarded. That damn system and its repeated enabling of unhealthy behavior. Sometimes curiosity truly didn’t kill the cat, but gave it a pleasant surprise instead.

With one mushroom in the bag, Jake began to look for his next target. He hadn’t even gained a level yet, but then again, he’d only been in the dungeon for less than an hour. Only the four Fungalmancers and three Deepdwellers had given any experience due to the "downside" of his class.

Jake traveled further into the dungeon, running in a zigzag pattern to not miss anything. Luckily the dungeon was relatively narrow, but he did notice it opening up more and more. In the beginning, it had only had a width of ten kilometers, but after approximately thirty kilometers it now had a width of around twelve. It was a small expansion, but it was there.

Through his exploration, he gathered a bunch of herbs, primarily mushrooms. While he did save some of them, he chose to eat the majority due to something the Golden Mushroom had said: unique environment. Maybe it was just flavor text, but Jake wanted to see if he could somehow study this uniqueness by learning from the herbs that inhabited it.

After half an hour and around fifty kilometers total into the Undergrowth, he discovered the next point of interest. This time it wasn’t a village, but instead what Jake could only describe as a hunting party… As for what they were hunting? The first instance of Jake seeing any creature that wasn’t some variant of Deepdweller.

It was an around seven-meters-tall hulking monster with slightly humanoid features. It had massive muscles and long hairs covering parts of its body, with a disproportionately large head with an even larger nose. It carried a massive club that looked to be made of wood and walked on two legs. Jake didn’t even really need Identify to know what it was.

That’s a troll.

[Undergrowth Cave Troll – lvl 149]

It was a troll.

The Cave Troll—true to its namesake—stood in front of a cave, roaring at a party of around fifty Deepdwellers and two Fungalmancers. The Fungalmancers were level 131 and 135, respectively, and the Deepdwellers were around the same levels as those in the village. Only a handful were above 115, the highest one at 119.

Jake decided to just keep his distance for now, making use of Expert Stealth to stay hidden. He noticed that the Cave Troll didn’t want to leave its cave, while the Deepdwellers stayed back and made noises in response. Neither party looked like they wanted to attack, and Jake could easily guess why.

He could feel that the troll was far stronger than the Deepdwellers. In a fight, it would no doubt be able to crush the other side effortlessly, but it would have to leave the entrance to its cave. Jake assumed that the troll was guarding the cave because something valuable was in there that it didn’t want to be stolen—like a Golden Mushroom.

Meanwhile, the Deepdwellers wanted to wait for assistance. Jake guessed the villages only got larger and stronger further into the dungeon, so these Deepdwellers had to have more powerful fighters in their midst.

Jake considered if he should just get the party started, but decided to wait…

…

It took nearly half an hour before anything happened. How the hell they could just stand there screaming at each other for half an hour straight was insane, and Jake came this close to just blowing up a Fungalmancer more than once.

Anyway, a small group of Deepdwellers came, and Jake saw something surprising.

One Deepdweller walked ahead of the rest, and the two Fungalmancers bowed in respect when it showed up. Why they did so was obvious based on the aura it gave off, and Identify confirmed that this was no normal Deepdweller.

[Deepdweller Warlord – lvl 146]

The Warlord was wearing some kind of armor that looked to be made of bones. It carried a weapon that looked like a halberd, with a wooden handle and body with a crystalline edge. It looked almost to be made of diamond. Size-wise, it looked just like all the other Deepdwellers.

It had arrived with a small entourage of five other Deepdwellers. They also all wore bone armor and carried more ornate-looking wooden spears compared to those the normal Deepdwellers used. Their levels were also a good deal above anything that wasn’t a Fungalmancer.

[Deepdweller Warrior – lvl 137]

[Deepdweller Warrior – lvl 134]

[Deepdweller Warrior – lvl 136]

[Deepdweller Warrior – lvl 133]

[Deepdweller Warrior – lvl 136]

Jake remained in hiding as the Warlord made some loud noises to its brethren, and the troll responded by screaming back at them. The battle was about to begin, and Jake just couldn’t wait to butt in and fuck shit up for all parties involved. Would it be a bit dickish? Oh, for sure, but none of these opponents deserved mercy, and he was morally in the right.

The troll defended a mushroom. Bad guy.

The Deepdwellers practically worshipped mushrooms. Even badder guys.

Jake hated mushrooms. Good guy.

It was just math.

Chapter 31

Deepdwellers vs Cave Troll (feat. Jake)

Jake came to a realization as he stood hidden far up in the Undergrowth’s air on solidified mana, observing the posturing of the Deepdwellers before the troll. As he prepared to watch the show, he observed something was missing, and it took him a few moments to realize what it was…

I miss popcorn.

It felt like an eternity since the last time he’d had popcorn, and the battle about to unfold before him made him truly understand how much he missed those small, poppy corns. He would have to ask Miranda about it when he got back, because some chef somewhere must have made it. But, wait—they had unlocked foodstuffs with the System Store… Yeah, he could just get at least the base ingredients through that.

Actually… this made Jake realize that he wasn’t even entirely sure how popcorn was produced. He’d only ever really had them at the movies or when he made them in the microwave. Were those small kernels actually made of regular corn? They were hard and dry… Maybe dried corn?

These were all critical questions that occupied his mind as his impatience with the Deepdwellers’ cowardice increased by the second.

Seriously, Jake had assumed things would get started when the Warlord showed up, but instead, it had just joined in with the yelling. He got that it was lower level than the troll, but they outnumbered it heavily. So even if the weaker Deepdwellers couldn’t do much damage, they could still do a bit, right?

The five warriors, the Warlord, and the two Fungamancers should be able to put up a good fight, shouldn’t they? So what the hell were they waiting for?

Well, Jake learned that only ten minutes later. More reinforcements.

Three more Fungalmancers and six more warriors came, all with a level between 128 and 137, along with nearly forty more of the regular Deepdwellers, most of those below level 110. Jake assumed they could only serve as distractions or perhaps living bombs.

Finally, when the Deepdweller side outnumbered the troll with over a hundred to one, they made their move.

The Warlord took the front as the Fungalmancers channeled magic into empowering both it and the many warriors around it. Eleven warriors and the Warlord charged, Fungalmancers right behind as support. Nearly a hundred regular Deepdwellers surrounded the troll.

As for the Cave Troll, it backed away towards its own cave, roaring higher than ever before. It smashed its club into the ground to intimidate its attackers, but the Deepdwellers were determined. Fungalmancers then waved their hands, and Jake saw the spears of the many Deepdwellers begin to light up with an ominous green color.

Jake sensed the poison and knew the Fungalmancers had done something to amplify it. The same green glow also appeared on the stones of the Deepdwellers with slings and the claws of the big and bulky Deepdwellers. Jake actually felt a bit for that last group, because they were sure as fuck not gonna survive melee combat with the troll.

The first strike came from over fifty spears and about a dozen thrown stones headed straight for the troll, timed with a charge from the Warlord and its comrades. Jake heard the Warlord make a weird noise as a green aura washed out of it and into the warriors around it.

They all began glowing green like their leader and engaged the troll.

The Cave Troll raised its arm, and the many spears and stones hit it like a rain of pebbles and toothpicks. Many of the spears were now sticking out of its arm and stomach, but honestly, this only seemed to make the troll angrier. It roared and swung its club, sending out a massive wave of force that blasted back the three closest warriors and continued into the mass of Deepdwellers.

Jake whistled silently at the power of the troll. That was some strength it had there, and Jake sure as hell had no plans of taking a direct hit from that club. The warriors who had been blasted back looked slightly hurt, but the green aura bathing them seemed to focus on areas with wounds, making them heal rapidly.

A few of the Deepdwellers impacted weren’t as lucky, as they were blown more than a kilometer into the distance. Likely still alive, but for sure hurting a lot.

In response, the Warlord closed in and attacked with its halberd. A blue glow emanated from the crystalline edge as it swung, sending a wave of energy towards the troll. Simultaneously, four warriors also moved in close to stab one of the troll's legs.

The wave of energy cut deep into the troll’s chest, and the spears penetrated even deeper, making the Cave Troll stumble and scream out in pain. It kicked with the leg that had been stabbed and blasted away one of the warriors, then took another mighty swing with its club, this time trying to smash the Warlord.

With extreme grace that Jake hadn’t seen coming, the Deepdweller managed to block the club with the edge of its halberd. The body of the halberd bent, and the Warlord used that momentum to spring over the club and cut into the face of the troll in a quite frankly badass athletic move.

The attack cut off the long nose of the troll, sending green blood splashing everywhere. It let out an almost supersonic roar louder than anything ever before, sending out a shockwave that blasted the airborne Warlord back to its brethren.

Throughout it all, the troll had been pelted with smaller attacks. Vines grew on its lower body, mold grew all over its thick hair, and it had dozens of spears sticking out of it. Blood was pooling beneath it. The warriors had also managed to land many deep stabs on one of its legs, and from the looks of it, the troll had trouble standing on it.

Jake didn’t feel any need to butt in yet, though. Even with the troll down on one knee and bleeding from its entire body, it by far gave off the most dangerous aura of anything present—besides himself, of course.

He was proven correct not long after. The Deepdwellers looked to be in high spirits as they kept up the aggression until, finally, the troll looked to have had enough.

Jake felt it before he saw it. From the looks of it, the Fungalmancers felt it too—they made some screaming noises, all but a moment too late.

*BOOM!*

Giant spikes of rock shot up in a giant area around the Cave Troll, impaling more than a dozen Deepdwellers and killing at least a few. The survivors weren’t unscathed, either, but had to retreat while waiting for their wounds to slowly heal. Jake even saw the Fungalmancers cast some kind of healing magic, blanketing the Deepdwellers in a shower of healing spores.

On the other side, the Cave Troll wasn’t idle either. Jake saw all of its wounds quickly closing up, and even the cut-off nose began growing back. All of it had happened incredibly quickly, and Jake was amazed by its healing powers. Then again… trolls having high regeneration was a bit of a trope, so it shouldn’t really surprise anyone.

The explosion of earth spikes by the troll had created a momentary stalemate as both sides healed up. However, this stalemate was broken by the third-strongest creature present. The Warlord cut through a spike of earth and flew forward, once more cleaving into the troll that was in the middle of regenerating itself.

This marked the resumption of the battle. The troll counterattacked with its big-ass club, but this time it was all slightly different. Earth moved, and the soil beneath them seemed almost liquid, as if the entire area several kilometers around the troll had been turned into a swamp.

Jake was far enough away to be unaffected, but only barely. He was also happy he was currently standing on solidified mana and not on the ground, as he got flashbacks to the Horde Leader and the Steeltusk Boars. He was sure that the Cave Troll would have felt him if he moved on the ground.

He looked on as the tide slowly began to turn. The troll manipulated the earth and pushed back the Deepdwellers. All the regular ones were utterly useless and forced to retreat, which meant it was just the warriors and Fungalmancers as well as the Warlord against the raging troll.

This was when Jake noticed the Fungalmancers using what Fungalmancers use: underhanded tactics.

Jake saw the crystals he had seen one of them consume to hulk out. Then, five of the warriors retreated and were handed a crystal each to eat by a Fungalmancer. He saw them hesitate for a moment, but some stern noises from the Fungalmancers made them relent and consume them.

All five began transforming only a moment later, bulking up and sprouting massive, cancerous growths all over their bodies. With the hesitation of the warriors and the effect the crystals had, Jake was sure that shit wasn’t healthy in the long run. He wouldn’t be surprised if consuming a crystal was a one-time thing—pretty much a suicide pill for temporary power.

The five warriors charged the troll, and once more, the tide began turning. Unlike Jake, who could dodge the hulking versions of the Deepdwellers, the troll was too large and slow not to be hit. To then make things even worse for the troll, the Fungalmancers began channeling the same damn ritual they had used to try and kill Jake.

That was where Jake drew the line. It had nothing to do with him just getting too trigger-happy to stay put. While it would be a bit fun to see what else the Fungalmancers, Cave Troll, and Warlord could pull out between them, he would rather be the one on the receiving end than sit back and wait any longer.

Holding out his hand, he began summoning his one-shot arrow, also more popularly known as Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. The arrow that appeared looked pretty regular but was just bigger than usual. Jake felt powerful energy from it, reminding him of necrotic energy, likely to counter the life energy.

Jake decided to double up and coat it in some extra common-rarity poison, and he also prepared a good stock of stable arcane arrows soaked in poison, all while observing the battle in the distance.

The mutated warriors were near unkillable and healed from any wound near instantly, but the troll did the same. Its skin also looked to be made of stone now, and he saw the warriors hit it fruitlessly the majority of the time.

A halberd occasionally struck the troll, easily penetrating the stoneskin and cutting off large chunks of flesh. The Warlord did most of the damage, with the warriors creating openings and keeping the Cave Troll distracted.

Everything was looking up for the Deepdwellers. The Warlord was the third-strongest creature present, with the troll in second place. As for the strongest? Well, he was just about to enter the scene.

An arrow came out of nowhere, taking a Fungalmancer entirely by surprise. It didn’t even have time to turn around, freezing up just as it was hit in the back. A meager scream escaped its mouth as it collapsed to the ground, dead a few moments later.

Another arrow arrived less than a second later and split apart mid-air into three. They landed amid Deepdwellers and caused a massive explosion of arcane mana, completely ruining the ritual being performed by the Fungalmancers.

By now, both the Cave Troll and the Deepdwellers noticed that something was going very wrong on the backline. Well, wrong for the Deepdwellers. One of the non-mutated warriors was distracted and didn’t react fast enough as the club descended and smashed it into a pulp.

The troll seemed perfectly content using the momentary confusion of the Deepdwellers to strike back and reclaim the advantage. For a moment, the Warlord appeared confused as its nostrils moved rapidly, unsure what to do. Finally, it made a screeching sound and got an answer from a Fungalmancer just before said Fungalmancer got hit by an arcane arrow in the back of the head.

Jake happily stood back and bombarded the shit out of them with a mix between Splitting Arrow and Arcane Powershots. Due to the distance, he even got some mileage out of the Perception amplifier on his stable arrows and, of course, his Archery of Vast Horizons.

Pinned by the troll ahead and an unknown new threat from behind, the Warlord made a swift decision. It ran past the Cave Troll and straight into the cave it was guarding, much to the dismay of the troll, which roared angrily and smashed the ground. A wall of earth shot up in response.

The Warlord swung its halberd, cut through the wall, and entered the cave. The troll ran after it, not caring about all the attacks it received from behind. Jake thought it was a bit of a dick move to go claim the treasure before the fight was over, but perhaps he shouldn’t be the one judging.

Jake began charging up an Arcane Powershot as he waited. He saw the Warlord exit the tunnel a few seconds later with a Golden Mushroom cradled in its arms. The troll had a chance to attack but hesitated to smash down its club, likely because it feared hitting the mushroom. Instead, it tried to slow down the Warlord with walls of earth and grab it.

All of this gave a certain someone a great opportunity to release a fully charged Arcane Powershot just as the Warlord jumped over a wall of earth.

An entire area of the Undergrowth was momentarily bathed in purple light from the arcane explosion pushing away the darkness. The explosion of pure energy got the attention of all the blind Deepdwellers as a single arrow was sent piercing through the air straight towards the Warlord. The powerful Deepdweller actually stepped on the air, preparing to dodge, but Jake was way ahead of it. He activated Gaze of the Apex Hunter.

The Warlord got hit right in its chest, sending it flying back hundreds of meters—but more importantly for the troll, it dropped the Golden Mushroom due to the impact. The mushroom was blasted off too, but Jake spotted that he indeed had been right in his assessment: Those little golden fuckers weren’t that easily destroyed. Not that he had tried on his own, as they were important quest items… Definitely not.

Everyone scrambled for the Golden Mushroom, with especially the Fungalmancers going crazy for it. Jake didn’t much care himself but took the chance to launch even more arrows and kill as many warriors as possible, including the mutated ones. The troll also took the chance to begin slaughtering the many regular Deepdwellers.

While those hulking monsters easily handled regular wounds, they sure hated Necrotic Poison. He also found that the occasional exploding arrow did wonders to blow off large parts of their bodies while they had difficulty healing due to the necrotic energies.

Jake had only been interfering with the battle for less than a minute, and it had already turned to shit, with the entire Deepdweller side scrambling. The Warlord was who-knows-where and likely heavily injured, two of the Fungalmancers were dead, several warriors were dead or too injured to fight, and a troll was rampaging in their midst.

So yeah, all in all, things were going great.

Chapter 32

The Paragon Option

Jake guessed he had to go get the Golden Mushroom at some point, but quite frankly, it just made everything easier for him currently. Jake just had to shoot in the general direction of the mushroom, and he was sure to hit several targets at once when his arrow went boom.

He had also inadvertently made the troll mad now, properly drawing the lines between the three competing factions. Jake called it competing, but his contribution as a faction was just bombarding them from several kilometers away with arcane death.

Half of the warriors were dead by now, the troll’s healing seemed slower, and the Warlord was still nowhere to be seen after it had been blasted away. So Jake switched his focus to the Fungalmancers to take those down.

One of them tried to avoid Jake by sinking into the ground, but that turned out to be a very bad idea. The troll stomped on the ground, and a block of earth emerged—the Fungalmancer within it. With a mighty swing, the entire block was smashed apart, sending rock, soil, blood, guts, and body parts of the Fungalmancer flying.

Right after, another Fungalmancer fell to a barrage of exploding arrows. The third and final one tried to get away but was hit in the leg by an arrow and a club right after. With no more Fungalmancers, the regular Deepdwellers seemed almost lost. The warriors tried to rally them, but panic had truly taken hold by now.

It all looked to be well and truly over for the Deepdwellers—until their true leader reappeared.

The Warlord walked through the air, blood dripping from a nasty hole in its chest and most of its bone armor broken. It had let go of the Golden Mushroom to keep hold of its halberd, which was glowing as intensely as before. It sniffed the air and seemed to get a good grasp of the entire battlefield. It even slightly turned towards Jake, once more making it clear it was aware of his exact position.

Jake expected the Warlord to attack either him or the troll, but instead, it headed into the midst of the surviving regular Deepdwellers. For a moment, it looked hesitant, and then it did something Jake hadn’t seen coming at all.

It took the halberd, flipped it one hundred and eighty degrees, and stabbed itself in the chest.

That was the moment Jake’s brain made a connection. Crystalline halberd… consuming crystal to hulk out… If that halberd was like those crystals…

Jake felt as though a gust of wind had risen behind him, blowing towards the Warlord. He knew it wasn’t actual wind, but the movement of the mana in the atmosphere. All of the life-affinity mana was sucked towards the Warlord like it was a black hole.

The body of the Warlord began glowing green, and the many Deepdwellers ran closer. The Cave Troll tried to make use of the opening to smash the Warlord, but all the remaining warriors got in the troll’s way, risking their own lives.

As for Jake? Jake sat back to see what it was doing.

This was when he remembered the Golden Mushroom and saw that one of the Deepdwellers had it—one that was running straight towards the Warlord.

The Warlord began mutating at a rapid pace, but unlike the others that had done so, it didn’t just affect itself. Instead, the green aura around it made all the other Deepdwellers also begin to mutate and glow green. Jake at first thought it was some kind of area-of-effect property of the crystal to make them all stronger, but was quickly proven wrong.

Once a Deepweller was sufficiently mutated, it ran towards the Warlord—straight into it. Literally. The growing Warlord absorbed the Deepdweller entirely, adding body mass to its grotesque form.

It was all an extremely bizarre and unsettling sight. The troll seemed to agree, as it tried to get closer to smash the Warlord again, but a warrior chose to go on a full-on suicide attack to make the troll stop. It jumped straight into the troll to tackle it as its spear glowed a deep green color. It succeeded in stopping the troll, but in return, it got grabbed and had its entire head bitten off by the troll. It turns out trolls have quite the teeth too.

In the end, the Warlord absorbed over thirty Deepwellers, and Jake thought it was done until one final Deepdweller chose to join the flesh collective—the one carrying the Golden Mushroom.

The moment it got absorbed, it was as if a pulse went through the entire now nearly ten-meter-tall Warlord. Golden veins spread through its body, pulsing with life energy. Jake was a bit shocked that it chose to absorb it, and he feared the mushroom was now gone for good… He could only hope it was still obtainable after the Warlord died.

Heck, maybe this was the key to getting it infused? Because he sure was doing this on hard mode now.

The troll roared and smashed the final warrior to death with its club, leaving only three living beings in the battle: Cave Troll vs. Mega-Mutated Warlord vs. Jake.

Jake did feel a bit inferior in the size department—no, not there—as he was battling two hulking monsters, both several times larger than he was.

He also discovered that he was vastly different in another area. The two forgetful monsters charged into each other as if they had completely forgotten the very deadly hunter not far away. Thus, it appeared that while the mutation made the Warlord a lot stronger, it also wholly ruined its mind.

On the other hand, Jake was a smart boy. He decided to do the most brilliant thing: kill the weakest enemy first to fight the stronger foe one on one. As for which one of them was weaker?

The troll was lifted up and smashed into the ground by the large, grotesque hands of the Warlord. The earth quaked and split apart as the Warlord continued slamming it up and down. The troll summoned a few pillars of stone that impaled the Warlord, but it barely made the massive monster flinch.

Earth spikes kept shooting up as the troll tried to strike back with its club, only to find itself restrained. It roared again in anger, sending out a shockwave that momentarily made the Warlord stumble. Just long enough for the troll to swing its club into the midsection of the Warlord.

Blood and flesh flew everywhere as several tons of body mass were smashed off the Warlord, yet it seemed to barely mind as new tumors grew and replaced the now missing flesh. The troll swung again, blasting off even more meat. It tried to go for a third swing but was punched in the head, making it fly back and impact the wall next to its cave.

The troll stood up, heaving for breath. If the fight had been equal from the start, the troll would have likely beaten the large flesh abomination Warlord—even after all the boosts from consuming its comrade and the Golden Mushroom. But as it was, the troll was spent.

It had taken so many wounds already. Poison from all the spears and all the magic from the Fungalmancers still slowly drained its life energy. Sickly green spots covered its body, and many of the wounds it had just received festered, as they were infected with fungal spores.

The Warlord struck it again, making it tumble to the side. Jake saw it roar and reach out towards the chest of the Warlord, but it was just punched again. It tried to make another scream, but it couldn’t release any more sonic blasts, so it resorted to crawling back into its cave. The Warlord smashed the upper parts of the cave, making them fall off and reveal what was within the cave.

Jake had been waiting for his opportunity to strike the troll and finish it off, but he now saw something he hadn’t expected.

Two small figures lay within the cave, in an area where the mushroom looked to have been. Both were bloody and injured, but not dead, as far as Jake could tell. A sinking feeling appeared in his stomach as he used Identify on them.

[Juvenile Cave Troll – lvl 28]

[Juvenile Cave Troll – lvl 31]

They were unmoving as the troll crawled up to them and tried to cover them with its body. The Warlord walked into the cave to finish the job, as—

It froze. A gaze it had felt before penetrated its soul and made the entire monstrosity of flesh quiver. It couldn’t move for over a second, nor take any actions as it was struck by an arrow from a fully charged Arcane Powershot—one that had originally been prepared for the troll.

The Warlord had a hole blown straight through it. Arcane energy burned into its flesh, and plenty of necrotic energy devoured its vitality. Yet it was insistent on finishing off the troll, seemingly not caring about the damage it took.

This turned out to be an awful decision.

Another three arrows struck it from behind, all of them exploding and blasting off large parts, followed by another Powershot that tore an arm off. The Warlord was stupid now, but it had noticed… the source of the attacks was coming closer. And fast.

It still tried—and failed—to end the troll before what would be its doom arrived.

A new impact hit it from behind, but this time it was no arrow. Instead, it was a human with wings that stabbed two swords into its large back, followed by a web of arcane string that wrapped around it.

“Fuck off,” Jake said as he pulled and threw the entire monstrosity of cancerous growths out of the cave.

His entire body burned with energy, as he really didn’t feel like holding anything back. Limit Break was active at 20%.

When Jake saw the two small trolls and the big troll move to defend them, something just flipped in his mind, and his body moved. He knew he was probably a fucking hypocrite and had flawed-as-hell logic, but when he saw what the troll did, he chose to help it.

For the Cave Troll, the mushroom had been a natural treasure to help what he assumed were its children. Jake couldn’t fault it for that, as it just wanted to keep assisting them. It was defensive of the cave because the children were in there… He remembered how it hadn’t moved from the cave when the Golden Mushroom was taken. Sure, it tried to get it back, but it never dared move away.

Shit, Jake even knew this was a dungeon. None of these creatures were ever going to leave the dungeon, as far as he knew, and were stuck in this small pocket dimension forever. Even Villy had mentioned that taking a dungeon creature out of a dungeon under normal circumstances was a pipedream. Yet he still came to its assistance.

Call it what you may, but Jake had chosen a side.

The Warlord got up from being tossed away, having taken little damage. From the throw, that is. Necrotic Poison burned into it with more power than anything Jake had ever inflicted before, and the reason for that was simple: uncommon-rarity Potent Necrotic Poison. He had used one of the precious bottles because fuck the Warlord.

He saw it wobble a bit as it got up. Jake didn’t bother giving it any time as he charged again, the rest of the Potent Necrotic Poison coating his blades.

With a single step, he appeared before it, both blades now also shimmering with arcane energy. Then, just as he attacked, dark mana joined the arcane, as he used two Descending Dark Arcane Fangs at once, cutting in a cross-shaped attack.

Both his arms shook from the sheer amount of energy he poured into the attack. Veins popped on both of them, making blood spurt out. But it was more than successful. The entire abomination was split into four pieces as the cross-shaped dark arcane blades continued through the air before finally impacting the dungeon wall and cutting a deep mark into the stone.

Instantly, all four pieces sprouted out tendrils and tried to assemble themselves once more, even with the necrotic energy and mana burning into its flesh. However, Jake didn’t let it. He swiftly summoned his bow and fired a Splitting Arrow that split into four—one for each body part.

Three pieces were blown entirely apart by the exploding arcane arrows, while the piece with the head remained whole, albeit heavily damaged. It looked like it tried to regenerate itself, but quickly gave up and switched tactics.

It began emanating a powerful green glow that Jake instantly recognized. The fucker was going to blow itself up.

Fuck you, Jake thought as he stepped over and kicked the mass of flesh with all of his strength, sending it flying away from the cave and himself. After he kicked, he took one more step to appear before the broken entrance to the cave and held up both his hands.

An arcane barrier started forming in front of him as he covered his body in scales, and just in time.

The still-mid-air lump of flesh exploded in a massive green explosion, not unlike the one he had experienced before. This one was far more powerful, though. Fortunately, it was also a lot further away, meaning that in the end, the explosion that hit him was far weaker.

His arcane barrier held up, and he managed to shield the cave entrance. If the explosion hadn’t occurred a couple of kilometers away—Jake kicked hard—it wouldn’t have ended as well as it had. Jake would still have been fine, but he couldn’t say the same about the three trolls behind him.

The explosion continued to fire out energy for five or so seconds before it stopped. Jake didn’t quite dare let the barrier down yet, but he did take the time to check his notifications, focusing on the latest one first.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Warlord – lvl 146] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 116 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 117 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 112 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

While Jake didn’t get any experience from foes lower than himself, he was pretty damn confident he got even more than usual from those above. Even then, it wasn’t like just the Warlord had given him two class levels. One also had to remember the Fungalmancers he had slain since entering the dungeon, and a good bunch of the warriors too.

Well, he did likely get less experience from the kills this fight due to the troll, but what can you do?

Jake quickly flew over to where the Warlord had exploded, and in his sphere, he quickly spotted the Golden Mushroom. Or should he say Infused Golden Mushroom? Because, yep, this one had also been upgraded. The key seemed to be making Deepdwellers blow themselves up.

He turned around and walked back into the cave. The troll was no longer huddling over the wounded troll children; it had managed to stand itself up and was now looking threateningly at Jake. He knew it was all a façade, as he could feel it still struggling with poison inwardly, and its legs were slightly shaking. The troll was in no condition to fight.

"I’m not here to fight you," Jake said as he walked towards the troll. It made a weak roaring sound, but Jake looked at it and shook his head. "Relax."

The troll didn’t look like it fully understood his words, but it seemed to get the gist. However, it was still wary as Jake took out a small bottle, tossed it to the troll, and made a drinking motion.

"Drink."

It hesitated, and Jake gave it a stern look.

"Drink."

The troll didn’t dare disobey. It threw the entire bottle into its mouth and chewed on it. Only a few moments later, its eyes lit up, and Jake could already see its legs stabilizing a bit as the troll’s natural regeneration kicked in along with the healing potion.

It has to have some skill to more effectively activate health points, Jake mused as he walked over to the two small, injured Cave Trolls.

Once more, the big troll was hesitant, but it didn’t stop Jake as he gave each of the two small ones a potion.

Half an hour later, Jake was sitting on the ground, meditating to refill his resources and to stave off the period of weakness from Limit Break. The two small trolls, which were equal to him in size, entertained him by poking him.

As for the big troll? It was also just sitting there, relaxing.

Jake knew it wouldn’t attack him. As to how he was so sure it wouldn’t?

Call it intuition.

Chapter 33

A Distraction

Jake sat regenerating on the ground, observing the trolls in his sphere. He was inside a dungeon, but everything was just like out in the real world. Yet he knew it wasn’t… Dungeons were special. He knew that he himself could meet the trolls now and befriend them, while the next party could kill them, and the one after that could never discover them to begin with.

The same troll could die a thousand times and give the same experience a thousand times, yet when party one thousand and one entered the dungeon, they would still see it. The dungeons were temporal pockets of sorts, so whenever Jake entered it alone, he started another timeline for the dungeon. A new reality. This was common knowledge throughout the multiverse, and one of the reasons why dungeons were such valuable natural treasures for monsters and enlightened races alike.

But Jake also knew dungeons wouldn’t last forever. One day, a natural dungeon would come to an end, and what happened to the monsters then? Where did these dungeon creatures come from, where did they go, where did they come from, Cotton E—

Anyway.

Were they born there? Had they grown up in the dungeon until one day a door appeared, and invaders came? What about if no one ever entered a dungeon… Would time just stand still forever? Jake didn’t know the answer to any of these things… but he knew someone who did.

Vilastromoz stood within his realm as he once more tried. The entire realm shook as he mobilized every inch of his power. He put his hands on the obelisk as the runes came alive just like all the other times, his mind focused only on this one task.

Usually, he would have split his mind into countless fragments. One could talk to Jake, another could theorize some magic or work on a concept, and if he needed something physically done, he could just use his Avatars. Or, if it was a smaller task that didn’t require much power, he could summon a temporary Incarnation. For him to have hundreds, if not thousands of these fragments of his mind up at a time wasn’t unusual.

But at this moment, everything was gathered for him to use his full power.

A dark green glow emanated from the entire realm for a few moments before everything faded once more. Blood poured out of the Viper’s eyes and mouth as he shook his head. "Failed again…"

It was expected, in most ways, but every time inspired an immense feeling of failure and grief. He clenched his hands in anger at himself. It wasn’t power… He needed something more, but he didn’t know what the fuck it was.

Maybe he should fully return his focus to—

"Sup, Villy, just making a phone call to see how you’re doing and to shamelessly get advice on things I probably should know to begin with."

The Malefic Viper was stopped in his train of thought as the message came. After Jake’s evolution, he could no longer stop them… He could zone them out, but the connection between them had changed. A blessed mortal could not stop the divine message of a god, and now he as a god could not stop the divine message from his own Chosen. It was weird and something he had never encountered before. Yet he appreciated it.

Vilastromoz—or Villy, as Jake insisted on calling him—answered with a smirk.

"I'm just dandy, and what studying did my Chosen skip out on this time?" Jake heard Villy say.

The words sounded normal, but Jake frowned. Villy seemed… down. His tone reminded him of the first time they’d met in his realm. If someone listened to it, they wouldn’t know the difference, but he trusted his instincts, telling him things weren’t as they should be.

"Are things alright on your end?" Jake asked with concern.

"Of course—why do you ask?" Villy laughed it off. "What could possibly bother a god?"

"I don’t know, but something clearly is," Jake answered. "You listen to my ramblings and constant questions, so of course you can do the same thing back. If anything is bothering you, just tell me. Even if you just need someone to listen. I am probably not the best at giving advice to anyone, much less a god, but we’re friends, man, so unload on me if you feel like it. Keeping things bottled up isn’t easy or healthy. Be you mortal or god."

Jake knew he wasn’t the most articulate, but he hoped to get the point across anyway. He always felt a bit bad about how he only ever got things from Villy while he didn’t give much in return. So if Villy needed anything, he would be there.

"I appreciate the thought, but no. Maybe in the future. Right now, a distraction is all I need, so hit me. What’s up?" Villy said all this after a delay. One far longer than usual.

"Alright, just poke me anytime if there is anything," Jake said, moving to the actual question he wanted answered. "How do living things and dungeons play together? I am talking of those that live in the dungeon."

"In what way?"

"Is there any way for dungeon monsters to leave the dungeon?" Jake clarified.

"Not under usual circumstances, no. Unless the dungeon has inherent mechanics allowing you to bring out living creatures, don’t expect it to happen. All dungeon creatures are, for all intents and purposes, considered dead in the context of the outside world.”

"What do you mean by considered dead?"

"When a creature enters a dungeon, it becomes a part of the world that dungeon creates. Its Records—everything it is—become bound to that dungeon. From there, two things can happen once a natural dungeon reaches the end of its lifespan. One is that it will simply disappear along with all the creatures bound to it. The second thing that can happen is that it merely stops being a dungeon and becomes its own accessible, separate space somewhere as part of the real world without any dungeon mechanics. Often a prolonged period will have passed for all the creatures in the dungeon, but no one will ever have entered it. For them, it would just be as if they had been stuck in a confined world for a while. The second one is absurdly rare, which is why it is better just to consider them dead."

Jake frowned as he considered this. He could see that it would lead to issues if one could simply make creatures leave with them… It also added the issue of there possibly being multiple copies of the same creature out in the real world. For example, what would happen if Jake took the troll out with him, and then Miranda entered and also took the troll out? That would create two copies of the troll. It was damn complicated, so he asked.

"As I said, sometimes you can bring creatures out,” Villy said. “You’re actually lucky—an old mate did many experiments with dungeons, and this isn’t common knowledge, as it really isn’t something that can happen often. If, say, you managed to bring a creature out, and someone else brought the exact same one out… the second one would disappear the moment it entered the real world. This is because they have the same Truesoul, and thus only one can exist. Well, there are ways to kind of circumvent this by doing some advanced stuff, but it’s way above anything you are capable of doing anytime soon."

"Does that mean I am screwed if I want to bring this nice troll and the small trolls out with me? And that I should just consider them almost virtual creatures that are already dead?" Jake asked, his frown growing even deeper. He was happy the trolls couldn’t understand him, as the two small ones were play-fighting.

"Depends. As a natural dungeon, it may have some ways to bring them out. You can also do it through some very limited exploits of sorts. Consider the kind of means deployed to get people out of the tutorial. If you kill them and do a true resurrection on the bodies outside, you ‘fooled’ the system. If you make them do some incredibly advanced ritual and bring them outside right as their souls transition between living and undead, you can bring them out.

"Besides that, there are some skills. Changing their races and thus souls in any way often leaves an opening, though this isn’t anything you can do. Trust me on that one. The only other way is to bind their souls to yours and make them be considered almost an extension of your being, but you have no ways of doing that either, as far as I can tell. This usually requires special items or a very special set of skills. In conclusion, your only real bet is to hope the dungeon has a natural way to bring them out. And I do mean really hope for it. The rewards given out by the system can be unpredictable, but there are many cases of them being at least partly based on what the people doing the dungeon need and want."

"Huh… I did theorize that was the case back in the tutorial, but then I got a bunch of light-affinity equipment instead… Speaking of which, I still have that book and staff sitting around… I really need to pawn it off…" He mumbled through the words, deep in thought at the new information.

"The dungeon rewards tend to be related to what is in it. So, based on the dungeon you are currently in, it will likely give out life-affinity loot," Villy told him, making Jake nod along.

"Makes sense. Also, no comments on me slaughtering mushroom lovers?"

"What do you mean? You are dutifully collecting mushrooms right now. I even saw you eat some. That you hate doing it deep inside is exactly what I would expect of a heretic. That you do it anyway because you want the rewards associated with doing so is just what I want out of my Chosen. So keep it up, Heretic-Chosen."

"Touche," Jake said, grinning. "One final thing… What happens if I leave the dungeon now and come back later? What if I wait a year or something? How does that work with all the time shenanigans?"

"After you leave, the time in your version of the dungeon will keep going for a short period of time. Usually up to around a day, sometimes shorter, sometimes longer. And I already know that your follow-up question will be what happens if you just stay in the dungeon forever… Well, nothing, really. Time will keep moving inside, but nothing will really happen. Due to how dungeons work, the creatures within cannot level or reproduce above a certain point. They simply don’t have the Records for it. So it will just be very boring. Of course, new herbs or ores or anything in that vein will never regrow either."

"Hm, so it won’t just randomly implode in on itself while I am in there? Nice.”

"The door may disappear, though, and the entrance forever buried, meaning you exit somewhere else after an extremely long time has passed, and you will find yourself in a world all but foreign to you, as your prolonged stay in the dungeon has slowly corroded your mind," Villy delivered this news as a half-joke, half-warning.

Jake smiled, glad that Villy now sounded a bit more like his usual self. He knew the old snake god was dealing with something, and Jake had a faint idea of what it was… but wasn’t going to press. He had enough emotional awareness to know some things shouldn’t be pushed, but had to come out when the time was right.

"Thanks as always, Villy. Remember, just ping me whenever. The connection is two-way, and as I kind of claimed it a bit, you should also abuse this inescapable bond." Jake smiled in thanks.

"Yeah… it was good to get my mind off things. As I said, maybe in the future."

"I’m not in a rush for anything. Besides, when the universe opens up a bit more, we gotta get together. Multiversal beer has to be a thing. So take care of yourself. You may be a big boss snake, but sometimes even a big boss snake needs to sit back and have a cold one with a friend.”

"I may just take you up on that offer… and believe me, there is alcohol even us gods can get smashed on, much less a fragile mortal like you. I’ll be sure to pull out some for when the time comes. See you around, Jake, and you take care too."

Jake felt the connection fade away as he got up. He felt fine now and ready to move further into the dungeon. The troll, on the other hand, still looked quite weak. Jake had already given it two health potions, but they honestly didn’t do that much. It had eliminated all the poison by now, but it was still low on health points, as far as he could tell.

Jake theorized that the damn thing had more pure health points than himself tens of times over. This did mean it was incredibly hard to kill in a fight, but also that it would take a long time to heal. Heck, even the small trolls needed more than one potion to be topped up, and they were barely E-grade.

How exactly that worked, he didn’t know. Maybe some skill that made Vitality grant more health points, or some massive percentage amplifier or something… Either way, it didn’t really matter. The troll couldn’t really join Jake in his quest for the Golden Mushrooms, as it had kids at home.

He bid the trolls farewell, and the two small ones wanted to follow but were held back by the parent troll. A good call, as Jake was about to get some real good slaughtering on. He felt like he had a good idea of what the Deepdwellers were all about now… which meant it was time to turn up the tempo and get this Deepweller genocide started.

Vilastromoz genuinely smiled as he said his goodbyes. Jake didn’t know it, but he had impeccable timing indeed. He had even picked up that he, a god, wasn’t feeling his best. The mortal had even dared question it and ask him directly. For a moment, Villy had focused on something other than his issues, and with it, his headspace improved.

Duskleaf, the Sisters of the Verdant Lagoon, Snappy… none of them would ever do that. None of them dared to. Even Duskleaf, who seemed so casual, never dared cross the line. He still talked to him formally, and Vilastromoz couldn’t remember any time his disciple had ever called him anything else but master.

The Sisters and Snappy? They would never dare assume they could do anything to help.

"He sure is a heretic… isn’t he?" Vilastromoz asked as he looked towards the large obelisk. "The last person who told me to take care of myself was you, I think. I know I should, but…."

He sighed. Today had been another failure… He would just have to try again later.

Over eighty eras, he had tried.

Trillions of years.

More than one hundred and seven million failures.

But the Malefic One still refused to give up.

Chapter 35

To Upgrade Or Not To Upgrade, That Is The Question

Jake always liked getting new skills. Not just because he got something new and shiny to add to his repertoire, but because the list he got was a testament to his progress. Every single offering was proof of his achievements and a small insight into what kinds of improvements he had made. It felt like a good pat on the back and a high-five for how great he had been. The skills also often gave him good ideas for what he could do himself in the future.

As with every other time, he went in with great vigor. He opened up the list of new skills offered and, as always, was incredibly disappointed with the first skill available. Well, at least it was an expected disappointment.

[Arcane Bolt (Rare)] – Inspired by the simple Mana Bolt, you have taken it to the next level and created the Arcane Bolt. Allows the hunter to summon bolts of arcane mana to defeat your foes. You can summon two kinds of bolts: a stable and a destructive version. The destructive bolts will explode upon impact, and the stable version will be tough and piercing. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Intelligence when using Arcane Bolt.

This was far from the first time he had been offered some kind of "Mana Bolt" variant, and it was a bit funny to have seen it progress from common rarity with the Dark Bolt back in the day to the rare-rarity Arcane Bolt he was offered now. He was even pretty damn sure he could get offered an epic-rarity version if he kept working on it. Jake liked making Arcane Bolts and firing them, but he didn’t feel like he needed a skill to do so at all. Would it make them stronger? Sure, but he seriously doubted they could ever get as good as his arrows.

Hence, he moved to the second option—which was another damn repeat. At least, it appeared to be at first glance.

[Disruptive Arcane Wave (Rare)] – Mobilize the arcane and dispel that which impedes you. Erupt in a torrent of destructive arcane energy, dispelling any spell constructs in your immediate vicinity by overloading them with mana and pushing away anything else in your immediate surroundings. Higher consumption of mana and stamina is required based on the power and stability of the spell constructs or physical impediments. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Wisdom, Intelligence, and Endurance when using Disruptive Arcane Wave.

Not much had changed from the Disruptive Mana Eruption he’d been offered at level 90, but upon closer reading, there was a difference; it wasn’t a mana eruption at all, but an energy eruption. It also used stamina and even now benefitted from Endurance. It was now more just a small, localized explosion of arcane energy around himself. A simple and probably effective skill that Jake didn’t need a skill for at all.

It did give some more inspiration, though. Jake knew he should really work on using his arcane affinity with not just mana, but also stamina. This wave clearly used both mana and stamina, making it even more effective on physical impediments as well as magical ones. Having had something like this skill during his second fight with the Indigo Fungus would have saved him from getting half his body sheared off.

But in the end, Jake had no interest in getting the skill itself. He would rather just work on mimicking the effects with free-range magic. Moving on.

[Barrier of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Epic)] – Stability is a cornerstone of your arcane affinity, making barriers an obvious application of your arcane. Allows the Avaricious Arcane Hunter to summon a barrier of pure, stable arcane energy in a bubble around you, blocking out any direct attacks that attempt to pass through—both physical and magical alike. Mana or stamina will be consumed depending on the nature of the blocked attacks. All concepts not deployed by you will be weakened within your barrier. Adds a small bonus to the effects of Wisdom and Endurance when using Arcane Barrier.

Now we’re getting somewhere, Jake thought. It was the first skill with "Avaricious Arcane Hunter" in the name and was epic rarity right away. As for the skill itself? It felt a bit like something he had done many times before, but also had some new stuff.

First of all, it was a bubble around him and not a wall as he usually made. This one was also once more arcane energy and not only mana, likely making it a lot better against physical attacks. Right now, the arcane barrier he summoned was best against magical attacks, though that hadn’t been much of an issue, as most ranged attacks he faced were magical.

This was another case of him needing to get off his ass and use stamina as well as mana with his arcane affinity. He had originally formed the affinity primarily using mana, but he knew affinities didn’t just affect mana. He still remembered the Aspiring Blade of Nature back in the tutorial, who’d used a powerful aura of sorts with a nature affinity.

More food for thought that he would have to sit down and seriously go over, hopefully before the Treasure Hunt.

The second very interesting thing about the skill was that entire thing about concepts. How would that work? It said it would weaken any concepts not deployed by him, though he had no idea what that meant. Would that mean things like gravity, space, and time itself would be weakened within his barrier? That sounded ridiculous and not at all like how things would work. Jake assumed it was great, though, and likely the reason behind the epic-rarity tag. If not, it was just a robust defensive barrier and nothing else.

If he had to make a slightly educated guess, he would assume the barrier could weaken enemy spells already within the barrier that affected him. For example, if he were poisoned, cursed, or on fire, it would weaken those effects. This was ultimately only a guess, but it made sense. It could also just mean that the barrier couldn’t fully block concepts but only weaken them slightly, so if he was hit with some weird spell akin to his own Gaze of the Apex Hunter or some mental skill, it was only a partial defense. Once more, he was just guessing, but it did have some interesting implications: If he isolated himself with arcane energy, he could at least partly suppress outside concepts.

To be fair, Jake would’ve been perfectly fine with selecting this skill, but naturally still moved on, as he had two more to go. The next one was a lot more interesting than anything prior, as it was truly something new.

[Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Ancient)] – Your prey is chosen, the hunt is on. Covertly mark targets, making you aware of their positions at all times until the marks expire or are dispelled. All damage done to marked targets is increased. Arcane damage has its damage amplified further. The extra arcane damage inflicted while the marks are active will be built up in the form of an arcane charge that you can detonate to release all the stored-up energy. Additional bonus experience earned for slaying a marked target above your level. (This effect remains even if your target dies to the mark detonating or within a short duration of the detonation). Adds a bonus to the damage inflicted, the duration of the marks, the marks’ subtlety, and the number of marks available based on Perception.

WARNING: This skill is unlocked by, and will serve as an upgrade to, your existing Mark of the Ambitious Hunter.

Jake had never encountered a skill selection that offered to upgrade a skill and not just grant an entirely new one. Was this something new to D-grade? Did it only include class-specific skills? Did this mean he would get a better version of his Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter, too, at some point? That would be rad.

The skill itself was honestly just awesome. Jake really loved Mark of the Ambitious Hunter, as it was one of those hidden heroes that helped him immensely. At this point, he didn’t even think about applying it to targets before he killed them for the experience, but this did mean that he hadn’t really made much use of the extra-damage part outside of using it against singular, powerful enemies. He couldn’t help but pull up the old Mark and compare them directly.

[Mark of the Ambitious Hunter (Rare)] – The prey is chosen, the hunt begins. Covertly mark a target, making you aware of their position at all times until the mark expires or is dispelled. All damage done to the marked target is increased. Additional bonus experience earned for slaying a marked target above your level. Adds a small bonus to the damage inflicted, the mark’s duration, and the mark’s subtlety based on Perception.

The old description sure was a lot shorter, and it also made the differences obvious. The new one would add the arcane charge mechanic, likely providing more extra damage than the old Mark even without arcane damage; it would also allow more than one mark active at a time, and it was likely just better in every single way. Shit, it somehow had even kept the aspect of only benefitting from Perception, his highest stat by far.

There was also the entire extra-experience part that maybe got improved further. Jake still had no idea how much extra experience he got from his old Mark, but he used it on every single kill on enemies above his level anyway. Everything counted, after all. He already had a strong suspicion that his class leveled faster than usual against higher-leveled foes by default, and the Mark only improved that aspect.

Jake wanted it a lot, but he was still unsure of a lot of things—primarily how it would affect him in the future. Skills were a limited commodity, which was why getting some from the Tutorial Store was so valuable. New skills usually only came from titles and level-ups, and he couldn’t just expect them to grow on trees. Choosing to upgrade a skill would mean not getting a new one, which was quite the cost.

On the other hand, was it really that bad? He already had skills he barely used now, so wouldn’t it be better to make those he actually did use better? Sure, he could upgrade the old ones, but he hadn’t had time to do anything like that yet. Skills could also fuse, like how his Hunter’s Sight had merged with Gaze of the Apex Predator to make Gaze of the Apex Hunter, or how Sense Herb and Sense Toxin had formed Sense of the Malefic Viper. Those instances had just been improvements and in no way losses, in his opinion, even if he had lost a skill due to the merging.

He also theorized all of the "of the Malefic Viper" skills were part of a whole and would eventually merge into a single, incredibly powerful skill. Sure, he had been offered the Malefic Dragonkin race change, likely as a result of having all the skills at ancient rarity, but he still believed they could be merged somehow. Would he be angry if two or three of his ancient-rarity skills merged and made a legendary one that retained all effects with more strength? No, of course not. At least, not in the short run.

In the end, Jake needed a second opinion. Standing in the empty chamber that had housed the mushroom, he said aloud, "So, Villy, hasn’t been that long, but I called anyway to ask you since I am unable to make decisions myself: Is upgrading a skill or picking a new skill best? I know you told me about skills being valuable, as you can only get a limited amount, so would upgrading an existing one not just mean that I am ‘losing’ a skill? I could potentially just upgrade it myself at some point, right?"

Within a second, Jake felt the attention of the Malefic Viper upon him and the connection strengthening as he answered, his tone the same as usual. It made Jake happy that his pal hadn’t gone back to moping, and in all honesty, reaching out to him had as much to do with having an excuse to hear how Villy was doing as getting advice.

"That one came out of the blue… You got a potential skill upgrade for one of your skill options while leveling up, I reckon?” Villy said. “Tends to begin happening around D-grade, but most often only if you pick a class or profession closely associated with the one you had before. Also, for once, don’t be ashamed at not knowing this—not that I think you know shame about such things—as this really isn’t common knowledge for most. People tend to hate sharing this kind of information outside of their organizations, and the system hasn’t been giving out much info related to D-grades to your universe yet, as far as I know. Most importantly… you would have had to actually talk to other people to learn about it—something we both know has a very low chance of happening.”

"Wow, that’s just mean," Jake answered with faux offense. “Am I not talking to someone else right now who is telling me? Also, I am pretty sure you didn’t actually address any of my questions.”

"You answered most of your questions yourself. Any skill you upgrade is the opportunity of getting a new skill lost. It’s pretty simple. Ultimately, it comes down to how much you value the upgraded skill and the nature of the skill. No two skills are created equal, and some skills can do things that cannot be done with freeform magic. Well, theoretically, everything can be done, but some things are just unrealistic. Also, it isn’t like having fewer skills is always bad. Many skills end up unused or forgotten, or perhaps end up having overlap with other, better skills. Often there is value in focusing on your most important core skills. Focus on your primary fighting method and improve on that while shoring up weaknesses. You don’t need a skill to do everything, but having skills related to what you do most is highly preferred. The rest can be fixed without the use of skills. All in all, having a hundred diverse and mediocre skills is worse than having ten you use and synergize with each other. Quality over quantity and all that."

Jake nodded along as the Viper spoke. It was pretty much as he had thought, and the thing about skills too hard to recreate also struck true. If he wanted to somehow create a skill like Big Game Arcane Hunter, he had no idea where to start, or if it was even possible. Villy said it would somehow be possible to do all that skill did… but Jake just didn’t see how at all. It was a skill that made him stronger against higher-leveled foes. Maybe some serious soul magic? He wasn’t sure.

Either way, Jake didn’t feel a need to hold back, so he shared the skill’s details.

"Well, the skill marks targets, increases my damage done, and makes me aware of their positions at all times. It uses my arcane affinity, too, and can build up a charge of arcane energy that I can explode. It didn’t have all the arcane stuff before the upgrade, and it could only be placed on one target at a time. It goes up two rarities, by the way. I do reckon both the damage done and the additional experience will also help in—"

"Additional experience?" Villy cut in.

"Yeah?" Jake answered. "Only against higher-leveled enemies, though."

"Well, that puts the skill firmly in borderline-impossible-to-recreate territory. If you want to upgrade one, a skill like this would be optimal. These kinds of signature skills can sometimes do otherwise impossible things. Seriously, creating things like that is hard. I didn’t make a poison that increased experience gain before a long-ass time with research. Though, to be fair, increased experience gain isn’t actually that valuable and will, for many, just mean hitting a wall at a faster pace. I reckon this won’t be an issue for you, and that it only works on targets with higher levels is good. Remember, the path to power is not a sprint but a marathon. Skills that increase experience gained honestly aren’t that rare, either, and most professions or monsters focused on leadership will have skills to increase the experience gain of those under them. It’s often one of the advantages of living under a powerful noble or Alpha.”

That actually wasn’t that surprising to Jake. The Pylon already increased noncombat experience gained, and that leaders had such skills was to be expected. Jake was sure Jacob had some like that, and maybe Miranda did too? Phillip as well? He should probably ask them.

"So, do you think it would be good to upgrade if the experience part isn’t even that valuable?” Jake asked. “That was, in my mind, one of the big draws.”

"For borderline everyone else, I would say that the increased experience isn’t worth much if it doesn’t also come with an increased chance of enlightenment or something like that, but for you in particular, it’s great. As a new initiate in a new universe, there are many advantages associated with having a fast leveling speed, and I also don’t think you have to worry about hitting any walls anytime soon… if ever."

"I see… Well, I do like the skill quite a bit, even in its pre-upgrade form, so making it better would be great…"

Jake would have to decide, but before that, he moved on to the last skill. Just by skimming it, he already knew… he would have even more questions for the Viper.

Chapter 36

The Morality of Domination

Jake knew his class was considered good based solely on the stat points it gave and the—in his opinion—not very restrictive downsides it had. Yet he hadn’t expected it to grant him a legendary-rarity skill right at level 120, much less one that would give him such mixed feelings.

[Domination of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Legendary)] – Your avarice knows no bounds, and you claim whatever you decide belongs to you. Allows the Avaricious Arcane Hunter to initiate a Soulbinding Contract with other living beings, forcing them to serve you if they surrender to your desires while making them more inclined to work towards realizing your avaricious goals. Any bound being will serve you for life, and your demise will mean their deaths, while your advancement will give them opportunities to continue serving you. In your arrogance and avarice, you have even become able to force those above your level to serve you. Your ability to dominate a target or not is determined on an individual basis. The number of maximum dominated entities is determined by Willpower and how powerful those dominated are. If those you have dominated are foolish enough to attempt to break free, crush their souls to dust. Naturally, your avarice does not allow any possession of yours to escape your will once bound, and only death shall be their release. Dominating a living being will count as slaying it, rewarding extra experience.

The description was incredibly long… and hot damn. There was a lot packed in there. This skill appeared to have little to no relation to his arcane affinity, as far as he could tell, but was clearly entirely related to the "Avaricious" part of his class.

He had to read it a few times to get it… and he really hoped he misunderstood something. Jake had seen many skills—especially those related to Villy—with some weird-ass descriptions, many of them obviously yelling "I am evil!" but this one took the cake.

Jake barely knew where to start… so he decided to share the entire damn description with Villy to get a reaction.

"A domination skill? Good time to get one," Villy answered, far more casually than Jake expected. “Soulbinding a dungeon creature will effectively turn them into your possession and allow you to bring them out. Yours sounds like a rather powerful version—definitely not an easy one to break out of. It even sounds like it includes a Record and experience-boosting part to make those dominated be useful to you for a longer time. Good skill all around.”

"I guess… but… it’s kind of fucked up, isn’t it?" The entire skill just rubbed him the wrong way from here to the moon. It was fucked up, right? Or did he have some skewed perception of things? He didn’t… did he?

"Well, these kinds of skills do have some drawbacks. For the dominated target to progress much further after being bound is rare. I can’t say if it’s due to the targets having low levels of innate ambition that limit them or if it’s just inherent in these kinds of skills. Having a few Soulbinds can be very beneficial, as they do things you don’t have the time or desire to do yourself while being one hundred percent loyal. They can function as meat shields too."

"You know what I mean. Isn’t this essentially just forcing someone into slavery?"

"So that’s what you’re worried about? What a weird mentality. You are killing so many already, so what’s the difference? Soulbinds are essentially just pieces of equipment that can serve certain functions for you. They may be living entities, but viewing them as anything more than tools is meaningless. Those with such weak mentalities to agree to a Soulbound Contract aren’t worth anything to begin with. And have no doubt—they do need to agree to it. The system has some hard rules related to things like these contracts, and signing one cannot be fully forced. Coerced? Sure, but not forced.” His tone was still far too casual for Jake to feel comfortable.

"I think there is quite a big difference between killing someone and forcing them into servitude and manipulating their minds to serve you till the day they die."

"I already told you, you cannot force anyone or anything to accept it. They will always have a choice—even if the choice will be between becoming Soulbound or death. It often doesn’t even come to that. Many pathetic individuals choose to become Soulbound by those more powerful or influential than themselves, hoping to improve their own fates that way. Sure, it works for some, but advancing a single more rank or living a more luxurious life than before by giving up control of your own life does not make you any less pathetic.” Jake could practically hear his voice dripping with venom as he continued.

"Look beyond your own culture for once. You grew up on a planet with a history where forced servitude has quite the bad connotations—ones I agree with—but for the wrong reasons. Slaves are not to be pitied or seen as victims. They are weak and pathetic individuals who surrendered themselves to fates worse than death. The humans who rose up and died to fight for their own freedom are to be admired, but those who chose to wallow in their own misery deserve no pity or mercy. Tell me—if I came to you here and now and told you to become a slave or die, what would you do?"

Jake frowned as he listened to the Viper speak. He knew he and Villy had different views on many things, and this was clearly one of them. Perhaps it was because the Malefic Viper was exactly that—a viper—but Jake believed things were a bit more nuanced.

"For me personally, I would tell anyone who came to me and told me to become a slave to fuck off, and I’d gladly fight them to the death and die rather than agree. But that is me, and the current me at that. It is inherent to human nature to try and stay alive no matter the circumstances, even if it means becoming a slave. The sheer desire to stay alive and the hope of one day escaping a bad situation is incredibly human. Sometimes all people have is hope, so they choose to hold onto that—because once you’re dead, all hope dies with you. There is also the whole family aspect to it and how some chose to become slaves to protect those they love. Oh, and finally, let’s not ignore that for some, slavery is all they know. It is their norm. They cannot even imagine the concept of freedom, so to expect them to desire the unknown is unrealistic.”

Jake had predicted the rant Villy began to deliver. "You humans always had weird views on slavery, Hypocritical, even. Your race—on your planet too—always had a tendency to enslave anything they deemed lesser than themselves, yet admonished others for enslaving—a tendency that continued after the system. Before, you could at least excuse your enslavement of other races and calling them pets or whatever due to the limited intelligence and lack of sapience for those enslaved, but what now? Fuck, it isn’t even a problem with humanity, but all enlightened races. You talked about how they knew nothing else… That is how every damn beast feels when they grow up slaves and gain sapience while already forced into it. They never even got the choice, as they decided before their level of intelligence was high enough to.

"Do you have any idea how many of your race have professions or classes related to ‘taming,’ as they call it? Those who force beasts or other monsters to serve as slaves are called tamers, while those who force other enlightened races into servitude are called slavers. The same human can advocate for making a beast into their ‘pet,’ and at the same time admonish the evilness of a slaver. There is no fucking difference between the two, only the perceived value of the lives of two different sapient beings and the fact that the enlightened one is often in a better position to decide. Fuck, if one had to compare, taming a beast is far worse. It is deciding that the beast will one day evolve into realizing it is a fucking slave or condemning them into never evolving into sapience at all. Either way, it is a fate far worse than death—a fate the beast will never have had the option of making. It would be like holding a toddler to its words for life, not even considering the child could grow up and change their mind.

"I have heard all the excuses. ‘Oh, but I am good to my pets!’ ‘I love my pet like family!’ Well, guess the fuck what? It doesn’t change shit. You’re still a slaver, and you should own up to it and stop making bullshit excuses to make yourself feel better. Ah, but don’t get me wrong, I am not saying it is wrong… It is just the pathetic double standard I hate. In fact, I would advise you to pick up the Domination skill. Get a few good slaves or beasts and have them serve as defenders of your city, or maybe just as temporary fighting power. Just don’t enslave anything you actually value—that would just be ruining them and nothing else. You can even bring that troll out with you. Slaves are tools, nothing more. Treat them as such, and never become some hypocritical asshole who talks about how you actually value them. If you did, they wouldn’t be slaves."

The Malefic Viper stopped his rant, and Jake now recognized the undertones of anger and disgust, especially in the middle parts. Throughout it all, Jake had frowned. He had to consider many things he had never even thought of before. Was having pets in the old world kind of fucked up? Jake would say no… but having them now would be, if they were sapient.

He was damn sure that Villy had a history with slavery. As a beast, the double standard of viewing tamers and slavers as different clearly irked him, and Jake could see that growing up in that kind of environment had affected him.

Jake had already come to terms with the fact that he was technically a mass-murdering machine. He knew that many of those he killed were intelligent beings with sapient thought, but he had killed them anyway, only for his own selfish goal of getting stronger. He didn’t delude himself into thinking what he was doing was somehow moral; it just was what it was. The way the world functioned. Jake was a hunter, so he would hunt.

A part of him hated the thought of ever enslaving anything or anyone or forcing them to do his bidding. Jake was a firm believer in not doing to others what he didn’t want them to do to him… which was why he was fine fighting and killing. He would be totally fine with a strong foe fighting and killing him in a fight, as that was just how things worked…. but he didn’t see any reason for needless cruelty.

Fighting foes far weaker than yourself was just pointless. Likewise, torture was a waste of time that led to nothing good happening. It was why Jake had hated the Minotaur Mindchief so much. If the Minotaur had just decided that it would kill all humans and gone on some righteous crusade, Jake would’ve called it a moron, but he would’ve at least understood it partially. But torturing people? Fuck that noise.

And what was worse torture than turning someone into a slave? To Jake, it would be the worst kind of existence he could imagine, which was why the concept was so abhorrent in his mind. Jake would truly rather die than be a slave, and would rather kill than enslave others. Temporary prisoner? Maybe, if the situation called for it, but the Domination skill was permanent. It was a one-way ticket to—as the Viper had said—turning another living being into a possession.

"Yeah, I am not a fan of slavery," Jake answered incredibly bravely. "I guess you dabbled?" He already knew the answer.

"Once upon a time, yes, but not since I became a god. There simply has been no reason for me to do so. People came to serve me willingly, so why would I force others to? Enslaving someone is also a great way to ruin any future they may have, which is why it’s pretty much never done with anyone of value. Also, you won’t have to fear ever being Soulbound.”

"Why not?" Jake asked. Well, Villy likely wouldn’t have it, and the blessing likel—

"You got a Bloodline. Anyone with a Bloodline cannot be Soulbound. You can still sign Soul Contracts, but not a full-on Soulbinding. The reason for this is simple… Soulbinding someone is binding them like an item to your soul, and as you know, you need to meet the requirement to bind an item before you can do so. Due to the nature of Bloodlines, this means that no one can ever meet the requirements to bind your soul.”

"That’s good to know, I guess," Jake answered. "Does all this mean there is no way to properly have animal companions or something like that? You know, without making them slaves or forcing them to serve you, but still helping them progress with you?"

"Your humanoid bias is showing again. That is literally what a party is, Jake. Leader-type professions help you and your companions to work together and progress in leveling up. There are plenty of such professions or even classes focused on fighting with companions of other races, not just other humanoids. Alphas, nobles, leaders, or other kinds of leadership-focused paths function to amplify the progress of other enlightened or monsters around them and are found everywhere. You don’t need a contract or some kind of magical connection to be companions. There will never truly be a soul-bond of equals unless you fully bind your soul to another. These kinds of bonds do exist, but they will never be available to you either due to your Bloodline. All your Soulbinds will automatically become those of domination."

"Not sure if that sucks or not, but I guess it doesn’t truly matter," Jake finally said. "I don’t like this whole domination business. If I could release people again and just use the skill to bring the trolls out of the dungeon, that would be one thing, but this is just too fucked up. So fuck that."

"Up to you. The skill is great, and I would personally have gone for it, primarily for the bonus experience and gateway into practicing soul magic—but don’t do it if you don’t feel like it’s your path. Taking a skill like this will greatly impact your future and your progress from here on out. Picking what is compatible with you in the long run is far more important than just going for some short-term benefits. You don’t need a bond to be companions or friends. It is only for those insecure that the other will betray them, or those lacking the confidence to have others serve them willingly. Or the worst ones—those too cowardly to battle themselves. Slaves have uses, but any task that a slave can accomplish, a willing servant or companion can do better. All who now serve me don’t do so because I make them, but because they want to. Probably for selfish reasons, the lot of them, but that’s still better than some forced bullshit contract, as at least they do it willingly—and reaffirm that they continue to do it willingly every single day by not leaving.”

"Yeah, I also prefer the non-slavery form of employment myself. Thanks for the talk, as always, Villy. I have a feeling this topic will come up again. I guess slavery just isn’t my thing, and honestly a bit of a dickish thing to do. Glad you grew out of that behavior.” He said the last part snarkily, bidding his goodbyes.

"Heh, talk to you later. Open to discussions on heavy topics at any time, and I always find them enlightening. Mainly because everyone else I talk to just agrees or refuses to even engage. Good luck and have fun. Oh, by the way, don’t be mad when you come to the Order in the future. Slavery abounds here!"

The presence of the Viper faded, and while Jake felt like he could still send a message, there was no need to force it. One didn’t always need to have the last word. Also, he seriously hoped that the last part was a joke… but he feared it wasn’t. He would cross that bridge when the time came.

Jake shook his head, many thoughts still tumbling around. It had been quite the conversation. Jake had heard another rather foreign perspective to his own, but it hadn’t really changed his mind, just expanded his thoughts a bit. Maybe it was just him being stubborn and having the culture of Earth too deeply ingrained in his personality, but he didn’t like slavery as a concept, and he was too damn stubborn to ever do so. He could accept that when it came to others; it maybe wasn’t that big a deal. The multiverse was big, and many different people existed. He was sure that he could find plenty of humans on Earth who thought it would be perfectly normal and moral to bind a beast to themselves with what was essentially a slave contract. Jake just wasn’t one of those people.

It did suck a bit that the first legendary skill he had been offered by either his class or profession was a dud, but he didn’t regret skipping it. It wasn’t him. Instead, he picked the Mark of the Avaricious Hunter, as that one was far more aligned with who he was.

You have chosen to evolve Mark of the Ambitious Hunter to Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter.

Accept?

Y/N

Jake naturally picked yes and felt the knowledge flood his head for a few moments.

[Mark of the Ambitious Hunter (Rare)] – The prey is chosen, the hunt begins. Covertly mark a target, making you aware of their position at all times until the mark expires or is dispelled. All damage done to the marked target is increased. Additional bonus experience earned for slaying a marked target above your level. Adds a small bonus to the damage inflicted, the mark’s duration, and the mark’s subtlety based on Perception.

-->

[Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter (Ancient)] – Your prey is chosen, the hunt is on. Covertly mark targets, making you aware of their positions at all times until the marks expire or are dispelled. All damage done to marked targets is increased. Arcane damage has its damage amplified further. The extra arcane damage inflicted while the marks are active will be built up in the form of an arcane charge that you can detonate to release all the stored-up energy. Additional bonus experience earned for slaying a marked target above your level. (This effect remains even if your target dies to the mark detonating or within a short duration of the detonation). Adds a bonus to the damage inflicted, the duration of the marks, the marks’ subtlety, and the number of marks available based on Perception.

It honestly didn’t come with that much new know-how, just the basics of how to use it. It was a simple skill, just the way Jake used it. No long moral discussions about how fucked it was to mark things or not. It was a skill made for hunting down targets and killing them, just the way he liked it.

Though he had some doubts that the dungeon’s resident Deepdwellers would agree.

Chapter 37

Righteous Crusade

As with all new skills—or in this case, upgraded skills—it took a bit of experimenting and testing to fully understand his newfound capabilities. It had gone up two entire rarities, with many newly added functionalities. The first thing he tested was how many marks he could place in total.

Before, it had only been one, and that was quite frankly annoying. It was fine against lone, powerful enemies like the Prima, but it sucked against crowds of Deepdwellers. He also wanted to test the subtlety of applying the Mark… but he hadn’t found anything that noticed him placing it so far. Maybe the King had known? Though, to be fair, back then, the Mark had just expired damn fast due to the level disparity.

Anyway, Jake currently stood staring down on the next unsuspecting village of Deepdwellers. He began marking them all from highest to lowest and instantly felt a difference. Every single Mark gave a far more distinct feeling compared to before, and it no longer just made him aware of their position—it even made him aware of how they looked.

It was like a general outline of their bodies appeared in his mind. At least parts of it, as he saw that it was more focused on the center of their body and their heads, while the limbs were barely visible in the outline. It was better than before, but not perfect. Back then, it had felt more like he had a small dot on a radar and nothing else.

Next came the number of marks. Jake continued his marking strategy and was surprised when he passed ten. Even more so when he surpassed twenty, then thirty, and finally forty. Mark forty-one and forty-two also went through, but he innately felt that it would remove the first one he had placed when he tried to use another Mark.

Jake frowned, as the number was oddly specific. While forty-two was indeed the meaning of life, he doubted it was related to that fact. He knew it was based on Perception, and a quick peek at his stats made him quite sure what the explanation was: one Mark per 100 Perception.

With a current Perception stat at 4290, he was close to getting another mark available. Not that he believed he needed forty-two… It already felt unnecessary. Or was it? Just as the thought appeared, he began to consider the whole arcane charge aspect. With that, it made a lot more sense, and he already had a tactic for how he would handle the next village.

Overwhelming arcane airstrikes.

Well, it wasn’t that different from all the villages prior, but this time he would have extra explosions.

Jake focused and began conjuring orbs of arcane mana. It had been a small surprise that he hadn’t been offered a skill related to these orbs, but he assumed they were more or less just offshoots of Arcane Bolts that Jake had changed a little to focus more on scope rather than potency.

They were just bombs that aimed to destroy the geography and buildings, not to actually harm the Deepdwellers severely. It would help him to better understand the arcane charge thing, though. It was a bit cruel, but this village would become his testing ground. Their deaths would be his test results.

With his eyes closed, he focused as the orbs condensed around him one by one. Each of them crackled with energy, as they were made with very unstable arcane mana—which also meant very destructive mana. Once he had summoned eleven, he felt himself begin to lose control, so he sent them down.

At the same time, he took out his bow as an explosive arcane arrow appeared in his hand. Due to the faster travel speed of arrows compared to his orbs, everything arrived at once.

Four arcane arrows exploded in different parts of the village, causing a chain reaction as the blasts hit the orbs that had also descended. Once more, the Deepdwellers had been unprepared, as a couple of the regular ones took heavy injuries in the first salvo. Additionally, Jake had made sure to aim his initial attacks in an area where nearly all the Deepdwellers were marked, and he instantly saw and felt the effects.

Those with marks now looked far more substantial to him, and even their limbs were lit up. He now realized it was the arcane energies in their body he could see. Jake also felt that at any moment, he could detonate the marks if he so wanted. Of course, it only worked on those who had taken a bit of damage, and the explosions would do little to no harm on most of them… except two.

Two of the Deepdwellers were hurt pretty badly, as they had each been hit directly by an arcane arrow. Jake felt the arcane energy that had invaded and was now nestled within the Mark. Where exactly this Mark was on their bodies, he didn’t know… assuming it was even on their bodies. He knew there was plenty of metaphysical stuff going on with many energy types. Well, the only way to find out where the energy was… was to see where it would come from.

With a mental command, he activated one of the arcane charges. A part of him had expected a giant arcane explosion, but what he got instead was way more… subtle. A faint purple-pink light emanated from every orifice of the Deepdweller as if something had flashed a powerful light within it, and it screamed out in pain. It was only a brief flash that caused no explosion, nor made any impact on anything outside… but it did a number on the marked target.

It hadn’t killed it, but it rolled around on the ground in pain. Jake wasn’t entirely clear about what had happened… It didn’t look to have taken any physical damage at all from the arcane charge being activated. Yet it sure seemed like it had been heavily hurt.

He turned his attention to the second Deepdweller that had been heavily damaged and activated its Mark, too, focusing more on the process this time. When it activated, Jake felt the arcane energy attack the exact same way the Mark amplified damage… Oh, shit.

Of course… All the way back in the Badger’s Den, Jake had discovered that his Mark of the Ambitious Hunter’s amplified damage just functioned as direct damage to the health pool of his foes. The same was true for the upgraded Mark, but Jake hadn’t expected the arcane charge to attack the exact same thing.

Back then, Jake hadn’t known that his Mark actually directly attacked the fourth layer of the soul. It damaged health points for any Vitality-based lifeform, but as it also worked on things like elementals, he assumed it only worked on consuming mana if that was what kept them alive and served as their health pools.

Somehow, his arcane energy could tap into that part of the skill and directly attack the health points of the foe with arcane energy. It was entirely unexpected, and it made him wonder if it was because his arcane energy made it possible, or if it was solely the skill. It had many implications for sure…

More experiments are in order, he thought. He even got a few ideas related to alchemy… but those were for later, as in after the dungeon.

Jake continued raining down destruction like he was a western superpower and the Deepdweller village was a poor but oil-rich country. He primarily focused on the marks and how they did their damage, and he even found that his Sense of the Malefic Viper helped a bit when he activated the marks. He felt his own affinity burning into the health of his foes.

The resident Warlord was an especially great test subject, as Jake allowed it to push itself all the way. He even allowed it to absorb the Golden Mushroom and infuse it—as well as plenty of its brethren—for him to keep building up an arcane charge larger than any before.

Because it could heal from most damage fast, the arcane charge just got bigger and bigger, making it easier and easier to feel. As the arcane charge wasn’t considered a poison, it didn’t count for Jake’s Sense of the Malefic Viper, only allowing him to rely on the affinity-sensing part of the skill—a part that was primarily aimed towards identifying affinities in the environment. Luckily for him, he had such insanely high Perception he could feel far more than anyone his level usually would.

Full Perception builds were truly the best.

Jake kept damaging the Warlord as it tried to kill him, but in its mutated, hulking form, it simply had no way to fight back. Shit, it had been more of a threat before its transformation due to its speed, while Jake could now just casually One Step Mile away and bombard it.

Another thing he noticed that made him very happy was that the skill worked well with even his stable arcane arrows. Not via the piercing of the arrows or the physical damage they caused, but the direct damage inflicted based on range and his Perception.

That damage was like that of his Mark, but Jake had never noticed that the damage was actually of his arcane affinity. At least, his new Mark recognized it to be. To say he was pleased to learn that was an understatement, as it meant he had just found even more synergy.

The entire fight just ended up being Jake doing damage with different arcane attacks on the helpless Warlord several levels above himself. Jake kited it and kept damaging it slowly until he felt the arcane charge on the Mark begin losing energy. It appeared there was a maximum duration for the stored arcane energy. Good to know.

Without further ado, Jake activated the charge that had been building up through the entire fight. Due to the sheer magnitude of it, he expected something more than what had happened with the weaker Deepdwellers.

When it was activated, it was like a flashlight was turned on for less than a quarter of a second within the Warlord before being turned off again. The entire Deepdweller just flashed in a pink-purple light through all its open wounds, making it look like a blinking disco ball of flesh and tumors for a brief moment.

And then… then it just kept attacking. Honestly, it was super underwhelming. Jake felt like the arcane charge had done shitloads of damage… but the Warlord just had an insanely high health pool and healed incredibly fast from any damage taken.

A bit miffed, Jake finished the fight the usual way. AKA by blowing it up with poisoned arrows using Arcane Powershots before moving in with Touch of the Malefic Viper as a finishing touch—pun fully intended.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Warlord – lvl 147] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 121 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 114 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake fished out the now Infused Golden Mushroom from the corpse and tossed it in his inventory as always. Without needing to delay, he moved on to the next village.

He didn’t know how many Deepdwellers there were, but he honestly hoped a lot. Jake was fully aware that his skillset happened to be incredibly effective against these life-affinity foes. He had powerful poison that was insanely effective at draining health points, his enemies tended to deal with ranged opponents badly, and their general level of Perception was low.

There were so many damn weaknesses to exploit for someone like Jake. He could see Neil’s party struggling with these foes, as they didn’t have the burst damage to nearly instantly finish off the Fungalmancers who could heal others, nor the poison to inhibit the natural life-affinity skills and natural regeneration of the Deepdwellers—especially the variants.

For Jake, however… this dungeon was his ideal hunting ground. So on a hunt he went. The next Deepdweller village was reached around thirty minutes later, about two hundred and fifty kilometers into the dungeon.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Shroomguard – lvl 145] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

The village fell as easily as all the others, and he claimed another mushroom. No level this time, so he moved on swiftly after a brief round of meditation.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Shroomguard – lvl 148] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 122 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Another village, another Shroomguard, another level. He had finally figured out how to get the Shroomguard to infuse the mushrooms: They could absorb it into their shields and merge with it, making them into turtle-like creatures with tough armor—armor that still couldn’t block Touch of the Malefic Viper. Three hundred kilometers in now.

Next village.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Warlord – lvl 149] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 123 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 115 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

This village had the biggest regiment of Fungalmancers so far, with more than ten in a single village. Not that Jake complained; the experience was good. He did have to spend quite a while chugging potions and meditating after, though. He even had time to get in a bit of alchemy. One would think the environment made making poisons hard, but it really didn’t matter. The Altmar Cauldron of Supreme Simplicity was too impeccably made to be affected by outside atmospheric mana.

Once he was healed up, he moved on. This village had been over four hundred kilometers in. The distance between them was growing.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Warlord – lvl 150] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*You have slain [Deepdweller Shroomguard – lvl 149] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 124 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

For the first time, he had encountered a village with two boss-tier variants. This village—or maybe calling it a city was more accurate now—had been a fucking pain, to put it lightly, and had taken nearly half a day to defeat.

It had taken him a while to find it too, as it was over two hundred kilometers from the last village—or in other words, six hundred kilometers in. It came to a point where he feared he had somehow missed one. He did find a few hunting parties and such around the place, but he had finished all of those off easily, as the best only had a single Fungalmancer or warrior with them.

There had been in excess of five hundred Deepdwellers in the village—he decided to just stick with calling it a village for consistency—and they had all been a pain to deal with. For some reason, though, the entire village had only had three Fungalmancers and a handful of warriors, making it easier in that department. It had also had two Golden Mushrooms, so that was nice.

From here on out, it would only get tougher… but Jake had no fear at all. He had yet to encounter any creature truly able to make him get serious. Shit, the strongest creature he had seen fight so far was the troll. There was also the Heartwarden he couldn’t Identify. Jake was banking on that one to finally provide a good fight.

But for now… for now, Jake would clear out any village he came across on his warpath through the dungeon, leaving not a single Deepdweller alive in his wake. For lest we forget, they were evil, mushroom-loving monsters.

Thus his righteous crusade continued.

Chapter 38

Schemes Of An Old Man

Jake’s skill selection for his class at level 120 had led to many things. A talk about slavery, a new skill for Jake to experiment with, insight into his own progress, and one more significant aspect: the system more or less telling him to start looking into using his arcane affinity with more than mana.

As he went deeper and deeper into the Undergrowth dungeon, he began doing a bit of practice with it throughout some of his fights. He had quite a few skills that used stamina, and he went with those first instead of trying to free-form stuff. Magic? He wasn’t even sure what skill-less manipulation of stamina was called.

That was when he remembered… he already had tried using a mix of stamina and mana before in a skill he had upgraded where he made the energies mix. When he upgraded Splitting Arrow, he’d fused the two energies to split the arrows. Stamina would function as the physical bodies of the arrows, while the mana would function as their inherent magic.

Coupled with the system assistance in upgrading skills once he was on the right track, upgrading it hadn’t even taken a day. Yet Jake hadn’t kept testing after that. Well, to be perfectly fair, it wasn’t like he had many chances to. The World Congress and then his crafting marathon had come shortly after the last time he upgraded a skill with stamina. He had just needed a reminder to keep working on it.

Of course, neither of those energies had been arcane affinity, but his arcane affinity was closely related to pure mana, after all, so it could serve as a base.

Jake began considering all his skills from one end to the other… and found quite a few he used stamina with. Arcane Powershot was the most obvious one... but how would he integrate his arcane affinity into the stamina portion of that?

The stamina portion of that skill was the stamina moving inside his body. Enhanced Splitting Arrow, Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter… both used either arcane energy or mixed mana and stamina outside the body. Finally, Shadow Vault also used a mix, but that one was honestly just too weird for Jake to study in the short term.

Anyway, Arcane Powershot used stamina in his upper body with arcane mana outside of it, enhancing the bow and sending currents running over his body. He used stamina inside his body and closest to his skin to make sure his own destructive arcane mana didn’t harm him while strengthening his entire upper body to draw the string and charge the arrow.

Meanwhile, the bow was infused with stable arcane-affinity mana. Which made Jake consider more deeply… what kind of effect would his arcane affinity even create when used with stamina inside his body? Was it even made to be used inside his body, or was it more suited for using it outside?

The arcane barrier was, of course, outside of his body. The Arcane Wave was outside, too, even if it did erupt from within him. But… he didn’t truly know if the energy it erupted with would all be arcane affinity. Maybe just the mana part was, as the skill used both mana and stamina.

Jake’s arcane affinity had two parts to it: stability and destruction. Together, his affinity was all about stable destruction, with both extremes always carrying a bit of the effect from the other. An explosive arrow needed to be highly destructive but still stable enough to avoid blowing up right away, while a stable arrow needed to be extremely tough but still able to deal damage outside of just piercing enemies. If it were just purely a physical arrow, it wouldn’t really be worthy of the arcane affinity, now, would it?

Mobilizing his arcane affinity outside the body wasn’t that complicated, but so far, all he really did it with was using mana… except for his new Mark. The Mark consumed stamina when he placed it on targets. Even the arcane energy that exploded within his foes contained no mana at all, but was some other kind of arcane-affinity energy. A part of it was clearly stamina with an arcane affinity… but all it did was deal damage directly to the health pool of his enemy… and Jake was still unsure if that was a special effect from his arcane affinity, or if it was just something the Mark made possible through system assistance.

This all led to the ultimate question: was it even possible to use his arcane affinity to make himself stronger internally? Theoretically, perhaps… but was he really going to risk experimenting?

With normal stamina, Jake had blown off more than one limb with his experimenting… What would happen if he tried to do so with even more potent stamina that had a tendency to go big boom? Sure, he could use the stable version… but would that even be better than normal stamina? No, he would absolutely need a mix. Jake felt like now wasn’t quite the time for that. Instead, he would focus on using the arcane affinity for external attacks for now.

The only issue was… he only really had the Splitting Arrow for that… or maybe his basic weapons skills? No, they weren’t really useable. All of this meant that Jake shelved the exploration of stamina mixed with arcane affinity for now, as he instead focused on clearing the Deepdweller dungeon. Hopefully, he could get a skill or some inspiration in the future that could push him further.

He was fully aware that was also one more option for stamina—some kind of aura skill. One that mimicked the Aspiring Blade of Nature or even the Nest Watcher back in the day, as it seemed to only use physical moves. Once more, he reached the issue that he didn’t know how to properly do that. A part of him also believed these auras were just outpourings of energy from inside the body—stamina was also called inner energy for a reason.

Keep things simple… and take the complications as they come, Jake thought as he flapped his wings and flew through the Undergrowth, picking up herbs here and there, hunting down the occasional hunting party, and searching for the next village.

Villages fell before him one by one, and he fought more and more variants as he got closer and closer to what he believed was the end of the dungeon—and the Heart of the Undergrowth.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 125 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 116 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 126 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Since entering the dungeon, more than two weeks had quickly passed—each fight took a while, after all, and his exploration of both the dungeon and his own skills hadn’t exactly helped his speed either. After the last village had been turned into a scorching hole of arcane energy, he finally reached something new. Jake had noticed that the dungeon had begun slowly closing in on itself again, becoming narrower and narrower after about the five-hundred-kilometer mark.

At twelve hundred kilometers, it suddenly ended in a large wall—a wall that was one hundred percent artificial. It was constructed, and Jake doubted it had been by the Deepdwellers. No, this was some kind of ancient construct made by some other civilization.

The entire wall was more than a kilometer tall and had a width of more than five kilometers, cutting off the entire path further into the Undergrowth. Jake tried to lay his hand upon it, and instantly he knew… there was no fucking way he could break it.

He did have one cheat, though. With his Sphere of Perception, he saw that the entire wall was nearly a hundred meters thick, but that still meant he could see a couple hundred meters into the other side. There, he saw what looked like a massive net of vines.. all looking like they congregated towards one area outside his range.

Jake scouted along the length of the wall until he saw an opening—and a single figure sitting in front of it, appearing to be in meditation.

It was a Deepdweller that was around four meters tall, and it carried no visible weapon. Everything about it besides its size made it look rather normal, as it didn’t even appear that bulky, but Jake could feel this was the strongest creature he had yet to see in the entire dungeon.

[Deepdweller Heartwarden – lvl 162]

Jake could now Identify it… and it was twelve levels above the second-strongest entity he had seen. Sidenote: Jake, with this successful Identify, concluded he could now only see the level of foes with a level forty percent above his own since reaching D-grade.

He smiled. The dungeon had given good experience, but had been a bit lacking in the excitement department. Maybe the Heartwarden could give him a good fight.

The old man blocked the sword of the young woman effortlessly as she slid across the ground to strike again. Her sword appeared to split into dozens as phantom blades rained down. Yet with a single swipe, all the blades disappeared, and the young woman was knocked flying away. She landed on the ground, holding the sword in a shaking grip.

"Your blade is restless. What is bothering you, my child?" Miyamoto asked his great-granddaughter.

Her name was Reika, and she was the youngest of the main family clan, meaning she was his youngest direct descendent, which had resulted in quite a bit of doting from all parts of the family. She did have four older siblings, so not much pressure had ever been put on her, meaning she had always pursued her passions over everything else.

Before Miyamoto had become immobile, Reika had always come by to watch him practice with his sword and had chosen to pick it up herself. Her family had disapproved at first, as it was not something they believed a young girl should spend her time on, but when she had proven her talent, they all relented. That the old patriarch had also liked it wasn’t a detriment either.

After the system, the young woman—who had turned twenty-five just a few days ago—had been one of the outstanding surprises of the clan. She had not been in the same tutorial as Miyamoto himself, but had instead entered with many university students, as she had been to a meeting with her Ph.D. adviser at the time of the integration. Another thing she had been stubborn about, having chosen to study chemistry and not economy or business management like most of her siblings.

In her tutorial, she had completely taken charge and managed to excel above all expectations, and had returned to the clan as the second-strongest member of the entire clan. She had helped claim other Pylons but had not entered the World Congress, as Miyamoto saw no reason to tip their hand and make everyone aware that the Noboru Clan had so many powerful members. This was also the reason they hadn’t brought any other D-grades than him despite having two others at the time.

"I still don’t understand… Why send me?” Reika tried to argue. “I am not a negotiator, much less a diplomat. Even if you wish for someone to learn about his alchemical prowess, I do not see how it wouldn’t be preferential to only send a small regiment of noncombatants and diplomats. Sending me and my companions could also possibly be interpreted as an unintended show of force and worsen relations.”

His great-granddaughter was not only a supremely talented swordsman—she was also their most talented alchemist. Miyamoto regretted not bringing her to the World Congress, as he wished he had made her meet the Hunter from Haven.

"This will not solely be political, but a chance for you to learn," Miyamoto explained with a fatherly smile. “Your approach to alchemy is one of modern thought, while Lord Thayne of Haven has knowledge of an entirely different path. One of ancientness handed down from an entity above our comprehension. I believe he has much to teach you, and not only about alchemy.”

Her tutorial had included plenty of ways to attain and progress the alchemy profession. Miyamoto couldn’t help but find it coincidental that an entire faculty of natural sciences students had found themselves in a tutorial with the alchemy profession freely available. Moreover, the tutorial had been sponsored by an alchemy-related god, which was possibly why it was organized.

Reika had gained this profession and had, only two weeks ago—a month after the World Congress—gotten it to 99 and evolved it. With it, she had attained her Perfect Evolution, and had since then progressed immensely fast in both her class and profession.

“Are we even certain this man will be open to teaching?” she said, trying to sound respectful while at the same time adamantly disagreeing. “From the reports, he seems the reclusive type, and not one to openly accept someone coming to spar with him and exchange knowledge, much less teach another for nothing. It seems like a needless gamble.” Miyamoto found it endearing, as she was one of the very few clan members who dared argue back.

It wasn’t even a discussion that was necessarily relevant right now. The distance to Haven was vast and would take even him over a month to pass, so it would have to wait till after the Treasure Hunt. He knew that she would be accepted, as that was one of the terms that the City Lord Miranda had agreed to in order to secure the votes for herbs and the Treasure Hunt.

The agreement was only to have a delegation or an embassy of sorts from the Noboru Clan. None of it included his great-granddaughter interacting or getting any guaranteed meetings with Lord Thayne, but Miyamoto had a good idea for how to get that when the time came.

"A man who strives to stand at the apex does not turn away chances to improve, much less a challenge," Miyamoto explained confidently. “If you have the confidence to stand tall before him with your level of skill and power, he will meet you, and he will hear you out.”

"How can you be so certain, Patriarch? We know close to nothing about him, and the intelligence team is still working on information on his familial situation and history—a daunting task with the interference from the Court of Shadows. I do not doubt he is as extraordinary as has been claimed, but to know his person is another thing." Reika shook her head.

Miyamoto saw that she truly struggled to understand his intentions and his certainty. His smile grew as he shook his head and confidently declared, "You are my great-grandaughter, and you are extraordinary too. Lord Thayne will not be able to resist a challenge and an opportunity to spar with another extraordinary human in the same field he is passionate about."

"How can you be so sure?" she said, a slight blush on her cheeks from the praise. Her long black hair was barely hiding the flush, which even went down her neck. Truly, praise had become too rare a commodity in the clan, but it also meant that each time it happened, the impact was higher.

"Because this old man would be unable to resist."

Of course, there was one part he didn’t need to mention. Something that was perhaps just a small hope an old man had in his heart. Lord Thayne was an extraordinary young man, only a few years older than his great-granddaughter. If something happened and the Thayne family was joined more closely to the clan, it certainly wouldn’t be something to complain about.

With the younger brother already taken and the City Lord of Haven not having that kind of relationship with Lord Thayne as the rumors suggested, he could only hope for nature to take its course if an extraordinary young man and woman with similar interests began spending a lot of time together. Even if it led to nothing, a friendship would also be valuable.

Of course… it was all just the schemes of an old man. Hope for what could possibly be. Who knew if any of it was realistic with what upheaval the Treasure Hunt could create, after all?

Chapter 39

Heartwarden

The Heartwarden looked completely unaware of the hunter that was currently observing it. Yet Jake had a strong feeling it was aware of his presence. So even if it didn’t know where he currently was, it should have at least picked up that someone or something was coming.

This was why Jake didn’t aim to repeat his opening attack against the Prima. He was certain the Heartwarden had something prepared, as while the Deepwellers weren’t the most intelligent creatures—mushroom worship, case in point—they weren’t complete idiots.

His Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter had the issue of only working on the intended target, meaning if the Heartwarden had put up some defensive measures, his attack would be completely useless. Jake wasn’t entirely sure it had, but he did notice that the area it was in was covered in what looked like four odd, magic circles. All of them seemed inert, but that could just be because they didn’t have power poured into them at the moment.

However, they did look to be of the same making as the wall. All the circles were placed on black slabs of stone that Jake assumed were made of the same material.

Jake couldn’t see what was inside the wall due to where he stood, but he was ninety-nine percent sure he couldn’t get in there without defeating the Heartwarden first. It would kind of be a shitty dungeon if you could just have your defensive fighter distract the big boss as you went for the loot.

Yes, Jake did believe the Heartwarden was the final boss of the Undergrowth—at least, the standard part of it. He hoped there would be more powerful foes deeper within, beyond the wall. However, discovering that would be for after the fight.

Having learned from past mistakes, Jake began summoning his Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. While he hadn’t fought this particular variant of Deepdweller before, he had fought plenty to get a good enough understanding of them to summon the arrow.

It was an arrow much like the one he’d summoned against the others. The arrow was black and exuded a faint feeling of death due to its inherent necrotic properties. Jake doubled up by coating it with uncommon-rarity Potent Necrotic Poison, as well as using the same bottle to prepare a stock of stable arcane arrows coated in poison.

Once he was done, he didn’t fire the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter. The arrow was massive like all others, and more than a meter long, but Jake had a strong feeling it would be a waste to just fire it. Instead, he wrapped it up in arcane strings and put it on his back as he drew a regular poisoned stable arcane arrow and began charging his Arcane Powershot.

Through testing, he knew the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter would remain for at least a while, so as long as he fired it within the next five to ten minutes, things should work out fine. However, he did feel it leaking some of its energy even now, making him aware he was on a timer.

Arcane energy swirled around him as he nocked the arrow, took aim, and drew the string. Arcane Powershot powered up as he focused on the sensation of the arcane mana across his skin and into the bow, the feeling of stamina welling in his upper body and allowing him to display strength far above his usual.

Once he sensed his body faltering, unable to take the buildup of energy without causing serious damage that could impede him in the fight to come, he released the arrow to an explosion of arcane power.

The condensed mana he had been standing on unsurprisingly blew up, but his wings were already summoned and worked to stabilize him. Another arrow was already being drawn as his opening shot arrived. Jaked spared only a moment to freeze the Heartwarden with Gaze of the Apex Hunter as he saw the results of his attack.

When the arcane arrow was twenty meters away from the Heartwarden, a barrier of green energy appeared in mid-air, and a green rune lit up on the back of one of its hands.

The arrow impacted the barrier along with all of the energy from the Arcane Powershot. It held up for a moment until it shattered, and the arrow continued down towards the Heartwarden. But it was too late, as it had already dodged to the side.

Jake landed his eyes on it again and saw it now had equipment in both hands. In one hand, it wielded a mushroom shield, and in the other, a crystal halberd. This was the first clue as to what kind of capabilities this creature had.

At the same time, as he observed the Deepdweller, it clearly also regarded him with some magical sense just before it attacked. It cut the air and sent a wave of green energy flying towards him, using a type of attack that Jake felt like every damn creature fighting with melee weapons had.

In Jake’s opinion, a feeble attempt at trying to be a ranged fighter. He easily dodged in the air, firing another arrow towards the Heartwarden. The rune on the back of the hand holding the shield lit up, making a barrier of green energy appear before it.

Just as the arrow hit the barrier, it split in four, all of them exploding with destructive energy. It burned away the barrier but also flooded the atmosphere with dense arcane mana. Enough for the creature’s mana sense not to detect the follow-up attack in time.

It blocked two of the arrows with its shield, but the other two hit it in its shoulder and stomach. Some would argue it had gotten unlucky, but Jake called it luck that one of the arrows that hit it was the "true" arrow—the one dripping with toxic energy.

Poison successfully delivered.

At least, Jake thought so, until he saw the shield-holding hand light up again. A barrier appeared—both inside and around the shoulder of the Heartwarden. He frowned as he felt the poison failing to spread through his Sense of the Malefic Viper.

With a quite grueling sound, a cube of flesh was ripped out of the Deepdweller’s own body, containing the arcane arrow as well as all the infected flesh. The cube was tossed to the side, the majority of the poison wasted. As for the wound? A rune on the back of the hand holding the halberd lit up as green energy pulsed across its body, making the wound heal even faster than when Jake consumed a potion.

Well, that’s one way to deal with it, Jake thought. It honestly wasn’t that bad, as he’d made the creature expend a lot of resources to remove the poisoned arrow. He had plenty of poison to give out, after all.

The Heartwarden seemed to know this too. It charged towards him, halberd held high. It was flying a lot like the Shroomguards had, but it also appeared to be able to step in the air like the Warlords, making Jake more certain this creature was a mix of the two.

It attacked with mighty swipes, but Jake simply dodged back, not allowing it to pin him down. His wings left a trail of poison gas that forced his enemy to constantly expel it while also landing the occasional shot. The fight was honestly going a lot easier than Jake expected. He did have some issues dealing damage, as it blocked most attacks with the shield, and what damage he did do was instantly healed… but he was slowly winning out, forcing the Heartwarden to reveal more of its powers.

This was when Jake learned it didn’t only have the powers of the Warlords and Shroomguards, but the Fungalmancers too. The ground below him began churning as vines flew up and grasped for him. It also began spitting out a cloud of spores from its mouth to counter his poison mist.

Jake cared little for the attack but sent a blast of arcane energy down towards the grasping vines, blowing up a few of them while easily dodging the remaining ones. In fact, the newfound powers didn’t change much, as Jake still stayed ahead of the Heartwarden at every turn.

Feeling confident, Jake increased his aggressiveness to actually deal some damage. He had failed to land a single poisoned arrow since that first one, with the Heartwarden blocking or dodging every one after that. To change up the situation a bit, Jake began firing more arrows, allowing the Heartwarden to get closer than before to decrease the travel distance.

Instantly he began landing far more arrows than before, as it failed to block every one of them, but at the same time, Jake also got a few scratches from vines or the green waves of energy it kept sending after him. Nevertheless, it was a trade he was willing to make.

Jake was waiting for a good opportunity to land the dose of death he carried strapped to his back in the form of a giant arrow, but it appeared that the Heartwarden made its move first.

The runes on both hands lit up at once, causing fungus vines to surface far faster than before as they gave off a green glow. Barriers also began appearing around him to block off his path of retreat, forcing Jake to either face the rising vines or the Heartwarden directly.

He chose the vines.

Jake fired down an exploding arcane arrow that split into four, sending out a giant blast that destroyed hundreds of meters’ worth of airspace and took the vines with it. He fired again and destroyed even more, yet his danger sense spiked—the Heartwarden wasn’t done.

That was when he saw them in his sphere. Millions of small splinters floating in the air from the exploded mushroom vines, as it appeared that small fragments of wood had been within. All these splinters gathered in a matter of seconds, and spears Jake recognized as those worn by the warriors appeared in mid-air, floating behind the Heartwarden like a giant wall of spikes.

Jake counted over a thousand… all of them now headed straight for him in a rain of wooden spears.

He wanted to dodge away, but the damn barriers appeared around him again as the rune lit up on its shield-hand. When the halberd-hand lit up, so did the spears as green energy was infused into them.

Scales covered Jake’s skin as he summoned a shield of arcane energy in front of him. Simultaneously, he flapped his wings and focused on his sphere and danger sense, allowing his body to move as it wanted—straight towards the rain of spears.

This was not a situation he could get out of unscathed, but he could minimize the damage. The rain hit him as he dodged the first few. He was struck in the arm, but he avoided one headed for his shoulder due to that. He took one in the shoulder but avoided one to the chest and took one in the chest to avoid one in the head. Jake felt the poison from the spears invade his body, Palate already eating it up.

He was headed straight for the unprepared Heartwarden, which was using all its focus controlling the spears. Jake broke free of the rain, and he saw all the spears turn in air and speed towards his back far faster than he flew… but Jake was ready.

The strings on his back delivered the arrow as he summoned his bow. His gaze landed on the Heartwarden, and it froze. Unfortunately, this would not be enough to stop the rain of spears, as only its body was frozen. The Heartwarden seemed to have accepted the trade of being hit by Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter in exchange for dozens of spears impaling Jake.

Sadly for it, Jake had other plans. He needed to break its focus and make it lose control over the spears for just a moment, so he set it off.

The Mark activated, and the entire Heartwarden flashed with purple energy for the blink of an eye as it screamed in pain, the spears behind him becoming disorganized. Jake released his arrow straight towards the Heartwarden, which was hit in the chest without even making the slightest attempt to dodge. He had a new Mark already in place before the arrow hit.

It was blasted back several kilometers and smashed into the giant wall it had guarded. It would have been impaled if Jake’s arrow was able to pierce the wall, but he would just have to take the giant bleeding, festering hole in the Heartwarden’s chest instead.

Jake easily dodged all the spears, as the projectiles now fell towards his body without direction due to their manipulator getting blasted to kingdom come.

The Deepdweller at the wall began glowing in a green light, and both its halberd and shield were absorbed into its body as it fell. Jake saw it start to enter its second phase—but he was way ahead of it. Limit Break activated at 20% as Jake moved in, not giving it any time to transform.

A few quick One Step Miles, and he appeared where it would land. As it began mutating, it was unable to move properly, which Jake took full advantage of. He shot poisoned arrows up into the still-falling corpse, delivering poison dose after poison dose.

That was, until armor covered its body, just like it had covered the Shroomguards when they absorbed a mushroom. Jake smirked and kept firing where the armor didn’t have time to form, and when its entire body was covered, he jumped.

The grotesque, falling Deepdweller mutated so much it began sending out fleshy tentacles towards Jake, black veins covering its entire body from over twenty-five poisoned arrows. The tentacles swiped for him, but two blades appeared in his hands as he cut at them.

He sliced and diced and jumped back as the wriggling mass of tumors and flesh began trying to take on a humanoid form. Once more, Jake did not allow it to do as it pleased. This transformation time was a huge opening that he had exploited and would keep exploiting.

He quickly coated his blades in poison as he moved in closer. The tentacles struggled, the body still forming. Where all the flesh came from, he didn’t know, but he saw it glow in a golden color, making him wonder if the damn thing had another Golden Mushroom within it.

The armor covered most of it, but where the tentacles came out, it was pure flesh. Jake cut off a part of a tentacle and used a Descending Dark Fang to deeply puncture the monstrosity of flesh. Jake flipped his wrist as two items appeared in it. One of them was a bottle with Potent Necrotic Poison, and the other was a small sphere pulsing with arcane energy. Jake pulled out the pin, then put the sphere and bottle into the wound as he jumped back, landing on the ground and doing a One Step Mile just before the explosion came.

*BOOM!*

As the explosion rushed over him, he pulled out another two spheres. He’d remembered them mid-battle, and now seemed like the perfect time to test them. The spheres from Arnold.

[Aluabsorbant Metal Sphere (Common)] – A sphere made of a composite metal by an extremely talented craftsman. Due to the materials used, this sphere has incredibly high conductivity and can effortlessly absorb and store most types of mana affinities. Once the orb has absorbed enough mana, the trigger pin will be fully inserted. Pulling the pin will release all the stored mana at once after a slight delay. (Charge: 99.8%)

Jake was surprised by the explosion, and based on the agonizing screams of the Heartwarden, it didn’t like it either. The explosion was about the same level of power as one of his explosive arcane arrows, so it wasn’t that extreme. It didn’t matter, though, as the primary purpose of the sphere had been to detonate the poison bottle.

He threw two more spheres to test them some more, then took out his bow and nocked another arrow. Arcane Powershot began charging as another explosion of arcane energy rushed over his body, his scales crackling with energy.

Another burst of arcane energy exploded out of him as he fired the Powershot before swiftly beginning to draw another. He continued this as he bombarded the form that was still trying to regenerate itself constantly. It summoned barriers he broke, sent out tentacles he ignored, and even tried to summon more wooden spears it couldn’t control. Every ten seconds, another arrow pierced it, infecting it with more poison and dealing tremendous damage. Finally… Jake activated the charge. In a final flash, the monstrosity went still.

In the end… the entire Heartwarden fight was another disappointment, even if it had had some interesting aspects to it.

*You have slain [Deepdweller Heartwarden – lvl 162] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 127 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 117 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake lowered his bow when the notification came. He had won a battle against a foe so many levels above himself… yet he frowned. Was he just too well suited against the Deepdwellers or what? They all seemed so easy to beat, even compared to other foes their level. Heck… even the Prima had been more difficult to deal with than this Heartwarden. It sure as hell would have been a far harder fight if it was above level 150.

With disappointment, he sighed and went to check out the corpse. Within, he found another Infused Golden Mushroom, to the surprise of no one.

There has to be more to this dungeon.

Jake turned his attention to the wall and the magic circles around the opening leading into it. He quickly went over to one of them, mushroom still in hand. The platform below him lit up with a green light as he stepped on it, and he smiled. He put the mushroom into his storage, at which point it instantly stopped glowing. He took out another one—this one not infused—and the same light appeared. Nice.

The next minute was spent with Jake placing regular Golden Mushrooms on the four platforms, making them all glow. Once he was done, he turned his attention to the wall.

Jake saw a large gate halfway into the wall. The green shield sealing it off slowly dissipated.

Jake walked into the hole and through the fading barrier, inspecting the gate more closely. He noted that it was quite intricate, with many runes on it, and in the center, he saw what looked like an orb, or perhaps… a heart.

He flew up and put his hand upon it, and a notification appeared.

You have laid your hand upon the Heart of the Undergrowth.

Your quest is done. The dungeon has been cleared of the Deepdweller explorers that sought entry to the Heart of the Undergrowth. For long, they have prepared, and at their precipice of success, the invader came.

Do you wish to complete the dungeon now or seek what the Deepdwellers tried to claim?

Easiest choice of my life.

Chapter 41

Census Taking (Hard Mode)

As Jake charged his Arcane Powershot, there was one aspect of his usual opening salvo he became a bit doubtful about. Some basic sense of danger seemed to be an inherent ability of most beings in the multiverse, which meant landing powerful opening shots could be problematic if the attacks weren’t fast or powerful enough. Even then, some foes could still avoid it. Unless, of course, the attacker had some way to stop their target from evading—like Gaze of the Apex Hunter.

This was where Jake was doubtful… Did a Golem have a soul as he understood it? Things like elementals did, but would it have a soul for him to gaze into if this thing had been constructed? Only one way to find out.

Jake released the Arcane Powershot, which sent out an explosion of arcane mana around him. The stone beneath his feet still looked untouched besides a few remnants of arcane energy.

At the same time, he tried to activate Gaze of the Apex Hunter. He tried and felt like he couldn’t get a proper look at his foe. Like it was hidden behind something. It was not unlike that time with Phillip and his skill that blocked Identify… meaning this enemy had some kind of soul-protecting skill.

Usually, there was no way a level 117 human could pierce this defense and still activate the skill. But Jake was no normal human. He was a human that had thrown the vast majority of his Free Points into Perception, had a Bloodline that made the Perception stat even better, and was using a legendary skill.

Thus, his piercing gaze shattered the veil that sought to protect it, and just as the golem was about to dodge, it froze.

*BOOM!*

It was hit by a stable arcane arrow. An explosion of mana followed—not from the arrow, but from what it encountered. Jake saw a faint, shimmering barrier running along the golem’s exterior. A barrier that had completely blocked the arrow except for a nearly unnoticeable nick in the silver-like metal of the golem.

His opening attack, which usually left his foe severely damaged if taken head-on, had done barely any damage, but it had allowed him to see that it had a shield of sorts that defended it. Jake was not going to sit around and wait for it to counterattack. He took a step, making him teleport back over a hundred meters as he drew another arrow.

The golem several kilometers away turned his way, and Jake saw two blue, mechanical eyes stare back at him. He saw them faintly light up, and his danger sense exploded.

Oh, shit!

Jake took another step, making him appear not directly behind himself, but to the side. This turned out to be a very good choice, as where he had stood just a millisecond earlier was now occupied by a blue laser beam of destruction.

It didn’t cause any explosion, but Jake saw a small mark burned into the stone ground from the laser, which was more than he could leave with his own arrows. That eye-beam was packing some serious pow—

He had to dodge to the side again as another laser came his way, forcing him to abandon his strategy of rapidly attacking before the golem could make it to him. Once more, Jake was happy he had his practically precognitive danger sense. If not, he could have likely taken a severe wound from that first laser.

By the way, he called it a laser because it was. It wasn’t just a beam of pure mana like the Indigo Mushroom had made, but a concentrated beam of light-affinity mana. The remnants of light mana left in its wake were apparent.

The golem fired off a few more lasers until it became clear it wasn’t going to hit. Jake would have happily kept going to have the golem run itself out of mana, which was likely also the reason it had stopped. Jake spent far less resources dodging than it spent attacking.

It charged towards him, taking quick steps, but it wasn’t overly fast.

Jake finally took this chance to fire another arrow towards the golem. It split into five in mid-air—a new record—shortly before it reached the golem. His foe dodged in between them, but the moment they passed, all five exploded in a massive blast of arcane energy.

The golem came out of it, sizzling with energy but otherwise untouched. When it was around two kilometers away, Jake fired another arrow, and the golem also made a move.

Its foot landed on the ground, and just as it did so, a blast of mana came out of its sole, propelling it forward.

That’s—

The golem arrived before him in less than a second, one of its arms transforming in mid-air. The metal seemed to fold and bend, forming a large, crescent-shaped axeblade. An axeblade it swung with extreme momentum. Simultaneously, a small hole opened up as the back of its arm sent out another blast of mana to speed up the swing.

—a fucking jet engine!?

Jake bent his back over ninety degrees to avoid the swing, but before he could even retaliate, the axeblade changed direction mid-swing as another jet appeared on the other side of the arm.

This fucking thing was damn fast and strong, but its unpredictable movements were equally as dangerous. Jake was forced to roll awkwardly to the side as the blade smashed down where he had just been. It managed to leave a small scratch on the floor below, sending cold sweat down Jake’s back.

Now that the golem was within his sphere, he could inspect it far more closely. Its body was made of shiny, silver-like metal as he had first seen, but he had been unable to notice the smallest details on it before. Incredibly tiny openings were all over its exterior, with some larger openings placed around its limbs.

It was from these small holes that it fired blasts of mana. Much like how Jake had used mana blasts from his glove enchantment to propel himself and affect his airborne mobility, this golem used jet-like blasts to make incredibly fast and abrupt movements.

He also saw that its hands and feet were somewhat modular. They weren’t like liquid metal, but clearly its legs and arms could take many different forms—including an axeblade.

Jake managed to equip his scimitar before the next attack came. He blocked the hit with the flat side of the blade, one hand on the handle and the other at the top of the flat body of the blade. A jet-like blast came out of its arm, making the attack even more potent. He was knocked back hundreds of meters before landing on his feet, only to block yet another attack.

This time he didn’t land on the ground, but made a small platform that teleported him towards the charging golem. It was taken by surprise, and Jake swung his scimitar with both hands like the weapon was a baseball bat, and the head of the golem was a ball.

It tried to dodge, but Jake froze it with his Gaze for a fraction of a second. A shimmer of arcane energy barely managed to form on the blade before he hit the golem, making it spin in the air from the impact.

Fuck, that hurt, Jake thought, grinding his teeth from the reverberations going up his arms. It felt like that time he’d hit a streetlight with a metal pole, except far worse.

The golem flipped a dozen or so times in the air till two mana jets re-stabilized it, at which point the fucker attacked as if nothing had happened. Unfortunately, his attack hadn’t even left a mark, as it, too, had been blocked by the mana barrier.

I need distance.

Jake stepped forward but teleported back. He repeated this several more times, putting over a kilometer between him and the golem within a few seconds. He summoned both his bow and wings at once and fired an arrow after the golem.

It shot towards him with another jet burst. While it flew towards him, the other arm transformed into a claw-like shape. It reminded Jake of those things used to lift and crush cars… except far smaller and with razor-sharp edges.

With a flap of his wings, Jake took to the air and saw the golem dodge his arrow. At the same time, he pumped out poison mist and began summoning two arcane bolts, hoping to accomplish one of two things.

First of all, he wanted to do a bit of damage. Not to the golem itself, but its mana pool. No being had infinite energy, so Jake had already resigned himself to focusing on slowly depleting his foe's mana pool. He hoped the poison mist that attacked its entire surface would help do that.

Secondly, he wanted to find out more about how it perceived him. If it had some kind of pure mana-sensing skill, his poison mist could help disturb that along with the arcane bolts. On the other hand, if it were sight-based, he would have other paths of exploitation.

Either way, the poison mist and bolts shou—

A pulse passed through him, dispersing the cloud of poison as well as destroying both arcane bolts mid-way through construction. Jake even felt a prickling pain in his summoned wings as it passed through, but it failed to do anything other than deal insignificant damage.

What it did do was ruin Jake’s momentum as the grappling arm extended and shot up towards him. For a moment, Jake thought it was because the golem couldn’t fly, but as it tried to grab him, the small jets on its legs activated and took it airborne.

Jake mirrored its trick. He dodged the grab by firing a blast of mana from one glove as he swung his blade with the other, sending a prolonged arcane blade down towards the golem. It didn’t even react as the stable arcane blade broke on its mana barrier, continuing its charge.

Well, it did react by looking straight up at him while in motion, its eyes glowing blue.

He barely managed to condense solid mana below his feet and use One Step Mile before the laser came.

The beam of light continued all the way to the other side of the massive cube they were in, making Jake wonder if it even had a max range. He didn’t have time to think much about it while dodging the constant attempts to grab him or cut him with the axeblade.

Jake had come to realize that trying to fight it at range wasn’t possible right now, so he decided to engage it in melee. While difficult, it was still manageable. Unfortunately. this forced him to do something he had hoped to avoid.

Limit break activated at 10% as he also drew the Nanoblade. Using up his stamina more quickly was a big risk, as he essentially aimed to outlast his opponent, but he really didn't feel like he had a choice. Being hit a single time from the axeblade would be a bad time, so he had to somehow keep up, after all.

He moved in, trying to stay rather close to avoid the extending grappling arm. On closer inspection, it reminded him of a certain doctor who used to fight a dude with spider powers in both form and function. The bladeaxe, on the other hand, was just a nightmare all by itself.

Jake couldn’t really block it with either of his weapons, as the impact was just too powerful, and it moved in absurd ways. Dodging a fast weapon was already hard, but dodging a fast weapon that could change direction mid-swing was just borderline impossible.

A few wounds here and there were unavoidable, but Jake tried to at least make his spilled blood useful—quite literally. All his wounds sent sizzling Blood of the Malefic Viper onto the mana shield of his foe, depleting its resources. It wasn’t like he didn’t return the favor for every hit either, as he managed to land many attacks too. The issue was that, to Jake, it felt like he was hitting a… well, metal golem.

He knew it wasn’t sustainable, so he tried to switch up the situation again by also making use of magic. He sent out blasts of arcane mana here and there, as he found his destructive mana quite efficient against the mana shield.

Yet even with Jake’s insane Perception and Bloodline, he could make mistakes.

Jake dodged a fraction of a second too late. One of the claws from the grappling arm managed to barely get around Jake’s arm and clamp down with immense strength. It wasn’t strong enough to do any damage by itself, but Jake had no way to get it off.

His danger sense screamed, yet he could do nothing but watch the blue energy fizzle at the end of the golem's arm as the shock came. Blue lightning audibly crackled up the length of its entire arm, sending a massive amount of energy into Jake’s body.

Without even thinking, he managed to condense his scales. Luckily, they didn’t give a shit about the claw and still transformed his skin. Jake hadn’t used them earlier, as they would only be a drain on resources while being highly ineffective against physical attacks.

Even with all that, it wasn’t enough. Jake felt the electricity invade his body. But he knew he couldn’t just do nothing, so he wrapped both hands around the golem's arm as his hands began glowing green. The lightning burned into his hands, and the barrier stopped him, but he kept pushing as another crackling sound came.

Jake clenched his jaw so hard several of his teeth broke, but the pain only made his senses sharpen. He mixed more of his arcane affinity into Touch of the Malefic Viper. So far, he’d only used the stable version with it to transmute items… but now he poured in the purely destructive aspect of his affinity.

The barrier had been eroded, and Jake’s hands finally landed on the true body of the Altmar Census Golem. At the exact moment he touched it, the golem swung its arm, smashing him down into the hard stone below. With a whip-like motion, it swung him to the other side. It repeated this to smash him back and forth, the electrocution never stopping.

It only managed to swing five times before it froze mid-swing, this time far longer than other times it had been frozen. Two yellow eyes set in a bloody face focused on it as another crack sounded out.

Jake stared at the golem, pouring all he could into Touch the Malefic Viper. Limit Break had also already been pushed up to 20% after the golem had gotten hold of him . The silver metal had become black and cracked, the corrosion now slowly spreading down the extended arm towards the main body of the golem.

The golem appeared to sense something was wrong, but for several seconds it failed to move at all. Blood began dripping from Jake’s eyes as he pushed Gaze of the Apex Hunter farther than ever before. His danger sense told him the moment he let up… things would end badly.

Two things then happened at once. With a twist, the extended arm was ripped in two, and the eyes of the golem turned towards Jake and fired a laser beam straight for his face. His eyes, more specifically, as it clearly had identified them as a primary threat.

Jake managed to barely roll to the side, dodging the laser. His entire body did small spasms from the electrocution, and he was smoking from his burnt armor and skin. He had marks all over his body from being swung into the unimaginably hard ground, and there were even two bloody imprints where he had been smashed down. In addition, both wings were broken and had to be de-summoned, as he had used them to absorb some of the impacts.

Yet he stood up again and threw a potion into his mouth. He just ate the entire flask, allowing the vital energy to run through him.

Luckily, the golem was momentarily distracted by assessing the damage to its arm. It quickly concluded that it would be detrimental to keep the weapon, as it detached parts of the arm and then retracted the rest back into itself. This turned out to be the right choice, since the detached arm began corroding on the ground after losing access to the main body.

The reformed hand looked damaged with missing parts, and it didn’t look like something it could heal quickly.

In the end, the damage it had taken was minimal, but at least it appeared that the hand wouldn’t be able to form a new weapon right away. Not that the golem needed it. It charged towards Jake, who now stood tall again.

He had lost both swords during the scuffle, as he couldn’t deposit them in his storage while being electrocuted. They now lay on the ground nearby. The golem charged the unarmed human, who in response made a motion as something appeared in his hand, its axeblade ready to cleave him in ha—

*DONG!*

The golem had ignored the attack. It had believed the stick of metal to be no threat due to the lack of mana coming from it. This had turned out to be a mistake.

Jake had learned something back when he hit a streetlight with a metal pole—it hadn’t only made his arm hurt, but also left a good dent in the metal of the streetlight. Far more than some silly knife or sword could ever do.

So… if he was fighting a big metal golem… he should use a big metal pole.

[Pillar of Encumbrance (Rare)] – A metal rod made of a type of metal with the natural ability to change weight based on the intensity of the mana infused within. Incredibly durable.

Requirements: N/A

The golem was blasted nearly five kilometers away before it stabilized itself. No visible damage had been taken, but the barrier of mana flickered for a fraction of a second upon impact, signifying the drain of mana from that one strike.

Jake stood back, arms aching from both from the sheer weight of the metal pole and the impact running through his bones. The golem seemed hesitant for a moment. Jake gave a toothy grin as he retracted his mana from the staff and let it go. It just stayed floating in mid-air, as it was now lighter than the air itself.

He took out his bow and fired another Arcane Powershot at the golem, signifying the start of round two.

Chapter 43

Minor Miscalculations

By now, he felt like he understood his foe well enough. His arrow didn’t need to hit hard, but instead do one thing: disrupt the fuck out of his enemy and drain a shitload of mana. This was his understanding, and the system seemed to recognize it as valid. The skill, at least, responded as an arrow began being summoned.

Out of everything Jake had ever summoned—besides maybe that soul-destroying arrow versus the Indigo Fungus—this arrow was the most unique. It was made of metal but had angular blue veins running along its body, making it look almost futuristic. The arrowhead was just a round, crystalline orb of mana that Jake recognized—his own destructive arcane mana. Jake hadn’t known the skill could integrate his affinity like that, but he wasn’t complaining.

Jake looked down and saw that the golem was still falling. He had gotten faster at making the arrows, only taking half a minute this time. Jake had focused on doing it as fast as possible, and that seemed to have helped. It was almost too fast… but Jake could use that.

He didn’t fire the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter right away, but instead aimed his bow upwards as he got a good idea. Jake couldn’t hold back a smile.

Deploying Time-on-Target stratagem.

Jake fired an exploding arcane arrow upwards with barely any force, turned around, and fired another barrage of arrows downwards. This resulted in ten exploding arrows flying down at the same time. He fired off a blast of mana after them, speeding them all up a bit more.

He repeated firing nine more arrows downwards, each of them with differing levels of strength. He had to do a bit of quick maths but mainly went by feel. Jake didn’t need it to be perfect; it just needed to be good enough.

Finally, he drew the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter and began charging his Arcane Powershot. Needless to say, Jake went for a full charge, which ended up being nearly fifteen seconds. He was fine with taking a bit of damage, as he hoped the blow would end up dealing far more damage to the golem than himself.

It was also because he needed to pack a lot more energy than usual into this arrow. He wanted to really make it deliver a torrent of arcane energy on its way down. The reason for this would become clear shortly.

He released the string, causing a massive explosion of arcane energy. Jake went for full-on scale with the explosion to maximize the energy traveling down with the arrow. This meant the entire airspace in a radius around him became filled with wisps of arcane energy.

But it also meant that the Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter that flew downwards with monstrous momentum carried an equally monstrous torrent of arcane energy with it.

Simultaneously, Jake began flying downwards, pushing his speed as much as he could. While flying, he kept firing arrows, one after another. It would be a while till he reached the ground, but he constantly accelerated on his way down.

After flying for a bit, he heard a huge explosion below as the Pillar impacted the ground. For the first time, the black stone had been broken. The Pillar had implanted itself only ten or so centimeters into the stone.

While that didn’t sound like a lot, it did mean that the golem was essentially tied to an immoveable pole. Below, it slowly got itself free, as it now had way more freedom of movement due to not being constantly pulled downwards by an immense force.

Jake had counted on it not being able to free itself right away, and he was right. It would likely take the golem a few minutes to fully free itself. Maybe if it spammed that disruptive wave, it could free itself faster, but it clearly didn’t want to waste mana.

Not that it would be a waste… for hell was raining down from above. It would soon arrive, and while the golem seemed aware of it, it hadn’t bothered to react yet. Maybe it thought it had more time than it actually did. This turned out to be yet another major mistake made by the golem.

Above, a single arrow finally encountered more than fifty others that were already falling with incredible speed. As it passed, it brought with it a tsunami of arcane energy, giving all the other arrows an accelerating push.

The golem’s ETA of the arrow bombardment had just been moved up by over a minute—something it clearly hadn’t expected, as it now began trying more desperately to get free.

As for what Jake was doing at this moment? He was weaving.

He conjured a web of strings that he wound around each other, constantly spinning them to form a shape. It looked like a long, thin drill, rotating while he weaved it. The Arrow of the Ambitious Hunter would hopefully destroy the mana barrier. The other arrows would hopefully damage it and make it unable to reform the shield, while the weapon he was making right now would serve as the finishing blow.

His two blades were still on the ground somewhere below, so he truly didn’t have any other weapon, which was why he chose to construct one.

Below, the golem was just about to get free by repeatedly blasting out disruptive waves, but Jake used Gaze once more. His eyes hurt like hell, and he had a growing massive headache from overusing it, but now was not the time to complain about it. The freeze ended up just buying enough time as the not-quite-an-orbital-strike-but-close hit its target.

Jake saw it before he heard it. First a flash and then a large, pink-purple explosion, followed by several dozens of smaller but similar explosions. It looked like someone had dropped a massive bomb. The explosion tore up the entire area, making him quite proud of how far he had come.

One could argue if one should be proud of making explosions that could level a smaller city, but he nevertheless was as he stared down at the widespread destruction he had caused. Throughout it all, he never stopped making his drill of strings bigger and bigger.

Jake flew faster than ever before, pushing mana into his wings to accelerate downwards. He had no idea how fast he was going, but it had to be nearing the double digits in kilometers per second. For reference… that was Mach 30. Faster than even the fastest unmanned rocket ever.

This entire box had some very peculiar properties—mainly in that it had none at all. All concepts and affinities were so openly deployed and easily detected. Perhaps it was to make the "assessment" part of the test easier, but it just made everything more… effective.

It was practically a vacuum of affinities, in most ways. The concept of "heaviness"—if that was even a thing and not just some kind of gravity affinity—had made the Pillar fall faster as it got heavier. A part of that concept, which the staff deployed, appeared to be its desire to "fall." It even made Jake’s poison not naturally disperse. All in all, it effectively made the natural suppression of the environment nonexistent besides the bare minimum physical laws.

Ultimately, this didn’t favor either of them. At least, it shouldn’t do so on paper. Yet Jake took advantage of this far more. The lack of wind affinity made air resistance a non-concern, and he’d been able to pull off his entire trick with the Pillar and even his application of arcane strings. None of it would be as effective in a more normal environment. Shit, with the passive, neutral mana all around, his strings weren’t naturally corroded by the environment, making them last far longer.

Long enough for the golem to have been hit by the entire bombardment.

Yet he kept accelerating. Despite the explosion, he could clearly see the golem. Not visually, but through his Mark of the Avaricious Hunter. And through that Mark, he knew. The golem had been hit by more than just a few blasts of arcane mana, as it now was practically shining to him, and the arcane charge buildup was quite substantial.

The golem appeared like it hadn’t managed to stabilize itself at all as the next attack arrived—a nearly two-meters-long drill of arcane mana coming straight for it with unstoppable momentum.

At the very last moment, as victory seemed assured, the golem’s left hand rose.

Jake didn’t know what he had expected. But what struck him wasn’t that.

The Pillar of Encumbrance was swung up by the golem and smashed into the side of the drill, and Jake only managed to move his right hand at the very last second. His left one wasn’t as lucky.

In a single swipe, Jake’s entire left arm from the elbow down was utterly obliterated by the Pillar, and the entire drill shattered in a spray of arcane energy wisps. But it didn’t end there… because Jake still had his own momentum to deal with.

He didn’t deal with it well.

Jake had resigned himself to not coming out of his descent unscathed, but he hadn’t expected it to end this badly. He smashed into the ground with his left side first, crushing the rest of the arm and breaking his shoulder and a few left ribs at the least. The wing was entirely crushed. He was happy that the D-grade evolution had gotten rid of a few pesky organs, as those surely would have been punctured or ruptured too. He only avoided getting his head bashed in by landing on his shoulder and having his mask absorb whatever impact he did receive.

Intense pain went through his entire body as his left side took catastrophic damage, turning him into an even more bloody mess than before. His response to all this was the only natural one: he attacked.

Less than a quarter of a second after hitting the ground, while ignoring all the pain and damage he had taken, he lifted his one leg and sprang forward, reaching out with his right hand. He grabbed the leg of the golem and lifted it up, smashing it into the ground.

This made the golem let go of the Pillar, and Jake sent out a string of mana to grasp it as he swung it and smashed the golem away from him.

"Shit," he muttered as he fell to his knee, breathing heavily.

Moving his chest hurt, and everything was aching. He still had a bit to go till he could use another health potion too. In his arrogance or stupidity, he had forgotten one crucial thing… The Pillar was not recognized as a weapon. Which meant it wasn’t bound by his mana. Which meant the golem could use it just as easily as Jake could. It still needed to purge his mana from it, but its constant disruptive waves seemed to have taken care of that. Coupled with him going way too fucking fast to dodge, he had royally fucked up.

Luckily… he wasn’t the only one looking like shit.

The golem slowly got up, looking a bit wobbly. The entire right arm had been broken by Jake pulling the axeblade off earlier, and its pristine metal body didn’t look quite as pristine.

Veins of still-glowing pink-purple mana were pulsing on its exterior from the arcane explosions, its right leg didn’t look that good, and while its left hand and arm looked mostly fine, they had still taken a bit of damage.

But more importantly… the mana barrier was gone. Even the golem’s eyes emitted a far dimmer blue light.

They stood in front of each other, both heavily damaged and low on resources. Jake still had Limit Break at 20% running, and his stamina was beginning to get very low. It was good that he hadn’t used that many skills besides Splitting Arrow, as he could see himself being out if he had. His mana pool was still okay, even if it was down to around a quarter. Without his mask, he would’ve been out of mana.

Jake took a deep breath and, through pure Willpower and mobilizing his stamina to flow into his damaged limbs, stood up. The Pillar was lying at his side, and he picked it up and saw that the lower portion of it had been slightly flattened.

It had likely happened when it smashed into the ground before. Jake could see where it had been embedded in his sphere, and noted that the ground all around that area was actually quite damaged. It appeared that his bombardment had packed quite the power—enough to cause light damage to the stone, at least.

"You’re tired too, huh?" Jake asked.

He didn’t expect an answer and didn’t get one either. The golem was within his sphere, and he saw parts of its metal slowly getting purged of arcane energies that were still burning into it. He saw no reason to let it do this in peace.

He charged forward, biting through the pain as he swung the Pillar. The golem dodged it, far less willing to take hits now, and counterattacked by trying to kick him with its good leg. Jake didn’t let it but instead smashed the Pillar down into the raised leg. He saw the impact make a small crack in the metal and smiled internally.

Not as tough without the mana shield, eh?

A smile that quickly disappeared when a jetblast of mana made its remaining hand fly up and grab the Pillar. Unfortunately, Jake couldn’t really maneuver the large staff with only one arm, making him unable to move it out of the way.

They both held onto it for a while, until the golem sent a charge of electricity through the Pillar and forced Jake to let go.

He jumped back and retreated—back towards where he had dropped the Nanoblade and the scimitar.

Both were still bound to him, so he could feel their general direction. They were nearly twenty kilometers away, and Jake had to dash like a madman while avoiding the swings of the chasing golem. It was faster than him by quite a margin, and Jake felt like he couldn’t make it to his swords as it was… so he turned.

With an abrupt movement, Jake did a one-eighty and ran towards the golem. He summoned a handful of metal spheres—the ones made by Arnold—and used his strings to pull out all the pins at once. Once that was done, he blasted them towards the golem as he took a step and teleported towards the swords with One Step Mile.

*BOOM!*

A large arcane explosion sounded out behind him as he kept running for the blades. He felt the golem had slowed down slightly, but not long after, he peeked back and saw it rush towards him. The arcane veins running across its body looked to have found renewed life, as they pulsed even more than before.

His trick did buy him enough time to reach his weapons, and with two strings of mana, he pulled them both to him. He threw the Nanoblade in his inventory and stood ready for the charging golem with the scimitar in his one remaining hand.

Alright… round three.

Chapter 44

Priorities

The third round wasn’t like the ones prior. There were no flashy attacks or advanced tactics deployed, no powerful skills used, or anything in that vein. Instead, it was just two opponents duking it out with sloppy blows in a battle of pure endurance and grit.

Jake dodged the wild swings of the golem as he swung his scimitar to try and land hits in return. His blade left shallow cuts on the golem’s body, while the golem seemed to want to take him out in a single smash. He was fine with how little happened, because he was just waiting as they slowly fought.

He kept dodging back when he could and fired arrows after the golem. It was a bit awkward, as he had to hold the bow with arcane strings or his leg, but he made it work. He had switched to the stable version to deal even more damage, even if they didn't hit as hard when he only had one arm. He had noticed that the arrows could leave clearly visible marks on the body of the golem. When he hit it on the shoulder, he even noted how its swing looked slightly off, as if he had done some internal damage.

After several minutes of this, Jake felt it. The cooldown’s over.

He retreated and took out a health potion. An hour had now passed, and he chugged it down greedily. A warm flow went through his body, and he could faintly direct the energy as he focused on healing his internals. Jake felt a lot better within seconds. Well, besides the whole missing-an-arm part.

The potion had turned the fight from an "I’ll probably win" to "I’ll definitely win" real fast. The golem was running on fumes, and every one of its movements was more sloppy than the one prior. With Jake now filled with renewed energy, he pressed his advantage.

Jake dove in with the goal of disarming his opponent by getting the Pillar away from it. Okay, he had already literally disarmed it once, and while he likely could rip out the other arm, he wasn’t going to risk it. Not when he could rip off something far more important.

He baited the golem into swinging the Pillar in a downward smash, and as it hit the ground, he grabbed it with his hand and kicked the golem. Simultaneously, he activated the arcane charge within the golem, making its entire body flash for a moment. The flash was so large it looked like a flashbang had gone off, and Jake hoped it would make the golem let go. Unfortunately, that didn’t work, and the golem didn’t even react to the arcane charge, even if it had done a lot of damage. Instead, it held on and just sent electricity into the Pillar. His arcane charge hurt like fuck when it activated, but if you were a golem without the ability to feel pain, it apparently didn’t bother you much, much to Jake’s annoyance.

The electricity it pushed into the Pillar was far less powerful than before, and Jake easily powered through as he kicked again, this time with a lot more force. He even made his foot explode in a blast of arcane mana upon impact. That managed to do the trick—the golem let go and was pushed back, staggering as it fell to the ground.

Jake used the staff to smash the golem in the side while it was still lying down, denting its already-damaged arm even more. He didn't hit it a second time; instead he stepped forward, stored the Pillar, and grabbed the golem's neck.

He pressed down with his hand as it began glowing green. The golem retaliated by punching his arm, but Jake just leaned in closer to take the hits on his back and shoulder. They hurt a bit, but the golem was now far too weak. It tried to electrocute him one last time, and its eyes even glowed as if it tried to fire an eye-beam, but nothing worked.

In the end, the golem’s arm fell powerlessly to the ground as Jake tore his hand upwards, ripping the head of the golem off.

*You have slain [Altmar Census Golem – lvl 150] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 128 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Avaricious Arcane Hunter] has reached level 129 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 118 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

Jake didn’t even have time to go through his notifications before the dungeon reacted. He felt air shift as space mana and the concept of space filled the air, and it seemed to have only one purpose: teleport away the corpse of the Altmar Census Golem.

Oh, no, you fucking don’t!

He tried to put it into his inventory, but it failed. Thinking fast, he released a wave of disruptive mana, but that only slowed down the teleportation. In a final gambit, he created an arcane barrier around himself and the corpse he was currently sitting on top of. He even used the steam-like energy coming off him from Limit Break as he tried to make it stronger, remembering his last skill selection.

For a moment, Jake felt like he was in his entirely own world. Cut off from everything. Light dimmed, gravity got less powerful, and more importantly, the space affinity in the air weakened. It still activated, but what teleported wasn’t the entire golem.

The legs and both arms teleported away, leaving the torso and head of the golem behind. Jake finally was able to put what remained of the golem into his inventory as he fell back on the black stone, breathing heavily. With everything done… he could deactivate Limit Break.

Weakness washed over him the moment he did so. He felt like his entire body weighed a ton, so he just closed his eyes, entered meditation, and checked his system message from clearing the dungeon.

Objective: Defeat the Altmar Census Golem (Completed)

Bonus reward for clearing the dungeon solo. Bonus reward for completing additional objectives. Bonus Pioneer reward.

Dungeon shutting down in: 23:59:32

It turned out he had plenty of time, so for now, he just relaxed. He rested and replayed the fight in his head, going over his fuck-ups. In retrospect, that divebomb move had been a terrible idea, but at the time, it had seemed smart and kind of cool.

Also… he was pretty sure he’d just made some kind of arcane barrier resembling the offered skill to avoid having his loot stolen by the dirty dungeon. Well, he doubted it was the dungeon itself, but likely something more related to the Altmar part of this entire scenario.

The arcane barrier he had conjured integrated a bit of stamina, as Jake had pretty much just mobilized every kind of energy he could. The only time he had ever seen stamina outside of his body was in that mist-like form that covered his skin during Arcane Powershot and when Limit Break was active. Something to experiment with, he thought, considering ways to use it in the future.

But for now, he rested—yet not before smiling and saying, "I hope you enjoyed the show, mysterious observer."

"Challenger has defeated the Census Golem. Automatic retrieval system activated, a—"

The Dungeon Monitor paused for a moment and frowned.

"Challenger has managed to block parts of the teleportation and claimed parts of the golem, including all core components. Inconsequential based on predicted existing relations of the challenger. Challenger has now chosen to rest upon the defeat of the golem and has deactivated all boosting skills. I sh—"

Once more, he had to cut himself off and practically gaped.

"Challenger is aware of the observations of the Dungeon Monitor despite system-assisted surveillance tools being used. Unknown method of observation… Possible divine interference, perhaps? No conclusion for now. Moving on to final assessments before the challenger makes his way here."

The monitor looked to the active teleportation platform not far away from him, then to the three system-created lockboxes not far from it. A wooden door had also appeared in the surveillance room, looking quite out of place. The projection’s eyes lingered a bit on one of the lockboxes as a smile crept onto their lips.

"Final conclusion: Challenger is reckless but inventive and highly adaptive. Stats put him firmly in the upper echelon for someone his level, but his application of these stats is even more impressive. All kinds of energy control are at an extreme level. High probability of arcane affinity. High probability of high-level divine blessing. Too many unknowns to give a proper evaluation, but based on current knowledge, I shall heighten the category of the challenger to N. Will confirm upon lockbox opening.

"Class appears to be an Archer archetype making use of magic liberally. No confirmed profession yet. Will ask during the exit interview. Providing additional observations and personal theorizing during the wait for the challenger’s arrival…"

Jake yawned as he sat up, stretching one arm while holding back a desire to scratch where his other one was currently growing out. It always felt weird to have it be all wriggly as it regrew. He did notice that it went a bit faster than when he’d been in E-grade. He couldn’t wait to be a few grades higher and be able to pop out limbs like green dudes from a planet once blown up by someone with a name related to the refrigeration industry.

Now he only had one issue—leaving the giant cube. Well, it wasn’t really that big of an issue, as there really only could be one place for the exit. The giant obelisk-thing the golem had come out of still stood in the middle of the cube. Looking as ominous as ever. It gave off a certain aura, but there was also something else mixed in. His Sense of the Malefic Viper made him aware that there was space-affinity mana in the direction of the obelisk. Likely a teleportation circle.

He ran over to it, keeping a relaxed speed since his body still wasn’t back to full power after the prolonged use of Limit Break. He felt like he had done a way-too-long session at the gym the day before and was just sore all over.

It still didn’t take him long to reach the obelisk, and once Jake got close, he truly inspected it for the first time with his sphere. The exterior was just blank, black metal, but the inside was entirely different. Jake saw humanoid figures within… a lot of them. Altmar Golems. He wasn’t sure they were the same kind as the Census Golem he had fought, as they didn’t all look exactly like it. Some of them sure got close, though.

Needless to say, Jake would be a dead little hunter if he had to fight hundreds of golems as strong as the Census Golem. Luckily, it didn’t seem to even be an option, as none of them gave off any response to his Identify, meaning they were just empty shells.

Shaking his head, Jake began running up the vertical length of the obelisk as he inspected its interior. It truly was some kind of golem-storage facility and even had a lot of technical devices within. Repair equipment, perhaps? All of it seemed weird to have in a dungeon, but he assumed there was a reason.

On the top of the obelisk was a magic circle, space-affinity mana coming from it. Seeing no other way out, he walked onto it and felt himself be teleported.

A few seconds later, he found himself back at the giant dynamo-thing. It was still spinning as fast as before, but the moment he appeared, it did something. A beam of light fired upwards from it, searing away the stone of the cave. It kept firing off energy for a few more seconds before it stopped.

Jake just stood there, unsure what that was all about. There was now a big hole above the dynamo, so had it just opened a new path? It seemed like a weird way to do it. Very energy-inefficient.

"Please come up, Challenger," Jake heard a voice say from above. It seemed to echo through the entire chamber, the voice distinctly male.

Seeing no reason not to, he summoned his wings and took a leisurely flight up the big hole. The dynamo sure had done a number on the dungeon ceiling with how long the tunnel was. Then again, this was all a part of the designed "dungeon scenario," so it wasn’t that out of place. It was basically just a big setpiece.

He emerged into a room filled with screens and weird devices. In the middle of it stood what Jake could only describe as a very realistic-looking hologram. He was certain it was a hologram because it only registered a silhouette of mana in his sphere, and it was slightly see-through. The hologram depicted a man with long ears, wearing a simple robe. It was definitely an elf. But he also saw something even more important.

"Welcome, Challenger,” the hologram said. “I must say, your performance was exemplary, and I would like to congratulate you. I am the Dungeon Monitor of this place and one of the primary designers of this entire dungeon. I would like to ask if you could possibly answer some questions?"

How a hologram could talk, Jake didn’t know. Magic holograms and all their secrets.

As for answering questions?

"Can it wait?" he asked, already walking towards his target.

"Pardon?" the hologram said, looking a bit confused at how Jake was barely paying it any attention.

"Loot first," Jake said as he Identified the three boxes. He had priorities, after all.

The first was a flat but rather large box with the rare-rarity tag. Nice.

The next in line was about the same size, but this one was epic rarity. Great.

And the last box was small but more intricate-looking than any lockbox Jake had ever seen before. It was ancient rarity. Awesome.

He began with the lowest-rarity box first. Funnily enough, he saw the hologram look a bit disappointed, as if it wanted him to open the smallest and best box first… but it would have to wait.

Jake opened the box, and inside he found a white bundle of cloth. It looked a bit like silk but was far too rough for that. Upon closer inspection, Jake saw what looked to be almost scale-like metal fragments within the cloth. Using Identify, he saw that it was a cloak.

[Altmar Prismatic Cloak (Rare)] – A cloak made out of a strange mix of fabric and metal created by the master craftsmen of the Altmar Empire. This cloak is incredibly resilient to both slashing attacks and will distribute a portion of all kinetic attacks taken throughout the fabric. This type of cloak is usually worn by elite units focusing on stealthily eliminating their foes. The cloak passively aids in making you harder to detect, and when infused with mana, this effect will increase manifold, allowing the user to become nearly undetectable. If the cloak is damaged, it can repair itself at incredible speeds and make it tougher defensively at the loss of its stealth functionality for a period of time. Enchantments: Prismatic Veil. Prismatic Reconstruction.

Requirements: Lvl 110+ in any humanoid race.

He really wanted to put the cloak on now and test it, but seeing the hologram just standing there and staring at him made it awkward. So he just put it in his inventory and moved on to the next lockbox as the hologram spoke.

"Ah, those cloaks are quite popular in the Empire. The cloth is made by some of our greatest young, talented tailors and is a beautiful display of the fusion between technology and more traditional weaving techniques. It’s even popular among those who don’t need the stealth component, as it offers great protection against nearly all physical attacks if needed. Additionally, they are also considered quite fashionable, and you can freely change the pattern and colors on the cloak after some practice, and—"

It turned out he didn’t even need to test the cloak out to learn more about it, as he apparently had an exposition hologram readily available.

Chapter 45

Altmar Signet

Apparently, it was a really great cloak. At least, it seemed so, since the talkative projection refused to stop speaking about it, overexplaining details of where it came from and even throwing in info about a cousin of his who used to make them. While it was a bit interesting, Jake did notice that despite it saying so much, it didn’t really give out any truly valuable information. Well, besides fashion advice.

Jake tried to ignore it at least a little as he went and opened the epic-rarity box. Within, he found a folded pair of pants. They were made of a very dark green fabric—almost black—and looked slightly worn. The fabric was rather thick as he picked it up, and he had to say the pants were rather heavy. They looked like they could actually provide some solid protection.

Yet the first thing he picked up was the smell. They smelled like… like that smell when it has just rained, and you are walking through greenery in the middle of summer. Yeah, exactly like that. It was a pleasant smell. The reason for the scent was obvious, as he could practically feel the life-affinity energy emanating from the pants.

Using Identify, he finally saw the description.

[Legguards of the Undergrowth (Epic)] – The Records of this long-forgotten place have led to the creation of these legguards. As you are the first to wander the Undergrowth, you can keep a piece of it with you as your path continues. An immense amount of life-affinity mana has found its way into these pants, and simply wearing them will fill you with vital energy and energy to help you on your travels. The legguards will passively absorb and store life-affinity mana in the atmosphere. This mana can instantly be released as a burst of healing if the wearer is a Vitality-based lifeform. Passively emits an aura that encourages growth. Enchantments: + 150 Vitality, +50 Agility, +50 Endurance. Self-Repair. Life Burst. Aura of the Undergrowth.

Requirements: Lvl 115+ in any humanoid race.

Goodbye, my dear Badger Pants, you have served me well, Jake thought. He had to hold back his desire to bind the legguards now and just jump into them. Sadly, he had a curious hologram looking over his shoulder, and it would be a bit awkward to strip in front of it.

While he had just skipped over the cloak to look at it later, he couldn’t hold himself back from inspecting the pants a bit closer and considering their properties.

First of all: stat points. Great stat points. 250 stat points. Jake’s current Badger Pants gave 25 Agility and 25 Endurance, so he would double up on those alone. On top of that, he would get a massive 150 Vitality and two other effects. He didn’t really count self-repair as another effect, as while it was great to have, he had just gotten too used to it.

The Life Burst enchantment seemed nice too. Almost like an extra health potion of sorts? He was a bit unsure how it would work, as the potions had inherent system-fuckery built into them to make them more effective. It was something to test out, for sure.

The last part was that Aura of the Undergrowth. To that, Jake had only one response:

I swear on my fucking life, if that aura makes mushrooms grow in my house, I’ll do something very unpleasant to these damn pants. Stats or not.…

He hoped for the best but feared the worst. Either way, the pants looked nice, and he would surely put them on once he was out of the dungeon to test them.

"The Pioneer, eh?" the hologram politely said. “I guess it does make sense, as most factions prefer to send their most talented to secure the title and bonus rewards. A bit risky, of course, but risk and growth go hand in hand. I shall not comment on the reward itself, but I hope it will serve you well.”

"Thanks, pal," Jake answered. "So, what makes you so curious about this last box?"

"My curiosity will only hold meaning to you after it’s opened," it said with a smile.

"Oh, okay," Jake said as he threw the lockbox in his inventory, making a mischievous smirk. "I guess I’ll just open it outside, then, since it doesn’t matter. See ya!"

"Wait, wait!" the hologram said, surprised. "Alright, the last reward should be a signet of the Altmar Empire for you to wear and serve as proof of your budding relationship with the Empire."

"So it’s a tracker?" he asked curtly, raising an eyebrow.

The hologram looked a bit flustered before answering, "Yes… but it will be openly shown as one of the enchantments and will also allow you to feel the direction of the nearest teleportation circle attuned to the Empire’s territory."

"Hm, sounds plausible," Jake answered, shaking his head. "Anyway, how come an elven empire has managed to create a natural dungeon like this? From what I know, that isn’t how things usually go."

From talks with the Viper, Jake knew that direct factional connections in natural dungeons were exceedingly rare. Of course, it could happen, but often they contained old and destroyed factions, not ones currently in power, and much less this prominently.

"I guess there are no issues in informing you," the hologram answered. "This dungeon is part of a larger grand experiment put in motion by the Altmar Empire to create particular areas that can be turned into dungeons. I do not know all the details of how everything is made possible; I am but one of many designers. A talented one, if I do say so myself—at least, all my teachers believe so. Anyway, the dungeon itself serves as a test to find talents and create connections to budding experts in faraway worlds, as the Empire is rather self-contained. Note that I have done a vocal transcript of everything that has happened so far. What you speak to currently is a projection of my soul at the time of construction. I do not know the current Realtime, but this particular experiment was started approximately five-point-one billion years after the integration of the 91st Universe. Everything we say is being recorded even now, and upon your exit, I will give you that recording to bring back to the Altmar Empire. Only if you have the chance, of course. I promise you will be justly rewarded."

Jake nodded along as the projection spoke. Honestly, he didn’t need that much information. The projection could just have said "dungeon experiment," and he would have taken it at that. But, damn, that projection really liked to talk.

"What’s your name?" he asked. "I’m Jake."

"I am Tiarsus Norlynn, C-grade dungeon designer at the time of upload. I reckon my name will hold little meaning, depending on how much time has passed, but perhaps the family is still around."

As the projection spoke, Jake multitasked and dialed up Villy to accomplish two things. First, to ask if everything said in there was purely confidential. It was. After he left, the only trace of the conversation would be if he brought out the recording. Once the next challengers entered the dungeon, everything would be reset, after all. Oh, and the second reason he called him up was to have him listen in because he thought it would be fun.

"We’re in the 93rd Universe now, been less than a year since the integration," Jake answered with a big smile. As only he, Villy, and a hologram of an elf would hear everything, he didn’t hold back any information. Villy agreed with his plan and thought it would be hilarious.

The hologram didn’t even try to hide its shock. "What? Truly? This is a new universe? Absolutely remarkable progress in such a short time. I am certain the Empire will be more than happy to invite you.”

"Thanks, doing my best. Became a Progenitor and all." He kept the big grin on his face. "Also, the Norlynn family is doing quite well. Villy told me you even had a god rise in the family a couple of eras back."

"We did? You’re what? Wait, who’s Villy?"

"Ah, Villy is my best-bud resident god. A Primordial or something. He made me his Chosen to have a beer buddy. People keep calling him the Malefic Viper or something like that. It’s a bit weird. Wait, maybe he’s just with me because of the Bloodline…" Jake snickered, perhaps overdoing it.

At least, the hologram seemed to think so, as it seemed to calm down and get more serious. "I guess I should have added humorous to the evaluation," it said with a forced chuckle, looking a bit miffed.

"Nothing I said was a lie," Jake answered, looking deadly serious. "Why hide anything when this is one hundred percent anonymous?"

"It doesn’t matter, does it? This conversation will hold little meaning, as I understand you have no desire to bring out the recording."

Clearly, the hologram didn’t fully believe him. I guess I did go a bit overboard, Jake admitted.

"No, I won’t. I am not going to bother Villy with getting a play-by-play, and I honestly see no reason to share personal information with the Altmar Empire when I don’t even know them.” Having made that clear, he finally moved on to the final box. "Ah, but I will open the box here together with ya. Let’s see if I get some cool stuff, shall we?"

Without further ado, he finally opened the last box, the projection completely forgetting its prior mood and returning to being overly curious. Quite an eccentric projection, that one.

Within the box, Jake saw a very simple-looking ring with a large N-shaped gem placed in it. He instantly Identified it.

[Altmar N-Signet (Ancient)] – You have been judged by the Altmar Empire and found worthy. This ring is made of unknown metal with an unknown gem embedded in it. This signet is proof of your performance and contains an identifying script designed to only be readable by the Altmar Empire. Yet even if this ring is primarily a display of status, it is far from just a showpiece. For with great status comes great power. The first time the wielder equips the ring, they will become able to distribute the signet’s energy into whatever stats they desire. Distributing the stats will make the ring Soulbound. Stats cannot be redistributed once set. Enchantments: +1000 stat points (undistributed).

Requirements: Lvl 100+ in any humanoid race.

Jake read it over before he closed the description and shook his head.

Nah, mate, you read it wrong. No way.

He opened it again.

Still says a thousand.

"You truly are from a newly integrated universe! That must be the explanation!" the hologram exclaimed, a bit excited. "Usually, they only reward 750 due to the location enchant on the ring, but the system seems to have fully redistributed the Records into simply rewarding pure stat points. Without a doubt, due to this being a new, closed-off universe. What an interesting interaction."

"Wait, a level 100 ring seriously gives 1000 fucking stat points?" Jake asked, still confused as fuck.

"Yes. Distributable stat points are a great way to shore up where you aren’t quite capped yet," the projection nonchalantly said. “I know it likely won’t help you much currently, besides getting some optimization done by making sure you stay capped in your most-used stats.”

"Not help me very much, my ass. I get like 500 stat points total from all my stuff right now; this is fucking insane." Jake just kept staring at the ring.

"You… you aren’t joking, are you?"

"No, that would just be a bad joke. Most of my gear is for around level 50 or something. This is a massive upgrade. Seriously, how the hell can you think it isn’t great?" He was beginning to wonder if the hologram was damaged somehow.

“In his defense, being capped in stats from gear is pretty much standard for all elites of the major factions throughout the multiverse," Villy chimed in. “The Order of the Malefic Viper too. Having gear lined up for certain levels isn’t anything new. You don’t even need high-rarity equipment, just equipment suited to your level. Shit, most get an entirely new wardrobe upon reaching D-grade. Of course, the more stat points you have from classes, professions, race, and titles, and all that, the higher your cap, so you may need some better gear than most others, but still. You haven’t gotten shit since reaching D-grade. It’s only natural your gear fucking sucks.”

"Truly a category N… You didn’t joke about being a Progenitor either, did you?" the hologram said. “That explains it… truly spectacular. I must insist that you pay a visit to the Altmar Empire if you can. I am sure your Patron’s faction can help you if you are truly blessed by a Primordial. You don’t even need the recording. The signet alone will be enough.”

"Maybe. What does the N stand for?" Jake asked.

"We judge challengers on a scale from one to ten," the hologram enthusiastically explained. “Most solo combatants who make it to the end of the dungeon while being below the level of 120 tend to be around seven-point-five to eight, based on prior experiments. Those judged to be above category ten are categorized with an N, standing for Non-determinable. Needless to say, this category is the highest and is simply an admittance that we cannot truly test you with the tools available in this dungeon. In the end, the system rules are still in place, and it has to be beatable.”

"And here I thought I was done with exams after uni," Jake joked, still admiring the signet. It looked more and more beautiful by the second.

He knew that putting it on now and beginning to distribute stat points would be something he could come to regret. Well… a small part of him did want to make it +1000 Perception, but that would just be stupid. He would save all the math for when he was out. For now, he would keep chatting with the hologram.

"So… this may sound a bit weird, but I kind of made a friend with one of the dungeon monsters outside,” he said. “It's the Cave Troll with its two kids. I was just wondering if there was any way to bring them out with me? Some hidden dungeon functionality or something?"

With a kind tone, the projection said, "Bring out some of the dungeon residents? No, not unless you have such means by yourself already. I would advise against trying to make use of dungeon monsters as a fighting force. It is rarely worth it, and their Records tend to be heavily affected, making progress borderline impossible for them.”

"Well, that sucks," Jake sighed. He had hoped for the dungeon to reward him some rare item to free the troll or something like that.

"One more thing," the projection began, looking a bit hesitant. "Could you perhaps leave the remains of the golem here? Proprietary technology was used during its construction, and unless you are part of the Altmar Empire, you aren’t allowed to possess it."

"Nah, it’s mine. Tough luck. Fucker was hard to take down; no way I am letting you keep it. Anyway, do you have any more questions?"

"Seeing as you have no interest in taking the recording out with you, no. After you leave, this hologram will cease to exist, and anything you tell it won’t matter. I would like to still heavily implore you to visit the Altmar Empire. We can do much for you, and I am sure that there is much for you to learn when part of a newly integrated universe. The Altmar Empire has always welcomed young talents from all races.” The hologram finished with a smile.

"I’ll keep it in mind. Thanks for talking, mate." Jake smiled as he walked over to the out-of-place wooden door leading out of the dungeon. He placed his hand on it as he turned it. "Oh, by the way, remember what I said about someone from your family becoming a god?"

"Yes? Did it truly happen?" the projection asked, quite expectantly. It was funny… It was just a hologram that would remember nothing, yet it still wanted to know so badly.

"Yep, sure did. And I never mentioned the name, did I??"

"No, I don’t believe you did."

"I heard the dude is called Tiarsus."

Jake didn’t allow the projection to say anything before accepting the prompt, exiting the dungeon—and leaving a flabbergasted hologram behind.

Chapter 47

Something Long Overdue

He now realized he had truly neglected his gear for far too long. Jake hadn’t made proper use of humanity and their ability to create items. Arnold had given him the Nanoblade, a far better weapon than his old Venomfang. Why not also get gear in his other slots? With the Badger Pants gone, he had replaced everything from the first dungeon, but he had more subpar equipment to get rid of.

Actually, Jake still had the two pieces of equipment he’d earned from the Challenge Dungeon, which was technically his first-ever dungeon. He still had the Boots of the Wandering Alchemist and the Prodigious Alchemist’s Necklace of Holding. The necklace had his spatial storage within, so replacing that was impossible. The fact that it only gave 25 Wisdom was a bit offputting, though.

Jake knew there had to be ways of upgrading Soulbound equipment somehow. Perhaps he could find a talented jeweler… but to be perfectly honest, he didn’t really want to. He needed someone he truly trusted both as a person and a craftsman before he would ever risk them trying to improve the necklace.

The second piece of equipment he still wore from the Challenge Dungeon was, of course, his trusty boots. Now, did they only give 20 Endurance and 15 Agility? Yes. Had the enchantment to reduce stamina expenditure been useless for many levels? It had been. Did he still love the boots? Fuck yeah.

They were just too damn comfy and durable. They looked as worn and old as the day he’d gotten them, which was the point. They looked just like the day he’d gotten them. Without any self-repair, enchantment, that was. They had survived being blasted by mushroom-mega-beams, blown up in dozens of different types of explosions, and a slew of other things… but nothing had managed to leave a mark.

Their comfort was also on an entirely different level. The boots were snuggly and just felt good on Jake’s feet, and in the end, isn’t that what’s most important when it comes to choosing footwear?

Okay, he would try to upgrade them if he ever got the chance… but who could upgrade them was the issue once more.

But even if Jake didn’t want to mess with these two pieces of equipment for now, that didn’t mean there weren’t other places to improve. His second ring, chestpiece, bracers, and gloves. These were the pieces of equipment he would seek to improve. The ring and chestpiece were okay for now… but he knew he could do better.

As for other "gear slots?" Villy had told him that humans could have ten pieces of wearable equipment bound at once. With Jake’s two rings, necklace, chest, legs, boots, bracers, mask, cloak, and gloves, he had those ten. This did mean Jake could toss away one of these things to potentially put on something else. Different humanoid races naturally had different pieces of equipment.

Jake himself could, for example, wear some earrings instead of rings, or a hat or helmet instead of the mask. The gear was still bound to the parts of the body they went on, though, and based on their effects to some extent. AKA, Jake couldn’t just wear four chestplates or two pairs of boots. He could wear an undershirt of some kind and a big chestplate on top, though, but that would mean he couldn’t bind a cloak.

To be perfectly honest, it seemed like yet another place one could really min-max and optimize, even if young geniuses from other universes tended to be stat-capped anyway. Jake had absolutely no intentions of doing some major do-over of his getup; he just wanted to replace some of his old shit with new shiny treasures.

He liked most of his current things. Especially the mask. Not just because of its legendary rarity and indestructible build, but because it was a mask. Jake had found that he actually really loved wearing a mask, and he found it sad he hadn’t discovered the comforts in wearing one before the system.

Then again, if he’d ever walked into a bank in a wooden mask with only eyeholes, he would likely have been arrested.

Also… it was probably about time he addressed what lay beneath. No, not in any philosophical way, but literally what lay beneath his lodge now. He went over and entered the cellar, and down there, he found a new door installed. It wasn’t a wooden door but one made of thick metal.

Beyond the wall was a hole. The entire hole looked a bit like an old mineshaft. Wooden boards entirely covered the walls, with metal plates in between to fortify and isolate the tunnel as a whole. It was nearly three meters wide and across, and one could easily fit a large elevator in there if they so desired.

If it had been a pre-system design, one would’ve been sorely needed.

The hole went down a bit over a hundred meters, where it opened up into a large and empty chamber that still looked to be under construction. There were beginnings of cutouts to other rooms. Jake also saw that a marking had been made in the direction of the cave with the dungeon. He had mentioned to Hank that he might have wanted to link them up, and this seemed to be the beginning of that.

Really, Hank had gone a bit above what Jake had expected. He’d just wanted a cave a few dozen meters below the lodge, but what he got instead was closer to an underground bunker a hundred meters below. Heck, the underground complex would be even larger than his lodge above by a good margin.

As he stood there, he felt oddly comfortable. It reminded him of the tutorial dungeon… a hidden livable chamber away from everywhere else. Now he just needed a spatial pocket with a garden in it.

Seeing as things clearly weren’t done in his soon-to-be alchemy cave, he made his way up to the lodge again. He had a feeling they had stopped to wait for him to ask for input. Their plans had been quite rough the first time around, and Hank probably wanted some clarifications.

Jake had already decided he needed new gear, and that he also wanted to visit Hank and ask him about things. He didn’t really want to do alchemy down in the cellar in case builders would head there again soon, and he didn’t have anything else to do.

So Jake went on a quest. To his own city.

As much as he hated to admit it… this would be his first time actually entering his own city and exploring it. All he knew about Haven came from him stealthily checking it out when he went in and out of the city. He had never walked the streets or seen the shops. It was about time he did so.

Jake wore his new cloak over his armor and pulled up the hood. He instantly poured in a bit of mana, and the cloak began changing color until it was black. That projection had said it would take some practice learning to control the colors freely, but that turned out to be bullshit. You just had to make those small metal pieces act as mediums and impose your will while manipulating the mana in the cloak. Took like ten seconds.

He decided to walk instead of fly to stay as inconspicuous as he could. The valley was not that far from the relatively bustling city of Haven, yet it seemed nicely isolated due to its nature as a valley. There also weren’t any people walking in his direction at all.

Haven didn’t have any walls or large defensive barriers constantly active—a rarity, as far as Jake knew. Wayward beasts, especially of the flying variety, were hazards to most other settlements, and the occasional alpha beast trying to lead its flock to take down a city also wasn’t abnormal. Heck, the Fort had to deal with the occasional attack. Luckily, at least none came from the forest where Haven was located, and the Mindchief still had left its mark on the area it was from.

Jake had also been told that his bird buddies occasionally made their way to the Fort, which served to scare away any opportunistic beasts. A pair of D-grades was far more than most beasts—even D-grades—could handle. Speaking of birds… he was a bit sad he hadn’t seen them upon his return. He missed Sylphie, that adorable little murder-hawk.

Well, everything at the Fort should be fixed by Miranda reaching D-grade and also claiming the Fort as part of the area influenced by the Pylon. That would make it clear to all beasts that, like Haven, it was the domain of Jake.

Beasts had the common sense not to invade the territory of a hunter.

As he walked closer, he focused on his hearing to discern the city’s noise far ahead of him. Jake had learned a long time ago that while Perception also increased all his other senses, it really wasn’t that effective most of the time. Hearing everything far louder was nice in some situations, but it could just as well be a distraction during a fight.

Improving his sense of smell would be nice, but again, it wasn’t really something he focused on. Jake had also noticed that the atmospheric mana made smell kind of useless, as the mana just kind of ate up all smells, making them not linger that long. Unless it was a magic smell. But those kinds of smells were most often placed because the source wanted you to smell them. He reckoned there were ways of using smell, based on the many monsters he had encountered that used the sense. Jake just hadn’t learned how to yet. Or maybe humans just couldn’t.

Anyway, he heard the noise of the city—people talking, arguing, someone landing on the ground with heavy boots on, someone yelling as they dropped something, and even the sound of kids screaming. To be perfectly honest, it was overwhelming. Like an auditory version of his sphere, he felt like he got overloaded and quickly stopped focusing on improving his hearing.

A minute later, Jake saw the first treehouse. A guard sat atop it and was looking not towards the valley but the city. He even saw a sign on one of the trees saying the valley ahead was off-limits. The guard was likely there not to keep people out, but to keep them away from his lodge.

The guard never even noticed Jake as he passed underneath, Expert Stealth on full display and his new cloak making him appear almost invisible. Coupled with the guard not looking specifically for him or using any Perception-related skills, it really wasn’t a surprise he missed the powerful D-grade passing underneath him.

Curious, Jake made his way to where the true city began. He saw the trees above filled with treehouses, sometimes with accompanying buildings on the ground. More trees seemed to have staircases on them than not, and he even saw hanging bridges connecting many wooden platforms above. Haven was quite the vertical city.

He also didn’t need a mega-Perception-boosted smell to pick up on the sweet scent of grilled meat. He hadn’t eaten for a good while, with the dungeon and all. Not real food, at least. And while he didn’t need it, he still wanted some.

The cause of the smell was a small booth at the base of one of the trees. There was a large man inside working it. He had a big rack of skewers in front of him with sizzling meat on it, and he smiled as he cooked, clearly enjoying himself. Jake saw the man infuse some herbs and spices with mana as he carefully seasoned some skewered meat before putting it on the grill.

It looked simple, but Jake detected some respectable mana control from the man. The metal rack was infused with mana as the man controlled the heat and poured mana into the food. There was already a small line in front of the booth, waiting for the latest batch to be ready. Jake joined them after deactivating Expert Stealth, and also made sure his cloak didn’t passively hide him anymore. Naturally, he still had his hood and mask on, but he at least avoided people overlooking him.

This would one hundred percent have happened, based on the man in front of Jake nearly jumping in fright as a figure appeared behind him. The man turned around and looked at Jake. He stared for a second before just giving him a nod and facing the booth again.

Jake smiled beneath the mask. He had felt the attempt at Identify. Could he feel it before? Jake wasn’t sure, but he could now. Maybe it was due to the sheer level disparity or his increased Perception stat. Hard to tell.

It took ten minutes before it was Jake’s turn. He stood patiently in line the entire time, just taking in the atmosphere and inspecting all of the city he could see within his sphere. It was actually great practice. Not looking at everything, but figuring out how not to look. He didn’t feel comfortable peeking into people’s homes, especially not after he saw someone in a bathtub.

The cook looked at Jake but didn’t try to Identify him. A real professional, that one. He was also level 61, which was pretty damn good.

"How many, chief?" the cook asked Jake with a friendly smile.

"Three," he answered. There was a small sign saying you could only get three, so… he took three. Also, there was a sale. It was 40 Credits for one and 100 for three.

"That’ll be an even hundred," the man said with a big smile as he wrapped up the three skewers.

Jake was damn happy at this moment that he wasn’t the only one in line, allowing him to see how payment worked. There was a small metal plate at the front of the booth where everyone placed a finger to pay.

It was a good system. The plate confirmed payments were made to both parties, as while Credits could be transferred directly, it was an entirely hidden action to all outside observers. This meant it would be borderline impossible to police scammers, as it would just be one word against another. Furthermore, the plate seemed to record all transactions, and Jake wanted to bet his ass the city itself could see all transactions taking place through the plate. Clearly, there was some system-fuckery going on with it.

Jake didn’t place his finger on the plate but just touched it with his will. He didn’t even need to make a mana string. He didn’t get why others didn’t just pay like that, but he assumed most hadn’t figured out how to impose their will on stuff. Honestly, it was so easy since it was just a system interaction, not anything that required power.

This action did earn him a stare from both the cook and the ones behind him. While none of the others waiting in line asked anything, the cook didn’t have any reservations.

"Neat trick. You new around here? I haven’t seen you before. I am darn sure I would have remembered you, as you’re sure a memorable type.” He gave a slight chuckle as he wrapped up the last skewer.

“I’ve been around,” Jake answered as he accepted the skewers once they were all wrapped up. He then used Identify on them.

[Seasoned Mixed Meat Skewer (Common)] – A skewer of different mixed meats from high-level E-grade beasts, grilled by a skilled chef and seasoned with herbs and spices. Gives a minor increase to stamina regeneration while not engaged in combat for the next 24 hours. Restores a small amount of health upon consumption.

"This is some good stuff," Jake continued. "Could you point me toward the bosses of the builders?"

"Either in the guild or the Fort. Pretty sure a big group went to the Fort the day before yesterday. I would check out both places. Caravans are traveling to the Fort nearly once every hour… though I have the feeling you’ll be fine on your own.”

"Alright, thanks. How’s business anyway? The city treating you well? Also, did you get access to the System Store?"

"Business is good, and Haven is a nice place. Very cozy. I got most of my ingredients for the seasoning and all the herbs from the store, with the help of the city office.” Then, a bit teasingly, he added, "Now, can you stop holding up the line? And enjoy the food!"

This was when Jake realized the gazes boring into his back weren’t those of curiosity and due to his trick when paying, but pure annoyance and impatience.

"Sorry," Jake muttered. He was a bit embarrassed as he hurried away, mumbling under his breath without thinking, "You too..."

"Have a nice day!" the cook yelled after him, a big, goofy smile on his lips, just making Jake even more embarrassed.

Why the hell had he said “you too”? Shit, so embarrassing.

It didn’t help that he had no idea where the hell this mentioned guild was. He remembered Miranda had talked about some profession archetypes making guilds… but that was it.

I’m sure I’ll find it in a jiffy.

Chapter 48

Leatherworkers

Jake didn’t find it in a jiffy. In fact, he didn’t find it at all. In his defense, though, he wasn’t really looking that hard. He was walking the city and checking different things out instead. The number of shops was insane, but even more insane was the average level of the people around here. It was quite a bit higher than he would have expected.

He saw many above 50, and even a good number above 60 managing the shops. Even more impressive were some of the people looking to be more combat-oriented, where he noticed a few around level 80. A strong party like them could likely escape a weak D-grade alive, making them quite respectable. Granted, they would still get fucked up by a single decent D-grade, but at least they were working hard.

Failing to hold back his curiosity, Jake checked out a few more shops. Some sold equipment, and some sold small, interesting baubles. Other places had more regular clothes or food, making it seem more like a normal city. The clash of a large shopping window with a modern-looking dress behind it and the entire magical forest theme was also immensely entertaining.

Having already decided to improve his gear, Jake also checked out some stores selling equipment. Unfortunately, most were a big disappointment. While he did find some leatherworkers with decent stuff, he didn’t come across anything he particularly wanted. Most were inferior rarity, with a few common-rarity items here and there. While some of it had higher level requirements than Jake’s current items, the rarities were just too low in comparison.

Just as he thought his quest was in vain, he noticed another leatherworker. This shop was quite a bit larger than any prior, but more important was the level of the shopkeeper.

[Human – lvl 83]

It was a woman who was currently cleaning some leather with a rough piece of cloth. The entire shop didn’t have a single customer, nor did it look particularly inviting, and the woman didn’t even turn around to regard Jake when he entered.

Jake didn’t go up to her either. His target was something else. On a wooden holder was a vest of some kind, giving off an oddly familiar aura. Using Identify, he quickly saw why.

[Vest of the Tri-Lighttail Dervish (Common)] – A vest made from the hide of Tri-Lighttail Dervishes, a monster known for its Agility and weight magic. It has been created through the collaboration of two talented leatherworkers. This vest contains some scarce remnant Records of the Dervishes and has even been touched ever so faintly by the concept of time. Enchantments: +100 Agility, +25 Strength, +25 Endurance.

Requirements: Lvl 75+ in any humanoid race.

He was honestly surprised. Who else had managed to hunt down Dervishes? Those monkeys were often around level 130. Shit, he was also surprised they had even found any, as Jake was pretty sure he’d done a number on the local Lighttail population.

Just as he was considering who could possibly have hunted the monkeys down, the shopkeeper came over.

"A good piece—came in yesterday," she said, speaking in a rough tone. “It ain’t cheap, though. It comes from a D-grade beast. But you look like you ain’t strapped, so don’t try to pull a fast one; I know what it’s worth.”

"I know. Where did the creators come across these hides? Who hunted them down?"

Having evolved to D-grade, Neil could maybe do it with support… Could the birds handle one? They should be able to, if they worked together. Hm…

"Hah, a bunch of scavengers brought the hides, and I made the vest with my partner. The scavengers caught a lucky break, as they explored the forest for valuables—primarily herbs and such—at the request of the City Lord. Heard they came across an area where some beasts had fought. Shit was torn up, according to what they said, and they found a shitload of D-grade Tri-Lighttail Monkey corpses of different variants. The beast that killed them took all the cores, though. Honestly, they were just lucky bastards, coming across the leftovers of some beasts battling. They made a shitload. Some of those beast corpses were mid-tier D-grades, for god’s sake.” She said this last part with some annoyance.

Jake just stood there, feeling his ears heating up as she went on. He didn’t dare say anything as her rant continued, getting progressively more irritated.

“For fuck’s sake, who gets that lucky? Luck isn’t even a stat, yet they just stumble into it so close to the city. Also, what kind of beasts just fucks up an entire horde of monkeys and then leaves their corpses behind like that? Well, I guess for anyone other than leatherworkers or cooks or whatever, the corpses aren’t worth much, and only the cores matter, but the beast could at least have made them all into rotten mushes. It did it with some of them, completely ruining the hide and meat. Some fucking solidarity would have been appreciated. Guess you can’t expect better from some stupid beast that can’t even clean up after itself.” She finally stopped and looked at Jake. "Anyway, wanna buy it? Make an offer."

His face below the mask had quite the grimace, but luckily she couldn’t see it. At least, she didn’t show any signs of knowing. As for if he wanted the vest? No, not really. It was an upgrade, but a minor one. The embarrassment of wearing it and the constant reminder of this day simply wasn’t worth 25 extra stat points.

"Hah, yeah. Lucky. Sorry, this wasn’t exactly what I was looking for, but it’s good craftsmanship." No matter how bad it made him feel, he couldn’t deny its quality.

He didn’t really regret not taking the corpses, though. He didn’t want to fill up his spatial storage with stuff he didn’t truly need, and he had taken all the far more important cores. It also just felt kind of weird for him to know he carried a bunch of corpses around his neck at all times.

Now, this only counted for the regular enemies… If he met a strong foe, he would sure as hell take the corpses now, like with the Altmar Census Golem. He hadn’t really gotten any other valuable corpses in that entire dungeon, as his poison did have the habit of destroying corpses. His arcane affinity too. This was likely why a small vest had been made from the hide of several Dervishes.

"It’s good, right?" She smiled at his praise of her handiwork. "Too bad we didn’t have the compatible cores. Can’t really infuse them properly with Records without those, so we had to make do with just going quantity over quality. Ah, I guess that would be a bit too much to ask. I reckon the beast that tore through their territory did it for those cores to begin with."

"Ye… yeah. I guess that’s why the ‘beast’ went through… You wouldn’t happen to have any gloves, would you? Good quality ones. Price isn’t the issue.” He nearly felt like he had to buy something with how much time he had spent in the store… It had nothing to do with how awkward he felt about the origin of the vest.

"Those over there," she said, pointing towards a table. Jake had already checked out that table with his sphere and seen that none of the gloves were better than his current ones.

Reading Jake’s body language, she added on, “But we could custom-make something by commission. My partner is just out with a delivery of some pants. Do you have any idea how often people ruin their pants these days? People are good at defending their chest, but suck at defending from attacks coming from below, so their pants and legs get ruined damn fast. And before you ask, no, we’re still working on making that self-repair enchantment. That shit ain’t easy."

Jake just nodded along once more, allowing her to rant. She continued on about how people expected the self-repair enchantment just because tutorial equipment had it, and how it was clearly an easy, low-level enchantment due to that. She cursed the system, the customers, the leather and hides, and even ended up throwing in a few off-handed comments towards those scavengers again. The number of times she mentioned the “moronic beast that killed the monkeys” also wasn’t just one or two.

He wanted to leave a few times but thought it would be rude, as he technically had been the one prompting her to speak. Luckily, he was saved. He spotted someone he recognized approaching in his sphere.

"Hey, Olivia, stop bothering the customers wit—"

She stopped as she looked into the room and saw who the customer was. Jake also looked back at her and waved.

"Hey, Eleanor—long time, no see," he said. "Making good progress, I see."

It was the archer of Neil’s party, who was also the partner of this Olivia woman. Yes, Jake also just realized now he hadn’t ever gotten the shopkeeper’s name. As for Eleanor, she truly had made good progress.

[Human – lvl 96]

Great, even. Eleanor was getting darn close to D-grade, and with plenty of time to the Treasure Hunt to spare. She was going for the Perfect Evolution, too, as far as he knew, meaning she likely would’ve been D-grade already if she hadn’t.

"Lord Thayne, I didn’t expect you here," she said, clearly taken aback.

Jake didn’t fare that much better. Had she just called him Lord Thayne? What? When had he shared his name? Also, what the hell was up with it being so overly formal? Well, it was better than calling him the Owner or whatever, at least.

"Wait, this super-edgy dude is that Thayne guy?" Olivia cut in, looking at Jake skeptically.

"Rude…" Jake mumbled before looking back at Eleanor. "And just call me Jake—no reason to be so formal. I didn’t know you made a leatherworking shop?"

"It isn’t mine, it’s Olivia’s,” Eleanor explained. “We just work together on most projects. We have different profession variants, and mine is better at handling some animal parts while hers is better at others. Anyway, how come you’re here? I heard from Neil you were in the dungeon."

"I was; I’m done with it. A truly nasty place, that one. I wouldn’t go with your party right after you all reach D-grade. You will need some solid anti-healing measures when you go, too.”

"What type of monsters?" she asked, and Jake quickly caught on.

"Hairless, blind humanoids that look kinda creepy and have mushrooms growing within them. Nothing to skin there… unless you’re one sick bastard.”

"I see. So, did you come for anything in particular?"

"Mainly just checking out the city. I am looking for some new gear, but I may just have Miranda look for something. Maybe have Lillian do it. Not sure. Anyway, it was nice seeing you, and I was actually on my way out. I may come by with a commission sometime in the future! Take care, see ya." Then he hurried out.

The reason was simple. He had seen Olivia begin to look very impatient, as if she was about to go on another rant. About what? He didn’t want to find out.

His only regret was that he forgot to ask about how they knew his last name. If they knew that, he assumed they knew his first name too. Another thing to ask Miranda about. All of that could wait, though, as he kept exploring the city. There was one place he especially wanted to check out: the largest structure in town.

"Seriously, that was that Lord Thayne guy? For real?” Olivia said to Eleanor. “I didn’t know you knew him. When did you meet?"

The archer just sighed and said, "Yeah, that’s him. I told you our party was one of the first groups to make it here. He saved Neil and the rest of us when we were in a pickle. Neil still thinks we owe him, and I kind of do too."

"Damn, friends in high places. He doesn’t look like much, though, does he? He looks straight out of a videogame or something. That mask and cloak don’t make him any less conspicuous in the least. Heck, I think I know like half the people in the city—anyone trying to look anonymous and mysterious like that stands out like dog shit on a newly mowed lawn.”

"Not sure we’re friends. I just know who he is. I’ve barely spoken to him more than a handful of times, and I don’t think we’ve interacted since that time with the bovines and the Fort. Also… you may judge his appearance as much as you like, but don’t do it in front of him.” She said the last part as a warning.

"Why? Is the big bad Lord Thayne gonna eat me up? I’m sure I won’t have anything to worry about with you around." Olivia chuckled.

"I am not joking, Olivia," Eleanor said rather gravely. “The first time we met, he killed people without any hesitation and near-effortlessly killed two people who my party and I didn’t stand a chance against. The next time at the Fort, he slaughtered some D-grade that had herded an army of thousands of cows. Today, he just returned from a dungeon filled with D-grades. If he wanted to, he could kill every single person in his city.”

She didn’t have even the faintest hint of jest in her voice.

"That’s some heavy shit… but Neil also reached D-grade, didn’t he? Can’t he—"

"I doubt Neil can even handle those two birds of his alone, much less Lord Thayne himself. He isn’t normal. Just be happy he is on our side, and don’t piss him off. He seems to place a lot of trust in Miranda, so let’s hope things stay stable in the future." Eleanor sighed once again.

"Enough about all that stuff. That Thayne guy is some monster, but he’s on our side, so who cares?" Olivia said a bit dismissively. Clearly, the topic was making her uncomfortable. "Did that old guy like the pants?"

"Oh, yeah, he liked them. I also stopped by and talked to Silas on the way. He seems to be settling into that school quite nicely and enjoys his job. He makes a good teacher, and he seems to like it. It also levels his profession damn fast." Eleanor smiled, more than happy to change the subject.

"How about Levi and Christen?" Olivia asked. "Those two stopped slacking?"

"Both working in the smithy like there’s no tomorrow. That System Store sure did them good. Too bad the leather wasn’t voted for. I reckon we will all reach D-grade within the next three weeks to a month max. Then we should still have a couple of weeks until the Treasure Hunt to get a few levels in. All of us with Perfect Evolutions, too!”

"Aw, you’re already perfect as you are," Olivia said teasingly. "Anything else interesting happened?"

"Oh, damn, I nearly forgot. It’s actually related to Lord Thayne. I mentioned those Tri-Lighttail Monkeys to Silas, and he said that Neil was pretty damn sure Lord Thayne is the one who hunted them all down. Apparently, he came straight from hunting them when he entered the World Congress. Quite the coincidence that he came by today and saw it, don’t you think?"

"Yeah, that’s pret—Oh… oh, shit," Olivia muttered.

"What?"

"I may or may not have spent five to ten minutes shit-talking whoever hunted down those monkeys…"

"Oh…" Eleanor said, lost for words.

She hoped Lord Thayne kept having a good day.

Jake had done all he could to repress the memory of the leatherworking shop and what had transpired within. He now instead stood before a frankly massive structure. He could see it was cross-shaped and was the biggest building in Haven by a fair margin. The logs used to construct the walls had to be hundreds of meters long, and it was over a dozen meters tall.

People were buzzing about at the entrance, exiting and entering all the time. They spoke in loud voices, and he noticed that the majority were wearing robes.

The building had some serious enchantments placed all over the walls, and it looked damn hard to break into. Jake had a slight urge to try and fire an explosive arcane arrow at the wall to test its durability. He, of course, didn’t. He just wanted to a little bit.

What he stood before was naturally the Temple of Haven—the next stop on his journey to explore his own damn city.

Chapter 49

Personal Improvement

Jake stood looking at the large temple, deep in his own thoughts. He was over to the side, and no one particularly bothered him. He got a few glances, but that was only to do with him looking a bit suspicious. He was more self-conscious about it now, but nothing that really irked him.

It had nothing to do with him hearing Olivia’s words before he left. If he took off his mask and cloak and just walked around like that, he would likely get far fewer stares… but if he was honest, wearing the mask and cloak wasn’t about going unnoticed or being inconspicuous.

Instead, it was about separation. To put a mask between Jake and anyone he had to talk with. To make sure none could read his expression, and for he himself to feel comfortable. It really had nothing to do with anyone else but him. There was power in a persona, and Jake knew that. It was how he had learned to survive his entire life. Granted, him being away for weeks at a time in dungeons that were all about killing didn’t do him any good either.

To summarize… Jake just felt less exhausted when wearing a mask in public. He would keep his bare face only between him and friends. He just felt more comfortable that way.

It wasn’t like not being recognized was an option either. Jake had hoped not to be recognized as "Lord Thayne," but just as a mysterious masked guy. He would be recognized as "someone standing out" no matter what happened. He hadn’t learned to hide his D-grade aura, after all, as everyone could feel it, so he would get the glances no matter what.

Well, he could have gone full-on stealth, but he still wanted to explore the city in a more "normal" way. Or at least, as normal as he could be. At least people seemed to have some tact and just acted friendly.

Also… being masked and scary-looking made people only look and not actively seek him out. None of the shopkeepers had given a damn either. In fact, most seemed to be happy when he entered, as they picked up on the D-rank aura. D-ranks were bound to have a lot of money.

He did attract a bit of unwanted attention in the form of a few rifle-bearing men who he saw check him out through binoculars from a distance. They never directly sought him out, though. That was nice. It would be awkward trying to explain that wearing all black and a mask wasn’t against the rules of Haven. Jake should know. He had just made up that rule, after all.

This didn’t mean no one ever approached Jake, though it tended to be people who recognized him. Pretty much everyone from the Fort knew how he looked due to prior interactions, and a few had walked up to thank him for back then. It was a bit awkward, as Jake wasn’t used to it, but he accepted their gratitude nevertheless.

As he stood there, he felt another person’s eyes land on him, and this one lingered. He looked back at who it was and recognized his observer. It was a young man with short hair and a strong build. The young man walked over towards Jake, a big smile on his lips.

"Lord Thayne," he said when he had walked over, practically bowing.

"Chris, right?" Jake asked.

It was one of the people from Abby’s old group. The first one to speak up against Donald. That was what had put him on Jake’s radar and made him worth remembering. At that moment, he had chosen an opportunity to get revenge against Donald and Abby over his own safety. That was respectable.

"You remember me?" Chris said with a mix of surprise of happiness.

"Well, yeah. I asked your name, didn’t I? That would be silly to do if I wanted to forget it." Jake shrugged.

The young man looked healthy and more full of life than last time. Back then, he had been full of resentment and grief, while now he looked more put together. His level was also pretty good.

[Human – lvl 57]

"I guess," Chris said, scratching his hair before asking, "How come you’re here at the temple? Are you here to visit? I heard the City Lord’s statue recently got made, and it has already been infused… It’s the only one in the grandest hall at the moment. Ah, I’m sure you already knew… Sorry, I just got a bit excited when I saw you. I came to see the statue today myself."

"Oh, Miranda got that statue made already? I guess I should go check it out. I haven’t heard many details of the temple. I just came by to check it out today.”

"If… if that’s the case, should we go together? I kept up with news, and I helped build the temple… I could be a guide or something?"

No matter how dense Jake could be, it was apparent the young man desperately wanted Jake to agree. Not like he had any reason not to.

"Sure thing," Jake agreed, smiling beneath his mask. While he didn't exactly crave social contact... he felt like having some outside people like Miranda would be good. After killing for so long, it would do him good to socialize a bit to not completely lose the ability to do so. "So, you’re a builder, eh? You get along with Hank?"

"Yeah, he’s great! He has taught me so much, and…"

Chris kept talking as the two of them entered the temple. A young chatterbox and an ominous-looking, mask-wearing, cloaked D-grade.

Miranda leaned back against the tree, breathing heavily. One of her arms was mangled, and she had a fist-sized hole in her stomach. She had to admit that she may have been in trouble without Jake’s health potion, even with all her preparations.

Green wisps of energy still floated in the air as remnants of the battle. The atmospheric mana in the area was soaked in Verdant mana from the formation that had been active until not that long ago—a formation that had covered an area nearly five hundred meters in diameter.

The formation was that of a pentagram made of staves with now cracked orbs on their ends in all the corners. The magic circle on the ground in the clearing had also helped immensely, as well as many of the explosive runes she had blown up.

Four entire days of preparation, all coming after more than one and a half months of killing the damn Oakwood Tigers to make this a one-on-one fight, had led to this day. Miranda had never thought she could do it, but with encouragement from her Patron gods, she had given it a shot and succeeded—in solo-killing a D-grade before her evolution.

*You have slain [Oakwood Tiger Alpha – lvl 103] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

The corpse was lined with glowing veins of Verdant Energy that had invaded its body. She had bombarded it with more regular spells too, but in the end, she had only stood a chance due to her immense preparations.

Miranda didn’t think of herself as a vindictive person normally, but that didn’t mean she couldn’t bear a grudge. The Oakwood Tigers had scared her for a long time, as she, Hank, and the kids had nearly died to one. It had taken her a long time to build up the courage to defeat one… and now she had nearly succeeded in wiping out all the Oakwood Tigers near Haven. Including their Alpha.

She had done it to face her fears, and it felt almost cathartic when she finally killed the Alpha. It was like a perfect circle of her journey to Haven had been made. Half a year ago, she had found what would end up being named Haven while being chased, and now she was the one chasing and killing the leader of the same monsters that had hunted her.

To truly drive home that the circle was complete, she also reached the level threshold from the kill.

* ‘DING!’ Class: [Neophyte Verdant Witch] has reached level 99 - Stat points allocated, +3 Free Points*

Which meant it was D-grade evolution time. Miranda began making her way back to Haven with difficulty as she went over the fight a few more times in her head. She had only won because she planned everything. She had studied the beast and how it hunted and learned about all its tricks. Countermeasures for every skill had been made, so the entire fight had been more a play than an actual battle—and she the scriptwriter.

What little improvisation she was forced to do had resulted in a mangled arm and vine attacks penetrating her stomach and chest. She’d used a health potion to make it through the latter one.

Miranda had gotten better at dealing with pain. However, since she’d begun leveling her witch class, she couldn’t handle it at all. She failed to focus while using skills if it hurt, and any wound practically paralyzed her for half a second from the pain. It had taken her a long time to build up her tolerance to an acceptable level. Without it, she would be dead.

The thought of risking her life wasn’t pleasant, but she had felt forced to. She desperately wanted to try and keep up with Jake and the city as a whole. Neil reaching D-grade had truly pushed her. He and his party had also killed a D-grade before evolving, using their teamwork to bring it down.

On her way back, she checked out her old profession. It had been the start of her journey to finding the place where she belonged in the new world, and a part of her felt sad knowing it would change.

Principal City Lord of Earth – The City Lord employed by the first human to found a city on Earth. Now on a path to create a haven for the survivors in the new world. A home to defend. City Lord is a profession focused on managing and guiding a city to glory. Grants skills related to management, economy, leadership, and control, as well as paths to protect your new dominion. However, be warned that should the city fall, you will not escape unscathed. Stat bonuses per level: +18 Free Points.

The profession had been great. Likely one of the better ones on Earth as a whole. She had put a lot of thought into the placement of every single free point, and after the Ladies of the Verdant Lagoon blessed her, she had begun making use of her Dreams skill to consult the other residents of the triplet goddesses’ realm.

There were plenty of loyal subjects of the Godqueens that would gladly help her with anything she needed. Humans among them. They had given her advice, and with that, she had what she hoped was a very optimal free point distribution. It was pretty standard to do this… and while she wanted to say that she was sure Jake put just as much thought into placing his points, she was pretty sure he didn’t. He probably just placed them wherever he felt like. Miranda wished she had the confidence to do that.

When she re-entered Haven, she stayed hidden and went straight for her home. Well, it was also her workplace, but she did have privacy in some parts of the large building. Once there, she evolved to D-grade without hesitation.

The first thing she did after evolving wasn’t to upgrade her profession, but instead to take a shower. Did she need it? No, not really, but she really wanted one. It also allowed her to properly identify some of the changes the evolution had brought.

Neil had already been a good-looking young man before becoming a D-grade, but was now at old-world actor standards. He had joked about maybe finally being able to land a partner with his improved looks, but it had led to some questions. Why had Jake barely changed when he became D-grade?

She had ended up asking a C-grade human within the Verdant Lagoon—an absolutely gorgeous woman who had explained how evolution worked in more depth. How it brought your appearance and some other things about yourself closer to your own ideal version of perfect. Did that particular mole bother you? The evolution would remove it. If you liked the mole or didn’t care about it? It would stay.

This had inadvertently resulted in all humans looking quite a lot better… but it wasn’t equal. You had to want it. Often those were just subconscious wants, out of one’s control. Everyone had small parts about themselves they wanted to improve if they could. Some more than others. She had learned that Jake was one of the people who didn’t truly wish for any significant change.

He had gotten a bit taller, and his features had been ironed out… but that was it. Not to misunderstand, he looked handsome, but he had been that way since the first time they met. A bit average, sure, but that coupled with his entire presence was a charming mix. To be honest, Jake’s confidence made Miranda feel vain as she stood and stared at herself in the mirror. While she had always put effort into her appearance, it was nothing compared to the makeover an evolution could bring. She felt like she looked like some of those internet influencers, except her mirror image wasn’t photoshopped.

I blame the unrealistic beauty standards set by advertisement firms and the advent of photo-editing technology, she joked with herself as she dried her long, orange hair. The evolution had even made her hair feel more comfortable to touch… Why the hell had she wanted that?

Shaking her head, she put on her clothes again. She felt them magically fit her slightly changed body, giving room or shrinking where needed. What was it Jake called that? System-fuckery, was it? There sure were some shenanigans going on.

Once dressed, she went and sat down as she began her profession evolution. She couldn’t evolve her class yet due to needing that extra level, but her profession had been capped for a long time.

She had a selection of five different professions on the list. When she evolved to E-grade, she had only had four. One of the new options was a straight upgrade to her existing one, not really adding anything new except tripling the stat points—which wasn’t bad at all, as it would offer 54 per level.

Two of the options were unrelated to her role as a City Lord, so she disregarded them instantly. One was related to her blessing from the Verdant Witches, and the other was some general social-type profession. Neither was better than just the straight upgrade.

Which left two remaining. Both were better than the straight upgrade to Principal City lord, at least stat-wise. The first of which gave 55 stat points. But…

Steward of Jake Thayne – You have sworn your life to uphold the interests of Jake Thayne and will serve him i—

No! No way! Next!

Mistress of Haven – You are the leader of the first city founded on Earth by the Progenitor and Chosen of the Malefic Viper, Jake Thayne. Haven had many expectations as the first city, and most were met, not through rapid expansion but by focusing on quality. More importantly, you have managed to stay in the good graces of Jake Thayne and keep your position. You are now more trusted than ever, as your bond with your benefactor strengthens. Grants skills related to management, economy, leadership, and control, as well as paths to protect your new dominion and remain in the good graces of the owner of the city. However, be warned that should the city fall, or if you fail to live up to the expectations of the city owner, you will not escape unscathed.

Stat bonuses per level: +59 Free Points.

Way better, if still a few implications I am not sure what to think about.

"Louise even helped bring food this one time, and we talked about old times. We even liked the same TV shows from before the system! Recently she began wearing this new dress; I think it’s pastel-colored? I’m not sure. I suck at colors. She looked really pretty an—"

Jake walked beside Chris, who was enthusiastically talking about his obvious crush on Louise. The young man wasn’t even trying to hide it, and had begun after he probed Jake a bit. Jake had admitted that he’d had a girlfriend before, which made Chris believe Jake was some expert when it came to the opposite sex. He hadn’t even gotten the chance to tell the young man that his first relationship didn’t exactly end amicably.

It was honestly enjoyable. Chris was a nice guy, if a bit naïve and overly outgoing. Just as Jake was thinking this, he felt the change.

The atmosphere underwent a subtle shift. The mana changed. Jake was clearly the only one who noticed it, as it was so minuscule… but it was there. And Jake also instantly knew the reason—Miranda had evolved her profession.

Jake kept walking and talking with Chris as the young man introduced all the different statues of weird gods they came across. They had decided to save the main chamber with the Ladies of the Verdant Lagoon for last. None of these gods were infused by someone blessed, and yet they still had odd auras around them. Likely due to the sculptor infusing some inherent magic.

He kept thinking about Miranda’s evolution and how he should go check things out once he was done at the temple. It turned out that wasn’t necessary.

Jake felt something. A probe of sorts. Something tried to connect to him, and it felt ever so slightly like when Villy contacted him. Yet it was blocked. It encountered an impenetrable wall—a wall that seemed to be both grand and disconnected from Jake. He couldn’t even comprehend it… and without the system letting him know, he would never have noticed it.

No… it was more a veil. A cloak… A shroud. Just as Jake felt the attempted connection fade, he let it through. Instantly, he lost all feeling of the shroud. The system stopped making him aware of it as Miranda’s voice echoed in his head.

"Helloooo? It should be working? Is my skill broken? Hellooo?"

Chapter 50

Temple & Blessings

"Message received, over," Jake responded mentally to Miranda. He turned to Chris, who was standing with him before an overly gaudy statue made of what looked like gold. "Another merchant god? How many damn merchant gods are there?"

"Finally, I was beginning to think the skill didn’t work…” Miranda said through the odd telepathic connection, which seemed to have a hint of karmic magic. “Anyway, hey, Jake, I evolved to D-grade and upgraded my profession, which got me a skill to contact you through some formation for communication. I was lucky I had the ingredients required on hand. It isn’t cheap, but I wanted to test out if it worked.”

"For some reason, there seems to be a buttload of gods who do trade and money stuff,” Chris said to Jake. “I heard from some people it has something to do with faith, but I’m not sure. All I know is that, yeah, there are so many. Maybe it’s because they’re more into investing in young talents? That’s business-like, right?"

Holding two conversations at once was a bit weird. Especially as one was in Jake’s head and the other in the physical world around him. It was some next-level multitasking, and Jake couldn’t help but try. He found it challenging to do… which was reason enough for him to do it.

"You forgot the ‘over’, over," Jake responded, teasing Miranda. Then, to Chris, he said, "That makes sense, I guess. Our world revolved a lot around economics before; it makes sense gods who focus on it found many worth investing in here.”

He kept up this dual conversation, neither of the two people he spoke to wiser to that fact. It did help that Miranda only spoke a few more times, though. She quickly gave a rundown on things and said she would be by the lodge the next day, which left Jake plenty of time to continue wandering about and even throw in a visit to the Fort.

"The range of this skill should be quite extensive. It’s rare rarity and only works on you, so it has to be decent. I can’t even contact Lillian with it, though she already has a skill to do that, so it isn’t a problem. Also, I’ll be sure to bring some food from this new place when I visit. The System Store having foodstuffs has added to the palate of the restaurants even more than before the dungeon. Anyway, see you then… over." With that, Miranda finished, making Jake able to focus all his attention on Chris. Jake felt Miranda would have had to cut off soon anyway, as her voice had started to feel a bit faint, making him guess there was a limit to the skill on communication time.

"Wanna go to the east wing now?” Chris asked, as they were about to be done with the west wing. “There are a few infused statues there. They have this insane aura, and people can even pray to them and get temporary bonuses… I even heard someone got a profession upgrade due to one of the statues, as well as a blessing.”

The west wing had only non-infused statues. Quite a lot of them, even. Jake also noticed they all had some similar aspects, so he couldn’t help but ask, "Are all these made by the same sculptor?"

"Yes! They’re all made by Felix, a really great dude, if a bit weird. He spends all his time making statues and has a backlog of ones to create even now, as far as I know. He even evolved his profession at level 100 and made the statue in the innermost chamber after that. The one with the Ladies of the Verdant Lagoon.”

The two of them walked through the crowd and entered the east wing. While the west wing did have some people in it, it wasn’t that many. The east wing, on the other hand, was absolutely packed. Jake easily saw the reason why.

At the end of the room were eight statues giving off powerful auras. Divine auras. Jake saw Chris unconsciously lower his head a bit as he entered the room beside him. Most of the people in there were praying and stuff like that, but there was one group that stood out.

Over to the side of the chamber was an area with what looked like yoga mats. Around twenty people sat on their respective mats with their eyes closed and brows sweaty. Most of their heads were held high, but they looked to be struggling.

Finally, one of them breathed out heavily, opened his eyes, and lowered his head. After a bit of labored breathing, he walked out of the room with unsteady steps. People made way and gave him a fast lane to get out, making Jake think it was a usual occurrence. On closer inspection… Jake was pretty sure two of the nineteen left on the mats weren’t conscious.

"What’s up with that?" Jake asked, nodding towards them.

Chris looked up at Jake, a bit confused, then answered, "They’re training their resistance to auras. Mental states or something. They try to resist the aura to build up a tolerance when it’s easier just to let it affect you."

"I see," Jake said, nodding.

Well, he understood what they were doing even if he couldn’t relate. The auras weren’t an issue for him at all. Heck, Villy couldn’t bring him down with his aura, so how could a bunch of statues from weaker gods?

The auras were weirdly clashing in the room. Each statue was ten or so meters apart, and each had an area of influence around them roughly based on their level of power, as far as Jake could tell. Some statues had auras extending further than others. It could also have something to do with the one who’d infused them? The level of their blessing? A combination, perhaps? Luckily, he didn’t need to figure that one out himself, as Villy came poking. Jake felt like he was beginning to have too many people in his head these days…

"The statues possess an aura dependent on both the god and the one who infused it. The higher the rarity of the blessing, the more ‘juice’ is packed into the statue, while the god is the quality of the juice. By the way, wanna do something funny? I promise it will be interesting?" Villy said in a teasing tone.

"Will it include the death of one or more people?" Jake asked back to clarify. Half-jokingly.

"Nah, no one will get hurt permanently. But it will be funny and interesting. Promise.”

"No destruction of property either," Jake stipulated.

He already had an idea of what Villy was planning. Jake wasn’t sure it was a good idea; in fact, he was quite sure it was a bad idea, but he was curious. He wanted to see what would happen… which was why he also didn’t resist when Villy’s presence amplified.

"Deal."

It was a bad decision… but… a bit funny.

An aura descended on the entire east wing. Instantly, the eight statues were suppressed, and every single person—except Jake—fell to their knees and couldn’t raise their heads. Jake, playing along, also crouched down.

It only lasted for around five seconds until the aura disappeared as if it had never been there. It took another ten seconds before the statues began exuding auras once more, and nearly half a minute before people began standing up, looking around in confusion and fear. Some didn’t get up at all, but lay unconscious on the ground.

The seventeen people on the yoga mats were all knocked out cold. Silly people tried to resist.

Panic seemed to overtake the entire wing as people began yelling and looking around. A few gazes landed on Jake, but with how many wore robes or cloaks in there and him staying crouched, he didn’t stand out that much.

"What exactly was the purpose of that?" Jake asked the clearly bored Primordial.

"Shameless flexing. Those gods all felt it on their end. Just wanted to take a good wee all over my—well, our—territory to make it clear that while they got statues here, they ain’t shit. Oh, and another small thing that you will find out about in a bit.” That last sentence sounded way too amused for Jake to feel comfortable.

"Wha… what was that?" Chris muttered, having managed to stay conscious and relatively put together.

He did look a bit wobbly on his feet, but otherwise, he took it well. Jake was a bit proud of that; Villy’s aura was quite something, after all.

Not that Villy had used his full aura. Jake remembered feeling it back in Villy’s realm and during the evolution of his profession. What had just been done felt like… nothing.

"Hey, Villy, toss me a percentage. How much ‘juice,’ as you say, did you put into that one?" Jake asked.

"We aren’t in the percentage points yet. I can’t really unleash it all, even if I wanted to. Well, I could still pour in enough for me to kill anyone—at least, everyone not in D-grade—within a few hundred meters of you, but it really isn’t worth it. Doing it is tiring as fuck, and anyone it has any effect on, you could just as easily beat yourself. So, no, not applicable in combat at all.”

Jake himself decided to stay in the real world. "Must be something to do with those statues. Can you tell me about them?"

"Oh… probably was just them… I don’t really get how these things work. Anyway, the statues depict…"

To summarize: The statues depicted a bunch of weaker gods or subordinate gods from larger organizations. Nothing interesting or fancy going on at all. Of course, to the populace of Haven, any god was an absolutely insurmountable being. It kind of made sense. To a regular human. It didn’t matter if a black hole was small or large; it could rip you apart, atom by atom, no matter what. If atoms were still a thing after the system. Probably not. Did black holes still exist? Probably. Jake couldn’t wait to go see one. Event horizons looked dope in pictures, and seeing one in person would be awesome.

After Chris was done, he hesitantly asked, "Would you like to go pray at one? It offers a temporary buff to your status menu… It’s quite good…"

"You go. I already got a blessing," Jake answered nonchalantly.

"Oh… you do? Well, that makes sense; I heard the best got them offered… I’ll be right back, okay?"

Jake waved him off to go get his blessing. Chris was clearly anxious Jake would leave while he was gone. An unfounded fear for sure.

"Okay, one last trick. Have the kid come back," Villy butted in unprompted. "Those stupid gods aren’t the only ones who can play… well, gods."

"Actually, come back here," Jake said just as Chris had taken a single step.

"Yes?" he asked, back before Jake even had a chance to answer.

"Place your hand on the guy’s shoulder or something."

Jake placed his hand on the confused young man’s shoulder.

"Now, just want for him to get a temporary blessing and pour in a bit of mana."

Following the instructions, Jake poured in a bit of mana, and he felt Villy also pour in something. Chris looked confused until he felt the energy enter him. He gaped for a while before making a huge grin.

"For real!?" he asked, excited.

"Yeah, go for it," Jake said, smiling beneath his mask.

Villy thought he was pulling a fast one, but didn’t seem to know that Jake already knew what he was doing. He had seen it mentioned in Jacob’s small booklet a long time ago.

Anyone with a certain level of blessing could, with the permission of their Patron, give out blessings themselves. In fact, the whole “meeting through evolutions” part of giving blessings was a rarity. Well, it had been a necessity for the new universe.

Jake understood why this was a thing. Gods shouldn’t waste time giving out every minor baptism or insignificant blessing themselves by meeting every prospect. So they had delegated that shit. And now Villy was having Jake act as a religious figurehead, blessing Chris.

As for why Jake let him? Because why not? Chris seemed like a nice guy, but blessings didn’t grow on trees. It would help the guy out, and also… it was kind of interesting, wasn’t it?

“Is this the first person on Earth besides me you blessed?” Jake asked the Viper.

“Ah, this is way less fun when you know. As for if you are the first… not telling,” Villy said, trying to tease Jake, but…

“So that’s a no. Good to know. Be nice to Chris, by the way. I don’t think he could handle you messing with him.”

“Talking directly to those you blessed isn’t just something you can normally do this easily. I can because you’re my Chosen. Also because it tends to fuck up the blessed person if you talk too often. Their feeble souls cannot handle it without dedicated skills for communication. Before you ask, yes, you are a freak of nature, and also, yes, I still want that sacrificial array deployed. We can compromise and go with a continental one, except for a planetary?"

Jake wanted to respond with a quip, but before he could, something unexpected happened. Two arms wrapped themselves around him as Chris gave him a big hug.

"Thank you so much! I can’t even begin to tell you… I’m just… What do you need me to do? I know nothing comes for free, and I swear I will do anything I can to make it up to you."

"It’s fine—no pressure and no expectations come with it besides for you to do your best. So just… let go, please?" Chris was still hugging him tightly. It was very awkward.

"Sorry…" he muttered as he reluctantly let go.

"It’s just a lesser blessing. I already got my investment’s worth tenfold with that hug," Villy laughed.

Jake cut off the super-rude snake god as he and Chris made their way out of the room and headed towards the main chamber, where only a single statue infused with energy resided—the Ladies of the Verdant Lagoon.

They came, they saw, and Jake had to say it looked great. He also noted that the aura didn’t affect him at all—as in, it didn’t even try to affect him. Chris also looked surprised and said he didn’t feel anything. Something to do with them being groupies of Villy, I guess.

To be honest, the main chamber wasn’t that interesting, yet it was even more packed. People prayed to statues that weren’t even infused, which to Jake just looked silly. The one Jake assumed was meant to depict the Holy Mother—or at least her symbol, which was also the symbol of the Holy Church—was especially popular. For the record, her symbol was a pair of wings. A bit boring… though Villy’s was just a snake. Both a bit boring.

Jake didn’t want to stay long, and neither did Chris. Well, Chris just wanted to follow Jake. As he exited the main chamber, still thinking about where to go next, he saw someone approach him in a hurry. The moment he saw Jake and Chris, his eyes practically lit up, and he rushed over even faster.

"That’s the sculptor, Felix," Chris muttered just in time.

"You!” the sculptor named Felix yelled at the entrance to the main chamber, drawing attention from all around. “You’re blessed by a Primordial, aren’t you? I felt it! I felt the almighty aura of a Primordial, and I still feel it linger even now! Haha! I never thought I would truly encounter one blessed by a Primordial this soon! Please help me in trying to display even a fraction of the brilliance of a Primordial with my meager skills!"

Felix's eyes were directed straight at the one blessed by a Primordial:

Chris.

Chapter 51

Servant & Territory

Jake was confused, Felix was excited, Chris was super confused, and Villy was laughing hysterically in Jake’s head.

It took Jake a moment to realize that Villy had seriously just blessed someone solely to fuck with him as a setup for this joke. Along with the hug, the old snake god seemed to have one hell of a time. Too bad for Villy… two could play that game.

Felix looked expectantly at Chris, who looked nervously up at Jake for guidance. They had attracted quite a lot of attention, as Felix seemed to be a bit of a local celebrity. Now that same shine was put on Chris, who everyone looked at. Only a few gave Jake a glance, which was actually quite nice.

Jake took charge and said, "Please, let us take this somewhere more private. His lordship does not wish to flaunt his position."

This earned him even more confused glances from Chris, but Jake just looked back at him, trying to convey that the young man should play along with the joke.

It didn’t work. The young man still looked panicky.

Felix shifted his attention to Jake and mumbled, "Yes… I understand. Please follow me!"

Putting a hand on Chris’ shoulder, Jake led him to follow him and Felix into a side room. A large, enchanted door separated the room from the rest of the temple, and upon entering, it was clear this was a workshop. Tools lined the walls, and two half-built statues stood in the center of the room. Enchantments also seemed to nicely isolate the room from the rest of the temple.

"Now!” Felix said with fanatic fervor. “Please, I must know… I felt the aura… but… which Primordial blessed you? Was it Stormild? Wyrmgod? No… you’re a builder… The Starseizing Titan? Rigoria? Please, I must know!"

Yep, this guy is a loony, Jake thought. Had the dude been making too many statues and now found his mind broken by godly auras? Or was it something else?

"Before answering, please let us know why you desire this information?" Jake said, continuing to play his role of bodyguard or assistant or… Well, he hadn’t really decided on a set role. He was improvising.

"Yes… sorry, I was just too excited. Allow me to introduce myself once more. I am Felix, a newly joined member of the Primordial Church and blessed by the Eternal Servant. Sculpting is my creed, and after being shown the magnificence of the Primordials, my life goal has been to depict one… naturally only with the approval of one blessed by them.” He was clearly putting in the effort to stay calm.

"I… I think there is a misunderstanding," Chris said, having built up the courage to explain himself. "I just received my blessing a few minutes ago from Lord Thayne."

He pointed at Jake—that little snitch—forcing him to stop the play… and enter another role. Villy wouldn’t get off cheap.

"You’re… But I feel no aura?” Felix said while looking at Jake, unsure if Chris was telling the truth. “I should be able to… I have a skill to see, so…"

"Chris, you tell him," Jake said. Totally not because he wasn’t sure how to explain the situation and make himself seem cool and mysterious meanwhile.

"Lord Thayne touched me and gave me a blessing related to the Malefic Viper… He was the one with it first," Chris explained. Granted, the kid didn’t know much, but apparently, just the mention of the Malefic Viper was enough.

Felix looked to be flummoxed for a moment and didn’t respond. He paused. Looked almost to be in a trance for several seconds.

Then… another aura appeared. Felix’s eyes glowed a deep blue for a split second. One of his eyes returned to normal, but the other kept shining, and the aura remained… The aura of a god. Tears began pouring as he fell to his knees.

"This servant greets the Chosen of the Malefic One," he said.

Or perhaps they said would be more accurate. His voice echoed with those of other people—first Felix’s and then the god’s. His body appeared to be half-possessed…

On a side note, Chris was knocked out cold the moment the god’s aura appeared.

Jake was, needless to say, surprised. By several things. First of all, could gods possess mortals like that? Secondly, whatever god did so clearly knew his identity right away… and third…

The aura of the god possessing Felix felt awfully similar to that of Villy—both in signature and power.

“Who are you?” Jake asked.

“Jake, give me some mana here,” he heard Villy’s voice say.

Jake didn’t think much before pouring out nearly 10,000 mana in a fraction of a second. A faint outline of a glowing green eye appeared. It turned out that was all the physical manifestation Jake could possibly facilitate.

One thing that did remain in full force was his presence.

Felix—or the god possessing him—looked at Villy with wide eyes as he practically prostrated himself. "This Eternal Servant greets the Primordial."

"I guess it’s been a while," Villy said.

His tone was odd, and Jake picked up on it right away. He sounded more formal... and annoyed? At least, he didn’t appear to be in a joking mood. Had he not predicted this would happen? Jake assumed he had…

"Far too long, Malefic One,” the god possessing Felix said in an echoing voice. “I have no words to explain my elation when I felt your return… The world has been incomplete for far too long.”

Jake didn’t really want to butt in, but…

Felix seemed to be breaking.

"Yo, better get the fuck out of that guy’s body, or he’s gonna die," Jake said in a scolding tone.

"Ah, it’s of no concern; it is merely another vessel… I shall bring another to—"

"I wasn’t asking," Jake said, staring into the eyes of the possessed Felix.

He felt the god stare back at him with a hint of surprise. Jake felt like he looked into an infinite ocean of light, and he saw twelve figures upon mighty thrones for a fraction of a second. The vision disappeared as fast as it had come, and the possessed man smiled.

"Truly worthy of being the Malefic One’s Chosen. I shall oblige," he said, his smile widening. Felix’s lips cracked due to the smile as blood began leaking out. Blood also began pouring from his eyes, ears, and nose, and his skin cracked in several places.

"It shames me our meeting was cut short… Please never hesitate to call upon me, oh Malefic One."

With those words, the aura faded, and the eye stopped glowing. Well, it didn’t really stop glowing so much as it disappeared, as there was now an empty eye socket where it had been. Felix was on the brink of death, and Jake didn’t hesitate to go forward and make him drink a healing potion.

All of these weird events left Jake in a room with two unconscious people and a floating green eye belonging to Villy.

“So… who the fuck was that?” Jake asked.

“The Eternal Servant…" Villy said through the weird floating eye. “I honestly don't wanna say much about him. He is what happens when fanaticism is taken to such an extreme it results in godhood. He is from the Second Era, born in the First Universe, and he is a bit… much. Yeah, just thinking about him is annoying. Man, I hoped to fuck with you by having a fanatic from his ‘church’ meet you, but now it just got weird.”

"So, what is this Primordial Church?"

"A fucked-up fan club of all the Primordials led by the biggest fanboy of the multiverse. I am not joking. Seriously, the guy exemplifies why the word fan comes from fanatic. He is batshit insane, and anyone who joins his church is pretty damn crazy too. Well, they can be normal most of the time, but confront them with anything Primordial-related, and they go mental.”

Jake was sure there were a lot of stories for him to hear in the future.

"Sounds like a lot. Will the dude cause issues for me? Also, what the hell was he doing with this Felix fellow? He nearly died."

"Besides possibly getting a meltdown due to the paradox of you being both a heretic and a Chosen, I doubt he will ever be an issue for you," Villy explained curtly. “He may be an annoyance. As for that mortal human… He is just a mortal human. Another instrument for the Servant to do his work. Why would a god care about the death of a single E-grade follower? To him, a single nanosecond more in the presence of a Primordial is worth more than that guy’s life.”

"Okay, dude is fucked up for real. Is that kind of divine possession normal?"

"No, not at all. The one being possessed has to accept it, and as you saw, it isn’t exactly healthy for the one being possessed. This guy must have a skill related to the Eternal Servant to do it, which is why I hadn’t seen this shitty situation coming. But you can meet people who can do it, and some possessions or partial possessions also have combat effects. You don’t even need to do it with a god, just someone quite a bit more powerful than you. Often it isn’t even an individual possessing the person, but a Record Fragment. It’s just integrating a part of a superior being’s Records for a short period to empower yourself. If you had taken a class to become my Champion, you would have one hundred percent gotten one like that. They’re basically just another form of temporary boosting skills with all the associated aftereffects.”

Jake nodded along, not at all unhappy he didn’t have some weird possession skill. He didn’t like the thought of being possessed at all. Why Felix was fine with it, he didn’t get either, but the dude did seem a bit broken.

"Thanks for the info, mate. I guess I’ll see you around? Also, you majorly fucked up, eh? Don’t worry; I’ll make sure to get you an absolutely wonderful statue that will truly show off your awesomeness.” Jake deviously smiled as he saw the floating eye about to run out of mana.

“See, this is why you got that damn heretic part of your profession,” Villy laughed as the eye slowly faded away. Not mad at all, but just bemused.

Jake himself just chuckled. He wasn’t going to do something overly obscene… but he would have some fun with it.

Now there was just one minor issue.

The room had changed from two unconscious people plus Jake and floating-green-eye-Villy to Jake alone with two unconscious men.

Jake sat down in meditation and began weaving some mana strings into the shape of a statue to pass the time and wait for them to wake up as he muttered to himself, "Now, how much can I get away with…"

While Jake was fucking around and being childish with the Malefic Viper, the rest of the world progressed towards the Treasure Hunt. But it wasn’t all smooth sailing. A month after the World Congress, around the time Jake entered the dungeon, the barriers went down.

Barriers sealing in the many D-grades bound to the unclaimed Pylons of the world. Variants and groups of D-grades were freed, and many of these were not as docile as the usual beasts. They weren’t all natives of the 93rd Universe. Far from it. Some of them were even sapient like the King of the Forest, with their own ideals and goals.

Even more so, when the barriers disappeared, the Pylons spawned. Spawned, ready for the taking. But… not only humans could claim them. The only reason no monster had claimed one yet was due to one always spawning after a human or a group of humans killed the guardian. The only exception to this was Jake’s Pylon, which beasts had tried to claim yet failed in taking due to Jake’s quest.

Now, nothing held them back, and all across the globe, monster nobles appeared. They claimed territories affected by the Pylons and made them their own, dominated other beasts or creatures in the area, and experienced massive growth as the Pylon sped up their progress.

This led to some of them being greedy. To wanting to claim more Pylons and grow more powerful. Other monsters were displaced as they lost the bout to claim a Pylon and went looking for another. The vast majority ended up in conflicts with other monsters. One must remember that humans were all concentrated in a small area, while the rest of the planet still existed, dominated by other creatures. These creatures now fought as they also struggled for dominion—just as humans did in their own smaller area.

But, of course, some found their way to human settlements. Packs of D-grade beasts that sought opportunities, solitary powerful D-grades that were ousted, or entire armies led by a powerful leader. All of these were now something humanity had to contend with on top of the usual native beasts of Earth.

Naturally, the beasts of Earth also had to deal with these newly released invaders. In fact, many Pylons were claimed by natives, as they dominated the territories of these Pylon monsters and claimed them as their own. Many didn’t due to them already living in areas suitable for their growth, but some monsters would always wander.

Humanity faced this new threat head-on. Many cities were prepared, featuring defenses, at least one D-grade, or powerful parties or formations to hold back any invaders.

The more powerful cities didn’t have any major issues. The Court of Shadows, Undead, Holy Church, Noboru Clan, Valhal, and many others handled these invaders easily. All of these factions had multiple D-grades in their ranks by now, and just the size and power of their permanent defenses were enough to deter any opportunistic invader.

No, those that truly suffered were the smaller settlements. Those who had a Pylon but no major fighting force attached. Sure, all had had to slay a strong D-grade to get the Pylon, but the killer of the D-grade hadn’t always stayed around. Or at least, they couldn’t be around all the time. The moment the strongest fighter left, the city would fall, and many of the invaders weren’t stupid monsters but intelligent beings. They waited, plotted, and seized the moment when opportune. This inadvertently led to even more growth for both parties involved, as many humans were forced into leveling their otherwise neglected class.

Gods were also involved. Humans were not the only ones who could be blessed. Some gods even began to place bets on beasts or monsters, blessing them and giving them guidance with the hope that they could take over the planet. These deities were not silly enough to think they could kill all the humans… They’d simply make them run away from the planet in due time, or have their blessed one leave themselves if it got too dangerous.

It was a new paradigm that resulted in far more beasts or monsters attacking cities as they were displaced. No city went unnoticed by these monsters. Some, they chose to steer clear of, however.

Those too big, like Sanctdomo, Saya, or Skyggen, were natural places to avoid. Others had powerful defenders. All of them were avoided after long consideration and scouting from the monsters—especially the sapient ones.

All but one.

While Jake had been in the dungeon, and Haven had lain undefended, some monsters had come by.

A gargoyle looked down from far above towards the forest below. Its gem-like red eyes stared down for a long time. It stood on a large horizontal tower that floated through magical means, nearly ten kilometers long and five hundred meters wide.

The gargoyle was the leader, a powerful monster that saw few equals in this new world. Yet it had been pushed away from its Pylon and forced to flee by a powerful native beast. The inner parts of the forest were not somewhere it could safely exist. So, it had taken its army and tower with it as it retreated, looking for a new opportunity. It had fled from deep within the forest… and the closest Pylon was in the outskirts. It had felt it due to its magical sensitivity.

It led an army of over a thousand gargoyles. Several D-grades were among them, and as the leader, this gargoyle was already a mid-tier D-grade at level 131. Its royal guards were all D-grades above 120. The city should be easy to claim, as all the readings indicated they had every advantage. No D-grades, either, according to their devices. It should be easy…

But…

"This place… is not ours to claim," the leader said as it commanded the tower to turn, and their journey continued as they went to seek out another Pylon.

It was not the first monster to come across Haven. It would not be the last either. But so far, none had dared enter. Sapient or instinctual, smart or dumb, they all felt it—they all knew—that one does not simply walk into the territory of a powerful entity.

Much less the territory of the Primal Hunter.

Chapter 52

Will of the Chosen

Hm, should I go for human-form Villy looking silly? Jake thought as he considered his options while waiting for the two men to wake up. Nah, that would be boring. Small snake eating a mushroom? That could be funny. Oh, what if I added a plaque below saying ‘danger noodle’? Yeah, that could totally be funny.

His hands were weaving different figures of stable arcane mana as he tried out a few shapes he thought could be funny.

After fifteen minutes, Chris woke up. Felix was still out, as it seemed like being possessed by that god had done a number on him. Without the healing potion, he would have certainly died. Again, that Eternal Servant guy was a major asshole.

"What happened?" Chris asked as he woke up. He didn’t try to stand up right away, but stayed on the ground as he rubbed his head.

"Felix got possessed by a god, and the aura knocked you out. I heard that can happen, so no reason to feel bad about it," Jake explained.

"Oh…" Chris answered. He sighed, sat up, and stared at the floor as he muttered, "Why do I keep being mentally assaulted and knocked out all the time today?"

"Sorry, that’s on me," Jake apologized. "On a positive note, that should be the last time. I hope it is, at least."

Chris nodded. He looked at Felix also lying on the ground and saw the bloodstains from the possession earlier. The missing eye was still being regenerated, but it wasn’t exactly visible.

"What happened to him!? Is he dead!?" Chris yelled as he got up in a jiffy and backed away from Felix.

On a second look, he did look like a corpse. His entire body was bloody from his cracked skin, blood had flowed from every opening, and he didn’t look healthy at all. If one looked a bit closer, one could see that no actual injuries besides the still-healing eye were present, but Chris hadn’t done that.

"I told you, divine possession," Jake patiently explained. “Apparently not the healthiest of things to engage in. Don’t worry, Felix should be fine. Physically, at least. I think he’s already a bit out there mentally.”

He didn’t mind talking him through everything gradually. Not like he had anything better to do, and Chris was a nice guy who just seemed to accept all the fucked-up shit he told him without question. Quite refreshing.

"I hope he’s okay," Chris said, clearly worried about the sculptor.

"He’ll wake up eventually. Anyway, while we wait, do you know where Hank is these days?" He had been meaning to ask for a while, but things had kinda happened.

"Hank and Louise went to the Fort," Chris explained, sounding more confident than before. “They’re always super busy there, and he needed to help them out and handle some issues. There are a lot of new settlers because of the increasing presence of beasts, and people feel unsafe due to the lack of a physical barrier between the outer parts of the Fort and the surrounding plains.”

I guess it helps to talk about things you actually know about, Jake chuckled internally. "Have there been any major issues with beasts?"

The Minotaur Mindchief was still on his mind, and Jake wondered if something similar had happened. Anton and Neil were there, both D-grades, so they should be able to hold enemies off. Neil, at least, should be able to put up lots of resistance. Jake didn’t know if Anton could really fight, but he had a feeling the man wasn’t defenseless.

"Not as much as elsewhere. I heard a lot of the smaller settlements are struggling, but the attackers only hit the places with Pylons. Apparently, Neil is in communication with some other space mages, and they let us know. I’m not sure about the details, though…" Chris looked apologetic.

"I’ll just have Miranda fill me in; we’re meeting tomorrow anyway," Jake said, waving it off.

The two kept talking for a while, and Jake came to learn a lot about the young man. He looked a bit meek and nice, but he was also headstrong and determined. Jake learned even more information he frankly didn’t need or want to about Donald and Abby, and it only helped confirm how absolutely shitty of people they’d been.

Chris had stayed with them with the goal of one day getting his revenge for what they did to his sister. He had outwardly looked loyal, but when he talked, Jake felt the pure hatred in his voice, coupled with the elation when he spoke of that one time he got one of the people loyal to Donald killed.

He was a scheming man who didn’t even flinch when he mentioned stealthily throwing a dagger at someone’s calf as he tried to dodge a charging beast. Jake liked him more and more as they talked. However, there were some things that made Jake uncomfortable.

Chris had been prepared to die. He had already written his life off, so when Jake had ended up “saving” him, Chris had decided that he would gladly use his life to repay that favor. It wasn’t normal at all, but the man had clearly been fucked up mentally by what he had gone through, and now had a weird mindset … no matter how normal he could seem most of the time. Jake was beginning to think Villy hadn’t just blessed him as a joke. Chris was loyal to Jake to an unhealthy level.

"What do you want to accomplish, Chris?" Jake finally asked.

"Um, why do you ask? What do you mean?" He looked genuinely confused by the question.

"You just got a blessing from a god, you don’t seem incompetent, and you are still only in the middle parts of E-grade. You’re gonna live a long-ass time, and that lifespan will only increase as you level up. While you’re still in your early days, you can change what you wanna do still. What you want to be. So, what do you see yourself doing in a decade? A century?"

It was something he had been meaning to ask, because besides "repaying Jake," Chris didn’t really seem to have any other real goals. He just trudged along and worked as a builder. Well, he did have a massive crush on Louise. Did that count as a goal?

"I’m not sure what you mean?" Chris asked, his confusion growing. "I’ll just keep working, I guess. Do my best. I think I’m pretty good at my job, and—"

"Yeah, that’s what you could keep doing, but what do you want to do? Seriously, nothing’s holding you back. Do whatever you want to, and as long as you don’t piss off people you shouldn’t piss off, no one that matters will judge you for it. So I ask again, what do you want to do?"

He himself had thought a lot about it. He knew exactly what he wanted to do and the way to reach that goal. Even if it was a simple-as-fuck plan, it was a plan nevertheless.

"I…" Chris said, staring down at the floor. He was silent for several seconds as he looked deep in thought, then looked back up at Jake seriously. "I don’t know?"

In retrospect, maybe it was a bit much to expect the young guy to figure out his entire path of life on the spot like that. Jake should have known better. Of course, that kind of thing was only okay to do with teenage students choosing higher education.

“Well, I guess your first goal should be to figure that out," Jake curtly said. “Also, if you’re worried about the whole god and blessing thing… the creed of the god that blessed you is to pursue freedom above all else. Be your own man and have your own goals. You don’t owe me anything. I helped you because Donald and Abby were pieces of shit and invaded my territory. That you also got helped too was just a happy little accident.” He didn’t wanna mince words with Chris. He had potential, but his mindset was just not something Jake could agree with.

He wasn’t comfortable with the young guy being so reverent towards him. Chris had already been awkward enough before Jake inadvertently helped him get a blessing from a god that, according to the title description, was very powerful. Now he was even worse. Jake didn’t want that; he wanted Chris to be his own man. If he then decided to still be on team Jake? At least that would be his own decision, not made due to some odd sense of debt.

Chris didn’t answer but just sat there in thought. Jake kept playing with his mana strings, making small, funny-looking miniature statues of Villy as they waited.

Silence overtook the room for a few minutes until a groan was heard from Felix. The resident sculptor looked to be in immense pain as he struggled to sit up. His one eye was still regenerating, and his body was a mess. Jake wouldn’t blame him if the guy asked them to lea—

"Oh, where are my man—" Halfway through the sentence, he got a coughing fit, spitting out a glob of blood before continuing, " —ners… I apologize for the unsightly appearance."

"Relax. You nearly died by being possessed by your Patron," Jake said, shaking his head.

"I know! A meager sacrifice to learn I am in the presence of a Primordial’s Chosen! Please, let me know of any way I can be useful! I shall do my utmost in creating a sculpture to the best of my abilities! Even if it isn’t able to display even a fraction of a Primordial’s magnificence, I must do it! I beg of you!" Felix said all this between spitting blood, coughing, and generally looking paler and paler.

"Just focus on healing for now; we can discuss the sculpture later," Jake said. But he had made a mistake. For between his hands was a miniature sculpture. One Felix saw.

"What could that be you are conjuring?" he asked as he looked at Jake’s mana sculpture intensely.

"Eh, just playing around with sculpture ideas. Nothing you shou—"

Jake didn’t get further than that before Felix prostrated himself on the ground and proclaimed loudly, "The depiction of a Primordial!? I’m so sorry for my arrogance and disrespect! To not be kneeling… I… I swear I will depict it just as shown! Have no doubts; it shall be as perfect as my meager skill allows! I shall—"

Felix didn’t get further before he let out a big cough, spat out a large amount of blood, and passed out again.

Jake and Chris just looked down at the sculptor.

"Is he dead?" Chris asked after a few seconds, when it became clear Felix wasn’t getting back up any time soon.

"No."

"That’s good."

"Yeah."

They stayed there for a few minutes more before Jake just shook his head, took a health potion out of his inventory, and put it down in front of Felix. "Let’s just leave. We can come back another day."

"That’s probably for the best," Chris agreed, undoubtedly wanting to leave himself already. "Is it okay if we split up here? I have to finish some work at the eastern side of town before Hank gets back."

"As I said, do what you want to. You don’t need to tell me everything you do; I don’t own you. So, yeah, see you around. I’m gonna head to the Fort myself.”

As Jake waved goodbye and began walking out of the room, his cloak shimmered and the light around him appeared to refract as his body disappeared. With Expert Stealth activated, coupled with his cloak, he became nearly invisible to both the naked eye and magic.

Chris looked after him in awe, making Jake feel at least a tiny bit awesome. His new cloak was not shit—that was for sure. Because Chris wasn’t looking at him, but only his direction, even when Jake was only ten meters away.

The young man exited after Jake and walked off, drawing quite a bit of attention that Jake thankfully avoided. Chris looked to be deep in thought as he began walking away from the temple. Jake’s words had clearly had an impact.

Jake saw all this through his sphere as he himself stood atop the temple. Everything inside had returned to normal. It had been a nice visit to town, and Jake had seen and learned a lot about it. Having Miranda tell him about how everything was developing and experiencing it himself was entirely different.

Summoning his wings, Jake took to the air to begin flying out of the forest and towards the Fort. Once he’d made it to the outskirts of the forest, he landed and began using One Step Mile to travel even faster. It wouldn’t take him long to reach there at all.

Guess I’ll go talk to Arnold first. It has nothing to do with me not knowing specifically where Hank is.

Felix woke up inside the temple. A splitting headache dominated his senses, but a feeling of elation quickly overtook that.

The first thing he saw was the potion on the ground. Felix instantly knew who it was from, and he picked it up and cradled it. The generosity of the Chosen… a gift… He would make sure to save it. The thought of drinking it didn’t even occur to him for a second.

The sculptor had been lost only a few months ago. He’d had no purpose. Death and flames had scared him beyond anything until the Eternal Servant had offered him another path. One where pain and hurt were but a matter of perspective. Where purpose was found not through personal accomplishments, but through recognition from a higher power—the Primordials.

It was their job to do not just what the Primordials wanted, but also needed. To carry out not only their words, but also understand what was left unsaid and do what would be best for them. This was why Felix understood. The Chosen had not needed to tell him. He had seen the statue the Chosen desired, and he would sculpt it. The form was scorched in his mind.

While it was true the sculpture itself made him confused, who was he to try and truly understand the magnificence of a Primordial? Who but the Chosen who had met the Malefic Viper in person could display it so accurately? Who was he to question it? He was just a simple sculptor.

Felix walked over, and with a wave of his hand, the two sculptures under construction shattered and turned to dust. Even in their half-made forms, it would be unsightly for other statues to be in the presence of a Primordial’s while under construction.

Yet he didn’t begin working right away. Instead, he sat down and meditated. He wanted to get started immediately, but the Chosen had ordered him to recover first. The Chosen said they would talk later, but he didn’t need to waste the Chosen’s time more than necessary.

He swore to himself that he would not leave that room until the sculpture was perfect—and just as the Chosen had shown him.

Chapter 53

Jake the Corpse Merchant

As expected, Jake didn’t take long before he made it to the Fort. On the way, he took note of one thing in particular: He never left the influence of the Pylon. Even when he stealthily entered the outskirts of the Fort, he was still within its range.

The Fort had expanded even more than before. Jake could see why Hank had to be there. If construction in Haven was rapid, the expansion of the Fort was just insane. He knew a lot came from caravans or smaller settlements that chose to integrate themselves, but this was far more than expected.

From what Miranda had told him, one of the major reasons so many came was the lack of regulations yet still-ensured safety. Many other cities had a faction ruling them, and that faction wanted to at least ensure a modicum of loyalty, or at least an assurance a group or a powerful individual wouldn’t work against them.

Miranda had asked if they should do something similar, but to Jake, that wasn’t needed. Sure, there were some basic rules that pretty much just boiled down to: don’t start fights, don’t be an asshole, and if you piss off the leadership of Haven, get the fuck out. If you chose to stay anyway? Well, that luckily hadn’t happened yet. Jake guessed this was where he would possibly have to come in as the owner to take out the trash.

Jake thought it was nice he hadn’t needed to do that yet. Phillip was apparently the guy in charge of security, and considering the man had half a rifle-bearing army already, it made sense. Should he go by and check up on him too? Nah, no need. He was pretty sure Phillip wasn’t a huge fan of Jake anyway.

Having the Fort now considered an actual part of the Pylon’s area after Miranda’s evolution was great news to everyone involved. It would offer the people of the Fort access to all the system-stuff City Lords made possible, and also allow Miranda to get a better handle on all those who lived there.

Sneaking through the outskirts of the settlement, Jake became aware of exactly how much construction was going on. Brick houses were being made by the dozen, and hundreds of workers were visible within his sphere at any one time.

It appeared that Hank had gone for a more normal look for the Fort. Brick houses, stone, and even something that looked a lot like concrete. If Haven was the city of wood, this would be the city of stone. Which, in retrospect, probably included most cities, much like those in the old world.

While Jake enjoyed looking over the city, he still prioritized getting to the central Fort itself.

No one noticed him as he jumped over the walls and into the courtyard that was a wealth of smithing and crafting as usual. The gun production was still going strong, and Jake noticed that the level of the crafters had increased yet again. Maybe some of them had evolved their profession already… If not, they would soon.

Entering the building, Jake saw all three people of note instantly. Arnold was in his workshop as always, while Neil and Hank were in the same meeting room he and Miranda had gone to back when they first came to the Fort. Seeing them all together made everything a lot easier. Being a bit cheeky, Jake marked both Hank and Neil with Mark of the Avaricious Hunter as he went to talk with Arnold—just in case they left.

Jake tried to sneak into Arnold’s workshop but found something odd at the door-entrance. A shimmer of sorts covered it. He could see it both in his sphere and ever so faintly with his eyes. Jake didn’t know what it was exactly, but it didn’t give him any feeling of danger.

Now, Jake did also notice one other thing: a doorbell right beside the door. It took him a few seconds to decide between trying to sneak in and just ringing the damn doorbell, and in the end, he decided on being polite.

In one smooth motion, he rang the doorbell, opened the door, and used One Step Mile to the other side of the room, where he crouched down and focused on the stealth functionality of his cloak and the Expert Stealth skill.

He saw Arnold turn towards the open door, looking confused. He then took a quick look around the room suspiciously. Jake, being childish, tried to sneak up on him as he began moving forward, but at that moment, he felt he’d been detected.

"Ah, you, great to see you back. How did the field test go?" Arnold asked nonchalantly, not even questioning why or how Jake had tried to sneak in. Shit, he didn’t even turn around, but kept tinkering with something on the workbench.

Jake looked up and saw his detector. A floating eyeball-looking machine was suspended from the ceiling, looking straight at him. He had to admit, Arnold was very industrious and had quite a number of different machines…

"It went okay; the grenade exploded with pretty good force," Jake answered, deciding to stop messing around and just get down to business. “Could deal noticeable damage to D-grades around level 130. Not that effective against the variants, though.”

"Hmm, so that hypothesis turned out to be accurate," Arnold said as he wrote down some notes on a tablet-looking device. "How would you compare the intensity of the mana released compared to your usual output?"

"About the same, I guess," Jake said.

He had noted the explosions were roughly the same as his explosive arcane arrows, after all. Considering the spheres were slightly bigger than an arrow, and the arrow was from an epic-rarity skill while the metal grenade was common rarity, that made sense in his head.

Arnold nodded and also noted that down. "I noticed you have a spatial storage. How much energy dissipated before you used them? And how long went between getting them and using them?"

This interview went on for a while. Jake went along with it, as he had kind of agreed to it when he took the metal balls to begin with, and the devices had been helpful. Also, the Nanoblade was nice, and Jake believed that staying in the good graces of Arnold would only be beneficial.

Jake learned that his grenades had been substantially more powerful than the ones left behind for Arnold. Arnold could only cause some minor damage to a D-grade, and it had taken dozens of them along with dozens of other attacks for the man to kill some. Yes, apparently, Arnold had been killing D-grades to test out his stuff. It suddenly made a lot more sense why the man had managed to reach D-grade. His class wasn’t as low a level as Jake had expected.

He badly wanted to see how someone like Arnold fought. Well, he did have a good idea based on all the drones and different robotics around. If he had a class that synergized and allowed him to make better use of all his creations, it would all make a lot more sense.

"The resulting damage was lowered further when a level 41 soldier threw a sphere too," Arnold said when Jake asked him about some of the other field tests he had done with Jake’s arcane grenades. “Quite drastically, I might add. Suggests even consumable items like these have inherent scaling to the level of the user. Quite peculiar how the same item can have such a massive difference in effect just based on who threw it.”

"Do you need more?" Jake asked. He could do a few if it was, but…

"No need. The biggest issue wasn’t the effect, but the leakage of energy and annoyance in handling them. The nature of the mana infused makes it inherently highly unstable and destructive. The leakage also only makes them more unstable but overall less destructive. Yours reduced in effect at a substantially slower pace. May be due to you being the infuser or due to the unique properties of the affinity," Arnold shook his head. “I decided to settle on pure fire-affinity mana instead. Far simpler, and equally, if not more effective in most cases."

That one hurt Jake’s feelings a bit. Had Arnold just told him his arcane affinity was worse than regular fire affinity? Thankfully, he hadn’t done that. Lucky man. If not, Jake would have had to “discipline” him.

"The ones with your mana are more effective within the first thirty-one hours and approximately forty minutes, while after that, the pure fire affinity becomes more effective due to the lack of natural energy leak and decline in power," Arnold said, saving himself from Jake’s untold wrath.

Arcane affinity is still better. Though I wonder, could I do fire magic? Jake thought. He would have to test that out for fun a bit later. He’d figured out dark mana, so he should be able to figure out fire mana. If he had the affinity, that is.

“Anyway, Arnold, I am in search of some new equipment, so I came to you, as you seem to be one of the best crafters. I understand you aren’t a typical craftsman, but I thought to ask anyway, as the Nanoblade is great. So if you have something, I may just have something for you too." Jake said this with a smile, finally turning the conversation to what he had actually come for. He was quite sure Arnold wanted what he was peddling.

"I have some projects that may be useful to you. If adequately compensated, I may trade them away. For the record, I am not in need of Credits. I have sold a few choice items to traders and on the System Store, and have more than adequate funds for now.”

It was as Jake had expected. Thankfully, Jake had something far more valuable than a few Credits.

"Before I show you, be aware that this won’t be a fair trade no matter what,” Jake said, making his caveat clear. “I am certain what I offer has more value.”

Arnold looked skeptical but nodded in agreement.

Jake made a motion, and an odd-looking piece of metal appeared on the ground. It was a head and a torso made of metal. Both of them looked badly battered and had dents and scratches, as well as many signs of Jake’s arcane affinity burned into it. The neck even had what looked like rust from Touch of the Malefic Viper.

Walking closer, Arnold frowned. "What is this?" He knelt down and placed a hand on the torso. His hand emitted some mana, and a pulse seemed to try and go through the corpse of the Altmar Census Golem.

He stayed kneeling for several seconds without moving or saying anything. The frown on his face grew by the second until he finally stopped infusing mana, but didn’t get up.

"This is way beyond me," he said, shaking his head. "Even while inactive, its core is protected, and all my attempts at scanning are completely blocked. I have no way of even researching it beyond the surface without trying to split it apart, and even if I do so, there is a chance it was built with some innate self-destruct features or something similar."

"Doubt it will explode or have any other issues due to where it comes from and how the creators wanted it back. Either way, does that mean you aren’t interested?" Jake asked teasingly. He already knew the answer. He saw the unabated greed in the man’s eyes as he stared at the battered golem.

"Of course I want it. What do you want?" Arnold said without any hesitation. His hand was still caressing the metal. He was already looking towards the head too, but Jake quickly came in and scooped it up.

"Depends on what you have to offer. I need equipment, or any other cool gadgets." Jake tossed the head up and down, taking way more pleasure than he should in Arnold looking nervously at him.

"I have more Nanoblades? Two of them, if you need.”

"I don’t need more than the one I got. Come on, I know you got better stuff.”

"Follow me," he relented as he went over to something that looked like a safe.

Jake noted it had quite a number of magical enchantments to protect anyone from snooping or breaking into it. He wanted to look inside with his sphere but held back, as he wanted the surprise. Besides, Arnold was already explaining as he began opening the safe.

"During my research of the mana inside the metal spheres, I noticed faint traces of stability within the destructive energies. This is what kept it from just blowing up or consuming itself. I attempted to take this stable aspect and increase it to create a tool to somehow make better use of the explosives.

"This proved far more difficult than expected. I couldn’t properly manipulate this energy, but I found a way to isolate and stabilize it. I had a tailor create a pair of gloves from a synthetic material I made using a few choice items from the System Store. A material with a close-to-flawless ability to absorb mana. Most of the ingredients combined to craft the material were uncommon or rare rarity. It was not cheap. I was satisfied with the workmanship, and I even got some worthwhile enchantments, as I wanted to use them myself. They were still returned to me as uncommon rarity. I made more modifications and infused mana from the orbs and an epic-rarity item I had acquired from some travelers. The man claimed to have bought it in the tutorial store. I am not certain about this claim. Anyway, even after it all, there are still major issues. I think it’s best you see them for yourself."

Jake saw him take out a small box. When he opened it, Jake saw a pair of gloves within. They looked thin and made of silk or something like that. Yet he felt a very familiar energy from them. He used Identify and instantly saw the reason why.

[Gloves of Sporadic Manifestation (Rare)] – Gloves made from a powerful synthetic cloth. These gloves are incredibly thin, nearly unnoticeable, and incredibly resilient against all magical attacks. Relatively fragile against physical attacks. These gloves contain a large amount of arcane-affinity energy, but the energy is directionless and cannot properly manifest its properties, yet the arcane energy still manages to amplify the existing enchantments through a powerful catalyst. All mana constructs created with your hands will last for longer due to the inherent power of stability within these gloves, but will become unstable if they come in contact with any other types of energy. Enchantments: +100 Intelligence, +75 Wisdom, +50 Willpower. Sporadic Manifestation.

Requirements: Lvl 105+ in any humanoid race.

He read it over and was impressed. Yet he had one major question.

"Won’t all mana manifestation be useless by default?” Jake asked, a bit confused. “There are other types of energies in the atmosphere all the time.”

"Yeah. That’s the exact issue. The gloves are useless to me, as they are only worth it for the stats, but wearing them would cause too many issues. If you can fix them, you can have them. I will even throw in that if I ever make anything useful based on my research related to that body, you will be the first to benefit. Also, take this with you.” He handed Jake a small stack of papers from within the box the gloves had been in.

Considering Jake had nothing to use the Altmar Census Golem for at all, he saw no reason to refuse the trade. Yet he still kept it cool and frowned at the opposition to make it seem like he was really losing out. It worked.

"…I may also be able to upgrade the Nanoblade…" Arnold said, looking like the offer physically hurt him.

Jake didn’t bother questioning why he was so reluctant, but just smiled. "Deal."

After some good business, Jake even offered to let Arnold watch as he tried to fix the gloves, but got the response that Arnold was "done messing with that unreasonable affinity.” Thus, he just ushered Jake out of the workshop after having him hand over the Nanoblade. What was the deal with the whole questionnaire if the guy didn’t care about Jake’s arcane affinity anymore?

Not wanting to get a headache from trying to understand Arnold, Jake just went on his way. He saw that Hank and Neil had both left the building too. Seeing no reason to track Hank down here and now, as the guy seemed to have headed to another construction site, Jake turned his attention to the new pair of gloves. He went into one of the closed-off meeting rooms in the central building of the Fort, sat down on his butt, and held the gloves in the palms of his hands.

Transmutation time!

Chapter 54

Taking Advantage of Mistakes

It had been a while since the last time he used Touch of the Malefic Viper on an item to transmute it. The last item he had transformed was his bow. Actually, that one could have gone better. Sure, the bow had gotten better overall, but the change from Windsoar Bow to Windsorrow Bow made him feel a bit like a baddie.

Before he began the process, he took out the notes Arnold had made on the gloves and read them over. It was a meticulous list of how they had been crafted. What items had been used, what methods had been applied, and which people had been involved.

Jake skimmed it mainly for fun, but had to stop as he saw the sheer amount of ingredients that had gone into them. Three different types of spider silk, a couple of uncommon- or rare-rarity metals turned to dust and sprinkled in, crystals containing mana, and even a Beastcore from a D-grade beast.

And that was just for the gloves themselves before Arnold really went HAM.

After that, Arnold had infused it with some filtered version of Jake’s arcane mana. To store it, he had made use of an epic-rarity… Oh, shit, it was a Crystalized Essence? An unattuned version? Jake had encountered a Crystalized Essence once before during the Valley of Tusks’ dungeon. It had been the cause of all the Soilwater in that pool, and that one back then had only been rare rarity.

How exactly a big crystal had been merged with those small and thin gloves, Jake didn’t get, but somehow it had.

Jake couldn’t help but think that shit had really been wasted. He didn’t understand how they could only be rare rarity with so many great materials in them. Natural treasures, even. Who the hell would waste a Crystalized Essence on a pair of gloves?

But… was it really all that bad? Because when Jake inspected the gloves and bound them to him, he felt the energy within them. So much untapped potential for him to exploit. So much fuel to burn and transform and bend to his will.

The last time he had met a Crystalized Essence, it had resulted in his Touch of the Malefic Viper upgrading to epic rarity. The first time he encountered massive success with his transmutation, he’d upgraded Touch to ancient rarity.

What was more fitting, then, than using both those experiences to possibly make his best transmutation ever?

He knew the Crystalized Essence was key. It was a powerful natural treasure with the ability to absorb and transform energy. To use one on some gloves was a waste, hence why the effects were wasted. Jake reckoned Arnold had gotten the deal of a lifetime on the Essence, yet he also understood why the man had been so unwilling to part with it.

It hadn’t been cheap to make. However, chances were the man could still salvage them and make them useful down the line, so giving them to Jake like this was a risk. Well, in the end, the machinist had still won out, as the Altmar Census Golem was quite the find.

Jake sat down in the room he had found and, with the assumption that no one would come to bother him, entered meditation and went to work. Thoughtful Meditation activated its effects, making him even more focused than before as he dove in headfirst without any more preparations.

He felt the gloves in his hands. They felt thin and frail to his touch, but when he dove his mind into the connection he had to them, he felt something entirely different. A directionless space of energy was within, a metaphysical crystal floating in the middle. At least, that was how he interpreted it.

It needed direction. Stability.

Arnold had just infused the space with arcane mana and attempted to make the crystal serve as its guide to make it stable. Yet he couldn’t. He had tried to make the Crystalized Essence into that of the arcane affinity, possibly to get a source of arcane energy himself to craft orbs without needing Jake or to keep the spheres fully charged.

The man’s approach had been logical, and even if Jake was a bit annoyed the guy hadn’t told him the truth of why he had made the gloves, he still understood why he had done it. He was even a bit flattered. The man had tried to find a way to replicate Jake’s arcane affinity, but ultimately he’d failed.

Because there was a crucial flaw in his equation. He couldn’t just think of Jake’s affinity like the fire affinity or water affinity, or even more advanced ones like space or time. All of those were natural. Jake’s wasn’t. The only natural occurrence of Jake’s arcane affinity was Jake. He himself was a core component, and without his will, his arcana couldn’t exist.

So when Jake entered the gloves and provided them his arcane energy, they almost hummed in satisfaction. Touch of the Malefic Viper dug in with his arcane affinity as Jake took control of all the energy. His will and power became the maestro of the directionless orchestra of energy, all of which began moving to his will.

The gloves glowed in his hands and crackled with energy. Purple veins coursed through them. These didn’t disappear, as it looked like the gloves had torn, yet thin strings still held them together. They pulsed with energy, but Jake didn’t let up. They could still take far more.

Time kept ticking on as Jake kept up the work. One would think it should be difficult, but it was actually surprisingly smooth. The groundwork had all been laid, the ingredients supplied, and all preparations carefully made. All it took was for Jake to do the legwork and give the entire thing direction. Time-consuming, yes, but not particularly hard. Naturally, he still had to focus throughout it all, but that had never been an issue for Jake.

The process still ended up taking him nearly thirteen hours. He had to chug down three mana potions during the process and a single stamina potion. Jake was tired and sweating, but the result wasn’t anything to complain about as he read the notifications.

*You have successfully transmuted [Gloves of Quintessential Arcane Manifestation (Epic)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 108 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake smiled to himself. Epic rarity. It was as expected, but he was still happy about it. With the materials put into the gloves, them only being rare was a travesty. One he had thankfully corrected, he was able to confirm via Identify.

[Gloves of Quintessential Arcane Manifestation (Epic)] – Gloves made from a powerful synthetic cloth. These gloves are incredibly thin, nearly unnoticeable, and incredibly resilient against all attacks. Will become immensely more durable if infused with arcane energy. The Crystalized Essence has been fully integrated. All constructs using your arcane affinity and your hands will last longer and be more potent. The gloves can store a large amount of arcane energy that can be released immediately. Channeling unattuned energy into these gloves will grant it your arcane affinity. Enchantments: +125 Intelligence, +75 Wisdom, +50 Willpower. Quintessential Arcane Manifestation.

Requirements: Lvl 115+ in any humanoid race. Quasi-Soulbound.

Never before had Jake been so happy that someone else had majorly fucked up when crafting an item. Arnold had tried to make the item Jake just had. But as always, it had the issue of being Quasi-Soulbound, making it useless to anyone but Jake himself.

Jake naturally put them on and took the old ones off. That made him lose 35 Intelligence and the mana blast ability. The 35 Intelligence was replaced with 125, so still a gain of 90—plus, of course, the 75 Wisdom and 50 Willpower. As for the mana blast? Jake could do that shit easily himself by now. The gloves made it easier and a bit more effective, sure, but he doubted these new ones wouldn’t also do that.

Feeling the influx of stats was always nice, and he couldn’t hold himself back from instantly experimenting with the Quintessential Arcane Manifestation part of the gloves. First, Jake summoned an arcane bolt to float above him. He felt it was exactly the same as before, besides the increased potency from his increased stats.

Next, he held out his hand and conjured a mana bolt in it by channeling mana through the gloves. This time, he felt it coalesce a bit faster than before, and upon closer inspection, it even felt a bit more potent and stable. It was just a small amount, but it was there.

After that, Jake got up and summoned an Explosive Arcane Arrow. To his disappointment, he felt that it was the same as before, with the gloves doing nothing. He frowned and tried again. It still failed. He used his hands to do it, and he believed it had to work.

He knew the issue already. He didn’t channel the mana through his gloves at all, not allowing their effect to work. Jake kept trying a few more times but kept failing. He found that the issue was in how the arrow instantly appeared. He couldn’t hold onto anything and channel it. The automatic parts of the skill trumped his own control, and if he had to channel it through the gloves, it would make summoning arrows slower…

Yet he refused to give up. The gloves said it would be all constructs, so what was he missing? Closing his eyes, he considered what he was doing wrong as he held out his hand and summoned arrow after arrow. That was when he got an idea.

Jake drew his bow. Not to shoot anything, but to make it feel right. He moved his hand as if he drew an arrow from the quiver. He imagined feeling the arrow being drawn as he pinched it with his fingers. The skill responded, and one appeared… with the bonus effectiveness from the gloves now working.

He shook his head, not fully comprehending what the issue had been… Was it because he hadn’t summoned it in his hand before as an outgrowth of his hand? It all felt so arbitrary, and quite frankly, Jake didn’t want to waste time on it.

Instead, he kept experimenting with the gloves and tried to get a good estimate of the effectiveness of the enchantment. He concluded the increased effectiveness was small but noticeable. A low single-digits increase, perhaps. It didn’t seem like a lot, but for someone like Jake, every bit counted.

He also tried to channel stamina through the gloves, as it said it would transform any energy into arcane energy. Unfortunately, that one didn’t work as he’d hoped. In the process, he also experimented with channeling mana into the gloves to make them more durable. This was clearly from the stability-focused part of his arcane affinity, and the effect was more than noteworthy.

The gloves became so tough he couldn’t even cut them with his scimitar as long as he kept supplying a stable source of mana. Jake was already imagining dozens of ways this could become useful in the future.

This experimentation went on for hours until Jake was thrown out of his focused state of mind and back to the real world. He had been so engrossed in his practice session he hadn’t noticed the people walking down the hall outside towards the meeting room he was in. He recognized Hank with four other men he didn’t know.

Jake semi-panicked for the moment. Not just because of his presence there, but because of what he had done to the room. He had chosen the room because it was isolated; it sealed in things, including sound and energy.

Now, Jake spending nearly an entire day inside the room hadn’t left any real physical signs… but the atmosphere of the entire room was soaked in his arcane affinity. It was overwhelming. He considered for a moment if he should just leave but decided against it. Instead, he would get his meeting with Hank out of the way.

Miranda had told him long ago to try and keep up the mysterious-defender-of-the-city persona. This could be an opportunity to look imposing in front of some of the new leaders of the Fort. He assumed they were new leaders because he didn’t know any of them, and he remembered all of the leaders back when Phillip had been the top dog around.

Jake sat down in the chair at the end of the table as he waited for Hank and the others to arrive. He did his best to act like the oppressive atmosphere was entirely on purpose and not because he had been flooding the room with arcane mana the majority of a day while practicing.

It only took a few seconds before the door opened.

"I was saying that switching t—"

The man in front abruptly stopped the moment he set foot in the room. His eyes went wide, and his legs began shaking. With fright, he looked at Jake, who sat in his cloak and mask at the end of the table. Jake just hoped he hadn’t scared the man too much.

Jake had definitely scared the poor guy way too much. Hank felt the aura the same time as his companions. The sheer presence of the room. He had felt something similar, if not as intense, when he entered a room Neil or Miranda had an ongoing ritual in. Because of that, he managed to stay relatively calm. The four others didn’t.

The first one shook and took a step back. One of the braver souls pointed at Jake and stammered, "Who… wha… are you?"

The two last men just stood frozen, staring at the ominous-looking cloaked figure at the end of the table. The owner was sure good at looking scary; he had to hand him that. Hank only thanked the heavens he hadn’t also decided to summon his wings.

"Lord Thayne," Hank said, bowing slightly, aware that he had to be as cordial as possible in front of others.

To keep Jake mysterious and feared was beneficial to everyone. One would think the revelation of who the owner was would make him seem less mysterious… but his brother turned out to be the leader of the Court of Shadows. And that was the only available information people knew. Hadn’t exactly hurt Jake’s image.

"That’s…?" one of the men beside him muttered.

"Hank. I came by to ask about updates on the project." Jake jumped in, doing a damn good job at being oppressive. If Hank hadn’t known that Jake could be odd and easygoing, he wasn’t sure he would have managed to stay confident.

"Yes, I planned on coming by for a meeting when I returned to Haven. There are things I need to consult with you on," Hank said, still keeping it as professional as he could. He didn’t want to discuss details with others around… and talking to Jake like this was just weird. It was way more relaxed when it was just him around. Maybe Louise or Miranda being present was fine too.

"Good. Keep up the good work," Jake said as he got up and began walking out of the room. "All of you."

He said the last words as he passed them, and when he was only a few steps down the hall, he teleported to the end. The air around him shimmered, and he disappeared.

Hank looked after him, nodding internally. He had sure come off as mysterious and powerful. He did a quick take of the men with him. Yep, the four of them were scared shitless.

Looking into the room they had planned on using, he muttered, “I guess we’ll need to find another meeting room.”

Chapter 55

Keeping It Friendly

Jake waited outside the building for a few moments as he looked through the Fort using his sphere. Hank and the four others went to another meeting room while Arnold looked busy with Jake’s Nanoblade. Arnold had it suspended in some device and was firing a laser or something on it. Jake wasn’t a craftsman, so he just shook his head and went on his way.

It had been close to a full day since Jake had been back in Haven, and it was approaching evening time. He had a meeting with Miranda planned, and while he could get engrossed in his practice, he hadn’t forgotten it. He would have to come back to the Fort again in a few days, but it was time to head home for now.

The return trip was swift, as Jake didn’t have any other side objectives on the way. He was back in Haven before anyone even knew he had left the Fort—assuming they were aware he had been there to begin with.

When he got close to his valley, he noticed there was activity within. Jake frowned for a moment—until he felt the auras responsible.

The hawks were back.

He had barely managed to get into the valley before a large green projectile hit him in the chest. The projectile turned out to be a squishy bird that nuzzled itself against his shirt.

Jake held the bird and rubbed her head. "Hey there, Sylphie, how have you been?" he asked while hugging her as she playfully squirmed in his grasp.

She screeched in response, telling him it had been all good. While Jake had been grinding alchemy and the dungeon, Sylphie had really entered her growth phase. She had been hunting actively, and coupled with her still-natural growth, she had gained quite a few levels.

[Sylphian Eyas – lvl 83]

It had been around one and a half months since Jake last saw Sylphie, and in that time, she had managed to go from 41 to 83. She had more than doubled it. One had to remember she was only a few months old, and she was nearly already a full-fledged D-grade.

Jake wondered if she would reach D-grade in time for the Treasure Hunt. Sadly, she wouldn’t be able to enter either way on account of being a beast and not a part of the enlightened species. Still, it made Jake happy.

While he hugged and nuzzled the young hawk, he also checked out Hawkie and Mystie. Neither had been slacking during this period. Back then, Hawkie had been 109 and Mystie 116, and now they had both gained a good amount of experience.

[Stormsong Hawk – lvl 120]

[Mystsong Hawk – lvl 126]

While they were slow compared to someone like Jake or Sylphie, the speed was still respectable. Especially considering that they’d protected Sylphie all this time and focused more on her progress than their own. He couldn’t help but chuckle a bit when he imagined the little featherball reaching the same level as her parents.

"You guys doing well too?" Jake asked his bird buddies.

Both of them gave affirming sounds as they also assessed Jake. He saw a small trace of defeat in their eyes upon realizing that he had grown as much, if not more than them.

He kept talking to them a while, having a one-sided conversation as he played with Sylphie. He felt that she was a lot more powerful. It was quite natural, of course, with her leveling so much, but she felt too strong. In fact… she reminded him a bit of himself back then. Jake imagined that if the level 83 Sylphie were put against the level 99 Horde Leader… she would win.

That was when he noticed his weird-ass time tree do something. Jake was a bit annoyed that no one was there to look out for and eat the bananas like he had told Hank, but quickly noticed why. He saw a banana ripen, and at that exact moment, a small magic circle activated. A tendril of myst fired up, wrapped around it, and pulled it down to the ground, where it was covered by some kind of energy. All while staying within the area of the tree.

Jake looked over at Mystie, gaping. "You made an automatic magical banana-retrieval system."

Mystie had once more amazed him. She had put down a magic circle at the base of the tree that Jake hadn’t even noticed when he came back from the dungeon. It was so subtle. It just pulled in the banana and somehow stabilized it until someone came to eat it. Had she saved some for hi—

Sylphie struggled herself free from Jake’s hug and, with impressive speed, zoomed over and scooped up the banana.

"Hey, that’s mi—"

Sylphie gulped it down, peel and all.

"—ne," Jake finished in defeat. Now he at least knew where all his bananas went.

Without any sense of shame, Sylphie flew back and landed on Jake’s shoulder, happy as a clam. She even had the audacity to nuzzle up to him. He could smell the bananas on her. If it were anyone else, Jake would be mad, but who the hell could be mad at Sylphie?

"Good girl," he chuckled as he praised her and petted her head, “but remember to share. Maybe I can make them even better? Make them into some kind of drink that makes the bananas taste even better?"

"Ree!" Sylphie agreed, though Jake had a feeling it would be an uphill battle. She seemed to enjoy bananas a lot, and he didn’t have the heart to actively try and keep her away from them.

I guess it’ll be a competition when she is here, Jake chuckled internally. The birds seemed to want to hang around since Jake was back, and he didn’t complain.

They ended up playing with magic until Miranda came back. Jake fired small arcane attacks, and the birds blocked or deflected them. Jake also blocked their blows as he practiced, and he even had a few games of tag. Hawkie was still damn fast, and Jake needed to predict his movements to have a chance to catch him. In a straight-up chase through the air, Jake would lose every time.

Sylphie was still the weakest, of course, but she had some fun tricks too. Jake called them tricks mainly to make himself feel better about not understanding what the little hawk was doing. He was embarrassed to admit he had no idea what the hell her magic was about.

Clearly, it was wind magic… but not really. It cut like wind and was speedy like wind, yet it seemed to be more. How exactly that was, he couldn’t pinpoint. All he was certain of was that it was powerful and in no way a low-tier concept.

Her offense was noteworthy, but her defense was even more potent. Jake’s powerful yet admittedly playful arcane bolts were sheared away by her green winds, and those she didn’t just blow away failed to have any effect, as she made a green bubble of sorts around herself.

Just as Jake was beginning to think that was all Sylphie had—green wind and a green bubble—she pulled out another attack. One Jake hadn’t seen coming.

He didn’t know why he hadn’t expected it. Maybe it was because of Hawkie and Mystie and how they fought. The small frame of the hawks. Their usual use of magic. All of it had made Jake not expect the hawk to do the most obvious of things—attacking with her body.

Jake felt her fly by first, her wing glowing green. The wing was like a razorblade, and Jake managed to avoid it as it cut through the air, making odd sounds. After a swift turn in the air, she came back with another attack, this time using her talons. Jake was curious and raised his arm to block. He allowed her talons to strike… and the result surprised him.

Both of them, it seemed.

He had to spend the next quarter of an hour consoling Sylphie after she had nearly ripped his forearm off. Her talons had begun shining as she struck and had penetrated straight through the armor on his arms. It had then gone through his skin with only a tiny bit more resistance, drawing plenty of blood. Finally, the talons had clamped down and cut into his arm even more. The only thing she’d failed to cut through was the bone. Even that had some clear marks, though.

It was nothing a healing potion couldn’t fix, but Sylphie still felt incredibly bad about it. She kept making apologetic screeches and nuzzling up to him, throwing glances at his already-healed arm. The skin still looked a bit tender there, and his armor was still repairing itself. Jake was sure she would feel better when all signs of her overeagerness were gone.

As for Mystie and Hawkie? They just sat on the side, looking like the proudest parents in the world.

She seemed to cheer up a bit at Jake’s constant reassurance that all was fine and his praises of how strong she was. He had to admit he had underestimated her. Those close-combat attacks were powerful. He couldn’t help but imagine how strong she would be at level 100. What tier was she in? The same as the Prima? Above it? Census Golem level? He couldn’t be sure.

Sylphie was still rather fragile if one did manage to strike her. Her small frame also made her susceptible to many of the same attacks that took down Hawkie. Her means of attack also weren’t that varied, but things like that could be shored up with time.

Shortly after, Mystie and Hawkie wanted to take Sylphie along, likely to continue hunting, but the small hawk refused to leave. She kept nuzzling up to Jake, and when her mom gave a stern screech, she just tried to hide away under Jake’s cloak.

"It’s fine; I’ll keep her company. You two go have some quality time together," Jake said with a smile. He could be the babysitter of the little murder bird while the husband and wife hawks enjoyed a nice date killing stuff together. He was such a romantic.

Jake and Sylphie kept playing—no fighting this time—until evening arrived.

Miranda had picked out the best she could find for dinner. She was afraid she had brought too much, but it should be fine. Even if there were some leftovers, she could just take them back with her or give them to someone else.

She entered the valley with a smile on her face. She didn’t carry anything, as she had gotten quite the upgrade since last time. A ring on her finger held a small spatial storage of about twenty-seven cubic meters. It even appeared to freeze time for everything within. At least, it kept the food hot. The ring had come from Neil trading it with one of his space mage buddies, and she could only wear it now that she was a D-grade due to the level 100 requirement.

In the distance, she could already hear Jake. It sounded like he was doing some kind of practice, as she heard the sounds of things flying around. Telekinesis practice? She still remembered the first time she’d seen him lifting those stones at the pond.

Yet what she saw instead was the smaller of the hawks shooting small bolts of semi-transparent green mana at stones that Jake threw up into the air. He cheered every time the bird hit one and turned it into dust, with the hawk happily flapping its wings.

She had to admit, she didn’t know much about the hawks. The two adults were both D-grade and more powerful than her, and she couldn’t really "communicate" with them like Jake. How the hell he could hold a borderline conversation with them was still insane to her.

Though she had to admit, the small green one was quite cute. Jake also clearly liked it a lot. A feeling that was clearly reciprocated, as she rubbed up against his hand as he scratched her.

Jake turned around as Miranda got closer. He greeted her with a smile, his mask already made invisible. “Oh, hey, Miranda, I—" He paused and did a double-take before shaking his head and smiling further. "Congratulations on your evolution.”

"Thanks," she answered happily, wondering about the holdup earlier.

Maybe Jake was a bit surprised by her evolution? Thinking about it, she probably was the first person Jake regularly interacted with who he had seen evolve.

"So… should we go in and eat? And is it fine if Sylphie comes along?" he asked, looking a bit embarrassed. Without a doubt, due to wanting the bird to join them.

Miranda naturally agreed, and they headed inside the lodge. There was plenty to talk about.

Jake walked inside with Sylphie, a bit flustered. He knew evolutions could bring changes… but he hadn’t really thought about it much. He had seen Arnold before and after evolution, and that guy had barely changed. He himself had barely changed. Jacob had always looked good, so his evolution hadn’t done much. And while Miranda had been nice in her own right, the evolution had sure done a lot.

He honestly felt shitty about it… He had always been bad around overly attractive women. Jake had even struggled with talking properly to Caroline. Miranda had been attractive before, sure, but now she had moved up a level. If it were in a larger social setting, Jake would be fine, but right now, he was alone with only her and a bird. But… it was just Miranda, right?

Yeah. Jake shook his head as he got inside, Sylphie looking up at him, a bit puzzled. He gave her small head a pat as he went to find some cutlery and plates. Honestly, feeling weird around women… wasn’t it about time for him to get over that?

Miranda was Miranda. The same person, just slightly "improved," if that was even the right word. Probably missing a few organs now, too, just like him. Really, his complex was just silly. Jake had many issues in the past. He still did. But now that the world had changed, he had thrown off so many burdens. So many parts of himself that he perceived as his own weaknesses.

Evolution was meant to push you towards perfection. At least physically. The mental work, Jake would have to do himself. He recognized it as a flaw and chose to see it as another challenge to overcome. He would do his utmost to have a nice dinner with Miranda and get through the meeting without acting weird. A part of him thought it was lucky Sylphie was there to help distract him and keep the atmosphere a bit more relaxed. Moreover, he was Miranda’s boss as well. He had a responsibility to act appropriately. But more than that, he was her friend. So he would keep it friendly.

Just keep things simple… and take the complications as they come, he reminded himself as he set the table and threw Miranda his usual smile. Stop treating people differently based on how they look. In the end, everyone’s kill notifications look the same anyway.

"So, tell me about that profession upgrade."

Chapter 56

Introspection & Self-Control

When Jake had asked if the hawk called Sylphie could join them, Miranda had naturally just agreed. Why would she not? It looked cute, and it could sit and listen in when they talked. However… she hadn’t expected it to also eat with them. Alright, even if it would eat with them, it would just get some meat or something and sit off to the side. That would make sense to her. The current situation didn’t.

Jake cut off a slice of meat and ate it, having nice table manners. Miranda did the same, as she used her cutlery. The hawk too.

A third plate was at the table, and in front of it, a hawk sat on its butt. The cutlery was glowing green as it imitated her and Jake, cutting off small slices of meat and bringing them to its open beak. The hawk even made chewing movements, despite Miranda being absolutely certain birds didn’t need to chew food.

Well, by now, Miranda knew she should really just call the hawk “she”… Jake talked to her like a person, and the hawk did act remarkably human. Miranda just had difficulty wrapping her mind around an animal being as smart as a person.

Besides the presence of the small hawk acting weird, everything was relatively normal. They talked about quite a few things, one of which was classes.

"I still find the concept of witchcraft interesting," Jake had muttered in between bites after Miranda had explained some more details about her current class. “I wonder how it allows you to attack through marking a target… I see possibilities there.”

She still hadn’t evolved her class yet at level 100, so she wanted some advice. Jake’s advice ended up boiling down to "pick what you like the most, and just go with your gut," which wasn’t the most useful.

Sylphie had just made a screech, which Jake had interpreted as her agreeing. How the hell he got that from a screech, she didn’t know. Miranda was fifty-fifty on him just fucking with her, but the hawk didn’t protest either, and clearly she understood their speech to some extent. At least, Sylphie could pass the salt when asked…

"With the Fort expanding, it won’t be long before we reach six digits," Miranda said proudly, talking about the citizens. "After the Pylon’s influence encompassed the Fort, the vast majority of the people there automatically became recognized as citizens."

"I’ve been wondering, what are the benefits of more citizens? Does it make you level faster?" Jake asked.

"Only partly. It appears to be based on how much work I do as a City Lord. In the end, I only have that much time and energy to work, and as we expand, help becomes required. From what I know, Sanctdomo has an entire government structure set up by now, with the Augur only working as the leader of a cabinet of leaders. It’s a far more efficient system and recognized as a correct path, but that doesn’t make it more correct than being a City Lord leading a smaller city more intimately. The levels of the citizens only appear to have an impact on growth."

She left out one thing, though… She also got levels by engaging with Jake. A part of the reason she wanted these meetings with him was that she nearly always got a level during them. Clearly, the system believed her interactions with Jake to be a crucial path of her role as City Lord. Based on her new profession, that had only become more important.

"Interesting…” Jake commented, nodding as if deep in thought. “I guess it makes sense. It’s like leveling through killing. Singular, powerful citizens under your employ will be viewed as equally valuable to dozens of weaker individuals, I reckon."

"I’m not quite sure it’s that simple. It depends on how much work I have to do. It’s about what issues I resolve or prevent. Or when I make good diplomatic decisions or create valuable relations with someone important. Even appointing employees who do a good job rewards me. Me dealing with a level 40 troublemaker will reward me more than a D-grade who just sticks to himself and doesn’t bother anyone.” She was leaving out that, according to the system, Jake was likely the largest potential source of trouble for Haven. Or perhaps just the most important element to handle.

"That sounds complicated… I’ll just stick to putting arrows in things," Jake joked, making Miranda giggle a bit.

Jake did seem a bit different today. More confident. A bit awkward as usual to begin with, but the dungeon and time away seemed to have done him good.

"You do that; then I’ll handle all those issues you can’t just fix with an arrow," she answered with a smile.

"There is no issue that cannot be solved with oil, duct tape, and arrows," Jake stated matter-of-factly.

Miranda’s smile only deepened as she shook her head. As much as she hated to admit it… Jake honestly could fix most issues with an arrow, or at least the threat of an arrow. And those he couldn’t… it was her responsibility to try and make sure those issues never even reached him.

"I’ll drink to that," Miranda agreed as she lifted her glass. Jake mirrored her movement, lifting his too.

"Cheers!" both Jake and Miranda said.

"Reee!" Sylphie joined in as she also lifted her glass, which naturally didn’t have wine.

Jake had made it very clear Sylphie was still too young to drink alcohol… no matter how nonsensical that statement was. She was a magical creature that in no way could get drunk from regular alcohol. Also, what did her age have to do with being able to drink as a goddamn bird? Birds were never meant to drink to begin with, as far as she knew. It was one of those things that she had just given up asking about. She had learned her lesson long ago, and yet Jake kept surprising her with his incomprehensible logic of—

’DING!’ Profession: [Mistress of Haven] has reached level 101 - Stat points allocated, +59 Free Points*

The notification stopped Miranda’s train of thought, and she just took a large gulp of her wine. Yeah, this is normal.

Like that, the dinner between two humans and a hawk continued.

To Jake, this evening was a great display of him keeping it cool and casual. At least, it was to begin with. After half an hour or so, he kind of just got in the groove of things, and everything returned to how it usually was.

While they sat there, he had a lot of time to reflect. The concept of him being afraid of the opposite sex grew more ludicrous the more he thought about it. But he understood why he had been.

For nearly his entire life, Jake hadn’t been a very emotional person. He’d never worn his emotions on his sleeves, preferring to keep them bottled up in solitude. Granted, he wasn’t the best at hiding them either, which led to many awkward situations.

He had never pursued anyone himself. Yet, he’d never had any resistance either when he was pursued. He’d had his first girlfriend back when he was a teenager, and that had only lasted for a few months, as Jake was “boring.” Which was probably very accurate. He was boring… and he was bored.

Honestly, before the tutorial began, he couldn’t remember the last time he’d truly had fun. Sure, he’d had enjoyable times, but if he was genuine with himself, the last half a year or so were the best in living memory. Of course, there had been hard times and difficulties, but all in all, everything had finally become… interesting.

The Minotaur Mindchief had wandered through his memories. Jake had wandered with it and experienced the mundanity that had been his life. Everything was black and white. Monotone. There was no color, nothing that truly interested him or made him happy. He now realized the reason for that had been simple… It was his own doing.

His Bloodline had always been with him. It had awakened on the first day of the tutorial… but that wasn’t the first time it had become fully active. His mom and dad had told him he was such a wild child. He’d been quiet as a baby, but when he became a toddler, he’d always had to push the limits. Climb trees, get in fights, and all that.

It was him pushing himself. Challenging himself. All of that had been fine and dandy… until Caleb was born. Caleb had been afraid of Jake. As his brother, Jake had had a natural sense of competition with his little brother, and without being aware, he had utterly tried to suppress Caleb with his presence back then. It had been childish and stupid, and all it led to was Caleb always crying. Always afraid.

Yet Jake also wanted to protect his brother—because while there was a rivalry, there was also a sense of family. So, in the end, Jake had begun subconsciously suppressing his Bloodline. Suppressing his emotions and his real self. Perhaps even then, his supernatural intuition had also made him aware of the truth: This was not the world for the Primal Hunter. The Bloodline was more trouble than good.

Until the tutorial, that is. When it awakened again.

This related back to his inability to interact with women he found attractive. Because it could lead to emotions. Emotions would lead to interest. Interest would lead to disappointment. Disappointment would lead to failure. And finally, failure could lead to anger.

Jake had never broken up with anyone. Every time, they’d broken up with him. Even Madeline had agreed that the honeymoon phase was amazing until Jake began getting boring. Most relationships had been duds from the start, lasting only a few months tops. Only Madeline from university had lasted over a year, and she was the first person Jake had taken a genuine interest in even after the first few months.

But… being emotional was still not something he could really do. It had led to her disappointment in the end. He didn’t know how to act. Jake had to admit that most relationships were just ones of convenience. Whenever a woman or girl came onto him, he had no real reasons not to engage. So when he’d been betrayed by the first one he actually cared about, he’d done what he had to do to protect himself.

This was why he had been actively avoiding potentially similar situations since back in university. It was just easier. If he didn’t let anyone in, they couldn’t hurt him. It was a simple solution, and Jake truthfully never had any need for romantic companionship.

Now that his Bloodline was fully awakened, everything wasn’t gray and dull anymore. He also noted how his attraction to Caroline had faded nearly instantly. She just wasn’t interesting anymore. In the end, he’d only ever found her attractive… but that was that.

It was just lust. A purely instinctual thing that Jake had learned to control a lot better than most, he reckoned. Even with a suppressed Bloodline, he had still had above-average instincts. But just because he was attracted to someone didn’t mean it would lead to something. He had gone through puberty with improved instincts without any incidents. That should be proof enough.

A part of him was fully aware that if he stopped controlling himself, he would turn into someone he didn’t want to be. Some people didn’t restrain or control themselves in this new world, and that led to fucked-up individuals. It led to people like Donald. Jake would rather put a dagger through his own throat than end up like that fucker just because he couldn’t keep his dick in his pants.

He was strong now. If he had walked in on Andy and Madeline as he was now, he would likely have broken Andy’s nose and told Madeline to fuck off without breaking down. He wouldn’t wallow in self-pity for years and drown himself in work. It had been the best choice back then—both for himself, Madeline, and Andy.

Because Jake had felt something when he walked in on them. Rage. Before the system, that had likely been the time his Bloodline was closest to reawakening. He’d wanted to get revenge when he saw them in that bed. The reason he’d just walked out was to control himself. Because if he had stayed… well, he would have killed both of them. No two ways about it. His only response back then had been to avoid the situation. To hide and keep all his emotions bottled up. It was pathetic and cowardly, but that was how he had learned to handle life.

But it was all different now. Jake had grown a lot. At least, he thought so himself. Maybe the increased stats made memories more vivid and sped up brain functions and all that, but reflecting on himself as a person had become a lot “easier,” if that made sense.

And right now, he was growing further, as he managed to act completely normal with a woman he found attractive. If it had been Caroline back then, he couldn’t have done it. He would’ve been awkward and unable to think straight.

All of this wasn’t to say Jake liked Miranda. Well, he liked her, but he didn’t like her. He was attracted to her, sure, but that wasn’t the same. He had been attracted to Caroline too, and she turned out to be a shit-tier person. A guy finding a woman attractive was pretty damn normal, to begin with, and with evolutions making everyone into supermodels… yeah. If he couldn’t act normal around women he found attractive, he soon wouldn’t be able to be around anyone of the opposite sex.

He liked Miranda as a person and a colleague. Jake truthfully wasn’t interested in a relationship. Not right now. He was still D-grade, and he had a long way ahead of him. A relationship would chain him down and create another weakness for him. He saw no reason to invite that into his life. Besides, he liked the dynamic he and Miranda had going on.

She was the brains of the operation, and he was the brawn. They were partners—even if, for all intents and purposes, Jake was in the superior position. He held all the power. But he could handle it.

Jake was confident that he was a person who wouldn’t find himself corrupted by power… because he had always been powerful. He had always suppressed himself. There were no two ways about it; Jake had been born superior to other humans. He had been forced to bury that superior aspect of himself to fit in and survive. Now, he just didn’t need to do that as much anymore. But that didn’t mean he didn’t have the practice. He could see others failing at this. Being corrupted by sudden power. Becoming more Donalds out there.

They would be wise not to visit Haven.

The man saw the city in the distance. It was an old, medieval-looking building surrounded by houses. The man smiled, as he had found his destination. He turned to his followers and said, "Looks like we’ve found Haven."

He looked at one of the women with him and gave her a pat on the head. "Good girl."

She nodded and smiled. None of the three others with the man said anything either. They knew not to speak, for such was one of their rules.

The man took out his notebook, and a pen appeared in his hand. He turned to one of the pages and in it made a star. He heard the muffled groan of the woman who was in charge of scouting as she got her star. She had done well; it was only fair to reward her efforts.

"Now show your appreciation," he said as he moved the cloth from her shoulder, revealing the star seared into her flesh and admiring his mark.

"Thank you, Sultan," she said with a bowed head and a meek voice.

"You’re welcome," Sultan said, his smile widening. "Now, let us go forth. To Haven."

The five moved towards what they thought was Haven.

Their mode of transportation was a nearly ten-meter long ship that levitated a few meters above the ground. One lined with gold and jewels.

Inside the ship were plenty of goods—and on top of it, a man and four women.

All five of them D-grade.

Chapter 57

Sultan

"Based on current estimates, Haven should enter the Treasure Hunt with eight to ten D-grades,” Miranda said, giving Jake an overview on their plans for the Treasure Hunt. “Neil and his party make five, then, of course, you, Phillip, and myself. I have no idea if Arnold will participate, and Phillip can’t get a straight answer from him either. I guess even he doesn’t know."

There were a few other potential prospects, hence the eight to ten, but it was rocky at best. If they could bring the hawks, it would be great, but sadly the system didn’t allow them to. Thinking about it, if beasts could enter, humanity would just be screwed. Jake was certain beasts existed within the forest that he couldn’t handle. And even if he could, he doubted there were more than a dozen on Earth who stood a chance. Something like the Prima could roll over most of Earth’s "elites."

"Arnold isn’t simple at all," Jake explained. “I reckon all those drones aren’t for show, and he has quite a few tricks up his sleeves. The dude is a damn solid craftsman, and he isn’t afraid of taking risks. He even made my new gloves for the most part and is working on my sword.”

"Yeah, he’s most certainly… Wait a second," Miranda said as she put up a finger. Her frown grew with every passing second until she looked back at Jake. "The Fort just had visitors. A group of five D-grades. Lillian sent a message, and they may need assistance. There aren’t any issues yet, and while Neil and Arnold are there, Phillip is not feeling too safe about it. They haven’t engaged yet, and they are stopped in some vehicle outside of the city. Phillip is approaching."

Jake frowned. He had just come from the Fort, and now they were being visited by a bunch of D-grades. "Well, let’s go," he said as he got up.

Sylphie also got up with them, and Jake saw no reason against allowing her to come along. Besides, he doubted he could stop her from just following them in secret.

Outside the Fort, a levitating ship sat docked as a man on its deck drank tea. The four women also stood tentatively off to the side, waiting. Finally, a person came to the ship not long after and was invited up.

It was Phillip, and to be perfectly honest, he hated his job at that moment. He was sweating a bit at the auras of five goddamn D-grades. It was worse than when he’d gone to visit Arnold, and just damn stressful to deal with them, as he didn’t know their purpose. For all he knew, they could be there to kill him and claim the city. At least he had already gotten the message that Lord Thayne and Miranda were on their way. So all he needed to do was buy time and hopefully not piss off whoever was on the ship.

Getting up on the ship, he saw how truly lavish it was. The entire ship was wooden with jeweled decorations. In the middle sat the man Phillip assumed to be the owner of the ship. He was a man who appeared to be in his late thirties to early forties, and in what looked like a nice gray tuxedo from before the system.

The man looked at Phillip as he got up on the deck and opened his arms in welcome. "Come, join me at the table. Oh, and do tell me—this is Haven, is it not?" His tone was friendly and welcoming. He turned to one of the women to the side. "If you would, dear."

She moved over and prepared a cup of tea as Phillip took a seat. He knew he was utterly outmatched, so it was better to just play nice. It was a bit weird to have a D-grade pour tea for him, though.

"Thank you," the man said as he nodded to her again.

She took a step back, giving them some space. Yet she was still close enough to move in if anything happened. Phillip had a hard time getting a read on the situation. It was very clear that the man was in charge, though.

"I guess this is technically Haven," Phillip answered. "I’m Phillip, the man who tends to take care of this part of the settlement. May I know your name and your purpose for coming?"

The man looked at Phillip, and he felt a shiver run down his back.

"I go by Sultan. I am a merchant, and I have come here to speak not with you, but the leader of Haven.”

"So you’re here just t—"

"Phillip, please," Sultan answered, holding up his hand. "Drink your tea and wait with me. The important details are for Mr. Thayne and me to discuss. He is coming here, no doubt? I sense your impatience. There is no need; I do not come to cause trouble."

Phillip opened his mouth but decided not to say anything. Instead, he just sat back and tried to relax. To be polite, he even took a sip of tea.

He hated to admit that it was exquisite.

Floating ship. Now that was fancy.

Jake got a brief briefing from Miranda about what was going on and headed off first by himself. Miranda and Sylphie would follow, but they were quite a bit slower than him. For the record, Sylphie was faster than Miranda, but was still slow compared to someone like Jake or Hawkie. Over long distances, Jake would leave even Hawkie in the dust due to One Step Mile.

When he got close, he once more took to the air to see where his goal was. It didn’t take long, as there was already a lot of growing intrigue around the area. Jake even saw a few drones checking it out. The ship wasn’t exactly small, either, so spotting it wasn’t difficult.

He began flying over, and halfway there he was noticed. A woman on the deck looked in his direction and made the man who was sipping tea with Phillip aware they had a visitor. A dozen seconds later, Jake landed.

"Welcome," the man said with a bow as he stood up. "You must be the Lord of Haven. Lord Thayne, correct?"

"Sure. Who’re you, and who are they?" Jake answered as he walked towards the man, also motioning towards the man’s companions.

He felt the four women tense up, but the man threw them all a glance, making them back down. Jake also took this chance to Identify all of them as he waited for the man to respond.

[Human – lvl 113]

"I am Sultan, a proud merchant, and these are my bodyguards of sorts. It’s a long story." Sultan gave a smile and waved it off.

Jake was a bit surprised at his level. 113 was not simple. Not at all. It likely meant that both his class and profession were up there. The four women, on the other hand, were a bit easier to get a grasp on.

[Human – lvl 101]

[Human – lvl 101]

[Human – lvl 100]

[Human – lvl 102]

All of them had only barely reached D-grade. Jake also got a distinct feeling none of them had achieved the Perfect Evolution. Meanwhile, he was absolutely certain Sultan had.

"A merchant, eh? So you’re here to peddle your stuff? Quite the unnecessary entrance for that." Jake shook his head.

"Ah, quite the contrary. Now, all know that Sultan is here. Do you not see the crowd gather? The fascination of the masses? Alas, I am not here for them, but you." Sultan walked closer to Jake.

"Why?" Jake asked, looking down at the man, who met his gaze.

They stared into each other’s eyes before Sultan looked away and said, "Truly, I have not gone wrong… I come to offer my services to you. I seek trade as much as I seek valuable relations. And who is more valuable than you?” He turned back to Jake. "A Primordial’s Chosen. Progenitor. Possibly the strongest man on Earth. For someone like me, who seeks out all of that which has value, tell me, what is more valuable than you?"

Jake stared at the man. He frowned before saying, "Phillip. Get out of here."

Phillip looked confused at everything that was happening, but didn’t have to be asked twice to leave. He had just been sitting there awkwardly from the beginning, and now he happily jumped down from the ship with a brief nod.

Sultan, without any prompt, waved his hand to summon a disc of metal. He poured some mana in, and a bubble appeared around the entire ship, isolating Jake, Sultan, and the four women. Jake felt that it was a one-way barrier. As in, he could leave, but nobody could enter. A basic privacy barrier.

"So I’m right," Sultan said, a huge smile on his lips.

That was when Jake realized… the man didn’t actually know about him. At least, he didn’t know it was truly him. But the reaction to his question confirmed it to Sultan, making Jake frown. He wanted to ask how he knew, but Sultan answered without being asked.

"Like many others, I have been granted divine patronage," Sultan explained casually. “The gods chat, you know? They are aware that the Malefic Viper has returned, and there are even rumors he has a Chosen. One who is a Progenitor and from the newly integrated universe. One who is even on a planet with an Augur blessed by the Holy Mother. This naturally makes many wonder if some conflict could potentially arise from that. It just took putting two and two together from there.”

"Good for you," Jake said. He didn’t really care that he knew. It wasn’t some grand secret that he was blessed or a Progenitor. It really shouldn’t be that hard to put things together. There was one thing bothering him, though. "I didn’t see you at the World Congress."

"Because I didn’t attend. I was preoccupied at the time. Besides, I prefer to stay unbound. Ah, but that doesn’t mean I am not open to a partnership. I have many things to offer you, and I am sure you have plenty to offer me too." Sultan went over to the table and sat down, adding, "Please, join me for tea.”

The man waved at one of the women, and she went into the small cabin of the ship. To prepare a new pot of tea, Jake reckoned. He saw no reason not to join him, as his dinner had been interrupted anyway.

"You call yourself a merchant. What wares do you sell?" Jake asked as he sat down.

"Whatever valuables I come across. Herbs, ores, weapons, armor—whatever I believe I can make a substantial profit on, I will peddle. Please, you are more than welcome to browse later on. I am sure there are things that may interest you.”

"I guess I’ll see," Jake said, then turned to a question many likely wouldn’t answer. "How did you reach your current level so fast? D-grades aren’t that common yet, and you waltz in here with a party of five."

"A lack of rest and a willingness to do what I deem necessary. I got a good start as I went through the usual cycle. Lucky Challenge Dungeon in the tutorial got me a powerful class, while my own old-world experience proved useful when it came to my profession.”

As he finished, the door to the cabin opened again, and a woman walked out with a tray. It had two teapots on it and two new cups. Jake instantly felt something was off with the teapots. He felt the herbs within, but in one of them, he also felt something else. Poison. Jake frowned, but before he could say anything, Sultan addressed it.

"Please do not think me a moron. To attempt to poison the Chosen of the Malefic Viper sounds like the stupidest and most pointless thing one can do. I had my dear bodyguard here add some poison to it, as I know those of your particular brand of alchemy tend to enjoy that. You are an alchemist, right? I saw the potions on the System Store and determined they had to be from an alchemist way ahead of the curve.” He gave a small laugh.

That… was honestly reasonable. Palate wasn’t some grand secret, but likely the most famous skill related to the Malefic Viper.

The woman poured from the poisoned pot into Jake’s glass, then took the other teapot to pour into the other new cup. But Sultan stopped her.

"No, dear, just use my current cup—that one is for you," he said with a kind smile, referring to the second clean cup.

For a moment, Jake thought it was just a nice gesture to have her join them, but he saw her face pale a little, even if her facial expression barely changed. After she was done pouring Sultan’s tea, he motioned for her to pour for herself too—from the poisoned pot.

With slight hesitation, but no complaints, she did it. Jake wondered what it was about… Did she have some immunity skill too? He was under the impression skills like Palate were rare…

"Now, let us drink," Sultan said as he raised his cup.

Jake did the same and took a sip. Damn. The tea was seriously delicious, and the poison within was also interesting. It was undetectable to anyone but someone like him with a skill specifically to sense it, and it was damn potent. About as potent as his best common-rarity poisons, even. It did come with the requirement of the target having to consume it without resisting for the effect to take hold and activate, however. This type, compared to his poisons, was far more suited for… assassination. Wait.

The woman who had consumed her entire cup of tea in one gulp began sweating and shaking. Jake looked over to see her collapse to one knee. She began coughing out blood, and dark veins appeared on her face. Tears of blood dripped from her eyes as she heaved for breath. From the look of it, she was in immense pain.

What the fuck is going on? Jake very reasonably asked himself.

"Don’t worry—it won’t kill her, just hurt her a little," Sultan explained nonchalantly, looking over at Jake. "I would prefer to talk about the upcoming Treasure Hunt and about me possibly working with someone to access your System Store, but I reckon you have questions?"

"What’s up with that?" Jake asked, referring to the woman. He was seriously considering if he should hand her a healing potion… but… she had willingly consumed the poison?

"As I said, a long story. But I shall give a bit of background," Sultan said with slight resignation as he began his lengthy explanation. "She went by Gabi, and was a talented young alchemist and healer. A nature healer, even. She was powerful for her level and excelled in all areas. Thus, her level skyrocketed. Gabi went to Sanctdomo after the tutorials, and there she signed up at their party-finding offices and found comrades. She did great and kept progressing, yet she had a peculiar issue: Her parties kept dying. Odd coincidence, was it not? So thought others. She was found to slowly poison her party members and then kill them when they got too weak. Her class and profession ended up both revolving around this. She thought herself clever, but did not know she was already under suspicion. In the end, she was found out and put in prison in Sanctdomo. But… Gabi was too valuable. Sanctdomo does not like killing those who have potential; she was only punished because she caused more harm than good. She was made to simply work as an alchemist in perpetuity to create potions. That is when I came along and offered a deal. I needed another bodyguard, and they needed to be rid of her. So, they sold her as a prisoner of war of sorts. And now… now she serves me and is bound to my will till the day she deserves freedom again."

Jake sat there, taking it in, not entirely sure if the man was spewing bullshit or telling the truth. There was one part of it he was rather sure about, though.

"So, she’s a slave?" Jake asked curtly.

"Not the word I would use, but effectively, yes. That is her punishment for her crimes. It was either death or servitude, and she wanted to live. I also believe she has more worth alive than dead.”

"And the three others?"

"All have similar stories, some worse than others," Sultan stated, his demeanor still unchanged. “They are the scum of this new world who deserve no mercy.”

"And they all just happen to be women?" Jake asked, pointing out the obvious.

"Well, yes. Ah, but don’t misunderstand, that is not a fetish of mine. I prefer a willing participant. I am a merchant; I could just pay for a professional in any of the larger cities if that was what I was after. No, I keep them around solely for my own sense of vanity and childish fantasies while naturally also needing powerful bodyguards.” He said all this without a trace of shame.

"The torture?"

"Ah, that one is easy. I am also a narcissistic sadist who enjoys inflicting suffering upon those I believe deserve it, and I find it incredibly entertaining and ironic to torture them in similar ways to their crimes.” The merchant gave a big laugh before turning serious. "There is no reason to pity those undeserving of mercy."

The woman named Gabi was still cramped over on the floor, moaning in pain and coughing out blood throughout this entire conversation. The other three women were just looking down at the deck.

Chapter 58

"I don't like you." - Jake Thayne, Year 1, 93rd Era

Sultan was relaxed and confident as he studied the masked Chosen of the Malefic Viper. A powerful man worth working with. He had done his research before coming and believed he had an understanding of the man.

As a Chosen, he would naturally be a reflection of his Patron, so with the limited information on the Progenitor himself, he instead studied his god and the Order his god was in charge of. He studied customs and the ethos of the Order. Their logos and foundational pathos—or lack thereof. Instead, there seemed to be a focus on each being taking charge of their own destiny, with morals judged based on how powerful a person was. To do harm upon those weaker than yourself was no sin, but a right. For Sultan to find a worthy partner that was compatible with him in this new world would be difficult, but he believed the Chosen would be his best shot.

Going into it with honesty would no doubt be the best strategy. Lies would eventually be picked apart, and half-truths would only serve to offend the Viper’s Chosen. The Viper was known as a straightforward kind of god, and his Order also valued not beating around the bush.

Sultan was a bit surprised at the questioning of slavery. To his knowledge, that was commonplace in the Order. For the Chosen not to have a few slaves—or at least slave-like servants—would be ludicrous. Thus, he would put all his cards on the table and negotiate from there. If nothing else, he was sure the Chosen would prioritize benefits over a slight disagreement.

Though that should not even be a concern. As far as Sultan knew, the Order of the Malefic Viper had quite the number of sadists, and would their Chosen not be the worst of them all? Nevertheless, Sultan reckoned he enjoyed the show.

Because Sultan knew he did.

Jake looked down at the woman and back at Sultan. At the moment, he was fifty-fifty in his head as to whether he should believe the guy. There was some evidence to his claims, though.

The kind of poison Jake had consumed wasn’t easy to make. Far from it. It would take a lot of practice to learn and a lot of time. Of course, it was entirely possible Sultan had made her learn to concoct it for other means, which was why he placed it as a fifty-fifty kind of thing. Also, his lie would be easily disproved just by checking in with Sanctdomo. Someone who was either close to D-grade or actually in D-grade already had to have left some records.

So, let’s say the story was true. Fuck Gabi. Jake would have killed her, but he also understood that imprisonment or even slavery was preferable to that for some people. Not to Jake, though.

Ultimately, Jake chose to assume the man had been honest—not because he thought him particularly trustworthy, but because it was the easiest thing to do for now. He had nothing to lose from doing so, and he would always take another, more lethal approach if the man proved to be a liar.

But… there was one thing.

Jake looked straight at Sultan, meeting his eyes as he said, "I don’t like you."

If the man wanted an honest conversation… Jake would be honest.

"And I don’t mean that I dislike you a little. I mean that I am contemplating if I should just kill you or continue listening to what may or may not be bullshit. But I’ll humor you for now. Let me make it clear: I don’t like slavery. I know, shocking. So what reason will you give me for not ending you right here and now? What purpose do you see in keeping slaves? Why not just kill them and be done with it? Are you so weak you need to force a bunch of slaves to protect you?”

Sultan looked at Jake, clearly a bit shocked at his response. It was the first time he’d showed bewilderment, as if Jake’s reaction wasn’t at all what he had expected. Jake was genuinely curious what the man’s arguments would be.

"That… was not at all the expected response. I appear to have made some serious miscalculations," Sultan said, taking out a potion bottle and handing it to the woman.

She instantly grasped it and drank, and shortly after, she calmed down and began breathing steadily. She backed off and gave Jake a weird look as she joined the other three women.

"For some reason, I was under the impression you would enjoy that. Is my information on the Order of the Malefic Viper and the Primordial himself that inaccurate?" It wasn’t a rhetorical question.

"I’m not a part of the Order, at least not officially, and I am not the Malefic Viper," Jake answered curtly. “I have no idea why the fuck you would attribute their beliefs to me. I’m me; they are them.”

Well, he knew why Sultan would do it—it made sense—but he also enjoyed making fun of the ego-tripping dude.

“Puzzling,” Sultan admitted as he unbuttoned the top button of his tuxedo. He was sweating a little, and the women were also tense with Jake staring down at their owner.

“I do not explicitly need them, but I do not see the value in them being dead either," Sultan argued. “To kill them would turn their value to nil besides a few experience points. It removes the values their futures could provide too. Even if we ignore their combat prowess, simply having them be crafters would be preferable, would it not? I am not saying it’s a perfect solution to keep them as slaves, but I would argue it’s the preferred option to simply slaying them outright. Even if they may deserve it.”

Jake had to hand it to him—most would’ve backed down. But Sultan clearly hadn’t reached his level through backing down and being weak. He chose to meet Jake head-on.

"Right, and the torture is, of course, another just action that has to be a part of any good punishment, right?" Jake asked sarcastically. “I am sure it has nothing to do with you being a royal bastard.”

"I understand your judgment. We as humans tend to judge ourselves by our intentions and others by their behavior. My words or justifications hold little meaning to you, so I won’t even bother trying to convince you I am in the right. Think me a maniacal monster who enjoys torturing others, a hero of justice, or whatever you want in between. Just know that I hold no ill intentions towards you, nor any of your comrades, and I am very selective in who I put under my control.”

"Lots of flowery words for someone dictating the lives of others just because he’s some sadistic fuck,” Jake sneered. “I guess you don’t have a good reason, though—you just like controlling others. Is that the only way you can get a true sense of power?"

"Ah, there we disagree. I did give them a choice. One that you seem unwilling to offer. It’s interesting, is it not? What is better—giving someone the choice of death or slavery, or just killing them outright, offering them no alternative?" He laughed. "Besides, it’s a choice that remains. I do not restrict them from harming me; it is just that harming me will begin the process of their deaths. It will start a timer. If they manage to kill me within the period, they will all live. If they fail, they die. Exciting, wouldn’t you agree? It helps keep me on my toes. Sadly, all four of them are too darn cowardly to take a stab at me. Who knows? They might have a shot if they attack all at once."

Jake frowned, becoming more unsure if the man was telling the truth. But… something was telling him the guy was. Sure, he was a sadistic bastard, but at least he had been honest about it. This didn’t make Jake dislike him any less; it just made him continue the conversation. He did have one burning question, though.

"You talked about releasing them… Can you even do that? As far as I know, the moment someone is enslaved, they essentially become Soulbound to a person, and their owner’s death would mean the deaths of the slaves." This part, he was actually curious about.

He saw the women off to the side shuffle a bit. They likely had never heard this conversation before, and were afraid Sultan had lied to them at some point about the potential to release them. If he had… well, Jake knew who was about to die.

"The method you speak of is the most potent way of binding others to you. Potent, but also limited, as you just said. It’s a perfect one-way bond that has many benefits, but also restrictions. One of those is the inability to release others for good. That is not my method. Instead, I use the far more regular method of using a medium. I use this." Sultan took out a notebook from his breast pocket. "This notebook contains the contracts and is an item Soulbound to me. If I die, the item will cease to exist, and thus they will be released. Alternatively, I can choose to nullify the contract, which will also result in the person being freed."

Jake leaned over and picked up the notebook without any prompt. Sultan didn’t even react, while the women moved a tad closer. Perhaps looking for a chance to do something. Jake knew that he would have tried to kill Sultan long ago if he were in their shoes. Well, he would never be in their shoes, because in the end, a slave contract always had to be entered voluntarily. He would never have entered it to begin with.

He opened the notebook and saw all the pages were blank. He ripped one out to see if he could, and it went smoothly. Next, Jake just threw a glance at Sultan before he burned it with Alchemical Flame. Was it fake? No… it just wasn’t a "true" item.

Sultan fished out another identical notebook and placed it on the table. Without any prompt, he turned a single page, and a contract was revealed.

"Please, this is the contract they are under," Sultan said, leaning back to give Jake space.

Skimming it, Jake quickly saw it corroborated a lot of what Sultan had claimed. The contracts specified they weren’t allowed to willfully kill anyone without his permission, that they had to defend him from harm and stay close to him unless they had permission to leave, and finally, that they could protect themselves as long as it didn’t conflict with any of the previous two rules. There were no terms for release or anything else—not even a rule saying they had to follow all his commands.

"So, where’s the rest of it?" Jake asked after looking it over.

"That’s it. The only things not specified are the rules associated with it simply by it being a contract of this nature. Such as my ability to kill them at any point. Of course, such a death is not instant. I reckon it would take around ten minutes, and as long as they kill me within the period, they would be fine. Ah, also if they get above me in level. That would mean I lose the ability to control them. I am sure there are other ways too. The multiverse has endless possibilities, after all, does it not?" Sultan explained all this with a casual smile. He was still sweating, but he didn’t seem that stressed out anymore.

"So why don’t they speak?"

"I told them not to. Nothing stops them besides their fear of retaliation. They can ignore all my commands too. That has yet to happen, by the way.” His smile only grew.

"Now we’re back to the torture. Let’s say everything you do is logical and makes sense. It isn’t, but let’s say it is. Where the fuck does the torture come in? Do you think it can reform them? Make them see the error of their ways? Would that ever work?" Jake turned to the women and pointed to one of them. "You, answer that. No, don’t look at him. I’m the one who asked."

The woman he pointed at was the one with a bow. It was the reason he’d picked her. When he asked, she threw a glance at Sultan, but Jake quickly redirected her back to him.

She hesitated to say anything until she finally spat out, "He’s lying! None of us have done anything wrong! We’re innocent, and he’s forcing us to work for him! He makes us do horrible things… tortures us… Please! I beg you! Help us!"

Well, that was unhelpful, Jake thought as he heard her pleas. The three women had looked slightly shocked as she yelled and been surprisingly slow to nod in agreement, almost too enthusiastically. He would say it was a sixty-forty situation. Sixty on her lying about being innocent, forty on her actually being completely a victim. Either way, it didn’t matter much to Jake; he primarily wanted to confirm that they could speak and think for themselves. Clearly, her outburst was not something Sultan liked or had expected. In fact, he frowned, and the sweat on the back of his neck indicated he had gotten quite nervous again.

"Needless to say, she is lying," Sultan said. “Please, simply check in with Sanctdomo. I implore you to trust me for now until you confirm it. I am willing to talk this through, and if you wish, I could even put their release as an item on the negotiation table. Just think about it.

"But let’s continue the argument further. I release them. Then what? You kill them? Hope they’ve reformed? Tell them to leave and cause havoc elsewhere? Waste strenuous amounts of resources to try and keep them imprisoned? I hope you see there are no good solutions here. I merely chose the solution that benefits me the most. Is it ultimately based on my own selfishness? Yes. D-grades don’t grow on trees quite yet. These four hold far too much value to simply kill for some idealistic belief. In my view, their states are based on the choices they made. Based on a choice I made. I chose to make them slaves, and they chose slavery over capital punishment. It was all choices, the same as you can choose to kill me now and release them. I doubt I would win, and you would be able to kill all five of us if you so wished. That would be my miscalculation and my mistake. It would be unfortunate to lose my life like this, but I would only be able to blame myself." Sultan sighed.

Jake just sat back and thought about it. Would he be right in killing all of them? Probably not. Maybe? But to be fair… he honestly didn’t care much either way. If he was perfectly genuine with himself, he didn’t care much about releasing slaves anyway. In his eyes, they were already weak failures, innocent or not. Because one thing was certain, no matter what… They had chosen slavery over death. That in itself made him dislike them.

So what would he get out of killing them? Pretty much nothing besides being able to steal some of their shit. Even then, Jake knew most merchants had spatial storage as a skill. Which meant robbing him wasn’t really an option. He would get a boat and what they wore. Probably useful… but not by much. Meanwhile, a D-grade merchant could offer a lot…

In the end, Jake did the only reasonable thing.

He raised his hand and fired a blast of arcane mana through the barrier surrounding them. It opened a hole to the outside world that tried to close itself but was unable to due to the destructive mana. In an interesting display, Sultan and the women all looked ready to pick up their weapons as if they wanted to fight together. The cowards truly preferred remaining slaves to Sultan over death.

Either way, the purpose for opening the hole was simple.

In flew a green figure that landed on his shoulder with a small, annoyed screech. Walking behind Sylpie were Miranda, Neil, and Silas.

When in doubt… make others figure it out.

"Mister Sultan," Miranda said as she entered. "Your reputation precedes you."

Chapter 59

Executive Decision

Miranda had been working at high speeds while making her way towards the Fort and waiting outside. Lillian fed her information as she traveled with the hawk, and she and Lillian managed to put two and two together after Phillip came back and told them the merchant’s name was Sultan. He was one of the people they had become aware of already, as he had made quite the name for himself in some of the surrounding cities.

A ruthless man with a massive ego, but one incredibly good at his job. He had bought and sold things in Sanctdomo, two of the other cities the Holy Church controlled, and many other settlements. Some Pylon cities, some not. The ship he traveled on was quite speedy, explaining how he could get around so much.

No one could really do much to him either. Sultan himself was powerful, and he’d had two slaves already near D-grade the last time he went to Sanctdomo. In Sanctdomo, he had “acquired” two more who were swiftly approaching D-grade. The first was a woman who had poisoned her former party members and been apprehended after one of the victims ended up being a close friend of a council member. Miranda guessed that was when the leadership of Sanctdomo had decided she was too much trouble.

The second woman was even worse. She was a Pathfinder—an evolution of Archer—specializing in some odd magic she had acquired from the tutorial store. She imprinted magical sigils on people and objects and used them to track things. It was an ability a lot like what Miranda herself could do with the Verdant Mark, except this woman could see through the eyes of the people she marked.

And what did she do with this? Well, she scouted. She’d been a premier scout of Sanctdomo for a while and used her sigils liberally. No one had questioned them, as they seemed so harmless. They’d spread to many people, and soon she’d had hundreds of them. Finally, she’d become so good at the skill she got a substantial upgrade to it … which was when she began becoming an issue.

Her mark had allowed her to always see, but now it didn’t even require the other party’s consent or knowledge. She’d become addicted to the knowledge and the feeling of control. She’d lived the lives of others, and especially one man she became infatuated with. She had been in a party with him, and they had gotten along great. All had gone well, until they returned… and she learned he had a wife and kids.

That day, she’d killed his family so he could be with her instead. But when she tried to get with him, he wasn’t the same anymore. He wasn’t his same bubbly self… so she got bored and switched.

Nine more families within the span of a month. Six wives, three girlfriends, fifteen children. She had a type, and that type was the man who already had everything. When she’d begun stalking her tenth victim, she was captured. After her capture, they’d done some digging and found out she had been locked up before the system as a serial stalker that had turned violent at times. The system had only made her worse, as now she could truly express herself.

As fucked up as it was, the month she had spent stalking men had given her more levels than anything before. As a Pathfinder, she gained massive amounts of experience from constantly avoiding detection and suspicion and stalking the men without them even knowing. She often also went without looking through their eyes, as she liked to watch them sleep. Of course, the carefully prepared killings themselves gave quite the experience boost too.

These two women were monsters, yet Sanctdomo had wanted to use them, so they’d had them imprisoned to continue serving the greater good through the use of their professions. But when they approached D-grade, Sanctdomo had an issue. They’d had no way to keep them trapped after the evolution. No D-grade with the skillset required to enslave them either.

That was when Sultan had come along and offered to take them off their hands. The current warden at the time, who’d been in charge of keeping them from committing more crimes, had agreed with permission from his higher-ups after Sultan paid a hefty sum.

This was all the research Miranda had time to do before Jake “invited” them in. It was about time too. The majority of the time had been spent juggling the influx of information from Lillian and an annoyed bird that wanted to break through the barrier right there and then.

"Mister Sultan, your reputation precedes you," she said with a smile as she entered.

The man was an egomaniac, so stroking that ego would be wise. Miranda also noted that Jake hadn’t killed him yet, but clearly the “negotiations” weren’t exactly going well either. The sweat on Sultan’s brow was visible, and the four slave women were tense.

If Jake were the bad, scary cop, she would be the good cop. She had chosen to read Jake not killing the merchant outright as a sign he at least wanted to extract some benefits. Did she doubt for even a second that Jake could kill the five D-grades? No, not at all.

"Ah, Ms. Wells," Sultan said, seeming almost relieved at her entrance.

She assumed it was because he was. He also threw a glance at Neil and Silas. Neil had been brought along because… well, he’d been there with Silas when Miranda asked to have him brought around. His lie-detecting skills would be useful. There wasn’t any fear of them resisting the skill, either, as that would just make the judgment even easier if they chose to do that.

While Miranda did have some trust in the information from Sanctdomo, she still chose to confirm it. A large part of her hoped that the women turned out to just be innocent blasphemers of the Holy Church or something silly like that. She doubted it but, at the same time, would verify.

"Silas and Neil, please take those four into the cabin and check their stories,” Miranda said, summoning a chair from her spatial storage and sitting down. “Ladies, be aware that all it will do is make our decision here easy if you try anything. Mister Sultan, as the formal leader of Haven, I shall represent Lord Thayne as the liaison of Haven and try to reach a beneficial conclusion to this whole endeavor. But be aware that you have already broken the law, as slavery is illegal in Haven, so I expect a proper response and recompense." On second thought… she would just be the second bad cop.

Sultan looked a bit taken aback, but chose to apologize right away as he waved off the four girls. "That must be my mistake; I was not aware it was outlawed and was not informed upon my arrival either."

The four girls followed Silas and Neil away. At least the man was reasonable enough not to argue. Jake staring at him the entire time sure didn’t help his situation either. Miranda smiled and responded to the veiled question.

"Naturally, you weren’t aware. The law was just established a few minutes ago. We haven’t needed it yet, and have chosen to have the law work retroactively.” She left little room for any counterarguments. "Now, please state your full purpose for coming here. With proper cause, we may be able to reach an agreement and a solution that does not result in receiving the capital punishment the law dictates."

Sultan had made another major miscalculation. Miranda didn’t like the guy at all either, and Jake had granted her the power to do whatever she wanted as the City Lord, which included randomly creating laws. As long as he agreed with them, there wouldn’t be an issue, and from her quick assessment, he seemed to be A-okay with outlawing slavery. Considering his hour-long rant on how fucked it was to enslave beasts during one of their dinners, she had assumed as much.

Miranda joined Jake in staring down Sultan as a new drop of sweat appeared on the man’s forehead.

Jake gave Miranda a mental thumbs-up. He should have just waited for her from the start to have her deal with all this shit. It all seemed so damn complicated when it really shouldn’t be. Killing all five of them would be the simple solution, but would it be the best one? He wasn’t making decisions only for himself, but Haven as a whole.

Now at least I’ll have the law on my side, Jake thought. Also, I should really ask Miranda about what the laws of Haven are.

If he had met Sultan out in the open while traveling or something, Jake would probably have just ignored him or killed him if he became an issue. If Jake got confirmation that even one of the women was innocent, or even if Sultan had lied a little about their circumstances, Jake would kill him. If Miranda ended up concluding killing Sultan would be the best course of action, Jake would kill him. Right now, he honestly didn’t care either way until he was certain about things.

Let’s say the women were as bad as Sultan claimed. Well, then they truly didn’t deserve his pity. If he just went around killing anyone who did stuff he disagreed with, he would be busy killing people who thought putting canned cheese on anything was acceptable.

Didn’t mean he didn’t have lines people shouldn’t cross. The torture part was just not okay, no matter how you spun it. That Jake would make sure the four were taken away, freed, or the last of Sultan’s slaves was a given from the very start. Also, dependent on what the women really had done… it wasn’t certain if he would respect their choice of slavery.

"I came to Haven for four primary reasons," Sultan answered, holding nothing back. “Firstly, to find a home base to operate out of. I am aware you are among the leaders in building a spatial network, and Haven will no doubt become a well-known city across the planet due to Lord Thayne’s presence. Secondly, I will naturally join the Treasure Hunt, and I feel like I need an affiliation with a faction to do well there. I have made many enemies on my path already; I need some backing too. Thirdly, the benefits offered from a Pylon, including the System Store, are just too valuable to give up as a merchant. Fourth, I wish to simply do my work as a merchant here. Even if I am made to leave, I still hope to at least trade first. I do not doubt that Haven has many valuables to trade, just as I have many valuables to offer. To summarize, I want to work for and with Haven.”

Jake didn’t doubt for a second that Sultan knew he was in some deep shit, pretty much surrounded by enemies on all sides. To be honest, Jake was surprised he wasn’t just looking for an exit strategy. Did he still want to stay after just being threatened with capital punishment?

If he just left, that would also be a solution. Jake didn’t care enough to hunt them down, and Sultan didn’t strike him as the vengeful sort. He was a coward. There was no way he would risk his life for something as petty as revenge. The most he could do was attempt some economic damage, but Jake reckoned he was too cowardly to do even that.

"This is a horrible way to try and join a settlement," Miranda said, shaking her head.

"I very much realize that now. My antics don’t fit in as well here as I had come to believe through my research. You have my genuine apology for that. As I offered prior, the four women can be given to you as a form of apology. However, I am curious… How has Haven managed to deal with criminals so far? As far as I know, dealing with prisoners has caused many issues and debates in most other settlements. Conventional prisons aren’t exactly feasible anymore. Even Sanctdomo isn’t able to contain someone at D-grade yet.”

"We don’t have many of those issues. Currently, we only give out smaller punishments, and those that would result in incarceration result in exile or simply capital punishment. So perhaps we’ve been lucky that we haven’t had that much crime. Worst were two cases of rape, and that one was an easy and swift death sentence, as the guy tried to run." Miranda waved it off. "Besides, how is that any of your business?"

Oh, yeah, I remember that one. Some guy who got sniped when he tried to flee, Jake thought, having no sympathy. Of course, by old-world standards, having capital punishments for most "serious" crimes would be excessive, but in this new world, it was just quick and efficient.

"I guess it isn’t for me to snoop… I was simply curious if—"

"Ree!"

Sultan was interrupted by Sylphie’s annoyed screech; Jake stopped rubbing her feathers. He looked over at Jake, and Jake just stared back at him as he slowly scratched the bird, which was now nuzzling up to his hand again. Neither spoke, and Jake fucking dared him to.

"A beautiful hawk… I am sorry if I disturbed it, an—"

Jake threw him a glance when he said “it,” giving the guy one more chance.

"If I disturbed… h—" Sultan watched Jake’s eyes closely "—er. Please, take this as an apology."

Sultan summoned a small, round, marble-looking thing, and Jake used Identify on it right away. He also checked it for poison and anything else. What he had summoned was something Jake had encountered before when he researched making food for Sylphie.

[Beast Pellet (Common)] – A beast pellet made by a talented cook using monster materials and herbs to create an artificial natural treasure. Consuming this will have no effects on an enlightened species but is highly beneficial to monsters.

As for Sylphie’s reaction? She looked over at the pellet for a bit and jumped down on the table, knocking over every single teacup and the two teapots—on purpose, as far as Jake could tell. Sultan still didn’t dare react, even when the tea dripped down on his pants. Sylphie went over and picked up the pellet incredibly slowly. She put it in her beak and ate it, crunching as she did so. Then she just wobbled off the table and leaped back to sit on Jake’s shoulder—disregarding Sultan all the while.

But… Jake could tell she liked the pellet. He had to admit; Sultan was smart. He had identified and tried to bring one of the most influential people in Haven to his side through bribery. And it had worked, because now Jake couldn’t kill him before figuring out where he’d gotten the pellet or if he had more.

It was at this time that Neil and Silas walked out of the ship’s cabin, both of them frowning.

"So?" Miranda asked, looking at Silas—but just looking at him, it was obvious.

"Fuck the lot of them," Silas said, disgust visible on his face. "Sometimes I really hate these shitty skills. I don't… I need some air…"

Silas walked off the ship. Neil looked concerned after his friend as he sighed. Jake was also a bit surprised, as Silas had always seemed like a meek guy.

"Neil?" Miranda asked. Sultan just sat back with his eyes closed.

"Two of them were as you said… but the other two… they’re worse," Neil said, shaking his head. Then he continued hesitantly, "They were partners… and…"

"They tortured and killed five hundred and eighty-two people, including one hundred and seventy-two children, all in an attempt to upgrade an item through a curse-ritual that harvested resentment and pain," Sultan said, shaking his head. "It took them a month of keeping them all alive and in constant agony. It only ended when the last person killed herself after her child’s soul broke. While I wouldn’t argue I am a good person, even I have standards. They were the first I ever took control of after they tried to ambush me on my travels, and I will understand it if you question me for keeping them around."

Jake looked up and over at Miranda and then back at Neil, who gave him an affirming nod and muttered, "And they seemed damn proud of themselves too…"

He threw a final glance after Silas, who was already far gone, but Jake could still see him shaking slightly. Jake decided there and then to make an executive decision as he put Sylphie down on the table. She read his mood and allowed him. Miranda looked over at him, and she understood as she made a subtle nod. He got up and received a few confused glances when he walked into the cabin with the four women.

A loud noise.

Two people were sent flying out through the side of the cabin and into the plains, a figure chasing them.

An explosion.

Yells and curses.

And then… silence.

A single person returned not even two minutes after departing and jumped back on the ship.

*You have slain [Human - lvl 101 / Crudelis Hexer - lvl 109 / Experienced Silk Seamstress– lvl 89]

*You have slain [Human - lvl 101 / Crudelis Hexer - lvl 107 / Recognized Jeweller of Zeil’Juia – lvl 91]

Jake walked over to the chair and sat down, cleaning his hands on his cloak. Sylphie just jumped back on his shoulder as if nothing had happened. Everyone looked at him.

"Continue."

Chapter 60

Concessions Today, Profits in the Future

The situation was just a tiny bit tenser after Jake took out the trash. He was considering if they should slap on a charge for contaminating Haven with toxic waste, but held back. During the brief intermission, the two women had exited the cabin. They now stood behind Sultan as if seeking protection from him, both looking terrified.

Miranda cleared her voice, bringing the attention back to her even if Sultan still threw glances at Jake. He didn’t seem mad or offended at all, but borderline elated.

"Needless to say, we reserve any right to dish out punishment as we see fit," Miranda said. “If it is decided by the leadership of Haven—especially Lord Thayne—to deliver the aforementioned punishment, then that is something you will have to accept.”

"Naturally," Sultan agreed, his smile now back.

He seemed less stressed than before despite just losing two of his "bodyguards." Not much bodyguarding going on, honestly, as those two had been weak. Jake guessed they were the kinds of casters who needed ample preparation to show their full power, and Jake hadn’t given them that. Not at all.

As to why he had killed them? Because they had crossed a line. Where exactly that line was, he couldn’t say. They just had, so he’d acted. Jake was inherently an impulsive person, so when that overwhelming feeling of bloodlust came up, he felt it hard to hold himself back. He’d still had the self-control to throw Miranda a glance and get a nod of approval from her. After that whole Abby and Donald business, Jake didn’t always trust his own sense of anger when it came to other humans.

As for the two last slaves? He didn’t care. One of them was that Gabi woman, and he didn’t know any details of the other—not even her name. Considering there hadn’t been any visceral reaction to her, Jake assumed she couldn’t be as bad. Miranda could decide what to do with her. They were fucked up, sure, but they didn’t incite any feeling of anger, only disgust. He did have some clue as to why that was, and also why he disliked Sultan so much.

What Jake truly despised was unnecessarily causing harm to others in a disproportionate way. He was fully aware that you sometimes had to kill weaker individuals when it came to fighting, but going out of your way to torture or kill someone weaker was just wrong.

This was why Jake didn’t just kill any random beast he came across, even while he still got experience from them. Killing a foe many levels below himself just for an insignificant amount of experience didn’t sit right with him. As an example, if the Minotaur Mindchief had only tried to kill powerful D-grade humans, he would’ve said fair game. The problem had been that it tortured and killed those significantly weaker than itself, like a fucking coward.

Sultan was a lesser version of that. He was a sadist who enjoyed torturing—not because he got anything out of it, but just because he was a bastard. Actually, if Sultan had just had those four slaves without the whole torture part, he could maybe even see them getting along. Sure, he was an ass, but who wasn’t a bit of an asshole these days?

It was not like Jake would even pretend he and Miranda were the good guys right now. They were essentially blackmailing and forcing Sultan to give in to all their demands. Shit, they had yet to actually offer anything in return besides his potential survival.

Yet, for some reason, Sultan seemed fine with all that. It was honestly perplexing in every way. Things were going terribly for him, weren’t they?

He hadn’t been wrong. Sultan had been questioning his decision to come to Haven, but after seeing the Chosen act, all that doubt had been dispelled like the morning fog.

Lord Thayne was domineering, assertive, and acted like he didn’t care about anyone else’s opinion. He was perfect. His bloodlust and power were enough to send shivers down his spine and make his heart pound. This was what a true powerhouse of the multiverse should be like.

Sultan had met the Augur during his last visit. He had even been asked to join the Holy Church or just become an affiliate partner, but he had refused. The church was controlling, and so was the city. In the end, you had to work for the collective, and while they supported the standouts a lot, Sultan didn’t like the way they did things. It was a hive of covert corruption and politics. Without the Augur, the shitshow that was the political arena of Sanctdomo would already have fallen apart. Being a part of that city would mean being forced into politics if he wanted any proper benefits.

But Haven? In Haven, there were no politics. Not truly. It was a dictatorship with Lord Thayne at the top and Miranda Wells acting as the voice of his will. This was far more to his liking. He had hoped to endear himself to the Chosen personally, but even if that had failed, he had time. Even if he couldn’t make Lord Thayne like him, he could at least make the Chosen view him as useful.

This was why he couldn’t help but be happy. What was giving up a few slaves? A silly hobby? The profits and power he could accumulate from working with Lord Thayne would outweigh all of that a thousandfold. Sultan wasn’t just looking at this in the short term either.

The Holy Church already had hundreds of talented merchants. With a city population exceeding fifty million, that only made sense, and that number was increasing, sometimes by hundreds of thousands a day.

Sultan himself would say he was better than every single one of Sanctdomo’s merchants, but he knew he would never get the best things. Because he wasn’t loyal, and he would never be loyal to anyone but himself.

There was no way he would be a primary partner of Sanctdomo. Meanwhile, Haven didn’t have any merchants associated with the city quite yet. At least, Sultan hadn’t heard of any, so no one worth his notice had appeared. It was a massive opening, and exactly what he had been hoping for. Getting in on the ground floor would be good now. And in the future? It would be massively beneficial.

For who was the Chosen a Chosen of? The Malefic Viper, a Primordial, with his Order of the Malefic Viper. To get direct access through the Chosen to the Order, one of the most prominent alchemy-related organizations in the multiverse, would be invaluable. Sure, they were known as ruthless, but who would dare touch him if he came working for the Chosen?

Sultan knew that without strength, there was no way to succeed in the multiverse. The best merchant needed the strongest backing. The richest man would be the strongest, and the most influential would be the one capable of killing anyone who disagreed with him.

He had seen firsthand what happened to those not strong enough. Sultan had lost everything once already, and he refused to be a victim in this world anymore.

Sultan knew that all of this was, in the end, a gamble. A gamble Sultan believed only required him to put some of his wealth and the potential of being forced to leave on the table. To begin with, at least. It had now changed to him already having lost two D-grade slaves, and he was sure he would lose the two others too. One way or another. Even his life was on the line, he didn’t have a single complaint about it. It was exciting.

Miranda Wells was a truly ruthless and talented woman. Lord Thayne was a monster in human skin. Even the green hawk was something else. A natural D-grade still viewed as a juvenile of its race? It was bound to become powerful. Sultan was certain Haven also hid other secrets—not that he was even close to comprehending the three before him fully. Neil, the space mage, he had figured out already. It hadn’t been difficult to dig up information on him and his party.

Sultan had spent only a few hours in Haven, and he was only becoming more and more determined to join them. Sure, Sanctdomo was large. It had hundreds of D-grades already. It had the Augur and many other powerful individuals.

Yet… if Haven and Sanctdomo clashed… he couldn’t see Sanctdomo and all their powerhouses coming out unscathed. No… he wasn’t sure he could see them coming out alive.

Before, he had wanted to join. Now he needed to, cost be damned.

If Sultan died because of his greed, then so be it. Sultan had chosen the life he led now, and he accepted death as a potential risk in pursuit of his goals. He was a man who went for what he wanted and either got it or died trying.

Sultan would take the losses and make concessions today for profits in the future. And while the Chosen didn’t like him, he sure as hell liked the Chosen. Hopefully, they could foster a relationship in due time; if not, he would have to focus his attention on the other influential figures of Haven—primarily those who held sway over the Chosen, naturally.

As for his sadistic hobby? Well, he would figure that out… Hopefully they would allow him to keep one of the slaves. Prostitutes always overcharged him for that kind of thing, after all.

The following half an hour or so were honestly too easy. Jake was confused as to why Sultan just went along with borderline anything and made concession after concession. He did have some points he refused to concede on, but nothing Jake disagreed with.

Neil threw in that they should make him sign a contract binding him to Haven, but Sultan refused adamantly, refusing to be bound by a contract to the city. To Jake, that only made sense. Why would anyone clearly talented bind themselves to another faction? Jake himself sure as hell never would.

Sultan argued he refused to sign anything limiting his own freedom. Ironic, considering he kept slaves. Miranda tried to insist on this point, but fast discovered it was an absolute dealbreaker. Ultimately, it didn’t matter to Jake if the guy was loyal. Having to write a contract to have someone be loyal and work for you seemed kind of unnecessary in nearly all cases. As Jake had no plans of sharing stuff like his Bloodline, there was no reason for him to sign a magical nondisclosure agreement either.

When they got to the slaves and what to do with them, it became more complicated.

Miranda turned to the two and straight up asked, "So, if you get to choose, then what do you want—slavery or capital punishment?"

It was an obvious answer, but they just wanted confirmation. Both wanted to remain slaves. By now, Jake had become aware one of them liked to kill entire families because she was fucked in the head, and had dearly hoped Miranda would throw him a "please just kill her" glance.

"Then the next question is if you would prefer to work under the authority of Haven or Sultan."

That was where it got surprising. The one called Gabi didn’t hesitate to want to get the fuck away from Sultan, as she began pleading about being reformed. Honestly, it was bad. Like, even Jake could say with ninety percent certainty she was just desperate to be freed. Didn’t work.

But… the other—the serial-killer and stalker woman—wanted to remain with Sultan… In fact, she stood oddly close to him, as if afraid they would take her away. Could Jake try to analyze her movements and intent? Sure, but that would be a massive waste of brainpower. While it had more or less been decided he wouldn’t kill her, that didn’t mean he would have to deal with her. Hunting kids was just bad sport, regardless of whether it was to kill or enslave them. Adding on to that, had Sultan walked in with a child slave, he would be dead already.

Ultimately, Miranda reached an agreement with Sultan—with Jake’s approval.

Sultan would join Haven on a trial basis and be allowed to operate out of the city. For official matters such as the Treasure Hunt and other such events, he would be recognized as a member of Haven too. He would also be granted access to the System Store.

In return, Sultan would pay an increased tax rate over everyone else for the next ten years, or until he had paid a total of 100 million Credits. Additionally, he would be forbidden from enslaving anyone and would be subject to an interview with Silas present every month or so—dependent on when it would fit into everyone’s schedules—to check if he had been up to any misdeeds. He was also banned from torture, though he managed to argue in an exception if both parties consented. Miranda didn’t ask the man further about his fetishes.

On the trading front of things—what this entire thing was meant to be about—Haven would have the right to buy any product of rare rarity or above from Sultan before anyone else, and with a maximum of a fifty-percent markup. This would essentially result in him selling at purchase price due to taxes.

There were many other stipulations and rules, and Jake only stayed in case things went south. Miranda and Sultan debated vigorously, and eventually Lillian came by, at which point they began drawing up a contract using one of Miranda’s skills. It was a balancing act of what to include in the contract and what not to. Some things—like the interview or inability to take slaves—didn’t enter the contract, so it ended up being solely trade-related.

Jake thought that was probably for the best. Sultan had been so dead set on getting to join Haven that he didn’t think they needed any loyalty clauses. Those were borderline impossible, to begin with, as the contracts had to be rather factual and to the point. This also meant that all of those good-faith clauses were out of the question.

Again, though, it wasn’t needed. As long as Haven turned out to be a beneficial partnership for Sultan, he wouldn’t leave. And if he left… well, who would actually care? Jake sure wouldn’t. He also didn’t fear Sultan would try some shit or cause issues in Haven. Maybe he would try to suck up to Miranda and get into the council thing she had going on, but that was only to be expected of any sleazy businessman.

In the end, the entire debacle ended up taking several hours, and only ended when a document was signed by Miranda and Sultan. Sultan also wanted Jake to sign, but he declined. Signing it would mean he would have to read it in detail, and that didn’t sound interesting at all. Sylphie also wouldn’t like it, as it would mean he couldn’t dedicate both hands to stroking her feathers as she sat on his lap.

Once everything was signed and done, they all sat back.

"Let me provide you a belated welcome to Haven, Sultan," Miranda finally said with a smile. "I truly hope we have laid the foundation for a fruitful future today, despite the less-than-fortunate first impression."

"Likewise, I look forward to working with you, Ms. Wells, Lord Thayne," Sultan said, earning a look from Sylphie. "And the young mistress, of course," he quickly added on.

Jake was pretty sure Sylphie didn’t really understand what he had said; she was just mad at not being included.

"Now, on to more important things than slavery or the morality of capital punishment or all that stuff," Jake said to lighten the mood, then turned to something he had wanted to say for a long time.

"Show me your wares."

Chapter 61

Sultan Has Wares, If You Have Coin

Jake didn’t know what to expect. He hoped Sultan would have some good stuff, considering his status as a D-grade merchant who had been around the place, but exactly how good, he wasn’t sure. This was the first real merchant he had ever encountered, after all. For the record, Jake hadn’t looted anything off the two D-grade women. Their equipment wasn’t actual gear, playing into his suspicion they were truly just there for show. Sultan no doubt kept all their stuff himself at usual times.

Smiling, Sultan answered his trade request. “My last visit to Sanctdomo wasn’t only to sell my wares, but also to seek out their experts. Knowing Haven would be my next stop, I made a number of commissions for things I specifically hoped would interest you. I do apologize if it is presumptuous of me to believe you do not already have better, but please take a look. As you are an alchemist, please let us start with a cauldron."

He waved his hand to summon a cauldron. "This cauldron was created by a talented smith and alchemist working together to bring out its…"

Jake used Identify on it.

[Mithril Cauldron of Peerless Conductivity (Rare)] – A cauldron created by a talented smith with the—

"No thanks, I got better. Next," Jake said.

He didn’t bother with the rest of the description, besides just quickly checking the enchantments and realizing it was a highly inferior version of his Altmar Cauldron of Supreme Simplicity. Neither the items nor Sultan’s background information on it made it worth getting.

Meanwhile, Lillian and Miranda were also there, with Lillian noting down all the items as she also Identified them. Possibly to look into if they wanted to buy any of the stuff Jake passed on.

Sultan didn’t seem offended, and moved on with a smile. "Perhaps something for your archery, then?"

The man summoned a bow and laid it on the table. It was made of some wood that looked almost red. It had some dark lines running through it as though it had been burned, giving it an interesting look. The string was entirely black and was made of some material Jake didn’t recognize, and at each end of the bow’s body was a small red gemstone. It was a lot like his current bow in design overall, if a bit larger. It was nothing that would matter, and Jake found himself quite adaptable anyway.

"This bow is made by the strongest archer and bowyer of Sanctdomo. A woman named Maria, if you have heard of her. As far as I know, she was a part of the World Congress too, so you may have seen her. This one cost me a pretty penny for the materials alone, and I believe it came out splendidly."

Jake listened to the explanation before he Identified the bow.

[Embered Bow of Scorching Plains (Epic)] – A bow made from an unknown type of wood that has been soaked in potent fire-affinity mana for a long period of time without being burned and then infused with a dozen other valuable materials. All brought to life by an incredibly talented bowyer. The bow’s structure is resilient yet flexible, the string near unbreakable for anyone below C-grade. The two gemstones passively absorb and transform mana into that of the fire affinity, imbuing all arrows fired by this bow with fire mana and the concept of embers. The two gemstones can be emptied of energy to release a large burst of fire-affinity mana in the form of a giant arrow that explodes on impact, scorching the plains below. Enchantments: Ember Arrows. Scorching Plains.

Requirements: Lvl 105+ in any humanoid race.

See, now we’re cooking! Jake thought. Shit, the bow was super fire-themed, so maybe he could actually cook just using the bow. He wasn’t going to try, but it was a fun possibility. According to Sultan, he had gone all out with his bow, and Jake could see that. Each of those gems alone had to be epic rarity, and he had no idea how many more items he’d put into it.

The one who had made it was also talented. This wasn’t like Arnold’s gloves, with so much untapped potential. The Maria who’d made this bow knew what she was doing, and she had done a splendid job.

"For the record, the craftswoman was aware it was commissioned as a gift for you," Sultan said. With a small chuckle, he added, "I practically got the work hours for free, and I am sure she also wanted to impress. She told me to put in a good word."

Jake nodded. "This is some good stuff. And you said it’s a gift?"

"Most certainly. Take it as a gift to cement our future working relationship."

Sultan’s smile grew even more as Jake took the bow off the table and into his inventory. He gave Sultan a nod of approval. Jake had to admit the bribery was working, as he now found Sultan slightly more agreeable.

He was also very impressed that a bowyer was already able to craft epic-rarity items of this quality. Maria was her name? Maybe someone worth seeking out in the future. She was in Sanctdomo, so it wasn’t an overly long trip.

Jake was already feeling pretty damn satisfied, but Sultan wasn’t done.

"Now, the next item is a sword…"

Jake didn’t need the sword, and it wasn’t even better than the Nanoblade anyway. And that was before the current improvements Arnold was making to it. Lillian noted it down in case someone else could use it.

"These pants, I got from a leatherworker and tailor pair in Skyggen, and…"

Jake’s pants were better. They were noted down again. Neil commented on Eleanor maybe wanting them.

"I noticed you always wear a cloak, so this—"

Didn’t need that one either. Miranda bought, it as her cloak sucked, so at least that one was useful.

"Certainly a new mask could be—"

Just no. Lillian wanted it, though. Not really to hide her face, but due to its effect of allowing some kind of farsight.

"How about a necklace…?"

Jake liked having spatial storage.

"Gloves…"

Way worse than his new ones.

Jake saw that Sultan was getting a bit nervous at this point due to the repeated rejection. Jake had taken the bow, but for everything else, he had passed, completely uninterested. The man had started with some of his best stuff, and many of the following items were “only” uncommon rarity.

Not to be misunderstood—there were some great things. It was just limited by how good of stuff Sultan could get—or anyone could, really—as Earth was still in its infancy as a planet of the multiverse. That there were people able to craft epic-rarity items was already incredibly impressive.

Sultan didn’t give up, though. He seemed to want to go through the entire set of gear pieces available, and eventually, he summoned something that did interest Jake a lot. It was a deep brown chestpiece of leather that looked very well made, if a bit simple. Jake Identified it and was pleasantly surprised.

[Leather Chestguard of the Juvenile Bristleback (Uncommon)] – A chestplate made from the tough leather of a young Bristleback. Created by a talented leatherworker, the workmanship is simple but effective. Has been infused with a Beastcore, making this chestpiece even more durable and enhancing the wearer’s resilience. Enchantments: +200 Toughness, +75 Endurance, +50 Vitality.

Requirements: Lvl 100+ in any humanoid race.

The merchant didn’t think this gear piece had much hope, from the looks of it, but he enthusiastically explained its properties anyway.

"I must say, this one was a gamble. A hunting team came in, having slain a young Bristleback that had just reached D-grade. It was a large, pig-like monster, and the leatherworker worked tirelessly to make something useful. Luckily they had the core too. The final project came out quite nicely, but it did take an entire bus-sized body.”

It was a massive upgrade. Jake mentally compared it to his old chest, and the difference was clear.

[Armor of the Nest Watcher (Rare)] – A chestpiece made from the cured leather of an unknown creature. Provides strong protection against both physical and energy attacks. The very lifeforce of the Nest Watcher runs through this armor, blessing the wielder with great Vitality and Toughness. Enchantments: Self-Repair. +75 Vitality, +50 Toughness.

Requirements: Lvl 55+ in any humanoid race.

Sure, it was a downgrade in rarity, but the level requirement was just that much higher, making it far better.

"I’ll take it—how much?" Jake said.

Sultan looked surprised but pleased. "Ah, normally I would charge 45,000 for a piece like this, but you can have it for 38,000, and I shouldn’t take a loss."

"35,000 it is.”

"I do agree 37,000 is fair," Sultan countered.

"36,000."

"36,500.”

“Alright, deal,” Jake finally relented.

He tried to put the chestpiece in his inventory but found himself unable to. This was when he noticed a faint bond of mana connecting Sultan and the armor, almost as if it was bound to him. He frowned and paid, and the moment he did, the weird bond disappeared, and he put it in his inventory.

"First time dealing with a merchant, I assume," Sultan chuckled. "It’s just a simple skill to bind something during a deal. Simply protection against thieving, so people don’t just swipe all your wares the moment they see them."

That… actually made a lot of sense. Jake totally got why that was a thing, and it was one of those practical skills that just had to exist. It was probably something every merchant or trading-related profession got with the profession.

As for why he’d haggled? Well, because that was just what you did. Sure, he had over 137 million Credits by now—in fact, he actually had more now than right after the tutorial due to having sold so many potions—but that didn’t mean he would waste them. Besides, maybe Sultan had other good stuff? Didn’t wanna splurge for no reason.

"Now, how ‘bout some new boots?” Sultan said with renewed Vigor after having just sold Jake the chestpiece. “I noticed yours look a little worn, and is it not high time for an upgrade?"

"No," Jake said curtly.

"Well, it can’t be a winner every time. I am ashamed to say I don’t have much else I believe would interest you in the equipment department besides one more item. Granted, this is assuming you are not looking for spears, halberds, heavy swords, crossbows, firearms, or pretty much most other weapon types. I assumed you are a one-handed-weapon-and-bow kind of fighter.”

Him listing the different weapons he had was clearly more for Miranda and the others than Jake.

"True. So, the last item?"

"Ah, this one I have been saving. The best for last. You always gotta start out and end strong, do you not? This one is an item I am quite proud of having acquired. Originally it was bought at the tutorial store, but it was never used. I do not know the original intended use, but what I do know is that it isn’t an item I have come across before. So please, have a look."

Sultan summoned a small token. It looked a lot like the tutorial upgrade tokens… because it was a lot like them, but at the same time very different.

[Token of Akashic Awakening (Epic)] – Infuse into a piece of equipment to attempt to awaken or amplify the Records within, upgrading the item to a maximum of epic rarity. If the item is already epic rarity, it will try to amplify existing effects through awakened Records. Overall effects may be unpredictable. WARNING: Touching directly upon the Records of an item may make others related to the associated Records aware.

Requirements: User must be below lvl 130.

"From rumors I have gathered, it is said that the Sword Saint used a similar—if far more powerful—item to awaken an old family heirloom to turn it into maybe the most potent weapon on the planet. This one can do something similar, but I would recommend using it on a piece of equipment already recognized as an item if you choose to buy it. My appraisal skills, at least, made me believe that would be for the best.”

Jake picked up the token and inspected it inside and out. "How much?"

He already had plenty of ideas on what to use it on, but he would still want the item even if he didn’t. The item was just too interesting, and he could see too many uses. Shit, he could use it to upgrade his boots or necklace, couldn’t he?

"Ten million Credits," Sultan said without batting an eye.

"Quite the price increase, don’t you think?" Jake asked with a frown.

"True, but this item honestly cannot be evaluated through normal means. It does something perhaps only a few extremely rare natural treasures can do, if it’s even possible for something found in the natural world. My Patron has told me that this item wouldn’t sell for millions, but billions, if not more outside our universe just because some powerhouse may want to research it. I am not trying to pull a fast one on you. This is simply the lowest I can go on an item like this… I am already reluctant to sell it as is, but I am a merchant at heart, and using such a valuable item myself would feel like a waste." Sultan sighed.

Jake kept frowning as he looked at it. Could he afford it? Well, yeah… but ten million wasn’t nothing. It was nearly a tenth of his total wealth on what would just be another epic-rarity item… Was it really worth it, unless he planned on just researching the item?

"Buy it and use it on the boots," Villy suddenly said from left-field.

Well, that was an easy way to settle it. "Fine, I’ll take it," Jake said, not even haggling.

From Villy’s tone of voice, it was a good item. He assumed his godly pal knew more than he did, especially considering how he told him to use it on boots he had earned from Villy’s dungeon. The Viper likely knew the origin of those boots. Or maybe it was a gag. An expensive gag. He wouldn’t put it past him.

"Pleasure doing business with you," Sultan said with a smile as they traded the item.

Jake suddenly felt like the man in front of him had gotten a bit stronger, and his smile even grew wider. Jake noted his race level had just increased by one too. Damn merchants and their completely legitimate leveling methods, Jake cursed internally.

The next hour or so was spent going through all the other knickknacks Sultan had. And he had a lot. Miranda and Neil bought some, while Lillian noted down everything and even nudged Miranda to buy some stuff for the city.

As for Jake? Jake bought three types of rare-rarity herbs, two of which increased Agility. The third increased Perception by 3 upon consumption. Sultan had exactly ten of each and said he had bought them specifically because he knew of Jake’s profession and class archetype. He wasn’t wrong, and Jake appreciated it.

What Jake appreciated even more was the one epic-rarity natural treasure Sultan had brought.

[Eye of the Libertas Eagle (Epic)] – An eye left behind by a slain Libertas Eagle, leaving all its Records within. The Libertas Eagle is especially known for its eyesight, which is said to allow the beast to spot its prey from nearly any distance. Looking into this eye is like staring into a far horizon. +25 Perception upon consumption.

It even had the best stat on it. Would Jake consume it? No, that would be gross. It was an eye. So he just had to avoid directly eating it. With these items, coupled with the time bananas and some other stuff, he knew his next objective.

Before the Treasure Hunt, he would craft some damn elixirs.

Chapter 63

Stupid Monkeys & Their Many Uses

Poisons? Now, poisons were easy mode. That was where Jake had quickly found his footing and created some cool stuff right away. It had felt natural to him, and he’d had so many skills to make it easier. Sure, there were many things he still couldn’t make, but he was pretty confident in his abilities.

Potions? Still kind of easy. Especially mana potions. Heck, all the three fundamental potions weren’t that complicated, and Jake had that shit down to a science by now. At least, he felt like he did, as his improvements were only marginal, and it would take him a long time to begin seeing tangible improvements.

Transmutations? Jake had found a way to be a dirty little cheater with those. He had no idea how to do a proper transmutation. He just pulled a fast one with his arcane affinity and made that affinity eat up enchantments on stuff to make the items more suitable for himself while making them useless for everyone else.

Besides that, he had done some other, more minor things. He had made a Beastorb, created weird concoctions to corrode a moon, and turned a moon shard into a small nuclear bomb of corruption and light. Also known as small things that are fun for the entire family.

Which all led to his next objective: elixirs, the staple of D-grade alchemists. It was one of the reasons D-grade alchemists were far more sought after, besides, of course, the better potions. Few professions could take natural stat-increasing treasures and improve or change them, but alchemists could. Well, cooks and some other professions could too, but alchemists tended to be the go-to profession for it.

It had been around two weeks since Sultan joined Haven, and Jake hadn’t heard much from the man besides him sending the stalker-slave woman with a delivery of herbs he had acquired from another merchant. Jake hadn’t even requested it, but he was happy to take the goods.

The woman had seemed oddly content with her situation, and Jake really didn’t want to question it. He had no idea what Miranda had done with that Gabi lady, and didn’t care about her either way. Right now, he wanted to focus solely on making elixirs.

Elixirs were quite a bit different from anything he had created before. Potions and poisons were far more—how could one put it?—temporary in nature. They were one-and-done kinds of things. Their energy only had to do its work for a brief period before fizzling out. Of course, there were poisons and likely also potions with more long-lasting effects, but nothing to the level of an elixir.

Elixirs had a strong feeling of permanence. A permanent effect on the Records of a person. A permanent increase in stats. For many other goods, Jake could infuse far more of himself into his creations, and it would be fine, but for elixirs, he needed a sense of separation. He needed to allow the ingredients to truly shine, with himself only being a facilitator of the process.

While that didn’t sound that hard or complicated, it sure as hell was. Because not only could Jake not come in and be a dominating force in the process, but the ingredients also had to be nice to each other and mesh. With many poisons, he could pretty much force them together with his will, but that wouldn’t work here.

Jake did have some advantages going into it, though. He had the eagle eye absorbed with Palate and was slowly learning about that, and a benefit of eating some of the bananas had been that he had gained a bit of understanding from those too.

Ultimately, this resulted in Jake making some damn solid progress. Jake burning through materials like he had no cares in the world also meant he didn’t have to waste much time considering things. He could just impulsively give it a go, and if it failed… tough luck. He could just try again. Also, snacking on ingredients was always a good time, even if some of the stuff tasted a bit weird.

Two weeks wasn’t a long time, but it wasn’t short either. In the beginning, Jake had struggled over if he should start with Agility- or Vitality-enhancing elixirs, but had eventually decided on Agility. Ultimately, he didn’t really wanna consume those for Vitality, but would happily chug down Agility elixirs. After that, he would make ones for Perception.

So even with difficulty, this meant that after two weeks of experimenting, three profession levels, and two race levels, he was confident in his first success. While it was difficult and a new challenge, Jake wasn’t an inexperienced alchemist anymore.

And, as much as he hated to admit it, his arcane affinity kinda did come to be of assistance again. At least, it helped him more easily tune into the permanence part of the creations by considering the stability inherent to his affinity. It wasn’t anything significant, just a nice nudge.

As for what ingredients he used? Well, to begin with, he stuck to those he had plenty of. In the last two days, he had moved on to also implementing those he had a bit fewer of. Tri-Lighttail Monkey Beastcores. Not that Jake lacked those… He had gone on a bit of a monkey genocide, after all, and even if he hadn’t taken corpses, he had gathered every single core.

Along with many other common-rarity and a few uncommon-rarity ingredients, he splurged a bit to increase his chance of success.

The crafting process itself went relatively easily. Jake used the core as the center, slowly melting it using his flames within the cauldron. Next, he added a few berries that were too weak to increase Agility by themselves but still contained the energy. After that, a bit of grass, a small piece of bark, and many leaves also went in. All of it was melted and pushed into the residue from the core.

Jake didn’t tell the core what to do, as the core residue was aligned towards Agility already, and the parts of the core not aligned towards Agility were quickly realigned by the ingredients. Jake had only failed three crafts using this method before, and the last time had been close. This time, it wasn’t close—it was a success.

*You have successfully crafted [Celerita Elixir (Common)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 112 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

Jake inspected the brew and nodded at the result. He barely noticed the level-up notifications and hadn’t bothered with them for these last two weeks. He probably should have, considering some of the implications they had.

[Celerita Elixir (Common)] – An elixir created from a mix of common ingredients, along with a few uncommon ones and a D-grade Beastcore of a Tri-Lighttail Monkey. Allows any who drink this elixir to receive some of the innate power of the materials, enhancing one’s Agility. +3 Agility upon consumption.

Requirements: D-Grade or higher.

He saw that this first batch only had enough for two elixirs. While that seemed terrible, it was the worth of two bananas. Not that his elixirs were as good as the bananas. There was one significant distinction: the requirement.

Anyone could eat a banana, while you had to be D-grade to get any use out of the elixir. Jake knew a lot of the difficulty around elixirs was related to allowing those weaker—especially those below D-grade—to benefit from them. Jake still had a ways to go before he could successfully craft those. Not that he was working towards it.

No, Jake would instead push directly for uncommon-rarity elixirs, and finally rare versions, before the Treasure Hunt.

He would use the eye and a few other items he hoped Sultan could procure in time for the rare version. Then, hopefully, he could also make a rare Vitality elixir with the Lifecore and the Lifevines from the blue fungus. But to do that, he would have to keep grinding.

As for what else was going on during this time? Well, Jake had been relegated to his porch, as the construction underground had really taken off. Jake had also learned that the reason Hank had delayed construction wasn’t that he had better things to do; it was because he had been close to his own profession evolution.

He had gained a new profession called General Foreman of Haven. Apparently, the profession was quite awesome and gave nearly as many stats as Miranda’s, which placed it well in the upper echelon of professions overall. The man wasn’t close to D-grade, though, having neglected his class entirely ever since he came to Haven. He had said he was done fighting, and while Jake didn’t understand it, he still chose to respect the man’s decision.

Anyway, after he evolved, Hank came back, and Jake’s underground complex continued making swift progress. Naturally, the alchemist who would own it had also been down to give some input. Jake himself had stopped interfering after that, instead sitting up at the pond with his cauldron and only spying through his sphere once in a while.

Being up there also allowed him to count whenever a new banana spawned on the tree, and Mystie’s automatic banana retrieval system captured one. Jake counted eleven right now. That’s right; he had managed to convince Sylphie not to eat them on sight, primarily through bribery and coaxing.

As for where the bird was these days? He really didn’t know. He hoped she was having fun, though, as she got closer and closer to becoming a fully-fledged D-grade hawk. The cute little bugger was probably out playing in the forest.

They grow up so fast…

The world was inherently unfair. The races struggled, doing everything they could to survive, but some had it harder than others. For example, if the leaders of a certain species fell, they would have to struggle to survive and rebuild, hoping a powerful alpha would not come by and claim their territory. This was rare, but could happen if the one who’d come to slay their leader consumed or took away the natural treasure they had originally gathered around.

This particular race’s leader had fallen, but their nest and hope for the next generation had been left untouched. A single of their Matriarchs had survived to rebuild with the hidden young, as she had been far belowground with them when the predator came through and annihilated all in his path. They grew fast, and before long, D-grades entered the forest to try and reclaim their territory.

No other beast had claimed it, as their natural treasure was gone. This didn’t mean that the territory was useless, though. On the contrary, there was an air of ancientness and the concept of time was more prominent there, making it an excellent place for these monkeys to live.

At least… it should’ve been.

The Tri-Lighttail Monkey jumped through the trees as it fled from its predator. It had been out with a group of its lesser brethren and had moved too far from the nest. It should have known better, but it hadn’t detected the foe till it was too late. Or, more accurately, it hadn’t recognized it was a foe until it was too late. For the predator had not been subtle.

A tornado had gone through, tearing into the trees. It wasn’t a powerful one, almost as if the summoner didn’t seek to do any damage with it but simply use it for aesthetic effects. It couldn’t be to hide itself. Surely not. That would be ridiculous.

But as ridiculous as it was, that tornado had turned into a frightening foe. A blast had slain one of the weaker monkeys nearly instantly, while a blade of wind cut into another. The Tri-Lighttail had tried to fight back, but it found that its weight magic did not have the effect it should. Nothing it could do worked.

What was ridiculous was that the one hunting it wasn’t a D-grade. It wasn’t meant to be the predator… yet it was. It was too fast, too strong, and its talons, wings, and magic cut into the Tri-Lighttail time and time again as it tried to fight back while fleeing back towards its home and the Matriarch. But deep down… it knew it wouldn’t make it.

Despite its small green form, the hawk was an utter monster.

Stupid monkey was mega bad at playing tag and super weak, even if it was like Mom and Dad. Sylphie had managed to sneak up on it super stealthily and attack with a mighty BAW! and a WHOOSH! Those had taken down the two bad guys with the bigger bad guy.

The big bad tried to do that stuff that made it harder to fly, but Sylphie used Green Shield to make it stop. Green Shield was nice. The stupid monkey then tried to throw stuff and hit Sylphie with its behind-ropes, but Sylphie was too fast and too smart for that!

Mom and Dad had told her that hunting the big baddies was dangerous, but she had followed them when hunting before, and they weren’t that tough. She could totally handle them! At least, this one she could… Some of them were still scary.

Sylphie wasn’t stupid. She asked the wind every time before she went for the baddie, and only attacked when the wind said it was okay. The wind was everpresent and nearly always answered. It wasn’t a speaky-thing like Uncle did, but more a whisper-thing like the… well, like the wind.

She kept flying after the monkey for a bit, whooshing it as it ran away with her super winds. It sometimes turned around to throw stuff, and the next time it did so, Sylphie used a super move. She cut the branch it was about to land on.

BUT!

It didn’t fall like it was supposed to! It kept flying forward like it didn’t care, which was super-duper unfair. Why did Sylphie fall down when she didn’t try to fly, and the monkey didn’t? It was probably cheating. It was like how Uncle cheated during tag all the time, making himself take super-long steps and making her snacks not move as they should. Super unfair!

Well, Sylphie always won in the end, because Sylphie never gave up! And she wouldn’t give up now, either, but instead show just how awesome she was. She made herself mega faster and flew forward as her talons began glowing green.

While Uncle was a bit weak, only really good at running away and playing with his smelly pot, he also tended to be very tough when hit. Mom and Dad also said he was. She thought she couldn’t damage him, but he said it was fine, so she wasn’t bad, and it wasn’t her fault when she accidentally… Sylphie still felt bad about it. Uncle had gotten hurt because her glowy-green talon-strike was too strong. She’d learned to only use that on the bad guys, like the stupid monkey throwing smelly stuff.

Uncle also didn’t like monkeys throwing smelly stuff—which was weird, because Uncle liked playing with a smelly pot, but maybe they were different? Different kinds of smelly? Sylphie figured it out. She was so smart.

One thing she had learned was that she had to get strong and defend Uncle so he could keep playing with her and his smelly pot. Sylphie liked Uncle; he was one of her three favorite people in the whole world. So in order to realize her goal, she had to beat up the bad monkey.

She flew close, and the monkey tried to get away, but she prevented that using her winds. It flailed and tried to hit with its tails but was blocked by the Green Shield. In the end, it had nothing more to use as the talons closed around its head.

As she struck, the talons became larger, and two of her glowing green claws dug into its eye sockets as it tried to struggle. It failed to get her off, and Sylphie dug into its brains and poured more power into her grip. Finally, she hit a tree, making her talons dig in deeper. She kept flying around with the struggling monkey for a bit longer, smashing it into tree after tree until it stopped moving and she got the good-job ding.

"Ree!" Sylphie screeched out in joy as she turned around to fly back home.

Hunting bad guys was super tiring, and Uncle had snacks at home. Oh, but she remembered to bring the not-so-tasty-anymore small core-thing from the monkey. Uncle liked those, and Sylphie got happier when Uncle was happy because she was one of the good guys.

Chapter 64

Singular Focus

Jake sat with a book in one hand, skimming through it as he stroked Sylphie’s feathers with the other. She lay napping on his lap, seemingly very content with the situation. She had been working hard as always, based on how she’d managed to bring back the core of a D-grade monkey. He felt an odd sense of pride that she’d managed to solo kill D-grades while still not a full-fledged D-grade herself.

She was getting there, though.

[Sylphian Eyas – lvl 91]

Considering how she only spent a bit of time every day hunting, it was impressive how she still got more than a level every two days. Hawkie had leveled far slower than she had. Of course, Sylphie could just sleep and reach level 100, but her hunting sped it up by quite a bit. Visually, she seemed to have settled on her “final form,” so to say.

A bit smaller than Hawkie, a good deal smaller than Mystie, and overall just a cute, cuddly, green, feathery ball of death. Others perhaps looked at her as something other than the adorable little thing she was, but Jake didn’t care about those people. He was just proud of how strong she was.

Was she as strong as Jake had been at her level? No. Not even close. He had killed D-grades a lot earlier, and the monkey she had hunted down had only been around level 100 to 105, as far as he could tell from the core. That didn’t make her weak, though. Far from it. On the contrary, she was a damn strong beast for her level, and he was sure she would only grow stronger as time went on.

From what Jake had seen of her fighting, she had extremely high-level skills and abilities but struggled with prolonged battles and keeping up the pressure. She consumed insane amounts of mana with practically all her skills, even if they were a bit overpowered. The green bubble she summoned to protect herself was especially impressive, and was in part the inspiration to Jake’s arcane barrier.

Ultimately, though, it didn’t matter. Jake didn’t need her to be strong; he just wanted her to be happy. He understood that happiness and power were often tied together in this new world, and Sylphie did seem to have an innate desire to grow more powerful. Jake would happily help foster that if it made her happy, and if not… he would protect her. She was already like family to him, which made him think about his “real” family. He hadn’t gone and seen them yet, even if he really should have. But… some parts of him were afraid.

Caleb had adjusted well, but how about his mother and father? Caleb said they were well, which had put his mind at ease, but he still worried. He especially worried about how they would receive him. Jake felt like he wasn’t the same person he’d been before the system. Far from it. He feared they wouldn’t recognize him, or would reject him. Shit, he had killed more humans than most of the famous serial killers from before the system.

It was likely a senseless worry, as their other son, the leader of a shadow-assassin cult, was accepted. So they had to be adapted to the new world at least a bit.

Jake wasn’t worried about Maja or his newborn nephew as much. He actually knew most medical issues from birth and all that were practically nonexistent post-system. His only worries there were if the two of them were safe, and if Jake knew one thing about his brother, it was that he would keep his family safe above everything else.

Also… if they were ever truly in trouble, Jake fully expected Villy to give him a heads-up. If not, the two of them would have issues. Villy also fully knew this and told Jake not to worry, but to focus on himself. Well, himself and the bird. Even Villy seemed to have taken a liking to Sylphie, seeing as he called her “interesting,” which was Villy-code for someone he liked.

The small hawk on his lap roused from her slumber and shook her feathers a bit as she looked up at Jake with her big eyes. Jake smiled back, rubbing her head and scratching her beneath her neck. She nuzzled up to his hand and looked to be enjoying it very much.

"You hungry?" he asked, getting a happy screech in reply as she flapped her wings in excitement.

Jake took out a pellet and offered it up to her. She gulped it down and nuzzled up to his chest.

"By the way, Sylphie, remember to not go too deep into the territory of those monkeys, and if you see one of the thin and long ones of them, get away from it. Those are pretty fast, and it may get dangerous, okay?" He knew the hawk would dive into the forest again soon.

She looked up at him with doubt, not entirely believing Jake’s advice.

"Trust me on this, okay?" he patiently explained. “Even your mom and dad can’t handle those without working together, so they may be a bit much for you for now, alright? I am not sure I could have taken them easily, if at all, before reaching D-grade myself.”

Sylphie looked up at him, still skeptical, but seemed to accept what he said. Jake nodded as he gave her another pat, and she got up, ready for another day of adventures. He saw her off with a smile as he dove into his work again.

It was the day he had made his first common-rarity elixir, and for the rest of the day, he wanted to practice that. He hadn’t consumed any of them yet, having chosen to wait. It wasn’t like Agility really helped with his alchemy, after all.

He had more than 600 stat points to fill with eating or drinking stuff, and he had already decided to have most of that be Agility and Perception. Perception would be the best due to the whole percentage amplifiers, but Agility was a close second because it was great for combat.

Besides, it wasn’t like he couldn’t get more titles or maybe skills to also enhance Agility down the line.

Anyway, for now, Jake dove into spamming out batches of Agility elixirs like there was no tomorrow. Then, when he felt well practiced, he would begin working on the uncommon-rarity version. It was a great plan, and he was sticking to it, and he was completely sure he hadn’t missed anything important.

Vilastromoz considered if he should remind him. Should he? Nah, Jake remembered. He did, right? Sometimes the Primordial hated that no effective mind-reading abilities existed—another hard rule of the system, and the sanctity of the Truesoul and all that. You could skim and even sometimes enter and read the memories with special skills, but that was more like watching a movie of the past.

Actually, it was something pretty close to what the Viper really wanted Jake to remember.

Path of the Heretic-Chosen wasn’t a normal skill. Not at all. In fact, he had never encountered an identical one before. Well, skills to experience the past were, as said, not that special, but the way this one did was just something else. It pulled out Records directly; it allowed Jake to see the entire situation—not just from the point of view of Vilastromoz, but also from other important actors and their interpretations of what had happened.

Even more striking was that Vilastromoz had no control over it. He knew that the Holy Church and many other factions liked to have these kinds of "experiences" for their members, but it was always a well-curated thing. It would show a predetermined moment, and it would be one highly regulated and "edited," so to say. But Path of the Heretic-Chosen? The god featured didn’t have a smidge of control. So it was as equally frustrating as it was interesting.

Nearly half as frustrating as how Jake had not even recognized he had reached level 110 in his profession and had unlocked another use of the skill. Maybe he couldn’t use it yet? Had the Viper missed him trying? Well, he couldn’t read his mind, so maybe? Maybe not?

Well, his head was in other places, primarily alchemy, so it wasn’t all bad. Jake still found time to relax with the Sylphian Eyas that was soon approaching level 100. Jake clearly cared for the bird, and Vilastromoz had to admit he could see the appeal. It was a powerful beast for its level, and Jake hadn’t even begun to realize how much he had affected it. Being born and growing up in his presence had some… peculiar effects. It wasn’t instinctively wary of him, for one thing. So yes, the hawk was also interesting for sure, but not as interesting as Path of the Heretic-Chosen.

Could Jake really have completely forgotten the skill because he was so damn focused on making some shit-tier elixirs and playing with an admittedly cute bird? Did he seriously prioritize that over a potential legendary skill and the ability to dive through time and space, experiencing the Records of the First Era and the rise of a Primordial?

No, that can’t be it.

That was exactly it.

Jake had completely forgotten the skill, as he was too engrossed in improving his elixirs, and the only breaks he gave himself were when Sylphie was back. Even those were spent reading books on elixirs. The books were from the dungeon, and he had to admit they weren’t that useful anymore, but they had to do for now.

Should he have remembered Path of the Heretic-Chosen? Probably, but his singular focus on elixirs wasn’t bad either. Not at all. He had entered a near trance-like state, only focusing on his alchemy and cutting everything else out.

Days passed as Jake grinded like never before. He churned out elixir after elixir and had a constant stream of ingredients coming in from Lillian, who monitored the System Store—including both system offerings and those of other people who sold through the store—as well as Sultan, who was also on the lookout.

Ten elixirs became twenty, twenty became forty, and forty became eighty. Soon, Jake had well over a hundred elixirs, all giving +3 Agility for anyone above D-grade. That was when Jake also switched to something else, primarily to introduce some diversity.

It took Jake less than thirty hours from when he switched to the first success.

*You have successfully crafted [Vitae Elixir (Common)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

[Vitae Elixir (Common)] – An elixir created from a mix of common ingredients, along with a few uncommon ones and a D-grade Monstercore of a Deepdweller Warrior. Allows any who drink this elixir to receive some of the innate power of the materials, enhancing one’s Vitality. +3 Vitality upon consumption.

Requirements: D-rank or higher.

These ones, Jake had no intentions of consuming himself at all. No, they were all for the System Store. Unfortunately, he couldn’t make as many due to the use of Deepdweller Warrior cores, which he had significantly fewer of, but he would have to make do for now. Well, all in all, it wasn’t an issue, as he had even more Deepdweller cores than monkey cores. He only used a Warrior’s for now due to how much more potent it was. When he got more skilled, he could switch to the regular ones. As for the Fungalmancer ones or the ones from the mini-bosses? He saved those for the uncommon and rare elixirs.

How much money he made, Jake didn’t know and didn’t care about. Jake just handed off the elixirs to Lillian by placing them outside his lodge, then had her sell them. Later, he learned that Sultan had bought a lot of them. Apparently, elixirs of all kinds were a massive rarity on Earth. Shit, any item that increased stats was a rarity.

Twenty-six days till the Treasure Hunt, Jake had another major success. He crafted an item he had hoped to make for a long time.

*You have successfully crafted [Sensus Elixir (Common)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

[Sensus Elixir (Common)] – An elixir created from a mix of common ingredients, along with a few uncommon ones and a D-grade Beastcore of a Sunshade Eagle. Allows any who drink this elixir to receive some of the innate power of the materials, enhancing one’s Perception. +3 Perception upon consumption.

Requirements: D-rank or higher.

The core had not come from any merchant or his own hunt, but had been delivered along with a dozen or so other cores of the same beast by Mystie and Hawkie. They managed to communicate that a canyon deeper within the forest was heavily populated with these eagles, and the two hawks primarily hunted those these days. Jake had a strong feeling neither Mystie nor Hawkie liked eagles very much.

Wait, don’t eagles hunt hawks? I guess it makes sense, then. Poetic revenge or something.

Anyway, they came by, took Sylphie with them, and returned within a few days with more cores before leaving again for a longer trip. He was limited in these cores, but for now, he would just make all he could. Oh, and these elixirs? They went straight to his belly.

You have assimilated a powerful energy of Perception.

+3 Perception

…

You have assimilated a powerful energy of Perception.

+3 Perception

At twenty-four days till the Treasure Hunt, Jake ran out of cores to use for his Perception elixirs. He ended up drinking twenty-three of them, meaning a total increase of 69 Perception.

Nice.

But him being out of materials didn’t mean he stopped. It just meant he began pushing for the uncommon-rarity version of the Agility-enhancing elixirs. This proved to be a quite different experience than other times he tried to push himself to upgrade a rarity. He dove in with an absolutely singular focus and didn’t hesitate to waste even rare-rarity materials—bananas included.

Jake went in with low expectations, but soon discovered something… The method was the same. All it took was more energy and better ingredients. Thinking about it, it actually made a lot of sense.

Why would one not just consume a lot of common-rarity elixirs and cap out that way? Jake had consumed over twenty without losing any effect. So perhaps that was why the system didn’t see any reason to make higher rarities of elixirs that much harder. It wasn’t like potions or poisons, where every rarity was a significant qualitative increase.

Elixirs were mainly just more quantity… and while it took some more control, focus, and finesse, it wasn’t that bad.

Nineteen days till the Treasure Hunt, he did it.

*You have successfully crafted [Celerita Elixir (Uncommon)] – A new kind of creation has been made. Bonus experience earned*

[Celerita Elixir (Uncommon)] – An elixir created from a mix of uncommon and rare ingredients as well as the D-grade Beastcore of a Tri-Lighttail Dervish. Allows any who drink this elixir to receive some of the innate power of the materials, enhancing one’s Agility. +10 Agility upon consumption.

Requirements: D-rank or higher.

Jake bottled up the two elixirs and received another notification. Another expected one with borderline little-to-no impact.

*Skill Upgraded*: [Craft Elixir (Common --> Uncommon)] – Potions for emergencies, flasks in preparation for the toughest of foes, and elixirs to build the foundation of power. Allows the alchemist to craft elixirs of uncommon rarity and below. Elixirs are able to grant those who consume them a permanent increase to stats. Must have suitable materials and equipment in order to create potions. Adds a small increase to the effectiveness of created elixirs based on Wisdom.

With another two elixirs in bottles, Jake didn’t hesitate to fire up another batch as he also began working on the other uncommon-rarity elixir—the one for Vitality. He got Vitality done, and was saving the Perception one for when he got more cores.

Fourteen days till the Treasure Hunt. Jake had been working like a goddamn uncommon-rarity elixir factory, and someone couldn’t wait any longer.

"Jake, for fuck's sake, check your notifications and check your goddamn Path of the Heretic-Chosen skill!" Villy suddenly yelled after Jake finished another batch.

"Wait, what?" Jake asked, looking around in confusion. Oh… right… levels.

Jake had to admit the last two weeks plus had kinda blended together, and he barely remembered anything besides alchemy. Even all his meetings with Miranda had been postponed, and he hadn’t really talked to anyone besides when someone came by with goods. Even then, it had barely been an acknowledgment of their presence. Sylphie, Hawkie, and Mystie hadn’t been back yet either, but he had a feeling they were fine.

He recognized that he had been a bit too focused and checked his notifications…

Oh.

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 113 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

…

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 119 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 124 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 120 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

It turned out that Jake going into a bit of a trance had worked out well for him. In his defense, he had only just gotten that last level thirty minutes ago.

Anyhow, Jake decided he should do this more often.

He wanted to go check out his new profession skill, but he had a feeling Villy really wanted him to check that Path of the Heretic-Chosen first.

Chapter 65

Presence

Jake opened up his system menu and went through all the stuff.

He had saved up a stupid amount of Free Points. 220 of them, to be exact. He should have probably just tossed them where they belonged, to begin with, but hey, better late than ever. As to where they belonged?

All in Perception!

Heck, if Jake were to do another of those weird Legacy trips from his Path of the Heretic-Chosen, it would be silly not to have as much Perception as possible to experience it fully. At least, that was what he kept telling himself to justify his questionable decision to just keep throwing everything in Perception. He just liked to do it, and his other stats had always been growing nicely, so it wasn’t that bad.

"Jake…" Villy’s voice sounded out before Jake got sidetracked again.

"Yeah, yeah, yeah. You know what? For you alone, I will check out my Path of the Heretic-Chosen before I pick my level 120 skill. Don’t say I never do anything for you!"

Jake shook his head and opened the menu thing. It wasn’t really a menu; Jake more just poked the skill and saw if it did anything.

He knew it wasn’t a sure thing that he could use the skill and potentially get an upgrade, but that he needed to reach some threshold he didn’t know about. He assumed he had reached the threshold for Palate nearly solely due to the Trial of Myriad Poisons, but he wasn’t sure about any of the other skills.

So he had to be honest—he was actually a bit surprised when the skill responded, and he knew he could activate it. A prompt came up before him.

Do you wish to experience the Legacy of the Malefic Viper? Uses remaining: 2

Jake stared at it for a while, wondering what skill it could be about. A part of him hoped Sense, but he seriously doubted it; it was only a faint, vain hope. Jake could also use more Perception.

"Yep, it works. Two uses too. I guess I’ll give it a go?" Jake said, semi-asking Villy.

"Go for it and tell me what you saw afterward," the god answered.

Jake nodded and accepted the prompt, and his vision went dark.

The council had convened, and they were ready to pass down judgment. They had attempted to scare off the beast several times, but it always returned. Where it had come from, they were unaware; one random day, it had entered the imperial oligarchy and begun ravaging it.

Yet it was not like the other beasts. Monsters born in the infinity of space were often simply beasts or unintelligent creatures that only sought to kill and consume. They were often weak for their level, and a single council member could take them down easily.

But… a council member had already fallen to this menace, forcing their hands. Sure, it had been the weakest council member, but it was still significant. It was a rarity they were forced to meet like this to begin with, especially in person.

Every single one of them were early B-grade powerhouses, and each had conquered their respective worlds long ago and founded factions with no rivals besides each other. In the end, an equilibrium had been reached, and now the war between their factions was simply a game to nurture new, worthwhile fighters. It was also a valuable source of experience for them as respective leaders.

"All agree, we spring the trap at Neonwell once the beast arrives?" a council member asked.

He was the most desperate, as the beast was now in his empire. In the last empire it had visited, the beast had slain the council member before moving on to find new challenges and claim all their national treasures. So, naturally, he feared he would be the next to fall without assistance.

"In agreement," one of the strongest council members said. However, even if none were strong enough to easily slay the others, that didn’t mean they were truly equal. The bribery to make this council member agree first had not been cheap…

"Fine," another agreed with a nod.

Two more nodded, and the last four also agreed after some hesitation, seeing as they didn’t want to be the only ones not participating. Once the beast was dead, that would reflect badly on them. The last time a council member had risen to B-grade and joined, he had gotten cocky, and… well, he hadn’t stayed a council member for long. Or alive, for that matter.

"We estimate the beast will reach there within the next two years, so let us prepare our defenses."

Jake’s vision shifted, and he saw a new planet. One entirely blue and glowing with energy, tens if not hundreds of times larger than even the Sun-sized Earth. It also looked almost crystalline, and very otherworldly. He saw all nine council members descend on the planet, and from there, his vision sped up. He saw the planet spin at high speeds as he followed it through space until, finally, the fateful day arrived.

A figure approached from far out in space. Wings beat as a shadow seemed to follow the creature, and a miasma marked its path, leaving death in its wake. It was a dark green dragon with spikes lining its body and two deep green eyes that observed the planet in the distance.

Jake recognized it as the form he had seen ascend from the planet on the mural back in the Challenge Dungeon. So, the Malefic Viper turned into a dragon at B-grade and left his home planet… Jake realized as he kept observing.

He hadn’t entered that state of extreme observation yet, so he knew this wasn’t the time. But he still kept careful watch and took it all in. At worst, it would be an interesting insight into B-grades, and at best, he could learn something from their battle besides what the skill intended.

The Malefic Viper stopped and observed the planet. He waited a bit and eventually landed on a large asteroid floating through space—the only one large enough for the several-hundred-meters-long beast. The Viper looked towards the planet once more. Did he know? Perhaps… perhaps not. Either way, he would use a true and tested opener.

Opening his maw, the dragon breathed in. Jake felt the mana in the atmosphere being vacuumed in from far and wide, and the draconic body began humming with energy. A green glow appeared around the mouth as a tiny ball of energy appeared… and then he breathed.

For a second, the world changed color. It flashed green as the Dragon’s Breath was released. Instinctively, Jake knew… this attack was a concept in itself. The Dragon’s Breath, the signature move of all dragons. He had always thought dragons to be majestic and kinda cool creatures that he totally wanted to hunt down…. but seeing one in action was different.

The breath took the form of a beam of green energy that headed straight for the planet, and Jake could already imagine the effect it would have. It would be like a giant meteor smashing down, scorching much of the surface with pure destruction.

At least… it would have, if it had hit.

Five spots down on the planet began glowing, and a barrier appeared in front of the beam, tens of thousands of kilometers into space. The council members who summoned it seemed to be aware it wouldn’t be enough, and soon five more identical ones were layered along with it, each barrier thousands of kilometers in diameter. It was a planetary defense of sorts.

A mighty explosion sounded out as the beam hit the first barrier, and it looked as if space itself collapsed on the impact point. Everything became warped, but the very next moment, Jake could see what was happening again, as space had seemingly repaired itself.

The first barrier was broken, and the second had already cracked. A second later, it gave out as the breath hit the third. That one only took a few seconds before it slowly eroded away, making it clear the breath held corrosive properties.

Barrier after barrier fell as the Malefic Viper kept using his Dragon’s Breath. When it hit the second-to-last barrier, a figure appeared behind the last one. He placed his hand on it, and the entire thing lit up with what looked like a magic circle inscribed upon it.

Just as the second-to-last barrier broke, he poured in energy, and the entire barrier got fired forward with incredible momentum towards the Viper. The breath simply wouldn’t have time to erode it in time, and the huge dragon was forced to dodge as the asteroid it had been sitting on was turned to cosmic dust.

Jake felt the impatience of the Viper as he flew forward down towards the planet.

His vision shifted once more, and Jake saw the eight other council members hidden in a weird spatial bubble of sorts behind one of the moons of the planet. All of them were hidden not just in the spatial bubble, but also under several arrays. They had been in there for over half a year, just waiting for this day.

Once the dragon got closer to the planet, another set of barriers activated. However, this one was not meant to keep the beast out—but to keep it in.

At the same time, a third set activated closer to the surface of the planet, effectively making a closed circle of space around the planet. Trapped within were ten beings—the Viper and nine council members.

While Jake couldn’t even use Identify on anything, he had a feeling they were all roughly the same level. At least, none of the council members looked worried, as Jake assumed they could see the level of the Viper. Unfortunately for them, they were under an assumption… One Jake perfectly understood. One he would have made many times without his instincts telling him otherwise.

These nine council members were absolute geniuses of their worlds. They were the strongest. They had great classes and professions, and had always fought above their own level. A beast of an equal level was just another easy prey to them. Sure, they had met variants and stuff, but out in the real world, they weren’t a dime a dozen.

So they went forth with absolute confidence and trapped the dragon within the barrier for a nine-versus-one battle. They weren’t aware, but Jake felt it. The Malefic Viper wasn’t the one trapped in there with them.

They were trapped in there with him.

All nine moved to attack. Jake saw attacks he couldn’t fully understand: flames that melted colors, winds of space mana that tore up the fabric of reality, and many more types of magic. Each was more useless than the last against the scales of the dragon, as they seemed to almost drink up the magic.

The attackers were taken aback by the lack of effectiveness. Yet hope was not lost. One of their members teleported right above the head of the beast and swung down with his hammer, hoping to—

It was blocked as the dragon raised his claws, making it evident it was not only tough versus magic. But surely, the Viper’s offensive capabilities besides the signature Dragon’s Breath would be—

Mana manifested in mid-air as the Malefic Viper counterattacked with green explosions. Meanwhile, a miasma of poison seeped out from the dragon wings and overtook the area. His claws swung and forced the one with the hammer to retreat with a scratch on his arm.

The exchange was brief, yet it had shocked the nine of them. But… that seemed to be enough. A seed was planted. One of doubt. One where death or severe injury was a possibility. Jake knew this because the time had come.

He intimately felt everything—not just what the Viper experienced, but also the nine. He knew the Viper had gone all-out from the start, even boosting himself right from the get-go to appear as strong as possible. This was planned.

Jake felt fear.

Anticipation.

Doubt.

Greed.

Anger.

Hesitation.

Bloodlust.

But more than anything… he felt pride.

A pride that manifested as an aura—a presence—blanketed the area, the nine council members within it. The entire atmosphere seemed to shift.

"Pathetic creatures," the Viper’s voice echoed through space. "How dare such weaklings think themselves conquerers? Kings? Emperors? You are nothing but prey to fuel my path. Be honored, for that is truly the greatest purpose your lives could have. Take joy as I devour you one by one. Do not fear for all which you have built, for it shall follow you. Embrace desolation, for it is the only end that awaits you and everything you have created. Embrace death. Embrace your fate. Embrace despair."

Every word made space vibrate; every syllable tore into the souls of the nine council members. Tore into their wills and their minds. All of it through the presence that affected the entire area. Mana in the presence? Jake rhetorically asked himself as he felt it.

Presences weren’t anything new. Everyone had one; it just came with getting stronger. It could become more prominent in some scenarios, such as when Jake felt a strong sense of bloodlust, and his presence would reflect it. In general, strong emotions would be reflected in your presence to some extent.

However, this was different. This was not that passive presence. This one felt alive. It was filled with the will and pride of the Malefic Viper. It didn’t simply communicate an emotion, but instead tore into the nine council members’ minds. Even more than that, it contained mana—something a presence normally never would—and to be fair, Jake wasn’t even aware it could.

The battle had barely begun, and it was far from over. Jake estimated the battle would be around equal and hard-fought by both sides, though he did believe the Viper would win. Still, the nine could at least get away. The majority, anyway.

Yet all of them stood stunned for a moment. Immobilized by the presence of the Viper. Jake felt what they felt… A sense of fear, despair, and hopelessness. Like no matter what they did against the Viper, nothing would work. It was like how Jake had felt against the King of the Forest… which actually made him think the Unique Lifeform had a similar skill.

It was a spell they would break out of soon enough… but—

The Malefic Viper’s neck snapped forward. A long fang penetrated straight through the chest of one of the council members as the Viper bit into him, leaving a barrel-sized hole due to the size difference. At the same time, the Viper fired out eight of the long spikes on his body—one for each council member.

Magic also began manifesting around the dragon. It was even more powerful and collected far faster than before, as the presence affected not only the other living beings within, but even the Viper himself and the area as a whole. The magic attacks all coalesced and headed for the eight council members together with the spikes.

All attacks hit at once.

All of them were thrown out of their stupor simultaneously.

All of them were now badly poisoned.

In a single moment, the tides had turned. An equal battle had become a one-sided one, as that sliver of doubt remained. The poison only added to the helplessness.

What transpired after that wasn’t a fight but a slaughter. Six council members died, and three ended up fleeing, but Jake was certain they, too, would be hunted down in time.

For the Pride of the Malefic Viper would not allow any of his prey to escape. He had pronounced their deaths, and he would carry out the sentence.

This time was a lot different than the last time he’d used Path of the Heretic-Chosen. Jake had experienced a far longer span of time, and even more emotions than ever before—from all parties involved.

Jake had felt it all, and he understood it. He actually questioned why he had never done what the Viper did already. Well, he realized he couldn’t have, as it wasn’t that easy… unless you experienced doing it firsthand. As long as you got the basic concept, it was simplicity itself.

Perhaps pride was just something Jake had plenty of. Perhaps he was specifically suited to imposing his will upon the world.

It wasn’t because the time-rewind aspect of the skill hadn’t worked this time or hadn’t been there. It just hadn’t been needed.

Because Jake got it the first time around.

[Pride of the Malefic Viper (Ancient --> Legendary)]

Jake felt his consciousness slowly return to the real world as the dragon headed down towards the crystalline planet below. He felt the Viper. He knew the intent. So he was certain.

The planet would turn into just another desolate wasteland.

Just like all those the Malefic Viper had come across before.

Chapter 66

Memories of (Questionable) Past Deeds

Jake returned to his lodge as if nothing had happened. Barely any time had passed in the real world during his journey through time and space. It had been another great showcase of the higher level of power, even if it all had gone past fast, and to be honest, not much had happened. Besides, it wasn’t like just seeing someone summon a huge barrier taught Jake how to. If it did, wouldn’t the easiest way to make new powerhouses just involve participating in movie marathons?

No, the reason why the Path of the Heretic-Chosen skill was so good was that Jake could directly experience everything from all points of view. He could feel the flow of the energy, and it was even partly adapted to his body. It was a shortcut to an upgrade, and pretty much explained exactly what he had to understand and do. That didn’t mean Jake always got it—he nearly hadn’t with Palate—but it was an incredibly useful experience. Shit, even if he had failed to comprehend Palate, he would still have gotten hints or just used a second attempt of the skill to "get it."

This time around had been far easier. Perhaps it was because it was simply doing things he already did and merging those things to make something better. This new ability was just infusing his presence with will and mana. Super simple stuff, that one, and it probably came far too easy to Jake.

Looking at the skill upgrade, he had to admit… the description was getting stupidly long. Would all his legendary skills from the Malefic Viper end up being like this?

[Pride of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – The arrogance and strong will of the Malefic Viper is known throughout the multiverse. Now, you have learned to take after him, your own pride now a tangible weapon. Allows the alchemist to force their will upon the world far more easily. Significantly increases the effect of all Words of Power spoken. Your pride increases all resistance to any kind of mind-affecting effects, but be warned that it wanes in despair. Passively provides 1 Willpower per level in Prodigious Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your will be truth, your pride eternal.

-->

[Pride of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – The arrogance and strong will of the Malefic Viper is known throughout the multiverse, and all of existence is made to quake in fear in his presence. Now, you have learned to take after him, your own pride a tangible weapon as you demand of the world to bend in your presence. Allows the alchemist to far more easily force their will upon the world. Significantly increases the effect of all Words of Power spoken. By channeling mana, you can make your presence no longer simply a warning, but a weapon to target the psyche of your foes directly. During this time, forcing your will upon the world in any area affected by your presence becomes even easier than before. Your pride increases all resistance to any kind of mind-affecting effects, but be warned that it wanes in despair. All effects of the mental-attack increase are based on the target’s vulnerability, the nature of your mental attack, and the disparity in Willpower between you and your foe. Passively provides 3 Willpower per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your will be truth, your pride eternal.

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 121 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 125 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

* ‘DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 122 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points

Jake had to admit that the two levels also came as a slight surprise, though a welcome one. Upgrading skills had always earned him experience points, but this one just felt too easy.

Another thing that surprised him was that Pride had been the skill in question to be upgraded. Jake hadn’t even thought that an option. He was sure Sense or maybe even Blood or Sagacity would be the next ones to upgrade. Perhaps even Touch if he kept transmuting stuff? Pride hadn’t even been on the radar.

As for what the improved skill could now be used for? Well, it was a mental attack, pure and simple. But not only that—the part about forcing his will upon the world affected by his presence was perhaps even more valuable. All it effectively meant was that Jake could do magic faster outside of his body. At least, that was how he read it.

Something to test for sure.

In fact, he had a lot to test. How much mana would it cost? How effective was it? The skill also didn’t directly mention any stat-scaling, but considering how it basically just made Willpower more effective, that kind of made sense. Well, it did mention it when it came to the mental attack specifically, but not any of the other parts.

He really wanted to go test shit, but he was interrupted before he had the chance.

Jake felt Villy’s presence descend, bringing with it the curiosity of the god he had just seen in a flashback.

"So, how did it go?" Villy asked with an emotion Jake couldn’t quite place. "Anything interesting? Did you get an upgrade?"

"Wow, one at a time. Yeah, it went well, yes, it was interesting, and I upgraded Pride to legendary rarity. Something about infusing my presence with mana, making it stronger, and doing mental attacks and stuff. Oh, and easier application of my will within my presence during this infusion.”

"Ah, I see. I guess that’s good to get, though it isn’t exactly anything new, now, is it? You also seem to be using your bloodlust and presence as a weapon quite effectively already.”

Jake frowned, a bit surprised. "No, I don’t?"

"Yeah, you one hundred percent do. All the time. The space mage attacking your little lodge was perhaps the most prominent time. It isn’t the most effective weapon, but you sure do use it to throw your opponent off and intimidate them. It’s pretty normal to do, and it makes sense Pride got upgraded. It wouldn’t have surprised me if you got it before Palate, either, with or without the Path of the Heretic-Chosen skill."

"That’s not an attack, though; that’s just something that happens. I see others do it too. Everyone gives off a passive presence. The Sword Saint’s felt sharp and intimidating; Jacob’s felt warm and inviting. Everyone just has them.”

"True, to some extent. The Augur’s is due to a skill, though, so you can’t really count that one. As for that Sword Saint? He is a little monster just like you, so that’s why he has one so prominent.”

"Huh…" Jake mumbled, scratching his chin. Was it really just something he did? "So, it’s a bit of a waste besides the stats? Not that I complain about free upgrades."

"No, far from a waste. Jake, skills that boost stuff you already do are great, especially if they don’t take a skill slot. Why do you think mine do so many different things? Also, it employs some concepts your crude intimidation doesn’t. But, trust me, it’s a good one, and that presence skill helped a lot throughout my years as a wee little dragon."

"Speaking of you as a wee little dragon," Jake began, snickering. "Saw your fight with some people who called themselves council members. Early B-grade, crystal planet. I heard your speech to scare them… Not gonna lie, kinda cringe."

"Oh… that time…" the Viper said, sounding a bit apprehensive. "Yeah… not many of my proudest moments in those times. Sure, I grew in power rapidly, but it’s a moment of my life I don’t really look back at fondly anymore. I had some issues at the time, I guess."

"Issues besides being a bit of a dick and killing anything you came across? Actually, why even do that? What purpose was there behind destroying that crystal planet?"

"Purpose… There was one, but it wasn’t a good one. As I said, I didn't do it for reasons I am now proud of. Really. I guess some context is in order. Remember that mural that depicted when I first entered B-grade and became a dragon?" the Viper asked rhetorically. "I hadn’t just been sitting there for a bit. Towards the end of C-grade, I managed to effectively destroy my planet. I consumed all the natural treasures, killed all creatures I came across until all that remained were the occasional weak elemental spawning. Not a single trace of biological life remained, and I was alone."

"Why didn’t you just leave?" Jake asked curiously. "You were C-grade. Peak C-grade. I am sure you would’ve been able to survive traveling through space, as there was nothing left in your old world."

"You are privy to the knowledge that was even a viable option. I was not. I had only ever known that world. I thought I had killed all other life in existence. I thought I would die there, alone on a planet I myself had destroyed. I thought that was the fate I had created for myself. So I sat on that mountain—and not just for a couple of years. I sat alone for millennia, simply staring into space, wondering if something would come. A new challenge would appear. New life would grow. Perhaps an elemental would finally become able to rival me? But no, nothing ever happened."

Jake frowned as he heard the Viper speak, and he could hear that these weren’t at all comfortable memories for him to share. It was the kind of knowledge he didn’t spread throughout the Order, and Jake doubted many knew. So he chose not to interrupt the Viper’s offloading.

"During those years, I didn’t experience many positive emotions. Loneliness, self-pity, and sadness… but more than anything, anger. Anger at the world for rewarding my path so far, only to so cruelly cut me off and leave me with nothing on a broken planet to slowly wither away. Angry at the system for even appearing and taking away my choice of dying as an unknowing snake. Angry at being forced to exist as a sapient creature. I hated the world and wished to see it destroyed… and in a twist of irony, the system awarded that. A skill upgraded, a level gained, an evolution granted and unlocked. With that race also came a skill that made me aware of other life in the world. It gave me the courage to leave… Courage to cause destruction elsewhere.

"My race name? Calamitous Banespike Dragon. The power was overwhelming. My path was set for me, but like your class has restrictions, so did my race. My entire existence. However, they weren’t so much restrictions as they were simply an amplification of that hatred. Every act of destruction fueled me with power and levels; every planet left a broken shell was my gain. This was my path, and at the time, I embraced it. Every movement I made, every plan or strategy I concocted… all of them had the goal of causing more destruction. Even my alchemy fell to the wayside, as I couldn’t sit still long enough to practice. I simply felt like I couldn’t coexist with the rest of the world, and rather than die, I would rather see everything else destroyed."

There had been more emotion in his voice these last few minutes than nearly all the time Jake had spent with the Viper collectively. The god had chosen to be open with Jake… Perhaps he felt like his Chosen would find out a lot of these things in due time. Or perhaps… he didn’t want to be judged as harshly. Or maybe because he wanted exactly that, considering Jake was Jake.

"That sounds like an utterly moronic mindset, even for a depressed dragon throwing a tantrum," Jake curtly said, shaking his head. "What was the end goal? To destroy everything again like the first time? To end up sitting in an empty universe of nothingness? Sounds like a zero-out-of-ten plan. Also, was the experience even that good from destroying an entire planet? Seems like absolute overkill and just causing unnecessary destruction and suffering."

A few seconds passed before the Viper answered, "True. I also came to realize the path I was on didn’t make sense in the long run. And if it was worth it to destroy a planet? For me back then, a single smidge of experience or a brief moment of enjoyment was enough reason to cause any amount of suffering or destruction. When nothing matters, why care about proportions? I simply destroyed and consumed like any other common beast, and the system awarded me every step of the way. Yet it also rewarded me when I stopped and began fixing my fucked-up state of mind." Villy spoke patiently, not at all vexed by Jake’s words. In fact…

"Also, Jake, calling a god that can destroy you at a moment’s notice a moronic, depressed dragon throwing a tantrum could totally get you killed. Even if it is the truth. Either way, I appreciate the honesty."

"Beating around the bush never suited me well. Anyway, what put you back on the so-called right track? Some wondrous moment of enlightenment? Some majestic encounter with a fated person? Oh, don’t tell me you came across a natural treasure that opened your eyes to the beauty of the world?" Jake chuckled.

"You may be closer than you think. Also, not telling. You can try if that skill of yours makes you see it. Though so far, it hasn’t picked moments of extreme importance, just moments where the skill was deployed with an extremely high level of effectiveness. While mental attacks with the presence are good, there are equally as many encounters where it did jack shit, so be warned."

"Damn. Even if I don’t, I’m just gonna make you tell me someday." Jake smiled, leaned back, and looked up towards the sky. "By the way, when can I leave the 93rd Universe? And when can people come in?”

"Well, you can leave once you figure out a way to do so. Nothing stops you besides it being hard as fuck to get back, which is the primary reason no faction has had people leave yet. As for non-natives, I’m not sure when they can come and go. It tends to open up rather slowly, with those weaker able to enter earlier than others. Probably not overly long, though. The main challenge is still transportation, as it is highly dependent on what you are capable of doing on your end." The Viper seemed more than happy to completely change the subject.

"Wait, so I could technically leave now?" Jake asked, surprised.

"Yep, I could likely have that space mage of yours fix up a magic circle to allow a quick one-way ticket to the First Universe pretty fast. Of course, you won’t be able to go back, and you will miss the Treasure Hunt and all subsequent events due to being stuck here, so I wouldn’t recommend it. Let’s talk about it after all those fun system events and when we have a nice two-way connection ready." Villy sounded as though he was half-joking, half-warning Jake to not even consider going yet.

"Relax, man; I don’t wanna miss the Treasure Hunt for the world. I’ll come by when the time is right, and not a moment earlier.”

The mood had turned a lot better with the unrelated talks, but Villy still brought it back to the main topic.

"So… you still had a use of that Path skill remaining, right?"

"Yep, I got one use left."

"Better get it done, then."

"Nah, I can’t."

"… And why not?"

"Doesn’t work. I poked it already; the skill doesn’t respond."

"You poked it?"

"Super hard too. Still no response."

"Huh."

"Yep."

"Well, see you, then, and thanks for the chat," Villy said as he figuratively waved goodbye.

"I’ll get to choosing skills, then. Thanks as always, and take care. See ya around."

Jake just smiled as he moved on to something equally as important.

*Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper profession skills available*

Chapter 67

Skill Choices Are Hard

After a good conversation with his resident god, nothing was better than a new skill selection.

Jake did want to use Path of the Heretical Chosen right away again, but the skill didn’t respond. He assumed he didn’t meet that magical unknown threshold, as it didn’t feel like the skill had a cooldown or some other limitation.

Jake had gotten some inspiration besides Pride. The moment all those magic attacks had hit the scales of the Viper, in particular, gave him some food for thought. All of that was for later, though, because now… now it was skill-selection time!

*Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper profession skills available*

Every skill selection was exciting to Jake, as he liked seeing what the system had cooked up. He already knew he would avoid all the shitty religious skills and stick to alchemy. A hallmark of his profession so far had been an overflow of high-rarity skills that he thought sucked ass because they wanted him to become a priest or some shit.

So with tempered expectations, he went into the skill selection. The first one was a very familiar one, but in a new and improved version.

[Transmute (Rare)] - Attempt to transmute any object into one of greater value. Transmutation is an ancient art used by alchemists since the beginning of time. Must have suitable materials. Transmute does not require any additional tools or equipment, but the skill’s effect can be amplified with the use of certain catalysts. Adds a small increase to the effectiveness and chance of success of attempted transmutations based on Wisdom.

That one brought Jake back a long time. Man, when was it, level 10? Heh, been a while, he thought with nostalgia. Ah, being trapped in a Challenge Dungeon on a timer that counted down toward death by poison. Good times.

Back then, Jake hadn’t really thought much about transmutation. He’d been a bit busy with the whole not-dying thing. With all the other skills also coming along, he had never picked it up until he eventually upgraded Touch of the Malefic Viper.

Would this skill benefit him? For sure. Jake wasn’t sure exactly what he could properly transmute, and his current way of transmuting things was crude as fuck and pretty much just a way of screwing up items to make them Soulbound to himself.

And to be honest, that was good enough for now. The only thing interesting about this choice was that it proved Jake had the potential to pick up old skills he passed on for higher-rarity versions now. That wasn’t enough of a reason to pick Transmute, though.

Hence, Jake moved on. The next skill was also a rare-rarity one.

[Refine Core (Rare)] – Cores from beasts or many other types of monsters are one of the most numerous kinds of treasures in the world, but does that mean one must simply accept their current state? Allows the alchemist to refine cores and empower the Records within. Refined cores will, in most cases, be more effective, and you can also choose to amplify specific effects. Adds a small increase to the effectiveness of Refine Core based on Wisdom, Willpower, and Intelligence.

Now there was a skill Jake knew a lot about already. It was one he had come across in many books when studying elixirs and even other unrelated books. It was mentioned nearly everywhere. The reason?

Everyone fucking had it.

Not even all alchemists. Everyone.

Blacksmiths, leatherworkers, tailors, jewelers, even the damn cooks had it offered. It was just one of those skills that was useful to everyone, as the use of cores was so universal. Practically every crafting profession would get it at some point, and the only impressive thing was that Jake could get it as rare rarity right off the bat, as he had read it came as uncommon rarity by default.

Now, just because something is popular doesn’t mean it’s bad. In fact, many things tend to get popular because they’re good. Movies, games, brands, and even things like books. Of course, sometimes they only get lucky because the consumers don’t know better and keep consuming products despite the obvious lack of quality. Luckily, this skill was not one such case.

This skill was picked because it was genuinely so damn useful. Enhancing Records of anything was just too valuable to pass up on. So, if Jake was logical, he should get it just for the ability to do it himself, and likely with better results than anyone else around.

One thing to also note was that this skill was not easily replicated without a skill. Not at all.

In summary, Jake kind of knew he would need this eventually, and it would be up to the last three skills if he just went with it or not. The next one was a step up, being an epic-rarity skill and an upgrade to one of his existing skills.

[Arcane Alchemist’s Purification(Epic)] – Your skill has evolved, and by deploying your arcane energy, you can stabilize the existing properties and destroy the unwanted. Attempt to purify any alchemical ingredient and reduce it to its most basic state while stabilizing it, or use Arcane Purification to eliminate unwanted properties from an ingredient, making it purer. Must have suitable ingredients. Purification does not require any additional tools or equipment, but the skill’s effect can be amplified with the use of certain catalysts. Adds a minor increase to the effectiveness and chance of success of attempted purifications based on Wisdom and Intelligence.

WARNING: This skill is unlocked by, and will serve as an upgrade to, your Alchemist’s Purification.

This one just felt more like a slap in the face than an actual skill offering. What the fuck had Jake been doing with his Alchemist’s Purification all this time to not get at least one damn upgrade to it? Seriously, this skill spelled out how to improve it, and it was so damn obvious.

His arcane affinity was all about destroying stuff or being super stable. Most often a mix of those two. So why didn’t he use that destruction on Purification, considering what the skill did was practically destroying an ingredient’s unwanted properties? Man, he would have to get that shit done.

Naturally, he didn’t pick the skill. It looked like one he could easily upgrade himself without losing a skill choice. It wasn’t like Mark of the Avaricious Arcane Hunter, where he had a super-valuable skill he could upgrade—one he had no idea how to upgrade by himself.

Jake moved on to the next skill. This one was ancient rarity. Surely it would be great?

[Heretical Ritualism of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – Claim power without reverence, sacrifice to none but your own will, and—

It wasn’t great.

No, just no. Fuck that; I read the last ritual skill, so fuck off already with that shit, Jake thought as he shook his head. When would the system understand he wasn’t going to be a fanatical maniac who would sacrifice his planet in some huge ritual?

Actually… maybe he should stop joking about doing that? Nah, it should be fine. He swiftly moved on to the last skill—a legendary-rarity one.

[Legacy Teachings of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist (Legendary)] – To be taught by a Chosen is an honor most would embrace wholeheartedly. To be taught by a heretic is a crime most would shun. But to be taught by a Heretic-Chosen is to learn both the endorsed and the unorthodox, heretical knowledge at once. A true paradox you can now pass onto others. Allows you to far more easily convey knowledge of alchemy and your path to others, and your teachings will have a larger impact on the paths of others. Allows those who listen to your teachings to earn experience and Records, and rewards you for their progress. The time to pass down your Legacy and your Records begins now, as you spread your unique path. Adds a noticeable increase to the effectiveness of Legacy Teachings of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist based on Wisdom and Willpower.

Finally, it had come. Jake had expected but also feared this would one day happen. The day where the system would try to force upon him the same title as his little brother, which would inadvertently lead to teasing about Jake just being a copycat.

In Jake’s defense, his brother was a schoolteacher, while Jake would be a teacher of being a dick to gods and cool-ass alchemy. In a school context, he would be the most irresponsible chemistry teacher around, just telling people to throw shit together and hoping it didn’t explode. Also known as everyone’s favorite teacher.

Back on topic, Jake truly wasn’t sure what to think about the legendary skill. The reason he viewed it as expected was that… well, it was pretty much a staple of D-grade to get some teaching skill to begin offering pointers to those hopeless E and—god help us all—F-grades. Someone needed to teach them how to brew stuff good and concoct poison even gooder.

So he had known this would appear sooner or later; he just hadn’t expected it to be legendary rarity right off the bat. He quickly came to understand why, though. It wasn’t just a simple teaching skill… It was one meant to pass down a Legacy. To spread a path.

The system clearly liked unique paths. It wanted Jake to spread Records about himself and teach others, even if Jake was pretty damn sure his teachings about being a Heretic-Chosen weren’t the most useful.

What should he do? Go up to people and say, "So, yeah, just meet a Primordial, and then don’t really care about them being a Primordial. You only need to be immune to their passive presence and suppression, be kind of weird, be able to detect if the god will be open to your antics, and hope they end up liking you and not just killing you anyway. Good luck."

Yeah, that wasn’t gonna fly. It would probably get a lot of people killed, though. Or maybe not? All the gods Jake had met so far had been pretty chill and seemed okay with him just treating them like people. But, of course, he knew this was primarily due to him being the Chosen of the Malefic Viper, so he just borrowed his friend’s clout.

Anyway, would Jake use this teaching skill? Maybe. It said it helped him teach alchemical knowledge but also stuff about his path, so did that also mean other stuff? Like philosophy stuff and the One True Path of putting every single free point into Perception?

Jokes aside, Jake had a hard time imagining himself as a teacher of any kind. He was fine with giving advice and pointers here and there, but if he imagined himself in front of a classroom of hopefuls, he could only cringe. He remembered this one time Jacob had had him come along to a university to talk about how great their workplace was, trying to convince the innocent students to get unpaid internships. Jake had only spoken for like five minutes, while Jacob spoke for one and a half hours, but Jake had still hated it.

Yet… that legendary tag. It also said it would reward Jake for the progress of those he taught. That was kind of nice. He just had to find someone to teach, or—equally as importantly—someone who wanted to actually learn from him. Considering how shitty a teacher Jake would be, he doubted he could find anyone.

Despite so many reasons not to, Jake just found it hard to resist. There was also an additional reason in the form of his race. Jake was a human—a shocker to everyone—and with that came a certain race skill.

[Legacy of Man (Unique)] – The human race has been around since the very First Era, and has stood on the pinnacle from the beginning. This is not simply due to extraordinary individuals in your midst, but your ability to stand on the shoulders of your ancestors and pass down Records. While each human’s lifespan may be short, your race’s collective knowledge is perennial, and through generations, humanity will prevail. Allows you to far more effectively pass down Records and makes anyone you teach far more likely to unlock new paths.

As a human, Jake was practically made to teach others. The system, at least, believed him to be.

He ended up just sitting there for a bit, mulling over the skills. He even went back a bit and saw other potential choices. Should he just take teachings? Maybe he’d want to in the future. He could see it as a new challenge, maybe? If he did a good job, it would reward him too, hopefully with more than just the satisfaction of seeing a student succeed.

Then again, Refine Core was a great skill. Maybe he could even find a way to upgrade it further. It would improve his elixirs for sure and have many other uses.

Skill choices are hard... Jake complained internally. In the end, he just went back to the best method: a coin toss.

Jake took out a coin.

Heads for Legacy Teachings of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist. Tails for Refine Core.

He flipped the coin, which flew nearly ten meters into the air and spun at incredibly high speeds. Jake sighed and nodded as he picked Legacy Teachings of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist.

The coin landed a few seconds later on heads.

I guess that settles it, he thought as he felt the knowledge of the skill enter his head. There wasn’t much, and it wasn’t a skill he would use here and now… but he had it.

Anyway.

Time to test out his new Pride upgrade and churn out some more elixirs to reach his goals before the Treasure Hunt.

While Jake was back at Haven grinding out levels, a group of three was deep in the forest.

Three flying figures soared through the air, chasing a large eagle. The eagle was nearly six meters from tail to beak, with long, powerful talons and a bulky body. It was physically more powerful than the three hawks chasing it combined, but what it had in brawn it lacked in magical prowess.

The three hawks were naturally Sylphie, Hawkie, and Mystie, and their foe was a Sunshade Eagle with a higher level than any of them.

[Sunshade Eagle – lvl 139]

Sylphie was still only level 99, so she wasn’t the primary damage dealer, but just there for support and the occasional strong hit that still did a bit of damage. It was mainly Hawkie and Mystie doing everything to allow her to land some hits to help her reach level 100 soon.

They had stayed on the outskirts of the canyon for the most part, but this time they’d delved deeper to find stronger prey. The hawk family had found what they wanted. These eagles tended to be easy to hunt down, as they always stuck to themselves and weren’t overly powerful. They didn’t have any noticeable magic either. The Sunshade in their name referenced their ability to fly high and appear almost invisible while in direct sunlight, only leaving a patch of shade.

It didn’t take long before the eagle succumbed to its accumulated wounds, finally dying to a blast from Mystie and a blade of air from Hawkie. The beast impressively kept flying till its very last moments, hoping to get away. Away… or back somewhere.

All three hawks felt it—a natural treasure. The two older hawks stopped in their tracks, aware of what this could mean. They were wiser than most other beasts. They had the Wisdom that comes with age and experience.

Their third member didn’t. Sylphie made a beeline for the aura of the natural treasure, her parents screeching at her to stop. They were already too late, as Sylphie had been a bit ahead of them from the start, and they could only chase after the unrestrained young hawk.

Hawkie caught up to Sylpie quickly and cut in front of her to make her stop, which she did. She looked confused but also a little embarrassed as Hawkie threw her a look. Mystie joined them soon after.

However, they didn’t have time to dally. Hawkie motioned for them to hurry up and get away before the—

“SCREEEECH!”

—local alpha detected them.

Chapter 68

Birds of Prey

Jake hummed as he finished up another batch of elixirs. It had been a few days since he got the new skill and the Pride upgrade, and he had spent this time practicing that skill and doing alchemy. He hadn’t used that teaching skill at all. Mainly because he hadn’t spoken to or interacted with anyone.

His practice with Pride of the Malefic Viper had been pretty simple. Infusing his presence with mana came naturally to him due to the instinctive knowledge from the skill, and the effect was quite prominent. He felt like everything around him became more familiar to him when he did it, and summoning magic around him became far more effortless. Shit, he could make more Arcane Bolts than ever while having the presence active.

There was one minor issue, though. It drained Jake’s mana pool at crazy speeds. It was like a turbo-charged version of Limit Break, but for mana. Well, maybe it was nearly exactly like Limit Break? Limit Break improved him internally, and infusing his presence increased his control over the external world.

He hadn’t had time to test the mental attack yet, but only practiced with magic. He would need to find an opportunity before the Treasure Hunt to not go in blind, but he had a feeling it would be effective. He especially wanted to see if he could make it more effective if he coupled it with Gaze of the Apex Hunter.

Jake had also spoken a bit with Villy about the teaching skill when the god got curious, and Villy had just told him that teaching someone could be a good move. This surprised Jake, as he’d thought the overly selfish god didn’t really care much about other humans on Earth. That was, until Villy pointed out how teaching others could be good for personal improvement, and how he himself had learned a lot by going back over some of the basics while training someone else. Apparently, Villy had had quite a number of students through the times, even if Duskleaf was the only one Jake knew about.

Anyway, besides that, Jake had made another nice pile of elixirs and even gotten another level under his belt in just three days. He had nearly entered another trance again, but avoided it due to diversifying things with some Pride training and the chat with Villy.

Jake took out a Fungalmancer core to make another Vitality elixir. He wanted to try and make a rare-rarity one of those soon before he moved on to improving his Perception version. By now, he had realized he likely wouldn’t have time to make a rare-rarity version of the Perception elixir, but at least he could move up to uncommon.

Just as he got done melting the core… he stopped.

Something felt wrong. Very wrong. Jake’s gut was telling him things were off… It took him a second to realize the source. Sylphie…

Jake stopped the brewing, tossed his cauldron and its unfinished sludge in his inventory, and took to the air.

His presence was infused, directed ahead of him. The mana gave way as his will manifested, and a small platform of arcane mana appeared in the distance. Summoned using his Sphere of Perception and his presence working together.

He used One Step Mile in mid-air and appeared on the platform ahead of him. Within a quarter of a second, another platform was summoned ahead of him. This one he also stepped onto, teleporting yet again.

The upgrade to Pride had allowed this. Jake hadn’t even known it was possible before this very moment; he’d just had to find the fastest way to move forward. Because it was easier to manifest his mana inside his presence, it was fast enough. Did it consume a lot of mana? Yes, but right now, his primary priority was speed.

Jake had effectively just unlocked full-on, air-walk teleporting as he used One Step Mile forward into the horizon. He didn’t know where it was; he just had a gut feeling about the direction. Jake wasn’t even aware of what he was moving towards. All he knew was that Sylphie, Hawkie, and Mystie were in trouble.

A good while after he left the lodge, one of the enchantments around the time tree shattered with a bang—one that had been laid down by Mystie.

Hawkie dodged the scorching white ray within a feather’s breadth but was still sent tumbling through the air. He managed to stabilize himself and accidentally made eye contact with the uncaring gaze of the alpha before him.

[Goldsun Eagle Prima – lvl 144]

It was a nearly ten-meter-long golden eagle. Its radiant feathers gave off a constant glow as it bathed in sunlight, its entire body practically humming with power and potent energy similar to the sun above.

He knew their opponent barely cared about them. It knew it was above them—not by a little, either—and didn’t wish to waste any of its more prominent attacks. It was arrogant, with power to back up that arrogance. The only one it regarded as anything worth mentioning was Hawkie’s daughter, despite her low grade.

Which was exactly why they had told her to flee. Flee as they tried to hold back the monstrous eagle before them.

A blast of mystical mana hit the eagle from the side, but it failed to damage the radiant barrier around the beast. It was a hastily constructed attack that was unable to damage their opponent, but if anyone could allow them a chance, it was his mate.

Hawkie engaged again, attacking with a whirlwind to kick up the dust from far below. He surrounded the eagle in a tornado of sand and dust, obscuring its vision. Its mate began another ritual to summon a blast that would hopefully damage the eagle enough to dissuade it from chasing their daughter.

The summoned beasts had been slain swiftly. They didn’t even stand a chance and were only mild annoyances to the Eagle Prima. An annoyance as mild as the whirlwind of sand.

A golden explosion of light pushed Hawkie back, scorching his feathers, and his mate had to summon a barrier to defend herself. A second later, she was forced to stop her attack when a searing ray came for her. Yet again, the eagle didn’t press the attack but just observed them before tossing out a few more orbs of light towards Hawkie.

Was it playing with them? Didn’t it want to kill them? Why was it waiting like this? Hopefully, at least time would be on their side, though hope was slim.

His mate had already dispelled some of the enchantments back at the lodge around the time-related natural treasure, hoping the human would discover it. She had done this the moment they were discovered by the eagle. They didn’t know if it could do anything, but he hoped the human who had given him his name could do something.

Either way… at least his daughter had to escape.

"REE!" Hawkie suddenly heard from off in the distance. A sound that made his heart drop.

He looked around and saw the green shape of his daughter being pushed back by another figure. It was a large eagle, much like the one he and his mate were fighting, but a bit smaller and far weaker. Still stronger than his daughter, who had yet to evolve, though.

[Goldsun Eagle – lvl 131]

It was the Eagle Prima’s mate… Hawkie became clear on that because of the other new arrival.

Behind the new eagle, another small form flew, looking a lot like the two others.

[Juvenile Goldsun Eagle – lvl 92]

That was when Hawkie realized… just as they had gone there to help train their daughter and get her experience and teach her things, so had these eagles decided to use his family to train their spawn.

His mate—named Mystie by the human—had the same look of despair he did. The Eagle Prima was just weakening them, with the intent of having its spawn finish them off. They had done the same for their daughter so many times.

Their mutual look of despair quickly changed to one of determination. The situation was bad, but that didn’t mean they had nothing left. The two of them had been together since before the system. They were mates for life. That didn’t foster only trust, but also some amount of power. The two of them had chosen two parts of a greater skill—one they could only use when together.

One they had practiced not to face this kind of opponent, but for if the human ever turned into an enemy.

The Eagle Prima hadn’t noticed their look, or it didn’t care. It welcomed its mate with a screech, and its mate responded in kind with its spawn. Sylphie, as the human had named her, was pushed back towards Hawkie.

A final look was exchanged as they began.

Hawkie began glowing in a green light that soon turned deep blue and began crackling with lightning. Mystie began emitting purple myst. They didn’t need to screech or communicate—their gazes had said it all. The purpose was not to defeat the Eagle Prima. That would be foolish. The aim was to make a way out for Sylphie.

Mystie dodged a wave of light, searing her one wing. Hawkie was blasted by a small orb. Sylphie took a nasty scratch from a talon.

They were all forced together as the Eagle Prima spread its wings. Magic in the air moved as a bubble of light was erected around them, designed to seal them all in and damage them via the increasing temperature. It was so big that it would take Hawkie nearly fifteen seconds to fly across it. The accursed spawn of the eagles sat outside the bubble, cheerily watching the show.

It wouldn’t get that chance for much longer.

Two energies convened.

Storm and myst came together and mixed. A cloud of purple lightning was born as a thunderclap sounded out, and for the first time since this entire battle began, the Eagle Prima looked surprised. Mystie and Hawkie flew towards each other, at which point Mystie turned entirely to myst and began swirling around Hawkie.

Hawkie turned in mid-air, his wounds no longer mattering. He pushed his body to its utmost as he flew towards the mate of the Prima. Their young spawn was behind the second Goldsun Eagle, and it chose to defend. Foolishly believing it could.

The Prima also moved. It tried to block their path but was too slow. Hawkie, fused with Mystie, turned into a nearly fifteen-meter-long bird resembling a purple, hawk-shaped thundercloud as they crashed into the Goldsun Eagle.

Myststorm Union

A mighty explosion sounded out as purple thunder exploded out from the impact. The fused birds didn’t slow as they consumed the Goldsun Eagle and headed for the spawn behind the barrier, a dark figure with broken, glowing purple lines pulsing on its body the only thing in their wake. It would be dead within minutes without assistance.

They crashed through the barrier and destroyed it, but they didn’t get farther than that.

The Goldsun Eagle Prima appeared before them, more radiant than ever. Its rage at having seen its mate practically slain was on full display, and it opened its beak and fired out a massive breath of solar light.

The Myststorm Union was still a new skill. It took an incredible toll on both of them and could only be used for a single attack. Most of their energy had already been expended on the Goldsun Eagle and the barrier, meaning they ran on fumes when the solar beam hit them.

Myst was burned through, lightning was dispersed, and the union was broken. Two figures were sent tumbling through the air, both far more injured than before.

Hawkie had been the one infused… He should have been the one taking the brunt force of it… but at the very end, Mystie had concentrated her essence to defend. He saw her fall through the air, already unconscious and scorched black from the beam.

The only good thing was that they had at least bought time for Sylphie to—

A green form crashed into the side of the Eagle Prima, glowing green talons at the ready and aiming for the beast’s eyes. It waved its wing, smashing Sylphie down towards the ground.

She hit it hard, and she didn’t get back up.

Hawkie saw red and charged the eagle again, hoping to do… something. He thought of maybe taking its spawn hostage, but saw it was already encapsulated in a bubble of energy to defend it. He burned every shred of energy he had left and fired off a massive, crackling blade of wind and lightning.

All it did was make the eagle block, and the opening Hawkie hoped would come wasn’t there as a talon kicked him back, leaving a large hole in his chest. It was a hopeless battle. His mate was already bleeding out somewhere in the canyon, and there was nothing left. His vision began darkening, and he heard the cries of Sylphie below. She was no doubt trying to get up and keep fighting. She was proud and brave like that.

He wasn’t disappointed she hadn’t chosen to flee. He was sad, but he couldn’t be angry… only proud. He had many regrets as he felt himself slowly fade away, but he had done a lot. He had managed to foster a wonderful daughter and found the perfect mate. It was only too bad the journey would end here. He was reluctant to go, and he could only hate himself for failing his family.

The eagle moved in to finish him off for good, not leaving a single chance of survival. It opened its beak to fire out a beam as Hawkie’s vision gave out, and he felt the energy that would be his certain death begin collecting… then stop.

Everything seemed to stop.

Then… something came. Hawkie felt it. Another being… a presence… one more powerful than the Prima by far. He didn’t have time to recognize it before it arrived, but deep down, he knew. Hawkie couldn’t see anymore, but he heard the arrival.

One moment, the beam was about to be fired—the next, massive explosions sounded out. Two of them.

Hawkie’s fall ceased as he felt the familiar presence. A warm liquid entered his beak… one he also recognized. He felt the warmth spread in his body as he was swiftly moved through the air. He heard the cries of Sylphie, who seemed almost… panicked? There was no reason for that. Didn’t she understand?

A true apex predator had arrived.

Jake had teleported through the air, every step faster than the one before. With Limit Break active at 20%, every fiber of his being was focused. Mana condensed, he stepped, and he teleported, his momentum increasing as he ran.

His speed was faster than anything he had ever achieved before. Every step was over two hundred meters, with more than ten steps now taken a second.

He saw the eagle in the distance. He froze it. He took a few more dozen steps until he landed not on mana, but the back of the beast.

Every shred of momentum he’d built up for far over a thousand kilometers was released with that one footfall. Jake’s leg hurt as the veins on it burst, while the frozen eagle was sent smashing straight down, a crack sounding out as its weak bones also gave out.

His focus wasn’t on the beast, however. He felt anxious as he teleported again and summoned his wings. He caught Hawkie and quickly fed him a healing potion. A quick flight, and he reached Sylphie and gave her one too. She looked confused and afraid at his presence, screeching with warnings. Sylphie tried to make him leave. Jake just smiled as he picked her up and flew over to where he felt Mystie. She also got a potion as Jake laid down Hawkie and Sylphie beside her.

"Please, just stay here," he said with a soothing tone as he patted Sylphie. He also gave Hawkie a nod as he saw him weakly open one eye. "You did well, mate. Now let me handle the rest."

Jake turned around, his smile gone as he looked down the canyon at the Goldsun Eagle Prima below, his eyes burning with rage and presence blanketing that entire section of the canyon.

He wasn’t in a good mood.